[SINGING] So you want to
build a web app with Node,
but you're not sure where
to put all the code?
Express is what you need,
the framework to succeed,
to parse those
requests at high speed.
Route your GET, POST
PUT, and DELETE.
Add request and
response to complete.
Middleware will help
finesse modules clean up
the mess in the Building
Blocks of Express.
In this level, we'll
learn how to create routes
for POST and DELETE requests.
Then, we'll see how
we can use the
body-parser middleware to
read form-submitted data,
and then generate responses
with the proper HTTP status
code.
We want to be able
to create new blocks,
and to do that, we
need two things.
First, we need a form,
and we also need a POST route
in our Express application.
Once we're done, this is what
it's going to look like.
We'll fill out the
name of the block,
its description, click
the Submit button,
and we can see our new
block added to the list.
If we click on the block name,
we can see its description.
Now, to create new
blocks we're going
to issue POST requests to
the /blocks route.
We'll send the new block data
as the payload of the request,
which includes a name
and a description.
The response for a
successful request
will be a 201
Created status code
and the block name
as the response body.
Now let's see how we
can implement this.
In our index.html file,
we'll add a new form.
In this form, we'll need
two text field inputs:
one for name, and another
one for description.
And finally, a Submit button.
Don't worry about
form attributes,
like method and action.
We'll be adding them in
JavaScript in the next step.
In our client.js file, we
start by adding a listener
to the submit event
on the form element.
Then, we prevent the form from
being immediately submitted
by calling the prevent default
function on the event object.
Next, we wrap the
object "this" in a jQuery
object to make it
easier to work with,
and then assign it
to the form variable.
We call the serialized
function in the form object
and assign it to the
block data variable.
The serialized function
transforms form data
to URL encoded notation.
So our Express app can
parse it back to JavaScript.
We send this data in the
data property of our AJAX call,
which is a POST request
to the /blocks path.
When the request is done
and we receive the response,
we get the recently
created blockName
back as the argument for
the anonymous function.
Now, to add new
blocks for block list,
we'll reuse the appendToList
function from earlier.
However, this function
expects an array of blocks
and not a single block.
We'll get around this by
wrapping our argument in an array.
This way we avoid
changing original function
to expect different types of
arguments, which is something
bad and you shouldn't do.
Finally, we trigger
the reset event
on the form element, which clears the input text fields.
This is enough client code to add the new block to the list,
but let's make one final change.
In our appendToList function, we'll
replace our plain text blockName
with the link element.
When we click this link, we'll
be taken to the page that
displays the block description.
That's it for client side.
Now, let's jump into
our app.js file.
Before we can read data
that's sent from clients,
we need to install the
body-parser middleware, which
is not shipped with Express.
We do this with npm.
Then, from our app.js file,
we require the body-parser
module and assign it to
the body-parser variable.
On this variable, we call
the URL encoded function
with the options
extended set to false.
This option forces the use
of Node's native query parser
module, querystring.
The return value is a
middleware function,
which we store in the
parse URL encoded variable.
With this middleware
function in hand,
we create our endpoint for
posting to the blocks path.
And then use the parse
URL encoded function
as its first handler.
Turns out, routes can
take multiple handlers
as arguments, which will
get executed sequentially.
The second and final handler to
the POST route is the anonymous
function where we implement
the creation of a new block.
So the parse URL encoded
middleware will run first.
And then our anonymous
function will run second.
Using multiple route handlers
is useful for re-utilizing
middleware that does things like
validation, loading resources,
authentication, et cetera.
Inside of our route,
form data is available
on the request.body object.
Inside of a route, we'll create
a new variable called newBlock,
and assign it the
request.body object.
Each element in the form becomes
a property in this object,
like we can see here with
name and description.
We use those to add a new
block to the blocks object.
Finally, we set the status code
to 201 Created and the response
body to the new block name.
Now if we run our
code from the browser,
we can see that
everything works.
Fill in the block name,
block's description,
we submit the form, and
there's our new block.
If we click on it, we can
see its description.
That's it for this section.
Now it's your turn to
play around with some POST
routes in the challenges.