[SINGING] So you want to
build a web app with Node,
but you're not sure where
to put all the code?
Express is what you need,
the framework to succeed,
to parse those
requests at high speed.
Route your GET, POST
PUT, and DELETE.
Add request and
response to complete.
Middleware will help
finesse modules clean up
the mess in the Building
Blocks of Express.
Now it's time we start
reading user-submitted data
from within our Express routes.
Then, we'll see how we
can intercept requests
before they reach our routes,
which gives us a chance
to run some pre-condition checks
and do some data massaging
before our routes kick in.
So this is the code
that we have so far.
And as you can see, the /blocks
endpoint is always returning
all of the blocks.
Sometimes, though,
we might not want
to return all the blocks,
perhaps just one and two,
so it would be nice
if we had a way
to limit the number of
blocks that are returned,
and we can do that using
query string parameters.
Let's see what
that looks like.
In our current application, we
issue a GET request to /blocks,
which returns all the blocks.
What we want to do now is to
be able to use a query string
parameter to limit the
number of blocks returned.
Here, you can see we added the
limit query string parameter,
and we're giving
it a value of one.
Query strings always come
after the question mark,
so it's not part of the path,
but a parameter added to it.
With this path,
obviously we only
want one block to be
returned, which is Fixed.
If we set limit to two, then we
want two blocks returned, Fixed
and Movable.
Now let's jump back
to our code and see
how we can implement this.
Query string parameters are
added to request.query, which
you can access from our routes.
So from our existing
/blocks route,
we add a conditional that
looks at the limit property
on request.query and then
verifies if it's a valid number
for limit by checking if it's
greater than or equal to zero.
Otherwise, the else
block is evaluated
and responds with all
blocks, just like before.
Inside of our if
block, we'll return
a portion of the array
using the slice function.
Slice is a native
JavaScript function.
It takes two arguments.
The first one is where
the extraction begins,
and the second one
is where it ends.
Both are zero-based index.
So in this example, we start
at the first element, zero,
and slice it all
the way up, but not
including the number assigned to
limit, whatever that number is.
Now let's run our code.
Curl works just fine
with query strings,
so we'll use it to make
our first request, limiting
the results to one element.
You can see it returns Fixed.
Then, we'll make another
one, limiting the result
to two elements.
We can see it returns
Fixed and Movable.
But how about if we omit
the query string parameter?
Then, it would just list all the blocks,
like it was doing before.
Let's add another feature
to our application.
We want to be able to fetch
additional information
for each block, perhaps
its description.
Let's see how we can
do that by leveraging
the power of URL paths.
To fetch the description
for the Fixed block,
we want to create an
endpoint for /blocks/Fixed.
This endpoint should
return the 200 HTTP
status code and the
description for the Fixed block
in the response body.
For the Movable block,
we want an endpoint
for /blocks/Movable, which again
returns 200 and the description
for Movable in
the response body.
And this should also work for
all other existing blocks.
But how can we do
this without creating
individual static routes
like we've been doing so far?
The answer is using
dynamic routes.
Dynamic routes are very
similar to static routes,
except for the argument part.
These types of routes allow
us to define named arguments
as part of the URL path.
In this case, :name is the
argument part of the URL path.
Express will automatically
add named arguments
on routes as properties on
the request.params object.
This is how we'll access the
block name in just a minute.
But before we do
that, we'll need
to change how we
organize our blocks.
In order to store additional
information on each block,
we'll move from a JavaScript
array to a JavaScript object.
The names of blocks will
be the object properties,
and the description will be
their corresponding value.
From inside our
dynamic route, we'll
create a variable
called description
and set it equal to the
block's description, which
you can look up from
the block's object
by reading the name argument
from the request.params.
Then, we use the respond.json
function to generate the response.
This function also sets the
status code to 200 Success.
To test this out,
we're going to use
curl with that -i option
we've seen before,
which tells curl to include
response headers in the output.
We can see that a request
to /blocks/Fixed returns
the proper status code and
the correct description,
"Fastened securely in position."
And a request to
/blocks/Movable also returns 200
and the correct description,
"Capable of being moved."
Our work here is not done yet.
How about if we make a request
to a block that doesn't exist:
/blocks/Banana? Notice that,
although this block does not
exist, we get a successful
status code back,
and, weird enough, a
blank response body.
The proper way to
handle requests
for blocks that don't exist is
to return a 404 status code,
which stands for "Not Found."
It's also recommended to
include an explanation
of the error in
the response body
in order to help whoever is
making the request figure out
what's wrong.
So let's go back to our code and
see how we can implement this.
We're back in app.js, and when
we get a request for a block
name that doesn't exist and
try to look up its name, what
we get back is undefined.
In other programming
languages, we
might get an error in this
case, but not in JavaScript.
So thanks to the dynamic nature
of the JavaScript language,
we can add a conditional for the description variable.
If you remember, undefined is evaluated to false.
Notice we're using the exclamation point,
which flips the Boolean value and helps with legibility.
So when we do have a description set, we go into the else block
and run our previous code, which returns
the block's description.
Otherwise, when
description is undefined
and the conditional
evaluated to false,
we use the status function to
set the status code to 404.
Next, we call the JSON function
to compose an informative error
message using the name
sent in the request.
If we make a request again for
a block that doesn't exist,
we'll get a 404 status code
back and the friendly error
description, "No description
found for Banana."
That's it for this section.
Now it's your turn to
try some dynamic routes
in the challenges.