Our current app.js file is
indeed free of repetition,
but you'll notice that
it's growing way too long.
In a real-world
application, it's
likely that we're going to
be dealing with more than one
or two routes, which means
that it would grow even longer.
A single file with
too many lines of code
is an indication
of a code smell.
We can get around this
by extracting our routes
to modules.
And doing this helps clean up
our code, and allows our routes
file to accommodate additional
routes in the future.
Ideally, we would require
the routes from a module,
and then mount them in
the application instance
by using app.use.
Now, let's see how we can do this using Node's module system.
First thing we do is
we create a dedicated
folder just for our routes.
All of our routes files
will go into this folder.
Then, we create a
routes file for blocks,
and call it blocks.js.
We require the Express
module, and then call
the router function.
This function returns a
router instance, which
can be mounted as a middleware.
To be able to access this
router from our app.js file.
we assign it to module.exports.
This exports the router
as a Node module.
Now, we're going to start moving
stuff from our app.js file
into this new blocks.js file.
We start by moving
the body-parser
in the blocks object,
which holds reference
to all existing blocks.
Our objective here is to
have all block-related logic
encapsulated inside
of this file.
Next, we build
our router object,
which now looks a little
different than before.
Notice there's no blocks in
the argument, just slash.
This is because
the path argument
is relative to where this router
is mounted in our app.js file.
If you remember,
back in app.js, we're
mounting this router on
the /blocks path,
so all paths here are assumed
to be nested under /blocks.
Still using the
same chaining function
calls, we'll move our routes
for GET and POST into this file,
and they still look
the same as before.
For the dynamic
/blocks/:name route,
we'll stick with the
same format as before.
And just like our
previous route instance,
we don't need the
/blocks part, either — just
the :name argument, which,
again, is relative to the path
where our router is
mounted in app.js.
Now, remember that
parsing code that
turns first characters to
uppercase and all remaining
characters to lowercase,
and used to live in app.param?
Well, we'll move it over
here to a new route, which we
haven't talked about yet: ALL.
The ALL route is called for
all requests for a given path.
It's an alternative
to app.param,
and you could use either one,
but for this specific scenario,
we're going to use ALL.
Next, we'll chain function calls
to the GET and DELETE routes,
which should look
the same as before.
By now, it should
look apparent to you
that when a request comes
in for this route, first
it's going to hit the
ALL route, and then
filter through the appropriate
action — GET or DELETE.
We've moved a lot
of stuff around.
So let's take a
moment to look at what
our complete blocks routes
file looks like now that we've
extracted it to a Node module.
Our routes file is now ready to
be mounted in our application.
Now, that new code from
app.js that we saw earlier
should make a little
bit more sense.
First, we require our blocks
routes file, and assign it
to the blocks variable.
Then, we mount our blocks
routes in the blocks path.
All requests to the blocks path
are dispatched to this router.
Our app.js file is now ready
to support additional features
from various other routes,
like buildings, users, et
cetera, without turning into an excessively long file.
As you can see, it looks clean and manageable.
That's it for this section.
Now, it's your turn to
refactor some routes
and place the last
building blocks of Express
in the challenges.