[SINGING] So you want to
build a web app with Node,
but you're not sure where
to put all the code?
Express is what you need,
the framework to succeed,
to parse those
requests at high speed.
Route your GET, POST,
PUT, and DELETE.
Add request and
response to complete.
Middleware will help
finesse modules clean up
the mess in the Building
Blocks of Express.
So we've added all the
basic functionality
that our app needs to work.
But in the process, we've
let some code smells arise.
Now, it's time we learned some
refactoring techniques, which
can help us remove
some code duplication
and make our code a lot
easier to work with.
Looking at our
app.js file, notice
that all routes seem
to be handling operations
on URLs that look very similar.
Some of them look
exactly the same.
The first and third routes both
handle the /blocks path,
but for different HTTP
verbs: GET and POST.
And the same goes for the
second and fourth routes,
both handling /blocks/:name,
but one for GET requests
and the other one
for DELETE requests.
It would be nice
if we could avoid
having to repeat all
these route names.
Let's see how we can do that.
To avoid this repetition,
we'll use something
called route instance.
We create route instances
with an app.route function.
This function takes the
path as the argument
and returns a route
object that handles
all requests to the given
path — in this case, blocks.
On this route object, we call
our functions GET and POST.
Only this time, no path
argument is needed.
Because a route object was
created for a specific route,
we avoid having to repeat
the paths like we were
doing before.
This used to be
app.get slash blocks.
And this one used to be
app.post slash blocks.
We can make this
code even shorter
by getting rid of the
blocksRoute variable.
BlocksRoute is only an
intermediate variable,
and it's not being used anywhere
else in our application.
To do this, we'll use something
called chain functions.
You'll notice that we
removed the semicolon
from the end of the line where
a route object was created.
This means the statement
continues on the next line.
Then, we started the
next line with a dot,
which indicates a function
call on the returned value
from the previous line,
which is a route object.
The route GET and
POST functions all
return a route instance, which
allows us to chain our function
calls like this.
Chaining function calls means
calling functions on the return
value of previous functions.
And this is a pattern commonly
found in Express applications.
Moving on to our
next route, this one
is a dynamic route, which takes
the block name as an argument.
As you can see, the
add.route function
accepts the same URL
argument format as before,
and this returns a route object.
Now, we can chain
functions, adding our routes
for GET and DELETE, again
without having to repeat
the path for each one.
This is the end of this section.
Now it's your turn to take a
stab at it in the challenges.