[SINGING] So you want to
build a web app with Node,
but you're not sure where
to put all the code?
Express is what you need,
the framework to succeed,
to parse those
requests at high speed.
Route your GET, POST
PUT, and DELETE.
Add request and
response to complete.
Middleware will help
finesse modules clean up
the mess in the Building
Blocks of Express.
You're watching Building
I'm Carlos Souza, and
in this first level,
we'll introduce you
to Express and see
why it's the framework of choice
of many popular web services.
We'll quickly go over how
to install Express using npm
and then jump right into
building our Web API.
In case you're
not aware, Express
is a web application
framework for Node.js.
It's minimal and
flexible, and it's
great for building
Web APIs, which
we'll do in just a minute.
It's used by popular services
like MySpace and the Ghost
blogging platform.
It's also the foundation for
other tools and frameworks,
like Kraken and Sails.js.
We can install
Express using npm,
or the node package manager.
The npm install Express command
will download and install
the latest version of Express
from the npm registry.
If we need to be more specific
about the version that's
installed, we can specify
the version number
after the @ sign, like this.
npm install express@4.9 installs
the latest version from the 4.9
branch.
Or if we need to
be really specific,
we can ask for the exact
version that we want.
npm install express@3.15.2 will
install this specific version.
This course covers the
4.9 version of Express.
Let's start with a simple
Hello World application.
The following code will
create a simple Web API
server that accepts HTTP
requests on the root path,
or slash, and responds with
the string, "Hello world."
First thing we do is
require the Express library.
We get a function back.
When we run that function, we
get an application instance,
which we store in
the app variable.
On the app object, we can call
functions that create routes.
The get function creates a route
that accepts HTTP GET requests.
Back in our get
function, we'll give it
a path to route, which is going
to be the root path, or slash,
and a callback
function, which will
run each time our application
receives a GET request
on the root path.
The callback takes a request
and a response object
and will use the response object
to send back the text, "Hello
world."
Lastly, we bind our
application to TCP port 3000.
Express also has other
built-in functions
named after other HTTP verbs,
like post, put, delete,
which we'll be looking
at in just a little bit.
The listen function also takes
an optional callback function
as a second argument, which
will run once your application's
ready to receive requests.
So once our server's
up, it's going
to print, "Listening
on port 3000."
To run our Express app, we
use the Node command followed
by the file name, app.js.
And as you can see, it prints
out, "Listening on port 3000."
Now, to issue request your
app, we're going to use curl.
A request to local host port
3000 returns the "Hello world"
response.
One thing about Express apps,
and pretty much any other Node.js
application, is
that whenever we
change code in our application,
we must restart our process.
The simplest way to do
that from the command line
is using Control-C.
It is important to understand
that Express extends Node.js.
The request and response
objects actually
inherit from Node HTTP.
To see what this looks
like, let's take a peek
at the source code from Express.
So inside of Express, the
request object's prototype
is set to the same prototype
as http.IncomingMessage,
which is an object from Node.
And the response object's prototype
is set to the same prototype as http.ServerResponse,
also from Node.
This is what inheritance looks like in JavaScript.
In other words, the request object inherits
from IncomingMessage, and the response object inherits
from ServerResponse.
The source code for Express is very idiomatic JavaScript,
which means it's easy to understand,
and it's very well written.
It's publicly available, being an open source project,
so I highly recommend you take some time to go through it.
But what does this
inheritance really give us?
Well, it gives us the ability
to call Node functions
from Express apps.
Let's take a look.
We go back to our previous
"Hello world"  example.
In our callback
function, we call
the response.write
function, passing
in the "Hello world" string.
Then we finish the response
by calling response.end.
Both response.write
and response.end
are Node functions.
So before, we're using the
response.send function,
and now, we're
using response.write
and response.end, which
are both Node functions.
And having this ability to
reach out to Node from Express
is extremely useful, as we'll
see in just a little bit
once we start writing
extensions for Express.
If we run this code,
we can see that we
get the exact same
output as before.
Now let's look at
another example.
When writing Web
APIs in Express,
we'll quite often be
working with data structures
like objects and arrays,
instead of just strings.
And we're going to want to
serialize those to JSON,
so let's create a new route
that responds with a collection
of blocks in JSON.
We'll name
our route "blocks."
Inside of this
route, we'll create
an array with three elements —
Fixed, Movable, and Rotating —
and assign it to
the blocks variable.
In order to serialize this
array to JSON, all we have to do
is pass the array to our old
friend, the send function.
The send function will
convert this array
to JSON and set the proper
response headers automatically.
Now let's make a request
to this route using curl,
with the -i option, which tells
curl to also print the response
headers.
As we can see, we get a 200 status code response back,
and the Content-Type response header
was set to application/json.
And lastly, we can see the response body, "Fixed", Movable",
and "Rotating", in JSON format.
If all we're doing is
responding with a JSON format,
there's another
function we can use
that reads a little bit better.
The JSON function
behaves exactly the same
as the send function
for objects and arrays.
If we run curl again, we can see
that the Content-Type response
header is still set to application/json.
But what if instead of objects
and arrays, we pass in a string
to the send function?
Well, then Express will
send back that string as-is.
If we make a request to this endpoint,
we can see that the Content-Type header was set to text/html.
Responding with HTML straight from our routes, like we're
doing here, is not something that we typically
do in Express applications.
If you want to do
server-side rendering,
you might want to look into templating libraries,
like EJS and Jade.
What if we need to move an
existing route to a different
location — for example,
/blocks to /parts?
We're going to want to redirect
requests to the new /parts
route.
To do this, we use the
response.redirect function,
passing in the destination
path as the argument.
So next time my request
comes in for /blocks,
our application's going
to respond with a redirect
to /parts.
If we make a request
with curl, we
can see that we get back a
status code set to 302, which
stands for "moved temporarily."
According to the HTTP
spec, the 302 status code
also requires a location
header to be set.
As we can see here, the location
header is set to /parts,
which is the argument that we
use for the redirect function.
And finally, a
friendly response body
is included: "Moved Temporarily.
Redirecting to /parts."
Since our /blocks path will
now forever redirect to the
/parts, we need to make this
a permanent redirect and use
the 301 status code.
To redirect using a
different status code
other than the default 302,
we pass the status code
as the first argument to
the redirect function,
like we see here.
Now when we run curl, we can see that Express sets the status
code to 301 and updates the response body, which
now says, "Moved Permanently."
That's it for this level.
Have fun in the challenges.