One problem with our
current dynamic routes
is that they only match
on exact block names.
When we make a request to
/blocks/Fixed with a capital F,
it is able to find the
description for that block
and respond successfully.
However, if we use a different
case for the block name,
say fixed all in lowercase, it
returns a Not Found response.
Let's see how we can
normalize request parameters
and make it so our Express
application can respond
to different casing variations.
Let's start with
our existing code,
but before we add any
new behavior, let's
refactor some of this.
This line, for example, is doing
two things at the same time.
It's reading the
request parameter
and looking up the
object's properties.
Let's split that to
improve code clarity.
First, we'll create a
variable called name
and assign it the value
from request.params.name.
Then, on the next line, we'll
create a variable named block.
To this variable we'll
assign the normalized name
of the block.
To normalize, we'll convert the
first character to uppercase
and all remaining
characters to lowercase.
Now the name stored
in the block variable
matches the same format using
the properties of the blocks
object.
That's all there is to it.
Now let's go back and
see if our code works.
First, we make a request to
/blocks/Fixed with a capital F.
We get back a
successful response
and the block's description,
"Fastened securely in position."
Then, another request to
/blocks/fixed all in lowercase
and it also works.
Finally, we get a little
crazy and alternate
between uppercase and
lowercase, and it still works.
Clearly our code
works, but what if we
need to create additional
dynamic routes that need to use
the same parameter parsing?
For example, if
we add an endpoint
that returns locations
for a specific block.
Let's call this /locations/name.
If we wanted this endpoint
to run the same parsing
code, making the first character
capital and the remaining
characters lowercase, we'd
need to copy and paste
our original parsing code.
And as you can probably
imagine, this copy and pasting
leads to messy code and
potential bugs in the future.
Now let's look at another
feature of Express
that can help us get
around this duplication.
Our application
instance has a function
called param, which allows
us to intercept parameters
sent by client requests.
We call this function
passing the parameter name
we want to intercept, in
this case, "name," followed
by a middleware function,
which, as you might remember
from earlier, takes a
request and response
object and a next function.
We'll move our previous parsing
code here, untouched, and add
two more lines.
First, we'll assign the block
variable to a new property
on the request object
called blockName.
This makes it so
that blockName can
be accessed by all routes
in the application.
Finally, we call next
so that the request
can move on to the next
function in the stack.
Going back to our routes, we
can remove all the parsing code
and simply access the
blockName on the request object.
Using request.blockName, we can
look up the block's description
and the block's location.
Our code is now a
lot easier to read.
Now if we go back to curl
again and make a request
to /blocks/fixed
all in lowercase,
we can see that it works.
And then, our request to
/location/fixED, with only "ED"
in uppercase, that works too.
Our code is clean, but if we
go back and visit our web app,
we'll notice that things
are a little different.
Initially, we had a
list of block names,
but we must have done
something and now
our web page is listing
block descriptions.
I wonder what caused that?
If you remember, when we first
wrote our blocks endpoint,
we were assigning a JavaScript
array to the blocks variable.
Then, we added our dynamic route
for /blocks/name and changed
the blocks data structure
from an array to a JavaScript
object, which is exactly
what introduced a bug.
If we look into
our /blocks route,
we'll see that we're sending
in the entire JavaScript object
to the JSON function
when in reality,
all we want is the
object's properties
or the object's keys.
To fix this, we use the
Object.keys function,
which returns an array with
the object's properties.
Once we fix our code, we can
go back and test things out.
If we visit our
web page again,
we can see that the
block names are listed,
and if we issue a curl request
to the /blocks endpoint,
we will see the list
of block names in JSON.
We've reached the
end of this section.
Now it's your turn to code some
user params in the challenges.