Now it's time we learn
how to build our own custom
middleware.
Together, we'll build a very
simple logger middleware
that displays the duration
of each request made
to our application.
When we're done, this is what
the end result will look like.
We can see that it
printed each request made
to the application along
with how long each one took.
Now let's jump to the code.
We start by creating a new file
for our logger named logger.js.
On this file, we
create a function
with the middleware
signature we've
seen before, taking a
request and response
object and the next function.
To export this function
to the outside world
and make it accessible to other
files that require this module,
like we'll do from
apps.js in just a minute,
we assign our function
to module.exports.
This module.exports style that
Node uses is called CommonJS,
and you're going to see this
all throughout Express and Node
applications.
Our logger middleware will
be called for each request
and before any of our routes.
In order to track the
duration for each request,
the first thing
that we do is use
the date object to get the exact
time when this function started
to run, and we'll store that
in a variable called start.
The plus sign converts
the date object
to the number of milliseconds
elapsed since January 1, 1970.
This is a standard widely
adopted in the Unix community,
where Express and Node borrow
a lot of conventions from.
Later, we're going to use
this start time to determine
the duration of the request.
Before we forget, let's go
ahead and add a call to next
to the bottom of
this file, which
moves the request to the
next middleware in the stack
once we're done.
We're going to be
writing our log
messages to standard output.
Standard output is
a writable stream,
which you can access through
the process.stdout property.
We'll set this to a variable
called stream so we can easily
use this later.
From the request
object, which was
passed in as an argument
to our function,
we'll get the request
URL and the HTTP method
used in the request and store
them on the URL and method
variables.
We'll need them to build
our logger message.
We need to know when
the request is finished,
but we've seen that
middleware runs sequentially.
So how can our logger know
when the request is finished
and calculate its duration?
The answer is by
listening to events.
Turns out the response
object is an event emitter.
It emits the finish event when
the response has completed
and has been handed off
to the operating system.
Here we've attached an
event listener callback,
which runs asynchronously.
Inside of our callback, we
can calculate the duration
by getting the current
time again using a new date
object and the same
plus sign trick
and subtracting the start time.
Next, we'll append the
method, URL, and duration,
and assign it to the
message variable.
We add two line
breaks at the end
to make it easier to
read in the console.
Finally, we print the
log message to standard
out by calling the write
function the stream object
and passing our
message as an argument.
And this is what our complete
logger code looks like.
Going back to app.js we can
now require our logger module.
And notice how we're
using dot slash,
which means it's a local
module and not an npm module.
What we get back is a
middleware function,
which we store in
the logger variable.
Then, we add it to the
stack by passing it
as an argument to app.use.
Now that's it for our logger.
Let's run our app
and see this working.
We fire up our Node app,
see that it's listening,
visit the browser, and we
can see each request printed
to the console, along with
the number of milliseconds
that it took to
process each one.
For a more complete
logging solution
I suggest you check out
this project called Morgan.
Morgan accepts options
for different outputs
and an optional destination file
where we can write our logs to.
The code is very easy
to read, and it's
where we got inspiration
to write our own custom
logger from.
Now that's it for level two.
You have fun writing your
own custom middleware
in the challenges.