Now we want to be able to
delete existing blocks.
To do that, we're going to need
a link next to each block name.
Once we click the
link and confirm,
we want that block to be
removed from the list.
And this should
persist on the server,
so if we refresh
the page, we can
see the block is
no longer in there.
From an API perspective,
what we want
is to make a DELETE request
to the blocks endpoint —
say, /blocks/Flying —
and we want to get a 200
Success response back.
The response body
should be set to "OK."
Now, let's see how we
can implement this.
We'll start by adding
a DELETE link next
to each of our blocks.
To add a DELETE link
to each of our blocks,
we'll jump back to
our client.js file.
We'll add an href element,
setting the block name
to the data-block
attribute, which we will use
to compose the AJAX request.
Then, we'll add an image
tag for Delete Image.
And that's enough to
display the links.
Now, we need to capture
click events on those links.
Then, we'll listen for
click events triggered
on that element
from any links that
have a data-block attribute.
The first thing that we want
to do in our event handler
is to add a confirmation.
It's always good
to add confirmation
for destructive actions like
destroying records, updating
records, et cetera.
If we click Cancel
on the confirmation,
then it's going to
return false here,
and it's going to stop
executing the event handler.
Next, we get the link
that triggered the click
event by reading the current
target property on the event
object.
Then, we wrap it
on a jQuery object
to make it easier to
work with and assign it
to the target variable.
Finally, we make the
AJAX DELETE request.
The URL path for
the request will
be /blocks/ the
block name, which
we fetch by reading the block
name from the link's data-block
attribute.
Once that AJAX call is
done, we find the parent LI
element for the click link,
and remove it from the page.
That's it for a client code,
which should be familiar.
If any of this stuff
feels a little strange,
you might want to check out
some of our jQuery courses.
Now, let's go back to the
Express side of things.
In our app.js file, we
create a DELETE route
by calling our DELETE function,
passing in the URL path,
and, just like the previous
dynamic routes we've written,
the DELETE route also
takes the block name
as the argument, :name.
We fetch the specific block
name from the blockName
property in the request
object, which, in case
you don't remember, is
being sent from app.param.
Then, we use the DELETE
operator from JavaScript
to remove that block
from our blocks object.
Finally, we call the
send status function
with a 200 status code.
We use send status when we don't
want to manually set a response
body.
This function does
it automatically
for us based on the status code
that we used as the argument.
The reason for this
is that some clients
can't handle empty
responses very well,
with jQuery being one of them.
So calling send status with 200
sets the response body to "OK."
Now, when we go back
and run our app again,
we can see that it
works as expected.
We delete the block,
and when we refresh
the page, we can
see it's no longer
part of the list.
That's it for this section.
Why don't you give it a
try in the challenges?