[SINGING] So you want to
build a web app with Node,
but you're not sure where
to put all the code?
Express is what you need,
the framework to succeed,
to parse those
requests at high speed.
Route your GET, POST
PUT, and DELETE.
Add request and
response to complete.
Middleware will help finesse
modules clean up
the mess in the Building
Blocks of Express.
Middleware are essentially the
building blocks of Express.
And in this level, we'll learn
what they are, how they work,
and how we can use them to build
rich JavaScript applications.
Express is a great
fit for building
Web APIs, which can easily be
consumed by rich JavaScript
applications built
with Ember, Angular,
or, if it's simple
enough, jQuery,
which is what we're
going to be using here.
These types of web apps allow
for more interactive experience
on the web, and they have
never been more popular.
Now, the concept behind them
is not so hard to understand.
First, the browser issues the
initial request to the server.
The server responds with HTML.
Further requests are issued
through JavaScript and AJAX.
The server responds with
data, typically in JSON,
and the client uses that JSON
to update elements on the page.
This way, interacting
with the application
does not trigger
full page reloads.
So let's see how we can
build this using Express.
We'll start with a
simple index.html file.
The important parts of this
file is the title element,
Building Blocks, and
an H1 element, Blocks.
We'll place this file in
a folder called "public."
To serve this file
from Express, we'll
create a get route
for the root path.
Then, from our
callback, we'll use
the response.sendFile function.
This function takes the path
of the file we want to serve.
We use the __dirname,
which returns the current
path of the application.
Then, we append
/public/index.html,
which causes the index.html
file to be served back
to the client.
Finally, we'll
listen on port 3000.
When we run our app and
visit it from a browser,
we can see our index.html
is being served and rendered
properly.
Another way that we can
write this functionality
is using the Express
static middleware,
which is the only
middleware that's
currently shipped with Express.
To use this middleware, we
call the static function
in our Express object.
We pass it the root
folder where we want
to serve our static files from.
The return value of
that function call
is passed to the
app.use function,
and this is all we need to
do to serve static files
from the public folder.
Now, if we run our app again
and visit it from the browser,
we can see that the
result is the same.
The static middleware defaults
to serving the index.html file.
But before we go
any further, let's
take a moment to understand
what middleware is.
Middleware and
Express are functions
added to the stack that
have access to the request
and response objects and
are executed sequentially.
Inside of each middleware,
we can do things
like validation, authentication,
data parsing, and whatnot.
So when a request
comes in, it passes
through each of these middleware
before reaching our routes,
as you can see here.
An Express application
is essentially
a stack of middleware
running one after the other.
It's kind of like
a plumbing pipe.
Requests start at
the first middleware
and work their way
down the stack.
So let's look at
the following stack.
So a request comes
in, and it starts
being processed in
middleware A, which
is added to the stack
using the app.use function.
Middleware A, like
any other middleware,
is a function that takes
the request and response
objects as an argument, as
well as the next function.
The next function must
be called in order
to move processing to the next
middleware in the sequence.
So calling next from
middleware A moves processing
to middleware B. Calling next
from B moves processing to C,
and so on.
So we keep doing that until
we reach a point where
we want to respond
back to the client,
and this can be either from
a route or from a middleware,
as we can see here.
We call response.send
from middleware N
and complete the request.
In this other graph,
middleware A calls next,
and middleware B responds
back to the client.
The flow stops once the
response is sent back,
and any remaining
middleware in the stack
or user-defined
routes will not run.
So if you try calling next after
the response has completed,
we'll get all sorts
of weird errors.
The source code for
static is a good example
of how middleware
works in Express.
It's only around
100 lines of code,
and it's easy to spot
the important parts
that we've talked about here.
If we look in the source, we
can see that static only cares
about GET or HEAD requests.
For any other type of
request, static calls
next and immediately
passes processing
to whoever is next on the stack.
Otherwise, it does its work,
and at the bottom of the file,
you see something like
this, a send stream which
pipes its content to
the response object —
so, pretty straightforward
Node code.
If you're used to
semicolons, then you're
probably bothered by this.
Yes, a pattern found
in the source code
for static is the
lack of semicolons,
but the code still works.
Now that we understand
how middleware works,
let's go back to our code.
We add an image tag
to our HTML file
and place a new image file named
"blocks.jpg" under the public
folder.
Once we restart our app
and visit the root URL
from the browser, we can see
the image displayed on the page.
The static middleware
will serve everything
under the specified folder—
in this case, public.
We've learned how to
serve static files,
like our index.html, and other
static assets, like images.
But that's only the first part
into building rich JavaScript
applications in Express.
Now it's time we
learn how to load data
from Express using AJAX calls.
Once we're done, this is
what our application's
going to look like.
These block names for
Fixed, Movable, and Rotating
are all going to be
loaded using AJAX.
To do this, we go
back to our HTML
file and add a UL element
with a class of block-list.
Then, we'll add two
JavaScript files: jQuery
to help us manipulate the
DOM and simplify AJAX calls,
and client.js,
which is where we'll
place our custom
client-side code that
will talk to our Express API.
Finally, we'll add a style sheet
to our page to make it pretty
and an image file,
bg-stars, which will
be the background to our page.
All of these files are placed
under the public folder
so they can be served by
the static middleware.
From client.js, we'll
make our AJAX calls.
Using jQuery's get function,
we'll issue a request
to the /blocks endpoint, which
should return a list of blocks.
The return value of the AJAX
call is passed as an argument
to the appendToList function.
append.ToList creates an
empty array named "list."
Then, it iterates through
each of the blocks
and creates an LI
element for each one,
with a text set
to the block name.
Finally, we append
our list to the page.
Now, back in our app.js file,
we'll create a new route
for the /blocks endpoint.
You've seen this code before.
And what it's doing is
creating an array of blocks
and serializing it
back to the client
using the
response.JSON function.
Now let's load up
our application,
visit the browser,
local host 3000.
We can see that it works.
Now, let's do it again
and inspect the page
with DevTools.
Notice the request here.
There's one for the HTML,
and then the page does a GET
request to the /blocks endpoint.
We can even look
at the data that
was sent back from our server.
There's our JSON.
In case you're not
familiar with DevTools,
you might want to check
out the Discover DevTools
course on the Electives Path.
That's it for this section.
I'll see you after
the challenges.