[SINGING] Deep within the jungle
lie treasures most unknown.
To track what we uncover,
we'll need to use Django.
AJAX, forms and grids,
we'll cross the pyramids.
Dust off your old durangos -
we're Digging Into Django.
Welcome back to
Digging Into Django.
This is level five, section one,
where we'll be going over Ajax.
We'd like to add a like
button to keep track
of the number of likes
for each treasure,
whether you're on the home
page or the detail page.
We'll also want to use
AJAX for the requests
so that the page will display
the new number of likes
without having to refresh
the entire page again.
So it's probably pretty
familiar to you by now,
but we'll want to create
a URL, view and template.
So the plan for creating
this like button
will be to create a URL
at localhost/like_treasure
that will go to our like_treasure
view, which will then
calculate the total number of
likes and update the database.
And then our index
and detail templates
will display the like button
and the updated number of likes.
And then we'll add
these two extra steps,
add AJAX to process
our request, and we'll
add a like field to
the treasure model
so it can save a
treasure's likes.
Let's tackle our model
first since we'll
need to access the likes in
the view and the templates.
We'll add likes as
an integer field
and we'll set its
default to be zero.
We can then migrate this
change to the database
by running python manage.py
makemigrations followed
by python manage.py migrate.
Then, in both of our templates,
at the bottom of the treasure
panel, we'll add a Like button.
This will use bootstraps button
class as well as glyphicon
to display a heart.
And for showing the
number of likes,
we'll check if the likes
are greater than zero
and then display them.
Otherwise, we won't show
anything except the heart icon.
Before we look at
updating the view,
let's look at this
process without using
AJAX or the process
that we're used to.
Let's look at the
process for when
a user requests the home page.
The URL dispatcher will
then send that request
to the index view,
which will look up
all of the treasures
in the database,
and then we'll
render the template
with all of those
treasures and generate
the corresponding HTML.
Then, any clicked
links within that page
will go through the
URL dispatcher again.
So if we want to
add AJAX to prevent
the page from refreshing when
we click the Like button,
things are going
to change a bit.
Parts of this process
will still be the same.
We're still going to
load the index.html file.
But when the Like
button is clicked,
the JavaScript is going to
intercept this click event.
The JavaScript will then get
the ID of the treasure that
was clicked and pass it
through the URL dispatcher
to our new like_treasure view.
Our like_treasure view will then
look up the treasure by its ID
and save the new
number of likes.
It will then take
that number of likes
and send that back
to our JavaScript.
Our JavaScript will then
update the Like button
with the new number of likes.
We could write this AJAX
in standard JavaScript,
but we're going to
use jQuery to help us
because it has a lot of
AJAX built-in functions.
So we'll download the latest
version of jQuery and put it
in our main_app/static/js
folder.
And then we'll also
create our main.js
for writing our application's
specific AJAX code.
We're going to show
you all the jQuery you
need to work with Django, but
if you want to find out more,
you can check out
our jQuery courses.
To include these new
JavaScript files,
we'll want to add
them to base.html,
and then they'll be available
to all the templates
that inherit from base.
In our main.js file, we'll
start by adding a button click
listener.
And when that button
is clicked, we'll
prevent the default
action and we'll capture
that button in a variable.
We'll then add a
jQuery AJAX function,
which takes in the
parameters URL, which will
go to our like treasure URL.
We'll use a GET request.
And the data is any information
we want to pass to the view.
We want to get the
treasure_id, and we
can get that by looking
up the data-id attribute
of the clicked button.
You might have missed
it, but we created
this data-id attribute inside
our button in the index
template.
So now we can see in our diagram
that we just got the treasure_id
and sent it to our URL.
Now we'll need to actually
create that like_treasure
URL in the corresponding view.
Our new URL will
be like_treasure
and we'll go to the
like_treasure view.
In our new like
treasure view, we'll
start by getting our
treasure_id from the request.
Then, we'll initialize a local
likes variable set to zero.
Then we'll check if our
treasure_id was actually
received from the get
request, and if it was,
we'll look up the treasure
that corresponds to that id.
So then if that
treasure is not none,
we'll look up its
number of likes,
and increase them by
one, and save that
into our local likes variable.
We'll then update that
treasures number of likes
and save it to the database.
Finally, we'll return our
likes as an HTTP response,
since that's what our
AJAX is expecting.
If we look at our
diagram again, we
can see we now got the
treasure by its id in our view,
and then saved its number
of likes to the database.
And then we returned that
new number of likes back
to our AJAX.
Back in our AJAX,
we need to capture
that returned number
of likes, and we can do
that in the success function.
We'll then update
our button element
with the new number of likes.
Notice that number of likes
that got sent from the view
is captured in this variable
that we called response.
So if we look at our
AJAX diagram again,
we can see we completed
our final step
of updating the like button
with the new number of likes.
And now we can see our new
fancy like button in action.
It instantaneously updates
without refreshing the page.
And if we click into the detail
view, the number of likes
is still correct.
Now it's time for
you to add AJAX
to your app in the challenges.