Welcome back.
In this section, we'll
be adding a detail page.
Now that our home
page is displaying
a grid of just images,
we'd like to be
able to click on
one of those images,
and be brought to
the detail page
to show more details
about our treasures.
The URL for the
detail page will be
localhost/id of the
treasure we're displaying.
For example, here
we have localhost/15
which is the id of the
golden monkey displayed.
For the new detail
page we'll need
to create this new
URL in urls.py.
Create a detail
view in views.py.
And create a
detail.html template.
We'll start by adding
our details URL.
This URL will capture any
number, save that number,
and then send it
to the detail view.
This regular expression
is a little more complex
than the one we saw before.
So let's break it down.
In our existing index URL,
we're not checking for any path.
Which means, it would
just match local host.
But now we want to
capture a number.
And how we do that
is with square
brackets 0 through 9 plus.
And that will match any number.
So then we just add
parenthesis and that
will capture that number, which
means it will then be passed
as a parameter to the detail view.
For instance, localhost/0.
That 0 would be captured, and
then passed to the detail view
as a parameter.
We're going to show
you all the regex
you need to create this app, and
to go through the challenges.
But if you're really
interested in knowing more,
you can check out
our Breaking the Ice
with Regular Expressions course.
So we said that this number
would be captured by the URL
and passed to the detail view.
So when we create
our detail view,
we'll have two parameters.
Request and then whatever
we name that number,
and we're going to
call it treasure ID.
Now we want to get the treasure
that corresponds to that ID.
So we can do
treasure.objects.get
and then check if that ID
is equal to treasure ID.
You may be wondering
where this ID
field came from in the model.
Because if we look at our
model, there is no ID field.
So how did we look up
a treasure by its ID?
By default, Django
automatically provides us
with an auto-incrementing
primary key field.
That means we can look up a
specific treasure with this ID
field, and every treasure is
guaranteed to have a unique ID.
Back in the detail view,
we can pass the template
the treasure we just looked up.
Now that we have the
URL and view set up,
the last step is to put
together our template.
This is a new template
called detail.html.
And because we passed
in the treasure object,
we can access all of its fields,
like name, image URL, value,
and location.
We haven't added any style yet
just to see that it's working.
To add some style
to our page we'll
basically copy the same styles
we added to the home page,
but we don't need a for
loop because we're only
displaying one single treasure.
I know we've added a lot
of HTML and CSS here,
but it's specific to the design
we've created for our page.
And you don't have to
memorize it or anything
because each app you create
will have its own HTML and CSS
elements.
So now we have all of the pieces
to our detail view in place.
The URL, the view, and
the detail template.
But we're missing one part.
We need a link
from the home page
to get to the detail
page of each treasure.
We can do this by wrapping the
entire panel in an anchor tag
that links to /treasure.id.
That way if you click
anywhere on the panel,
you'll be taken to that
treasures detail page.
Now we can see this
in action by clicking
on a treasure on the home
page, and being taken
to that treasures detail page.
Now it's time for you to
create your own detail
page in the challenges.
Good luck.