[SINGING] Deep within the jungle
lie treasures most unknown.
To track what we uncover,
we'll need to use Django.
AJAX, forms, and grids,
we'll cross the pyramids.
Dust off your old durangos -
we're Digging Into Django.
Welcome back to
Digging Into Django.
This is level three, where
we'll be covering adding
the ability to upload images.
Users can now add
treasures through the form
we created in level
two, but they still
need to have an image URL of
where their image is hosted,
and we'd like them to be able
to upload an image directly
into the app.
To do this we'll want
to use an image field,
and there's a few steps
to getting that working.
First we'll add the
image field to our model,
then we'll need to install
Pillow to use that image field.
Then we'll migrate our
changes to the database.
We'll update settings.py
to add a media directory,
and finally, add a special URL
to urls.py to serve our media
files locally.
So let's do each of
these steps in order.
First, in our treasure model
we'll get rid of image URL,
and we'll add our new
image field, which
has two required parameters.
Upload two is the location
inside of the media directory
where we'll add our
images to, and default
is a default image in case
the user doesn't upload one.
So since we just
changed the model,
you'd think we'd want to
run make migrations.
But if we try to do
that, we get this error
that Pillow's not installed,
and we get some information
on how to install it.
We can install Pillow
with pip install Pillow.
This will download it
and install it for us.
Now that Pillow's
installed, we can
run python manage.py
make migrations,
which will add our image field.
Then we can run python
manage.py migrate,
which will finish migrating
your changes to the database.
At the bottom of
settings.py we'll
add this media
root variable that
will tell us the location
of where to store all
of these user uploaded files.
So all our images will go
in that media directory.
And media URL handles serving
the media from media root.
Because we're running
our app locally,
we need to add this special
URL to our urls.py file.
This will match any
image in media slash,
and will serve that file
locally from the media root
directory we just created.
Now we've finished all the
steps to set up an image field,
but we still need to refactor
a few things to replace
our old image URL with
our new image field,
in forms.py views.py, and
both of our templates.
In forms.py we'll just
replace our image URL
with our new image.
And remember, since we declared
that image field in our model,
it will pull over all of
the associated properties,
and the fact that
it's an image field.
So now in our post
treasure view,
we'll also need to pass our
request.files to our form.
Finally, in our
index template we
can change that ENC
type to multipart form
data, which is required
when submitting files
through a form.
And then in both our index
and detail templates,
we'll need to change the old
treasure.image URL to our new
treasure.image, and then add
.url to get that images URL
field.
So now our image
field is ready to use,
and we can see that we
can create a new treasure
and upload a
corresponding image,
and then we can see that
new treasure displayed.
Now it's time for you
to do some challenges.
I'll see you in the next level.