[SINGING] Deep
within the jungle
lie treasures most unknown.
To track what we uncover,
we'll need to use Django.
AJAX, forms, and grids,
we'll cross the pyramids.
Dust off your old durangos -
we're Digging Into Django.
Hi.
I'm Sarah Holderness,
and this is Digging into Django.
This course builds upon the
concepts taught in Try Django.
And for Django in general,
it's helpful to know
basic Python, HTML, and database
concepts which you can brush up
on in these courses.
In Try Django, we created
the Treasure Gram site
which displayed a list of
the treasures we've collected
along our expeditions.
In this course, we'd like to
add the following new features
to our Treasure Gram app.
A grid layout, a
detail page, a form
for adding treasures, image
uploads, user authentication,
user profile pages, and
a Like button with Ajax.
To start, let's look at
creating a new look for our app
with a grid layout.
So the plan here is
to use Bootstrap,
so we can create a grid
with columns of width four,
and then we can create a new
row every three treasures.
If we look at the current
code in index.html,
we'll want to start by
getting rid of the table that
stored our treasures details,
like the value, material,
and location.
Since those will now
be on the detail page.
And we'll want to keep the home
page simple with just images.
Then if we look at the
remaining code in our
for loop that displays
each treasure,
we have a panel
with the heading,
and the image displayed.
That whole piece of
code is what we'll
want to put in each of
our rows and columns.
We've collapse the code
for displaying the treasure
to make it a little
easier to read.
But what we've done is add a
row outside of the for loop
and a column inside
of the for loop.
If we take a look at
our grid right now,
we can see there's a good
start with the column set up,
but there are a few problems.
The problem is since some of our
images have different heights,
letting the columns overflow
doesn't really work.
To fix this, we can create a
new row every three treasures.
But how would we do that?
We can check and see how many
iterations of the for loop
we've done, and see if that
number is divisible by three.
Then we know we want
to create a new row.
To see the number of
iterations of the for loop,
we can use this special
variable inside of the for loop.
Forloop.counter will give us
the number of iterations so far.
So for the first iteration,
we'll have one as the counter,
then two, then three.
Then we want to check if the
counter is divisible by three.
And Django provides special
filters that we can use.
You use a filter by writing
the value on the left, pipe,
then the filter name, which
here it's divisible by,
and the argument,
which is three.
This will return true or false,
depending on whether it's
divisible by three or not.
So if we put this all
together in an if statement,
we end up with something
that looks like this.
An inside if it is divisible by
three, will end the current row
and start a new row.
And now we have
this piece of code
we just wrote inside
of our template, which
is going to end the last
row every three columns,
and then start a new one.
And now we can see our grid
is working even if we have
images of different heights.
In case you are
wondering, there's
some other for loop
variables we can use.
We already saw .counter.
.counter0 will start
counting at zero.
And .first and .last will
return true or false if this is
the first iteration of the
loop or the last iteration
of the loop.
There are also a lot more
filters available to us.
For example, for
add you can do pipe,
add, and a number, and that
will return the value plus 2.
You can add pipe
lower after a string,
and that will return that
string in lower case.
And you can even
chain multiple filters
to get different results.
There are many more
Django template filters
which you can read
about in the docs here.
That's it for level
one, section one.
Good luck in the challenges.