Welcome back to level
2, section 2
where we'll look at creating
our forms in a smarter way using
Meta classes.
We'll end up with
a form that has
the exact same
functionality as before,
but with a lot less code.
If we compare to our
original form code,
there will be a few differences.
First, we'll need to
import our treasure model
since we'll be referencing it.
And our treasure
form class will now
inherit from
forms.ModelForm, which
is the first step to
linking a form with a model.
Notice we don't have to
create any of the fields
as we did before.
Instead, we'll just use
this class called Meta.
The name of this class
will always be Meta,
and we'll use it to
link our new form
to our already created model.
Inside the class we'll
specify that our model
will be Treasure.
And the fields will be a list
of all of the model fields
we want to show up on our form.
Now that we've changed our
form to be a model form,
we'll go and update our view.
We can replace all of the code
we had before for manually
creating a treasure and
saving it with this one line,
form.save(commit = True).
And in this single step,
we're reading all of the data
from the form fields and
saving it to the database.
Even though we're
doing save on the form,
this is actually creating
a treasure object for us
because the form is linked
to the treasure model.
Afterwards we'll still
redirect to the home page.
Now you can see that our
form is working exactly
as it was before, but
with a lot less form code.
Now it's time for
you to practice
with ModelForms and Meta
classes in the challenges.
Good luck.