Welcome back to
level 1, section 3
where we'll be covering
template inheritance.
Each page on our site
will have repeated code
for at least the navbar,
the header, and the footer.
It would be great if we could
share this repeated code
across different templates.
To do this, we can
create a base template
that will hold the repeated
code for the navbar
and footer that other
templates can then extend.
In this base template, we'll
start by loading static files.
Then we'll have
all of the repeated
code for in the
navbar, and then we'll
create this block that
we'll assign a name to.
We'll call ours block content.
This is a special
template tag that's
a placeholder for all
of the content from all
of our other templates.
So we're actually not
going to fill this block
in with any code.
Then in index.html, we'll start
by extending the base template.
And then we'll write
all of the code that's
specific to the index page.
And that will be wrapped
by this block tag that
will tell Django to
put all of this code
where it belongs in
the base template.
So the final rendered
index template
will have all of the navbar,
then the copied in index code,
and then the footer
combined into one template.
So what's the
actual code we would
put in our base.html template?
We start with loading
the static files.
Then we put in our head tags
and we load our CSS files.
We'll add our navbar.
And we can even put
in the main tags
that will contain the block
content from each template.
And then finally,
we'll add our footer.
Then in index.html,
we'll extend base.
And then inside of
our block content,
we'll add all of the code
for displaying our treasures.
The detail template
will look very similar,
except it will have code
specific to the detail
page for displaying
a single treasure.
If we look at this in
action, nothing has changed.
But behind the scenes, our
code is more organized.
So if we change something
in the navbar, for instance,
we only have to change it
in one place, in the base.
Now it's time for you to
organize your templates
in the challenges.
Good luck.