Welcome back to Level
5, Section 2.
Remember how in Level 2
we said that a GET should
be used when we want to
retrieve data from the server,
but a POST should be used
when we want to send data
to be saved to the database?
Well, we'll want to change
our AJAX to use a POST.
We'll want to use a
POST because we're
updating the treasure with
the new number of likes
in the database.
So there's just a few
changes we need to make
to change our GET to a POST.
In our main.js
file we'll change the request
type to a POST.
In our view, we'll
also change request dot
GET to request dot POST.
But now if we try
to run this, we
see that we get an error because
a Django POST needs a CSRF
token.
But since we're doing
the POST through AJAX,
we can't just put the CSRF token
in the form like we did before.
So if you remember
from Level 2, we
had a form POST with a CSRF
token added in the template.
For AJAX, we can look up the
CSRF token in the user session
cookie and then add
that to the POST header.
The code to do this
is kind of crazy,
but luckily Django
provides this code for you
on their docs website.
So we're going to look at it
so we can see how it's working,
but we're not going to
go into great detail.
The first function
we find in the docs
is this get Cookie function
that will take in a string
and look up the
corresponding cookie.
And we can see we use
this below by creating
a CSRF token variable that
will store the cookie returned
by this function.
So we want to add this CSRF
token to every AJAX POST
request.
So we're going to use this
AJAX setup function that
takes in a before send function
that will append the CSRF
token to the request header.
This before send function will
run with every AJAX request.
Now we can see our like button
is working exactly the same
as it did before, but
we're using a POST request
like we should be.
Congrats on making it to the
end of Digging Into Django.
Good luck on the final
set of challenges,
and I'll see you in the
final wrap up video.
It's just going to give our
page a nice look and feel,
and that's why we added it--sorry
We're going to send
data that's going
to change stuff on the database--
Notice we don't have to create
any of these car fields.
Notice we don't do have
to do any of that crap.
Now we can see our
form is working exactly
as it was beform-- beform?
So it's proddy-- sorry, I'm sorry.
I can't talk anymore.
Good luck with stuff
in the challenges.