Welcome back to
level 4, section 2
where we'll cover
user authentication.
Now that we have users
that can create treasures,
we'd like to add the ability
for only logged in users
to be able to create treasures.
So we'd like to add
login and logout
functionality to our app.
We'll start by
adding a login page.
And the plan for doing
that is the same as usual
with adding a URL,
view, and template,
but we'll want to add one more
step for adding a login form.
We'll start again with adding
our URL that matches /login
and goes to our view login_view.
We can't name our view
login because there's
a built in login function
we'll be using later.
Now we'll want to
create our login form.
It will inherit from forms.Form
and will have two fields
for the username and password.
The username will be a CharField
with a label for username
and a max length of 64.
The password will
also be a CharField,
but we'll use that
password input widget
that we talked about earlier.
Now we'll go to
creating our login view.
But first we'll need to import
our login form we just created
and the built in login, logout,
and authenticate functions.
Because we want the option
to either POST our submitted
log in form data or simply
display the login form,
we'll check if the
request was a POST,
and then authenticate
from there.
Otherwise we'll
display the login form.
This is a little
different than how
we handle POSTing a new treasure
form because in our index view,
we were displaying the form, and
then in our POST treasure view,
we were processing the form
data in those separate views.
And now we're doing
that in just one view.
First we'll create
our login form,
check that the form is valid,
get our username and password
from the form, and
then authenticate
with that username and
password, which will
return the authenticated user.
We'll first want to check
that the user is not None
and the user.is_active,
and then we'll
login the user with
request and user
using that built
in login function.
And then we'll redirect
to the home page.
We can also provide feedback
with else statements
by printing out whether the
account has been disabled
or the username and
password were incorrect,
and we'll just print
those statements
to the console for now.
Finally, we'll create
the login template
by simply displaying the
form inside of form tags.
And we'll still
need that csrf_token
we used before for POSTing.
You can see the method
is POST, and the action
means that we're just submitting
back to this same URL.
Now you can see our login form
working on our login page.
That's it for
level 4, section 2.
Now it's time for
you to practice
with user authentication
in the challenges.