[SINGING] Deep within the jungle
lie treasures most unknown.
To track what we uncover,
we'll need to use Django.
AJAX, forms and grids,
we'll cross the pyramids.
Dust off your old durangos -
We're Digging Into Django.
Welcome back to
Digging into Django.
This is Level 2, where
we'll be going over forms.
Right now, there
is no way for users
to add treasures in our app.
In Try Django, we were
adding new treasures
through the admin
or the Django shell.
But we don't want
regular users to do that.
Instead, we can
create a form to show
on the home page that will allow
users to add new treasures.
That way, only staff or dev
can interact with the model
through the admin or shell.
To use a Django form, we'll
create a new form class
called TreasureForm, which
is very similar to when
we created our treasure model.
In forms.py, we'll first
import forms from Django,
and then we'll create
our TreasureForm class
that inherits from forms.Form.
We'll have similar
CharFields and DecimalFields
that will map to HTML
input elements just
like our ModelFields
map to a database table.
Just like we did
with ModelFields,
we can set the
max_length and the label
to display in the HTML.
By setting these,
Django takes some
of the work out of
creating form fields
and validating form data.
Before we get to
displaying our form,
let's add a URL that will
handle our form submission.
We'll call this post_url, so
localhost/post_url will go
to the views.post_treasure
which will handle our form
submission.
You may be wondering why
our URL was called POST URL.
Well, there's two main types
of requests-- a GET and a POST.
By default, all of are URL
requests are of type GET.
For example, if
we make a request
to the server for a treasurer
with a specific treasure_id,
that's going to
use a GET request
and return that
treasure back to us.
However, with our new treasure
form, when we press submit,
that's going to send
a treasure that's
going to add an object
to our database.
So, since it's
updating the server,
we'll want to use
a POST request.
That's why we named
our URL POST URL.
Now in our views we want to
start with creating our POST
treasure view.
But, before we do that, we
want to import the TreasureForm
we just created.
Then we'll create our
post_treasure view
that takes in a request.
It then creates
that treasure_form
from that request.POST
submission.
And then it checks
if the form.is_valid.
Then, if the form.is_valid,
we'll go ahead and create
our treasure by looking
up the attributes
in form.cleaned_data.
Remember that Django takes
care of cleaning the data
and validating it for us.
So now we can save that
treasure to the database
by doing treasure.save.
Then, outside of
the if statement,
we'll redirect to the home page.
That way, even if the
form wasn't valid,
we'll still redirect
to the home page.
We'll also need to update
our index view so that it
can create our new form
and pass it to the index
template for rendering.
Now we've handled
the form submission
but we haven't
actually displayed
the form in the template.
At the bottom of our
index.html template
we'll add our
form, since we want
it to show up at the bottom.
We'll add a form HTML
element with the action going
to our post URL, and
the method is post.
Then, inside that, we can
simply display our form
with curly bracket and
the variable name form.
Notice we also have to add the
special Django template tag
csrf_token.
Django handles a lot of
security tasks for us,
like this token which protects
against cross-site request
forgery attacks.
This is just one of
the ways that Django
helps protect your apps
with simple functionality.
And now we can see the HTML
form that was automatically
generated for us.
We can also add some
style to our form
so it fits in better
with our home page.
We'll wrap the form in
a panel, add a title,
and then we can also display the
form with form.as_p which will
format the form like
an HTML paragraph,
with each field on
a separate line.
And, if we look at the HTML
source for this page that
was generated, we can see
that all the labels and input
fields are filled in for us.
It even has the csrf_token
which now has a value filled in,
and it even provides the
max length and type variables
to validate the data for us.
And now we can see our
new form in action.
We can enter data into
these fields, and submit,
and we see our new
treasure displayed.
You may be wondering if Django
forms can render anything other
than just simple text fields.
Django form widgets can
render more complex input
fields like password input,
date pickers, and file input.
And they're as easy as adding
a widget to your form field.
And we'll see more widgets
like this later in the course.
That's it for level
2, section 1.
Good luck creating some
forms in the challenges.