[SINGING] Deep within the jungle
lie treasures most unknown.
To track what we uncover,
we'll need to use Django.
AJAX, forms, and grids,
we'll cross the pyramids.
Dust off your old durangos -
we're Digging Into Django.
Welcome back to
Digging Into Django.
This is level 4 where
we'll be covering users.
Right now we can upload
a treasure to our app.
But our treasures
don't have any owners,
so we don't know whose
treasures are whose.
Well, we can solve that by
adding a relationship to a user
model from our Treasure model.
So that's what
we'll be doing now.
In databases, there are
three different types
of table relationships--
one to one, one to many,
and many to many.
We want a user to have
many treasures associated
with their account, so we'll
use a one to many association.
The way to relate
two tables together
is to mark a field in one
as a foreign key in another.
So in our Treasure
model, we'll have
a user field that's
a foreign key that
belongs to the User model.
But you may be thinking,
we don't have a User model.
Django actually
creates a User model
as part of the auth
module, which is what
we use to log into the admin.
So we'll be using that,
and we'll import that here.
Then we can create
a user field that's
a foreign key to the
user model like this.
So now that we've made
this change in our model,
we need to migrate these
changes to the database.
We'll run python
manage.py makemigrations.
This will tell us
that we're trying
to create a
non-nullable field user
and ask us if we want to
provide a one off default now.
We'll select 1 to provide
a one off default,
and then we'll enter 1 which
corresponds to the first user
in our user table.
That will then create
our migration file.
Now we can apply
that migration file
by running python
manage.py migrate.
Now we can create new
users through the admin.
So we'll create a new
user called Indiana
and set up all his default
information, including
his password.
For any new treasures
we create, we'll
want to assign a user
to those treasures.
But for our existing
treasures, we
can use the admin to go
through and assign users
to those treasures.
Now if we go back and try to
add a treasure through our form,
we have this problem.
We get an error.
And that's because we have
this non-nullable user field
and we're not adding
that through the form.
So we want to add the user to
the treasure in our view.
Now if we go into our
post_treasure view,
we'll want to
change a few things.
First we can call form.save
without committing it,
and this will return a
treasure which we can
capture in a treasure variable.
Then we'll assign the
user to the treasure
as the request.user, since
user is sent with the request.
And then we can
save that treasure.
And now that treasure has
a user associated with it.
So now that we have
this user field set up,
we can display a profile page
for each individual user that
will show all of
the treasures that
belong to that specific user.
To do that, we'll want
to go through the steps
we've seen before for
creating the new page,
like setting up the URL,
the view, and the template.
For the URL, we want
localhost/url/user_name name
to go to a user_name's profile.
For the view, we'll want to
look up all the treasures that
belong to that user_name.
And in the template, we'll
display all of those treasures.
First we'll create our URL
with a regular expression that
matches user/, and then
a word of any length.
Backslash w plus will
match a word of any length.
And then adding
parentheses around that
will capture that value.
And then we can send it as
a parameter to our view.
In that view, we'll now have
two parameters, the request
and the username.
We can use get to look up the
user object in the user model
by its username and checking if
it matches the passed in user
name.
The next step is to get
all of the treasures that
belong to that user.
We can use a filter
on treasure.objects
with that new user object to get
all of that user's treasures.
And finally, we'll pass that
username and treasures list
to our profile
template for rendering.
Then we'll create the
profile template, which
will look almost identical
to our index template,
to display the
username as a title,
and then display all of
the treasures that belong
to that user in a for loop.
We can see that the
user profile page is
working for our Indiana user.
But we can only get to this page
by manually typing in the URL.
So we want to link to this
page from the home page.
We'll need to add an anchor
tag underneath our title,
which will link to
/user/treasure.user.username.
And the text will
just be the username.
Then to link to our
detail page now,
we'll add an anchor tag
inside of the panel body
around the treasure photo.
So when you click on
the treasure photo,
you'll now go to
the detail page.
Finally we can see our home
page linking to our new profile
page.
That's it for
level 4, section 1.
Good luck in the challenges.