Welcome back to level
four, section three.
We're almost done with
user authentication,
but we'll also want to add
the ability to log out,
and links for logging
in and logging out.
To add log out
functionality, we'll
just need a URL and
view, but not a template.
The log out URL is pretty
similar to the log in URL,
except named logout.
In our log out view, we'll
use the built in log out
function that takes
in the request,
and then we'll simply redirect
back to the home page.
But right now if we
go to our home page,
we don't have any links set
up to log in or log out,
so we'll want to add those.
Since we want those to
show up on every page,
the best place to add those
is in our base.html template.
And we'll add those right after
we display the Treasuregram
logo.
So we only want to show a
log in link if we're not
actually logged in, and
then if we are logged in,
we want to show a log out link,
and a link to our profile.
And we can accomplish this
with a big if else block.
If the user is
authenticated, we'll
show the link to their profile
and a link to log out.
Otherwise we'll just
add a link to log in.
Before we were hard coding
any links in our templates,
but there's a
better way to do it.
You can use a URL template tag.
And you can do that by writing
URL, the name of the URL,
and any parameters you
want to pass to that URL.
So here we have the profile
as the name of the URL,
and user.username that
we want to pass there.
So if my username is Sarah,
the URL will look like this.
Then we can add the links
to log in and log out
with the same URL tag, except
they don't need any parameters.
And we can also
add a little style
by adding our CSS classes.
Now we can see our log in and
log out process in action.
And that's it for level
four, section three.
Good luck in the challenges.