Hey code-school friends.
Welcome to the third edition
of the JavaScript Road Trip.
As you know by now, JavaScript
is a very powerful web
scripting language used
all over the world,
in innumerable
web-based applications.
And a knowledge of it is going
to be an extraordinary asset
to you on your journey
as a developer.
Now, if JavaScript is
still sort of new to you,
you probably want to go hang
with road trips one and two,
because we'll definitely be
taking several, if not all
of those concepts
and layering them
into the topics of this course.
As far as new stuff,
we'll be examining
the fine art of the
function expression
as well as the cool and often
mind-boggling use of closures
and then the impact of
hoisting on load order.
Ultimately, we'll wrap up with
an introductory exploration
of the awesomely important
JavaScript object
and then examine
their blueprints
in the form of constructors
and prototypes.
So with that, let's start
the JavaScript Road Trip,
Part Three.
[SINGING] From the Labyrinth of
Loops to the Variable Valley,
we'll see the Cliffs
of Value first.
JavaScript's right up your all.
Built-in's Bluff, Files
Falls, Array Archipelago,
declarations in a
desert, where you'll
find out how far you'll go.
Learn the program, take a ride.
Buy a ticket, step inside.
All aboard, you're
at the station
to increase your education
Bon Voyage and skinny dip,
as long as functions
you don't skip
on this, the
JavaScript Road Trip.
To start off this
leg of the road trip,
we'll be examining a
special usage of a function
inside of JavaScript called
the function expression.
Periodically, when
we code, we need
to make an efficient
choice about which
function to actually build
when our program loads.
Typically, we do this
when we've received
a special piece
of data or when we
need to build a one-time,
one-run function
for our websites.
Also, we want to make
sure that we do this
without building every
possible function that we could
when our program loads in order
to conserve program memory.
Additionally, we often want to
take functions and pass them
to other functions.
Or we may want to immediately
call the function as soon
as it's built.
And with that, we hope
you enjoy traversing
the forest of
function expressions.
So here we in level one.
Welcome back to JavaScript
Road Trip Three.
So in this level,
the first level,
we'll be looking at function
expressions-- pretty cool
thing, which we like to
call functions on the fly.
Now, in order to understand
what a function expression is,
we'll first need to look at
what you already understand,
which is a declared function.
Check this one out right here.
You can see here,
on this first block,
a declared function
called diffOfSquares.
Now, we've given it
two inputs-- a and b.
And you can see
that we've square a
and squared b and
then subtracted
them-- see the minus
sign in the middle.
And then that's the value
that we are returning.
So there's our
declared function.
This function,
since it's declared,
is actually loaded right
when the program is run.
And it is loaded into
memory and held there
until you want to use it.
Function expressions
apply things a little bit
differently.
So the first thing
that we would do
is we would
establish a variable.
Let's call it diff.
And then what we would
do is we would rearrange
the declared function into
an assignment statement.
And this particular thing is
called a function expression.
And it loads only when this
particular line of code
is reached inside your program.
So take a look, you can
see the function key word.
Then you can see the
diffOfSquares, function name,
and the inputs all in
the same place, and then
the very same function body
that does the same stuff that we
had in our declared function.
Again, this loads
only when your program
reaches that line of code.
Another thing you
should take note of
is that since this is now
an assignment statement,
meaning we're taking
this entire function
and assigning it
the variable diff,
we need a semicolon
here, on the end
of our final bracket
of our function body.
Now, in order to call our
cool new variable diff,
we're actually going to
use the variable's name.
That's right, it's
going to be diff.
We're not going to use the
diffOfSquares name that's
inside the function.
Then we just pass
two parameters to it.
We're just going
to give it 9 and 5.
And you can see that
that returns 56,
because you get 81
minus 25 returns 56.
Something to check
out here is that I
have given parameter parenthesis
to the variable diff.
We haven't seen
that before, right?
And then we pass parameters
into those parentheses
that we've given to diff.
And we need those in order
to actually call the function
and give it some parameters.
Now, you might be
wondering, why in the heck
do we still have that
diffOfSquares name if we're
just going to use the
diff variable name?
It's an excellent question.
And guess what?
We don't.
So let's take a look at that.
There's this cool
thing in JavaScript,
and in other languages,
called the anonymous function.
It means that you can
build a function expression
without a name, because
it's being assigned
to a variable that will
hold the entire contents
of that function.
So since we don't need
that diffOfSquares name,
we can go ahead
and get rid of it.
Let's get rid of it.
There it goes.
And now we will just scoot the
parameters and the first body
bracket up against
the function keyword,
and we have an anonymous
function, particularly
an anonymous
function expression.
Now guess what?
Just because it's anonymous
doesn't mean anything.
We still call the function
with our new variable name.
And we pass in some
parameters, 4 and 2.
That would give us 16 and 4.
And when we subtract
those, we get 12.
Now, in our previous
JavaScript courses,
we've been logging
out tons of variables
to see what they hold, to
see what their contents are.
What might happen if we did
that with our new diff variable
that holds a function?
Well, as you might expect, you
will get the actual function
body returned as a result,
so that you can always
check the contents of
a variable to see what
function it is
actually referring to.
Let's take a look and see how
we can use function expressions,
stored functions in a
national park terminal,
specifically at the forest
of function expressions.
One of the cool things about
variables that hold functions
is that they can be passed
into other functions for use
inside that function.
Well, let's take a look at that.
So say we had a JavaScript file.
We'll call it terminal.js for
the national park terminal.
And we wanted to build
a greeting for people
that were attending, let's say,
the Badlands National Park.
So here, you can see
we have established
a variable called greeting.
And in that particular
variable, we
are going to store a
function expression that
will alert a
message to the user.
"Thanks for visiting
the Badlands.
We hope you stay is
better than most."
Next, near the end
of our file, we
will establish a declared
function called closeTerminal.
And what that will get past
is a function expression.
The parameter name for
it will be message.
And then inside closeTerminal,
that function will be called.
So maybe you can
kind of see how we
will use the greeting
variable coming up.
Later on in our file, after
our customer has perhaps
interacted in some other
ways with the terminal,
the closeTerminal
function will be called.
And you can see
that we've passed
greeting into closeTerminal.
So let's take a
look at what happens
when we pass greeting
to closeTerminal.
Well, the message parameter
becomes the greeting variable.
And then inside
closeTerminal, the function
that's in greeting gets called.
Then we would get
the alert message.
"Thanks for visiting
the Badlands.
We hope your stay is
better than most."
So one greeting is pretty cool.
But what if we had
multiple greetings?
We could have multiple
different kinds
of greetings for different
kinds of customers.
Function expressions are
very cool and very useful
in this way,
because they give us
a flexibility in determining
exactly which functionality we
want to store and
then pass in later.
So let's go ahead and
scoot our stuff down.
[INAUDIBLE]
And now we are going to try
to build multiple greetings.
So we'll establish
our greeting variable,
but we're not going to assign
a function expression to it
quite yet, because we need
to decide whether we have
a new customer or
an old customer.
So we've got some
code that'll be
there in our
terminal.js file that
will decide whether
we have a new customer
or an old customer, and
therefore new customer will be
true or false by the time
we reach this conditional.
If we have a new
customer, then we'll
go ahead and assign
our previous message
that we built to the
greeting variable.
But otherwise, meaning
it's not a new customer,
then we'll make a
different function.
And we'll say, "Welcome
back to the Badlands.
Guess they aren't so bad, huh?"
So that's for our old
customers-- people
that have been to
the Badlands before.
So now you can
notice that we have
two possible greetings
with one variable.
Let's see what we
can do with that.
So now, if new
customer somehow was
set to false by our
terminal, we know
that when we would pass
the greeting variable
into closeTerminal, we would
get the old customer message.
"Welcome back to the Badlands.
Guess they aren't so bad."
And then if we were to also
change new customer to true,
we can see the
message that comes up
is exactly the old one
that we had built before.
So that's a brief introduction
to function expressions.
And we will release
you to the challenges.
I hope your stay is
better than most.