Welcome back.
In this section,
we'll be looking
at how to use function
expressions with the map
method of arrays.
Now, a function expression
is just that, an expression.
And you can use it in any place
that an expression might go.
You don't necessarily need to
store a function expression
inside of a variable
at all times.
Let's take a look at why.
So say we had an
array of numbers.
And we stored it in
a variable called,
as you might expect, numbers.
And then we established a
new variable called results.
To that variable, we will
assign something very special.
You can see that we call the
numbers array with its map
method.
And then inside of the
parameters for that map method,
we're going to pass
some coolFunction.
Now, be aware that the
map method of an array
will always take in a
function as a parameter,
whether it's a function
expression or a function
expression stored in a variable.
But it just has to be a function
that the map method gets.
So check this out.
Here is the visual
impression of our numbers
array with each of the numbers
inside of its own cell.
And what the map method does
is it takes our coolFunction
and applies it to
every single cell.
Whatever coolFunction
does, it does it
to each one of
the cells in turn.
So you can see that our
cool function here, whatever
it may do, it gives us words in
our final array that says, "wow,
these are some pretty
cool results, man".
Now you might be thinking,
this seems like a loop format.
And guess what?
It sort of is.
So here's what this
sort of functionality
would look like
in a loop format.
Well, the first
thing we would do
is establish a results
variable and then use
a loop to go over each item
inside the numbers array.
And then we would
use our coolFunction
on each item inside
of the numbers array,
storing the result
in the results array.
So what's cool about
the map method is
that it takes all that code
you see there in the loop
and does it all conveniently
in one line of code.
So now let's actually
build a function
to pass to our map method.
This time, we won't
use a variable.
We will use a built
function expression
in the parameter parentheses.
So let's check that out.
What we're going to do is we're
going to just simply double
each number inside
of our numbers array.
So there's our function keyword.
And here we have, right
after the function keyword,
our parameters with the
arrayCell parameter.
That's because we have to
pass each cell of numbers
into our function expression
in order for the function
expression to know which
one that it's looking at.
Inside our function
body, we'll say, just
return the arrayCell,
whatever that may be, times 2.
So we will get a doubled value.
And that will be passed into the
identical cell of the results
array.
Now, something important
here to remember
is that you always have to
close your function body.
So make sure that
you put a bracket
at the end of your
function body,
as well as close the map
method with a parentheses.
Then, tying the whole
statement together
since we do have
an assignment here,
is a semicolon to make sure
that we execute the function
and pass all of the results
to the results variable.
So let's check out how our
doubling function works.
We pass it right
into the map method.
And it is applied to every
single cell of the numbers
array.
And you can see each one
of these numbers being
doubled in turn.
Then, if we were to log
out our new results array,
we would see an array with
all of the values doubled
from our original numbers array.
Oh hey, one more thing.
Short functions are
often built in one line
for clarity and simplicity.
You don't always have to build
full blocked functions inside
of the parameters.
If it's nice and
short, sometimes
for clarity, simplicity,
legibility, we
will build those
functions all in one line.
So now you've seen how to
build a function expression
in the place of a parameter.
So we will give you now
to the challenges where
you'll have some fun with that.