Hey, everybody,
and welcome back.
Now just to review, before
we move on a little bit,
we have built
function expressions
and assigned them to
variables and then called
the new variable, like we
did here with some CUPCAKES.
And then the next
thing that we did was,
we had an array full
of values, and then
we built a function expression,
itself as a parameter,
for the map method.
When we passed that
function to the map method,
the map method
applied our function
to every cell of our array
and then built a new array,
as a result.
You can see that
here with our juices.
So now what we're
going to look at
is how to return a
function from a function,
using function expressions.
So say we had a
mystery function.
Ooh, spooky.
And then in there we
had some mystery code
that we did a bunch of stuff,
and then at the very end
we returned a
function expression.
That's what we're going to
be looking at right now.
Let's check out how we
can return functions
from functions, using
our special ticket
system for our Forest to
Function Expressions Theme
Park.
Now within that,
we'll use an array
as a queue for
Fast Pass delivery.
Let's check out the arrays
that we start with here.
We've got a parkRides array.
Now inside our parkRides array,
we have subarrays, four of them
to be exact.
And in each subarray,
we see the ride's
name, as well as the time
that a customer currently
would be estimated to
wait for that ride.
So you can see Birch Bumpers
has a 40 minute wait,
Pines Plunge has a 55
minute wait, et cetera.
Next, we have a fastPassQueue.
Now Fast Passes are
organized according
to whichever Fast Pass
is available next,
immediately next, in time.
So the very first index
of our fastPassQueue
shows Cedar Coaster, and that's
because the very first Fast
Pass that's available
is for Cedar Coaster.
And then it would go Pines
Plunge, then Birch Bumpers,
and then Pines Plunge again.
Before we move on, we
have to kind of understand
how a queue operates.
So we're first going to build
our queue as we see it here.
The first cell that
would be in our queue
would be Cedar Coaster.
Let's say that
that's what we wanted
to have as our first Fast Pass.
And then what if we wanted to
add Pines Plunge to our queue?
New items in a queue
are always added
at the very end of the array
that represents the queue.
Just like in real life,
when you get into a line,
you go to the back of the
line to be added to the line.
Now we'll add Birch
Bumpers onto the queue.
But wait, we know a
method that adds cells
to the back of arrays.
So what would we be
using here actually
in order to get that
cell onto the back?
That's the push
method for arrays.
So you can see that if we
add Pines Plunge with a push,
it will go right to
the back of our queue.
So now we've built the queue
that we see in our array.
But we need a way to get
the very first cell off
of the queue.
Right?
Because that's how lines
empty, from the front.
But we don't have
that method yet.
Guess what?
Arrays have a very specific
method for that process.
That's called the shift method.
When we call the shift method
on any array, what happens
is the very first cell of the
array gets popped off the front
and returned.
So here, you can see that
if we called the shift
method on our fastPassQueue,
the very first cell would
be chopped right off,
which holds Cedar Coaster,
and Cedar Coaster
would be returned.
So that shortens our
queue just a little bit.
Right?
What would happen if we called
the length of our array?
We can see that
that will yield a 3.
And that's because the shift
method, just like pop and just
like push, will modify
the length of the array
automatically.
Now shift is cool
because you can
pop the front of the queue
off but also store the result,
because it will pass
back the result.
It doesn't just let it fly away.
So then if we were to shift
again on our fastPassQueue,
the first cell would
get popped off,
and we can store it
inside of a new variable
that we'll call firstFastPass.
If we console.log
that variable out,
we will see Pines Plunge
returned as the result.
An important thing to
note here about shift
is that it's always going
to return this first cell
regardless of whether
you toss it away,
like on the left hand side
here where we just called
shift and got Cedar Coaster,
or whether you store it
in a variable and then
use it for something.
Now we're going to go
ahead and use our queue
to build our simple
ticket system.
Let's check it out.
So like we said before,
functions can return functions.
This is a very important
thing about JavaScript.
Since functions can be
treated as expressions,
we can return them like values.
So in our new ticket
system, we will
have a function
called buildTicket.
And that will take in three
parameters, the first of which
we will call allRides.
Now this will be the array
of our rides and, of course,
their wait times too.
And then we will have a second
parameter called passRides.
This will be the array of
all of those Fast Pass rides,
in order.
Lastly, we will have the
pick variable parameter,
which will be the actual ride
for which our customer would
like a ticket.
First thing we'll do is check to
see if the very first Fast Pass
that's available, found
in passRides index 0 ,
is the same as the
customer's pick.
And if that's true, we'll just
shift the very first cell off
of our Fast Pass array and give
it to a variable called pass.
Then we will return a function
expression that alerts, "Quick,
you have a Fast Pass to" whatever
ride they just got a pass for.
Notice here that we're treating
the function as an expression
and returning it directly.
It's not stored in a
variable, nothing like that.
It's just immediately returned
as a function expression.
Then if the very
first Fast Pass is not
the one they're looking for,
then what we're going to do
is cycle through the entire
rides array, all of the rides,
with their wait times.
And inside that
loop, we'll check
whether the first
index in each subarray
matches the name of the ride
the customer would like to have.
And when it does, we will
return a different function.
This one says, "A ticket
is printing for," the ride
and, "Your wait time is about,"
a certain amount of minutes.
Now notice that the
minutes are contained
in the second index,
which is the index
1, of each of the subarrays
in our array of rides.
So now we know what our
buildTicket function does,
let's see we can do with it.
If we establish a variable
called wantsRide, that's
the customer's wanted
or desired ride,
we have Birch Bumpers
assigned to that right now.
Then we will create
a new variable
called ticket, to
which we will assign
the results of our
buildTicket function.
Notice that we have called
this buildTicket function
with the following parameters,
parkRides, our array of rides;
the fastPassQueue, which has
all of our Fast Passes in it;
as well as the
wantsRide variable,
which has the customer's
desired ride in it.
And then later, when we call
the actual ticket function,
perhaps when the
customer has closed out
of the ticket
terminal, we would need
to put a set of parentheses on
that variable, and a semicolon,
in order to let
JavaScript know that we
want to call that variable
as the actual function
that it contains.
And as a cool result, we
get our pop up that says,
"This is your ticket
to Birch Bumpers.
Your wait time is
about 40 minutes."
Now why did we get
this particular alert?
It's because Birch
Bumpers was not
the very first ride in
our Fast Pass array,
and so we went ahead and
issued that customer a ticket
for the ride that
they actually wanted.
Now what happens when
we change that ride
to Cedar Coaster, which is the
very first ride in our Fast
Pass array?
Well, when we call ticket
this time, we'll see, "Quick!
You've got a Fast Pass
to Cedar Coaster."
Additionally, once that
Fast Pass to Cedar Coaster
has been printed,
our Fast Pass queue
will be shortened by one cell.
Now up until now, we have been
storing our returned functions
inside of a variable.
JavaScript has a cool situation
where you can immediately
call the function
when it is returned.
Let's take a look at that.
So this time we
want Pines Plunge.
Again, you can see that
that is the very first Fast
Pass in our queue now.
So now we're going to allow our
ticket variable to disappear.
We're not going to
use that anymore.
And we're going to scoot our
buildTicket function over,
still using the same parameters.
But what happens when we just
call the buildTicket function
without returning
it to anything?
Well, what happens is
it returns the function
that it builds, only.
There you can see the
entire body of the function,
as an expression that has been
returned from buildTicket.
And nothing happens.
Now even though we got
this function returned
from buildTicket,
nothing has actually
called the function
that got returned.
Now if you look inside
that function body,
you can see the pass variable.
The contents of
that pass variable
are saved in a process
that's called closure.
And we're going to look
at that in the next level.
But for now, you just know that
inside of this function body,
we have the first available Fast
Pass, which is Pines Plunge.
So again, we've got this
function expression,
but we need more in order
to call that function
expression immediately.
So let's see what we need.
Well, if we scoot our
semicolon out a little bit,
and then we swish in some
parameter parentheses,
then the same thing would happen
to our returned expression.
It would also get
some parentheses.
So now we're kind of
on the right track.
We're getting closer
to calling it.
And once we scoot our
semicolon back in,
then our function expression,
with its parameter parentheses
and its semicolon, becomes an
immediately invoked function.
When that happens,
what do we get?
"Quick!
You've got a Fast
Pass to Pines Plunge."
How awesome is that?
An immediately invoked
function, no variable necessary.
And our Fast Pass queue
shortens right up.
And now, just a
few more challenges
until you have received
the badge for level one.
How awesome.
We'll see you back
for level two.
[BEEP]
He said it's a--
[LAUGHING] New or false.
[BEEP]
Then we will check to look.
Take 1 billion.
[BEEP]