[SINGING] From the Labyrinth of
Loops to the Variable Valley,
we'll see the Cliffs
of Value first.
JavaScript's right
up your alley.
Built-ins Bluff, Files
Falls, Array Archipelago,
declarations in a
desert, where you'll
find out how far you'll go.
Learn the program, take a ride.
Buy a ticket, step inside.
All aboard, you're
at the station
to increase your education.
Bon Voyage and skinny
dip, as long as functions
you don't skip on this,
the JavaScript
Road Trip
Hey, everybody.
Welcome to level two
of JavaScript Road Trip
Three, the Cold Closures Cove.
Guess what?
Congratulations, you've
already made a basic closure.
A closure is a package deal.
Let's take a look
at one that was
in a previous example we
showed in the last level.
So in the Build Ticket function
that we had in the last level,
you can see in our two
returned anonymous functions,
several variables
like 'pass' and 'pick'
and 'allRides' that
were not created
within the function
that's being returned.
That's very important.
The entire their
contents of any of these
returned functions will still be
available outside the function,
outside Build Ticket
when they get returned.
When we return a
function from a function,
and it is complete with
variables that showed up
in the external function,
we have a closure.
So to kind of illustrate
this a little bit better,
let's look at very small
example of a closure.
A closure will wrap up the
entire local environment,
complete with all of the
necessary variables that
came from an external scope.
Here we have a function
called testClosure.
And in it, I've just
established a variable
called x and assigned
the value 4 to it.
And then I'll return x from
this function, a very simple
function.
Now, that x variable
is only local.
That means it can only
be accessed inside
of the testClosure function.
So let's take a look at that.
If we were to call testClosure,
we'd get a nice return of 4,
as you might expect,
because we returned x.
But if I tried to
access the x variable
from outside the function,
I would get an undefined.
That's because x disappears
just as soon as the test closure
function is wrapped up.
In other words, a
function's local variables
are just not available once
the function scope has finally
closed.
Now let's make it just
slightly more complex.
So now we'll establish
that same x variable as 4.
And then we'll
build a new function
inside of our
testClosure function.
And we'll call that
function closeX.
Now, inside of there, we
will return the x variable.
And then outside, inside of
the testClosure function,
we'll return the
closeX function.
Now here, the
inner function will
be able to access the
outer function's variables.
Why?
Because they feel like global
variables to that innermost
function.
So when I say, return x
inside of the closeX function,
closeX kind of looks around
in its own local environment
for an x, and it
doesn't see one.
So it looks outside there,
to the global scope-- inside
of test closure finds
that x and assigns
the 4 to the x inside of
the innermost function.
It's really important
to note that x is not
stored anywhere inside of the
innermost function-- not even
as a parameter.
So now let's check out
calling our external function,
testClosure.
And if we do that and
we assign the results
to a new variable,
checkLocalX, we
know that the entire function,
closeX, the innermost function,
gets returned and
assigned to checkLocalX.
Now, let's check
out what happens
when we call checkLocalX.
We get 4.
Woah, that is crazy.
This is interesting, because
even though test closure has
completely finished operating,
its scope is closed.
We can still access
the local variable
that was declared
in that function.
Why is that?
Because it has been bound as
a closure inside of closeX.
So how can we use
closures practically?
Well, they're very
helpful in what
we call function
"construction zones".
They make the creation
of very similar functions
very efficient.
So let's see how
this works if we
were to try to make
some transportation
modes for the Cold
Closures Cove.
Let's say that we
had a submarine
to get across the cove as
well as a battleship and then
a giant seagull--
not only that, it
is a pirate giant
seagull with blue feet.
Since we have these
three different modes
of transportation
across our cove,
we can make a
buildCoveTicketMaker
for our different
modes of transport.
Here's our function.
And inside that function, we
would return another function
that uses a name and alerts,
"Here is your transportation
ticket via the 'transport,'"
which will get closed up from
the external function.
"Welcome to the
Cold Closures Cove
'name'" which will be involved
on a local level as a parameter.
Now our builtCoveTicketMaker
function
will make a ticket maker
for every single mode
of transportation.
They'll be similar functions
but just slightly different.
So if we wanted to make ticket
makers for the submarine,
the battleship, and
the giant seagull,
we would establish
three variables
called getSubmarineTicket,
getBattleshipTicket,
and getGiantSeagullTicket.
And we would call
buildCoveTicketMaker
for all of those variables.
So now that all of our variables
have ticket makers inside them,
we can call getSubmarineTicket,
getBattleshipTicket,
and getGiantSeagull
ticket to see
what's inside those variables.
Well, look there, they
have exactly the same function
inside each variable.
But that's very deceptive,
because bound variables
and their values
will not be evident
inside of a stored function.
In other words, examining
the function's contents
will not show you a
closure that has occurred.
In our getSubmarineTicket
variable,
transport actually
holds "Submarine".
And of course, in
getBattleshipTicket,
transport is "Battleship".
And in getGiantSeagullTicket,
transport is "Giant Seagull".
Until we've actually called
any of these variables that
have functions in
them, the 'name' variable
that is inside those
functions will stay undefined.
So let's change that.
Let's actually call
our ticket makers.
Now let's show how that works.
So we'll scoot our semicolons
out of the way here.
And we'll pass in some names,
Mario, Luigi, and Bowser,
to our different ticket makers.
What happens now?
Well, Mario gets a
ticket to the submarine,
and Luigi gets a ticket
to the battleship,
and Browser is forced to
take the giant seagull.
So now that you have a
little bit of information
to be dangerous
with some closures,
we'll give you some
challenges and see you back
in the next section.