All right.
So now in this
section, we're going
to look at a very important
feature of closures,
specifically their ability to
modify their bound variables
in the background.
Let's take a look at that.
So to demonstrate that
specific behavior,
we're going to add
a passenger tracker
to our buildCoveTicketMaker.
What's a passenger tracker?
It will keep track
of how many times
we've given a specific
ticket to any particular mode
of transportation.
So here's our original
function, and we'll
shuffle it up a little bit.
Now, we're going to
stick a new variable here
at the very beginning
of that function called
passengerNumber, and we're
going to set it equal to 0.
What does that mean?
That means that every time
we build a TicketMaker,
it will get a passengerNumber
of 0 to start.
We're still going to
return the function that
has our alert in it.
But inside that
function, we will
increment our passengerNumber.
And what does that mean?
Well, it means that when a
particular TicketMaker is
called, whether
for the submarine
or for the battleship, we
know that a new passenger has
been added.
So we will increase
the amount of tickets
that have been given.
We'll also add to
the alert printing
out the passengerNumber.
Now when we call our
buildCoveTicketMaker
for our submarine, well,
we'll get a TicketMaker back.
And inside that new
TicketMaker, when we call it,
we see our new passengerNumber
incrementer as well as
our new line inside
of our alert.
Something you should notice
is that passengerNumber's
initial value is not evident
here, but it does start at 0
and gets incremented
every single time
our TicketMaker is called.
So let's scoot aside
our semicolon here
and put Mario trying to get
a submarine ticket again.
And what happens?
We get a ticket that says,
here is your transportation
ticket via the submarine.
Welcome, Mario.
You are passenger number 1.
That's because this
is our very first call
to getSubmarineTicket,
and our passengerNumber
has been incremented to 1.
Now, what would
happen if we then
put Toad asking for
a submarine ticket.
He wants to ride with Mario.
So look, we get, you
are passenger number 2.
Wow.
So that's pretty cool, right?
That means that even though
our function's local scope has
completely disappeared,
it has retained
the value every single time
of our incremented variable.
So now that you've
seen how closures
can make ultra-secret changes
on the inside of a function
to their variables,
we're going to give you
some challenges regarding that.
And we'll see you back
in the next section.