So now that we've had a
chance to melt your brain
with some closures,
we want to show you
some common mistakes
that happen with closures
and then maybe give you
some preventative measures
to make sure that you don't
make those same mistakes.
The most common mistakes with
closures occur inside loops.
So what we're going
to do is we're
going to try to make a torpedo
assigner for our Cove's
Submarine.
Let's take a look at that.
We'll build a function
called assignTorpedo.
That means we're
going to try to give
a specific passenger
on the submarine
a torpedo to be in charge of.
We'll pass in the
name of a passenger
as well as a list
of those passengers.
We'll establish a torpedo
assignment variable.
That's going to eventually hold
our torpedoAssignment function.
And now we'll build a loop that
checks the entire passenger
array for the specific
passenger that we
want to assign a torpedo to.
So when we find
the passenger, we
will start to build a function.
And inside that
function, we'll alert
"ahoy" to whoever
the passenger is.
"Man your post at
torpedo number."
And then we will use their
index value, adjusted for zero,
to assign them to the
right torpedo number.
Then, of course,
at the very end,
we'll return our
torpedoAssignment variable
that holds our
function expression.
Now we'll establish an
array called subPassengers.
And we'll put a whole bunch
of passengers in there
that you may recognize.
Next, we'll make a new
variable for a new function
called giveAssignment.
And then we will call our
assignTorpedo function.
We'll pass in Chewie
as the passenger
we want to assign a
torpedo too as well as
the list of all of
the sub passengers.
Then when we call our
giveAssignment function,
we should expect that-- Oh, no.
What happened?
"Ahoy, Chewie.
Man your post at torpedo 9"?
That's no good.
Chewie's not in index 9.
What happened?
It should be torpedo 4.
So the mistake that
we made here is not
knowing that
closures bind values
at their very last opportunity.
It's really important
that we pay attention
to when we return our functions
and the final variable states
that happen when
we do the return.
So way before torpedoAssignment
ever gets returned,
the I loop counter
has progressed
in value, all the way to
8, and stopped the loop.
What happens then
is that 8 plus 1
happens to be 9 when the
torpedoAssignment variable is
returned.
The function's actual return is
really when the closure occurs.
That's when the environment
is packaged up together
with all of the necessary
variables and returned.
So when we called our
torpedo assigner for Chewie,
the I value that was actually
in the function was 8.
And so he got torpedo 9.
But what can we do to sort
of ensure the correct value
every time?
There are several options
that we could use.
Let's take a look.
Well, first of
all, if we get rid
of the torpedoAssignment
variable
entirely and just have
a function expression--
then if we scoot our function
keyword over and automatically
and instantly return as soon
as we find our passenger,
then we will have
locked i into place.
And when we call
our function, we
find out that Chewie is assigned
to exactly the right torpedo.
And that's because
i, the i value,
our loop counter, was
not allowed to progress.
A second a way that we can
ensure the correct value
is to design our
torpedo assigners
just like we did
our ticket makers
for the modes of transport.
Let's take a look at that.
So we'll change our function's
name to makeTorpedoAssigner.
But this time, we will only
pass in the passengerArray--
not the name and
the passengerArray,
because the 'name'
variable we're going
to pass into our
function expression.
Inside our function expression
we'll have our loop.
Notice now that
the loop is inside
of the function expression.
Something to note
here as well is
that passengerArray is actually
being closed into our function
expression.
Notice that passengerArray is
a parameter and not a variable
we ever established
inside of our function.
That's because parameters
can be closed up too.
So inside our loop,
we'll, of course,
check to make sure that
we've found the right name.
And when we do, we'll
alert our message.
Again, the only
closed variable that
ever comes from the external
scope is passengerArray.
And that never changes.
Woo-hoo, we love that.
And now we can pass torpedoes
out like they are candy.
TIE fighter dead ahead, but
we're sort of underwater.
It's a submarine.
Anyway, so when we finally
make our torpedo assigner
and then we pass Chewie to
our getTorpedoFor variable,
we'll get the Chewie has
torpedo 4, just like we wanted.
Additionally, we could call it
again, but this time, for R2-D2.
And we should get that
torpedo 6 belongs to R2-D2.
And we do.
Super cool.
You're a closure master.
And we will see you
very soon, after you
tackle these
exciting challenges.
[INAUDIBLE]
[BEEP]
You broke it.
That time of day.
[BEEP]
I've had no beers.