[SINGING] From the Labyrinth of
Loops to the Variable Valley,
we'll see the Cliffs of
Value first. JavaScript's
right up your alley.
Built-ins Bluff, Files
Falls, Array Archipelago,
declarations in a
desert where you'll
find out how far you'll go.
Learn to program, take a ride.
Buy a ticket, step inside.
All aboard! You're
at the station
to increase your education.
Bon voyage and skinny
dip! As long as functions
you don't skip on this
the JavaScript Road Trip.
Ever have one of your
programs produce errors,
not because your logic or
your problem solving design
is incorrect,
necessarily, but instead
because the load order
of the functionality
within your website
seems to be getting
in the way of your success?
Turns out load order is a very
important thing in JavaScript,
especially when parts of your
program rely on other parts
very heavily to succeed,
but can't find those parts
exactly when they need them.
Now, this level may
seem a little short,
but don't let that deceive you.
Because this packs on
a very important bit
of broader perspective
for you as a developer.
And with that, enjoy your
hike in the Hoisting Hills.
Hey guys, welcome
back to Level Three.
This is the Hoisting Hills.
Now in JavaScript, hoisting
is not something that you do.
It's just something we
want to make you aware of.
It's a concept about
program load order.
So let's take a look at
this program right here.
You can see it's got
three functions in it
as well as two global variables.
And within that, function two is
going to call two subfunctions
as well as initialize another
local variable inside function
two's scope.
If all the stuff that's
in function to works OK,
then function two will be great.
And then if everything in the
global scope works all right,
then our program
will be just fine.
Sometimes though in
the process of coding,
we produce a code order
that doesn't produce
a correct output because the
way that JavaScript prioritizes
the loading of variables
and functions into memory.
So now we're going to look
at the load order in tandem
with this concept
called hoisting.
For example, if in our
function two local variable one
needs sub function
two for something
but it's not loaded yet, then
local variable one will fail.
And ultimately,
function two would fail.
And if function two's failing
and our entire program depends
upon it, then our
program fails too.
So we're going to look at
this load order concept,
a concept we call hoisting,
so that you can always be sure
that your programs
run correctly.
So think about when we initially
open a scope in JavaScript.
The first thing that's going
to happen inside that scope
is that memory is
going to be set aside
for all of the
necessary variables
and the declared functions
that the compiler sees
within the scope you have built.
So let's take as an
example this sum of squares
function that you can
see we've built here.
Inside it you see the variable
x being declared and then
assigned a value that comes
back from an add function.
And then that
variable is returned.
Towards the end
of the scope, you
can see the add function
being declared just
as a regular declare function.
Now, that's what we see in
our code when we write it.
But let's look at how
JavaScript actually
sees it when the compiler
runs the program.
So the first thing
that happens is
that the variable x
is hoisted to the top.
It's given memory space at the
very beginning of the scope
initialization.
But it has no value.
The very first value
that it has is undefined.
The next thing that
happens is the whole
declared function is hoisted
to the top of the scope
and sits there in memory
waiting for us to use it.
And then, and only then,
the executable code,
the stuff that we actually
want our function to do,
that's when that gets run.
Now, this is a great example
of a function the works
exactly as we would want to work
when it loads and when it runs.
But let's take a look at a few
examples where hoisting has not
quite the impact
we would expect.
So first here we're
going to build
a function called
get mystery number.
And inside that
function, we first
declared a function
called choose mystery.
And it's going to return 12.
And then following
that, we're just
going to say return the result
of the choose mystery function.
Then after that,
you can see I've
declared another function
called choose mystery again
and that returns 7.
So if we were to call
get mystery number,
what do you think
happens in this case?
Little tricky.
So all of this code loads
like this in the compiler.
The first thing that
happens is the very first
declared function gets hoisted
all the way to the top.
That's the first choose mystery.
But then the lower
choose mystery,
the one at the
bottom of the code,
gets hoisted also to be the
second function in line.
When that happens, the original
choose mystery function
is completely overridden.
It is no longer there.
Then the final and only
executable statement
says return the result of
calling choose mystery.
So what's actually
going to happen here
when we call get mystery number?
We get a 7.
Again, this is the case
because all the functions have
been hoisted up to the top
and then one was redefined.
It's completely gone because
of the second function.
Let's take a look at another
build of the get mystery number
function.
This one's going to involve
function expressions now.
Something to note here is that
function expressions are never
hoisted.
They are always
treated as assignments.
So let's take a look.
First thing I've got here is a
variable called choose mystery,
and I'm assigning to it
a function expression
that returns 12.
Following that, here's
my executable statement,
the return statement
of choose mystery.
And then after that,
another function expression
that's also called choose
mystery in the variable.
But that one returns 7.
What do you think
will happen now
when we call the get
mystery number function?
Well here's how
JavaScript loads it.
The first thing that happens
is the variable choose mystery
is hoisted to the top and
memory space is provided for it
and the value is
set to undefined.
So JavaScript has
no idea right now
whether that's going to be a
number, a string, an array,
or a function expression.
Following that, the second
variable declaration
of choose mystery is
hoisted to the top,
which is also undefined and
that completely overrides
the other choose mystery
variable that was undefined.
Then we arrive at an
executable statement,
that is when the choose
mystery variable gets assigned
a function expression,
this one returning 12.
Following that, we see the
executable statement return
choose mystery.
And so this function is going
to terminate at this line.
It's actually going to
call the choose mystery
function right now.
And then this later assignment
of a function expression
to the choose mystery
variable is actually
unreachable as a result
of that return statement.
So again, once
we've returned, we
can never reach that code
that's underneath the return
statement.
So when we call
get mystery number,
the only function
expression that's
ever been associated with choose
mystery by the time we return
is the one that returns 12.
OK, so let's shuffle around
the build a little bit
and see how hoisting might
impact this situation.
What if we move the return
statement up to the top?
That's the very first thing
that our function sees.
And then we put our two
expressions, our two function
expression assignments,
down underneath the return
statement.
What do you think the get
mystery number function will
return in this case?
Let's take a look.
So the first thing that
happens is the first variable
that's ever declared, which
is the first choose mystery
you see on the left, that
gets hoisted to the top
and it's assigned
an undefined value.
Same thing happens for the
second choose mystery variable.
And the first one is gone.
It's completely overwritten.
Then we tackle the return
choose mystery statement,
because that's the
first executable
code in our function.
But there's a problem.
Because check it out.
After that return statement,
both of the choose mystery
assignments are
completely unreachable
because the function
thinks "Oh well, I'm
just going to return and call
this random choose mystery
variable that he's assigned."
And as a result,
we get an error.
So this function does
not complete it all
and never returns anything that
we would want it to return,
neither 12 nor 7.
So remember our train system
from Road Trips one and two?
Let's take a look how hoisting
might impact a capacity status
function for the
JavaScript Express.
So we will build a capacity
status function that
takes in the current number
of passengers on the train,
as well as the
capacity for the train.
Then if the train
is full, we want
to execute a function here
that alerts a message that
says no seats remain and
then returns us a false
so we know that we don't
have any seats left.
Next, if the train
is not full, we
want to execute a function
that alerts a message with how
many seats actually do
remain and then returns true.
So what would this
look like in code?
Well we would say if
the number of passengers
currently equals
the capacity, that
means we've got a
full train, then
we'll call a function
called no seats.
Now, we haven't defined that
yet, but we will in a bit.
Otherwise, well, if the
number of passengers
doesn't equal the
capacity, we know
we have some seats remaining.
So we'll call a function
now called seats avail.
And that will tell how
many seats are available.
Now let's work on those
particular functions.
First we'll look at no seats.
What if we in our
normal coding process
just started to assign a no
seats variable a function
expression?
And we said, "Alert,
no seats left."
And then we return to false.
Next, if we did the same thing
on the seats avail function
and we just assigned a function
expression to the seats avail
variable, inside the
seats avail function,
we would just alert a
message that tells us
how many seats are
left for passengers.
And that function
would return true.
So now let's test this out.
What if we called
capacity status with 60?
And 60, that means we have a
capacity of 60 on our train
as well as the train is
full, we have 60 passengers.
So let's trace our
code and see what
the hoisting does in this case.
The first thing that
happens is the two variables
that will eventually get
function expressions are
hoisted to the top and they
will have undefined values.
After those variables
are hoisted,
we have the whole slew
of executable code.
The first part is the
conditional statements.
If we have the same amount
of passengers as capacity,
we'll call no seats.
Otherwise we'll
call seats avail.
Following that
happens the assignment
of the function expressions.
That's when no seats
and seats avail actually
get their functions.
So do you already
see the problem?
Hopefully you already
see the problem here.
Because when we get to if
the number of passengers
equals the capacity, we
will get a true on that
because it is true
that our capacity does
equal our number of passengers.
And then the compiler
will call no seats.
But uh-oh, it doesn't
even exist yet by the time
that it is called.
So this function will
completely error out
and we will not have
any message at all.
So, well, we now know that
hoisting causes problems.
What can we do to
fix these problems?
Couple ways.
Let's take a look at one.
First thing we could
do is actually change
the order of our code.
If we push all the
variable declarations
and their assignments
north up to the top and all
of the conditional code
down to the bottom,
the variable declarations
will happen in the hoisting
as well as the assignments will
happen directly after that.
So if we look at that
capacity status test case
again with 60 and 60, the
first thing that happens
is the variables get
hoisted to the top.
They're both undefined,
but the cool thing here
is that they immediately get
assigned their expressions.
Woo-hoo.
We like that.
And then the conditional code
is all the way in the bottom,
so we don't have to
worry about any execution
until everything's hoisted,
all the assignments are made,
and then we can
make an execution.
So now when we check to see
if none passengers equals
a capacity, it still does.
But this time when we call
no seats, everything's fine.
There's a function in
the no seats variable
and we're good to roll.
And we get our
nice alert message.
"No seats left!"
Second way to fix this
particular hoisting problem
would be to not have
function expressions at all.
Instead we could have
declared functions.
We're going to try
another test case here.
We're going to put
20 in so that we
can see how the else part
of our conditional works.
Because in this case, what?
The number of passengers
will not equal the capacity.
And let's see what happens in
the hoisting of this situation.
First thing, all the
functions pop up to the top.
They are loaded
into memory and sit
there waiting for
us to use them.
Again, the conditionals
fall to the bottom
because they are the
executable portion of the code.
Then we'll get a check to see
if the number of passengers
is equal to the capacity.
In our new case, it is not.
And so we'll skip
that if statement.
And we'll head
straight to the else
and we will call
seats available.
And guess what, seats
avail is already in memory.
We'll get a very
nice status that
says there are 40 seats left.
That's because 60
minus 20 is 40.
All day.
This was kind of a
short level, but we
wanted to make sure that you
understand that hoisting is not
something you do as you code.
It's something that sort of
happens to you on the back end
when your programs get loaded.
So be very careful as
you code, and we're
going to send you
to some challenges
now to make sure you understand
the hoisting concepts well.
See you soon.
If I have the puberty thing.
Because it will pop out.
Think about what you think.
JavaScripts Road
Trips [INAUDIBLE].