[SINGING] From the
Labyrinth of the Loops
to the Variable
Valley, we'll see
the Cliffs of Value
first. JaavaScript's.
right up your alley.
Built-in Bluffs, Files
Falls, Array Archipelago.
Declarations in a
desert where you'll
find out how far you'll go.
Learn the program.
Take a ride.
Buy a ticket.
Step inside.
All aboard!
You're at the station to
increase your education.
Bon voyage and skinny dip!
As long as functions,
you don't skip
on this the JavaScript Roadtrip.
Hope you've enjoyed
those last few levels.
And now we're going to take a
little bit of a different fork
in the road and look more in
depth at some JavaScript data
structures, specifically
the JavaScript object.
As you might expect, objects
are huge and powerful aspect
of the object-oriented
programming languages.
And objects in JavaScript
are no exception at all.
In this level, you'll be
looking at how objects contain
multiple pieces of related
data in one container,
as well as how to access
and manipulate that data,
as well as how to
build functionality
that an object can
own all by itself.
Now, this level's
kind of chunky.
But if you stick
with it, it'll soon
be smooth sailing for
all of your JavaScript
object-oriented
programming skills.
So with that, it's
time to dive in.
Here is the Ocean of Objects.
Welcome back.
This is Level 4, the
Ocean of Objects.
Hope you had a
great amount of fun
hoisting your hearts out
in the last challenges.
Let's move on to
exploring the object.
What is an object?
Well, an object is a container
of related information.
There'll be multiple pieces
of data called properties
that are grouped
within an object.
Let's take a look.
When we have an
object in JavaScript,
there are multiple properties
that belong to that object.
And we can represent everyday
stuff with JavaScript objects.
Since common things usually
have these bits of related info,
they will often make
a really great object
examples for JavaScript.
So let's take a
look at an object.
This is called a book.
You know what a book is, right?
They're kind of dusty in
the corner in your room.
Yeah.
Those are books.
Anyway, we have here some
properties of a book.
One would be the
title of the book.
That's a property.
How about the author?
As well as the publisher?
The number of chapters.
The number of pages.
And the Illustrator of the book.
These are all things
associated, bits of data,
associated with the book.
We could also have a box.
Some properties
associated with the box
might be the height,
the width, the length,
as well as the volume,
the material it's made of,
and whatever is inside
it - the contents.
Now, because an object
contains multiple bits
of value put together, it's
often called a composite value
because there are
multiple pieces.
Just like with
every day objects,
properties can point to
specific amounts or qualities
for that object.
So here we could have the
height being six, the width is eight,
and the length is 10.
Therefore, the
volume would be 480.
Material it's made of is
cardboard in this case.
Notice that's a string.
And the contents could be
this thing called booksArray
which is probably an
array of all the books
that are inside the box.
Properties, as you
may have noticed,
can refer to numbers,
strings, arrays, functions,
or any number of things,
including other objects.
Let's try now to create
an object with JavaScript.
Now, there are multiple ways
to build objects in JavaScript.
But we're going to look
at an easy way, probably
the one most often used.
It's called the Object literal.
We'll start here by
declaring a variable.
We'll call it my box.
And then, we'll assign
to it an empty set
of brackets, followed
by a semicolon.
Now, the curly brackets
say to make a new object
in JavaScript.
In this case,
however, it's empty
because we've got nothing in it.
To add a property inside
of an Object literal,
we give the property a string
name followed by a colon
and then assign a
value to that property.
We could do that multiple times.
The properties are just
separated by commas.
So we've got out width now,
our length, and our volume.
Let's add the material.
And we'll also add the contents.
But now, we will go
ahead and list out
an entire array
for the contents.
Sweet.
Now, we've got a
box object that's
complete with all
of its properties.
A cool thing about
objects, especially when
you initialize them, is that
they will accept variables.
So if instead we didn't
want to put the contents
as an array inside the my box,
we could build the array
outside the object.
And then, just pass in the
variable that holds that array.
Now, we've got a reference to
the books Arrays inside my box.
Great.
So we got an object.
Well, what do we with it?
Typically, objects
are used because you
want to refer to their
properties together.
So let's take a
look at how we can
peek at a particular
property inside of an object.
Remember when we accessed
the length on strings,
and we use the dot operator?
We're going to do that
again here with objects.
So if we wanted to find
the width inside my box,
we would do mybox.width.
And that accesses the property.
And we get eight.
Sweet.
If we wanted the materials
to do the same thing,
look it pops back
cardboard as a string.
And if we wanted to
access the contents,
we would do mybox.contents.
And what happens there when
we ask for mybox.contents?
Well, my box looks inside
at the contents property,
sees the books Array
variable, which
refers to the books
array outside the object,
and that is what gets returned,
the entire books Array.
Which you can see here.
Changing property
values inside of objects
is one very useful
aspect of objects.
And we can do that
with the dot operator.
If we wanted to change the width
inside of our mybox object,
we would just call
mybox.width again
and set that equal to
12 which will change
the width inside
the object to 12.
We can show that by logging out
the property mybox.width which
shows a very nice
12, now, as a result.
Uh oh, though.
That makes our volume incorrect.
So we're going to have to
do something about that.
We're going to set
the mybox.volume
equal to the length times
the width times the height.
Which is what volume is, right?
This is a good
example of how you
can use properties of
an object to impact
other properties
within that object.
And now, we get a
nice volume of 720.
So everything is
right with the world.
What happens if we wanted to
modify the contents of our box?
We want to put a new
book inside our box.
Well, we would call
mybox.contents,
and that returns an entire
array, the entire books Array.
And with that, we can apply
all of the array methods
that we already know
from Roadtrips 1 and 2.
So let's push on that array
On the Road by Jack Kerouac.
You can see that very
quickly On the Road
is added to our
books Array on the outside.
But whoa.
How did that happen?
How did we modify the external
array outside of the my box?
The thing is that when we passed
in books Array as a variable,
all that does is
make a reference
to the external array.
It doesn't create a
brand new copied array.
Very important to understand.
So that when you get that
array back from mybox.contents,
it's going to be
the external array.
And when you push
to that, you're
going to add it to
the external array.
Now, if we were to log
out, our mybox.contents
will refer to booksArray.
And we get the entire
newly adjusted array.
Also just to show that
we mean what we say,
if we log out the booksArray, we
will get the same exact array.
Another cool thing
about objects is
that you can continue
to add properties
even after you have built
your object Literal.
Even after that
object is created,
you can throw as many
properties in there as you want.
For example, if we wanted to add
a weight property to the box,
we could do mybox.weight
and set it equal to 24.
When you do this,
the my box object
is going to hunt around inside
itself for the weight property.
And finding none, it
will create one for you
and set it equal to 24.
We could also add a couple
destinations for the box.
If we did mybox.destination1
and set it equal to Orlando,
that would show up
inside of our my box.
And then, if we
did a destination 2
and said that was Miami,
that would also show up.
We've got a second way
of accessing or creating
properties that's just as
important and sometimes more
important than the dot operator.
That's the bracket method.
You can think about
this as similar
to accessing array indices.
The thing about these brackets
as opposed to the brackets you
would use on arrays is that
you must pass in a string
in order to reference
the property.
So here if we wanted to find the
volume property using brackets,
we would pass in
the string volume,
and it would give us 720.
If we also wanted to
find out the material,
we do the same thing
and get back cardboard.
You can think of an object
just like an array but
whose indices are accessed with
strings instead of numbers.
Here's a pretty cool thing about
the whole bracket and string
access.
If you want to make
properties that
have spaces between the
words, that's totally fine
because the object
just looks for a string
and will find whatever
string name you have provided
or create whatever string
name you have provided.
So here, if we wanted to
add the number of stops
that our my box is
going to make, we
could do that with
a nice string.
Notice the spaces.
Number of stops.
And set that equal to 2.
You got to be real careful with
those property names that have
spaces though because if
you try to log out, m box.
"# of stops",
you'll get an error.
That's because there's no
such thing as a dot string.
You can't access a
property with a dot string.
It's always got to
be bracket string
or dot a string
name with no quotes.
In this case, when you
want to access your my box
number of stops, you
have to use a bracket.
Yet another cool thing
is that those brackets
will accept expressions.
And that's going to enable us
to get dynamic property access.
That's going to enable
us to avoid hard
coding every last property
access that we would want.
Let's take a look.
So here we've got a for loop.
We establish a loop counter.
And we're going to loop over
the entire amount of stops
that our mybox goes through.
And then, we're going to
log out each destination.
How are we going to do that?
We're going to access each
of the destinations 1 and 2
by using a dynamic expression
inside of the bracket.
Notice, that we've got a string
destination plus the loop
counter.
Notice the loop
counter starts at 1.
So as this loop progresses,
we would get an expression
destination 1 and destination
2 inside those logs.
And what will we get?
We'll get Orlando, and
then, we'll get Miami.
In this way, you could
continue to add destinations
to your my box,
and it will be able
to log out each one
with this simple loop and
the bracket expression.
Here's where it gets interesting
because our contents could
actually be individual objects.
Each book that's in
our contents property
could actually be
its own book object.
Let's take a look.
First, we need to delete
our contents property
with the delete keyword.
Let's see we can do here.
So there's the delete
keyword, and we
say delete mybox.contents.
Notice, the syntax.
What's going to happen here
is that the delete keyword
will completely delete the
entire contents property.
It will not be there anymore.
It's not just deleting
the booksArray variable
and leaving the
contents name there.
Nope.
Property is gone.
From our delete command, we
get a true back saying, yes, we
have deleted the property.
If we log out,
console.log booksArray,
we still get the same array.
That's because we haven't
actually deleted the array,
we've just deleted
the property that
references the array
inside of our object.
Now, you got to be careful
about that delete command
because guess what?
It's always going
to return true.
If I tried to delete
mybox.nonexistentproperty,
we get a true back.
What?
Weird.
It was never even there.
Now, why is that?
You should think about
the delete command
as asking, is this property
gone after it has been deleted.
So of course, if it looks for
something and it's not there,
it's going to say true.
The property is gone.
Cool.
Now, we'll build a function
that creates book objects,
and we're going to
add those to our box.
Wow.
This is going to be fun.
First, we'll need
a property that
tracks the number of books
that's inside of our box,
and we're going to go ahead
and set that initially to 0.
Our function will need
it to dynamically assign
property names in
that bracket fashion
that we just saw earlier.
So here's our function.
We call addBook.
We're going to pass
in the box that we
want to add the books
to, the name of the book
as well as the writer.
As soon as the addBook
the function is called,
we want to immediately
increase the number
of books inside of our box.
We'll do that with our
bracket expression.
Why our bracket expression?
Because the string
has spaces in it.
So we want to be real careful
there to use the bracket.
Now, here's where the money is.
Check this out and
follow really closely.
We're going to call the
box with an expression that
is dynamically made.
And what's it
dynamically made from?
First, the string
book concatenated
with another reference
of the box inside which
is the number of books.
So you can tell you that when
we call this very first add Book,
we're going to get
Book 1 out of it
because the very first
number of books is 1.
And then, what do we assign
to that new book property?
We start up an object Literal
where the title property
gets the name and
the author property
gets the writer parameter.
Cool.
So there's our function.
Now, we're getting
ready to add some books.
Let's do it.
We'll call add Book,
and we'll pass in my box
because that's the box we
want to add the book to.
We're going to add
Great Expectations
by Charles Dickens.
First thing that happens
is our number of books
gets increased to 1.
And we get a fresh book
object inside of our my box.
Notice that the correct book
number in the property name
has been dynamically assigned.
How cool is that?
Next, we'll add The Remains
of the Day by Kazuo Ishiguro.
That will automatically increase
our number of books to 2.
And add a brand
new book number 2.
We see the title and the
author assigned appropriately.
Third, we'll put in
Peter Pan by J.M. Barrie.
Our number books increases to 3.
We get a new book object
called book3 as the property.
And our title and
author are just fine.
And then, when we pass in lastly
On the Road by Jack Kerouac,
we'll get our fourth book
and our fourth book object.
Now, you might ask, well, if
I've got a bunch of objects
inside of objects, how do I
get to those deep internal
properties that are inside
the internal objects?
Well, we can just use a
subsequent dot notation
to access those properties.
So if I wanted to get to
the title of, say, book 1,
I would use
console.log, mybox.book1
which pulls out book 1.
And then, it looks at the title
with that next dot notation.
And what do we get?
We get Great Expectations.
Another way of doing
that, of course,
is with the bracket expression.
So we could use
mybox on book 4 which
pulls out the book4 object.
And then, looks at the author
property inside of book 4
which gives us Mr. Jack Kerouac.
Wow.
So your brains are filled with
object knowledge at this point.
So we're going to give you
some challenges to mess around
and play with object,
add stuff, delete stuff.
It's going to be great fun.
And we'll see you back
in the next section.