Welcome back.
In this section, we
will be exploring
functionality inside of objects.
So here, we're going to start
with an aquarium object -
we are in the Ocean of Objects,
after all - an aquarium object
filled with other objects.
And let's first build some
add and remove functionality
for our aquarium.
Inside our aquarium, you can see
we have some fish, a star fish,
as well a couple toys, a coral
castle and the dragon statue.
Our aquarium looks pretty good.
But what if we wanted
to add some creatures?
Well, we can build a
function called addCritter.
And in that, we would pass
a container - in this case,
we're probably going to be
passing the aquarium-- as well
as the name of our creature,
the type, the species,
and the length.
We can also create
an add Toy function.
This one would get the
container, the name, the type,
the material, as well as
whether it moves or not.
To add a creature
to our container,
we would do container
bracket name
and assign to it
a brand new object
literal where we pass
the parameters into each
of the properties
for that object.
Now wouldn't it be nice if
these functions actually
belonged to the aquarium
instead of being
external to the aquarium itself.
Let's try adding one
of these functions
to our aquarium object.
Important thing about objects
is that properties can also
be functions.
That's going to allow us to
add our add Critter function in.
Something to be aware of
is that you will often
hear an object's
function properties being
referred to as its methods.
So to add a new property
that holds a function,
we would just create an
add Critter property, much
like we would create
other properties.
And then inside of it, we would
build an anonymous function.
Now something to really
pay attention to here
is that our container
parameter has disappeared.
And that's because we're
making the function belong
to that very container.
We're going to use
a special syntax now
that refers to the
aquarium object.
Now, the this
keyword will always
refer to the owner object of the
function in which the this is
used.
So in this case, when
called, add Critter
will say, "Hey, aquarium -
that's what the this does -
make a new property
with this name - that's
the one in the bracket -
and then assign to it
an object with these
particular properties.
Sweet.
We've got a property
that holds a function.
Awesome.
And now, it's available as
a property on the aquarium
objects.
So let's go ahead
and add a creature.
Let's add a yellow
tang called "Bubbles."
If we pass in the name Bubbles,
which we know is a fish
and the kind of fish is
a Yellow Tang species.
And its length is 5.6.
We just call the function
just like referencing
any other property in aquarium.
But in this one, we put up a set
of parentheses for parameters
and pass in the information.
And here comes Bubbles.
He drops into the aquarium.
And we have all of Bubbles'
properties set correctly.
Hmm.
Well, our tank's
looking a little full
so let's try to build
another method that
will be able to remove any of
the objects from our aquarium.
And since you already
know how to build
a function inside the object
literal with a property,
let's now try to build
a function on the fly.
And we can do that with the
dot operator and a function
expression.
All we will need here, to
delete any property whether it's
a fish or a toy or even
a function, is its name.
What we'll need here
is a temp variable
that will help us hold onto
the object that we remove.
So what we're
doing here is we're
saying, create this temp
variable and assign to it
a reference to the object
that this name points to.
Why are we doing this?
Because we still
want to have access
to the object outside
of the aquarium.
We don't want it to float
off into code oblivion.
We want to be able
to use it or maybe
place it on the table
or something like that.
Next, we will remove the actual
property from the aquarium.
That's with the delete keyword.
Finally, we'll return
the temp variable
so that we can still
have a reference
to that removed object once
the take Out method is finished.
Let's test our take Out method.
So we'll get a variable
established here
called fish Out Of Water.
And we'll take out a fish.
Who are we going to take out?
We'll take out Marlin.
What happens is that Marlin's
entire property is completely
eliminated.
And Marlin gets established
inside the fish Out Of Water
variable now.
If we were to log out the
fish Out Of Water variable,
we can see that the entire
fish object of Marlon
is still available.
But wait a second.
That kind of sucks because
we lost Marlin's name.
So let's see if we
can fix that problem
with some clever
property trickery.
We're going to add an extra
line to our take Out method.
This is going to make sure
that we get Marlin's name
when we remove him
from the aquarium.
Don't let this frighten you.
But stay very close on it.
The first name in
this line of code
will find the desired
object in the aquarium
and using the parameter
name as the property name.
So this bracket name is
finding, inside the aquarium,
the object we're looking for.
Then we use a dot.
And that second name will
create a new property
inside the object that
we want to remove.
This is kind of cool.
Notice though that
that dot name is not
the same name as the
function's parameter.
That's very important.
This third name, however,
is the function's parameter.
It assigns the old property
name, which we already
know is Marlin, to
the newly created name
property in the removed object.
How sneaky and cool is that?
We love it.
Now, when we take
Marlin out, and then we
log out his variable, on
the back end of our object,
we see a new property
name called name.
And Marlin's name is there.
Woohoo, no identity crisis.
Fantastic.
Now the cool thing
about our take Out method
is that it will
take out any object.
We could delete even
our dragon statue.
So let's try that.
We'll establish a
variable called toy
and go ahead and take
out the dragon statue.
It shows up inside
the toy variable.
And when we log out the
toy, this time, we can see,
not only has the toy been
taken out of the aquarium,
but look at the back end.
You can see the name was
saved, dragon statue.
So now you know how
to add and manipulate
functions inside of objects.
And we're going to give
you a few challenges that
do just that.
I hope you enjoy them.
We'll see you back
in the next section.