Welcome back.
I hope you enjoyed
those challenges.
And we're on to the
third section of Level 4.
We're going to try to count
some fish in our tank.
What if we wanted to know
exactly how many fish we have
inside of our tank
at any given time?
Let's take a look.
So we've got our
aquarium object.
And we've just some
icons here for shorthand.
But just know that those
represent the objects
that we've added or that
were in there earlier.
You'll notice that
we put Bubbles up
near the front with
the other fish,
just to have a little bit better
organization for this task.
So let's count our fish.
Let's see how many fish
we've got going on here.
The first one is
the Nemo property.
And if we look at
its type, we see
that Nemo is definitely a fish.
We'll follow that with Dory.
Dory is also a fish.
Bubbles is a fish.
But Peach is an econaderm.
We call it a star fish.
It's not really a fish.
Then we move onto
the coral castle.
And that's an environment.
Well, add Critter is a function.
It's definitely not a fish.
And take Out, same thing--
it's definitely not a fish.
So three fish total.
And how we did that
feels like a loop.
So intuitively, we
think maybe if we
loop over the properties
of our object,
we could find out how
many fish are in there
just by checking the type.
There's one caveat here though.
And that's that the aquarium
does not have a length.
That's completely undefined.
It's not like an array where we
can just count the cells using
the length property because
generic objects don't really
have a native length,
like arrays or strings,
we would not be able to use
that length inside of a loop
parameter.
We need a different way.
Welcome to enumeration
using the for-in loop.
It's a new kind of loop we're
going to show you right now.
The for-in loop
will let us access
each of the innumerable
properties in turn.
You might ask what
innumerable means.
For right now, you should just
know that it means every object
or property that we have added
to this object ourselves.
We'll go into exactly
what innumerable
means in a later course.
So here we have our very
special for-in loop.
You can see the for
keyword, which looks just
like the for-loop keyword.
But inside the
parameters of this loop,
you can see on the
left-hand side,
the word key and in between
the two words is in.
And on the right-hand
side is aquarium.
Now, key here represents
every single property
that is present
inside of aquarium.
And the end keyword
will look in the object
on the right-hand side
for every possible key
on the left-hand side.
You could think of
it like accessing
each index of an array.
Now, if we were to log out each
of these keys, which you know are just
property names, we would get
Nemo, Dory, Bubbles, Peach,
Coral Castle, add Critter,
and lastly take Out.
Something to note here is
that our word key is not
any special keyword or anything.
We could use whatever name
we want before the in keyword
to refer to each property
inside the object, such as, say,
item or even the
letter p for property
or any real intuitive
word that you like.
Think of it like a
parameter that points only
to the string names
of the properties.
The cool thing is that it's
a name you get to create.
For now, though, we're going
to go ahead and stick with key
since it's an often-used word to
describe the name of a property
within an object.
Now that we've got our
enumeration set up,
we need a way to determine
which properties in the aquarium
are actually fish.
First thing we'll do is we'll
set up a variable called
num Fish.
That's going to be our counter.
Then we set up a conditional
where we ask the aquarium
if the current
key that we're on,
which is just a
property name string,
has a type that is fish.
Something to note here
is that once we've
accessed the object
that the key refers to,
we can just check
out its type property
to see if it matches
the string fish.
And if that's true,
we'll go ahead and just
increment our num Fish variable.
What happens, though, when
we get to the add Critter
function, which is way down
there at the end of the object
and we try to access
it and then see
what its type property holds?
Well, that's going
to be undefined.
So that's still OK because
undefined does not equal fish.
So we will never increment our
numFish variable on a function.
So let's check out how our
loop actually progresses.
The first thing that happens
is that key becomes a Nemo.
That's our very first
current property.
And so our conditional looks
up aquarium Nemo and asks,
does it have a doc type?
Does it have a type property?
Yes, it does.
Let's check it out.
What is it?
It's fish.
So does type equal fish?
Yes, it does.
That's true.
And our num Fish variable
is incremented to 1.
The same thing happens for Dory.
It does have a type property.
And that type is fish.
So we get num Fish
incremented to 2.
And then when we do Bubbles,
the same procedure happens.
And we get num Fish
incremented to 3.
But then we get to Peach.
And it does have
a type property.
But it's type is not fish.
It's econaderm.
So type is not equal to fish.
And we do not increment
the num Fish variable.
Same thing occurs
with the Coral Castle
because its type is environment.
Lastly, we get to add Critter.
And it doesn't even
have a type variable
so it will be undefined.
And that will stay
false when we try
to check whether the
type is the fish.
And we will not
increment num Fish
for either add Critter
or take Out.
And if we try to log out
our num Fish variable,
we can see we have three
fish inside of our aquarium.
Now we've built all this
functionality outside
of the object.
We really want to put
that inside the aquarium
so that we can call an
aquarium fish counter.
So let's scoot our
stuff over here.
And we'll go ahead and
establish a new property
inside of our aquarium
called aquarium.countFish.
And we'll assign a
function expression
to that particular property.
Inside it, all of our
code that we built.
Now something special needs
to happen inside of our code,
though, because every place that
we had aquarium-- can you think
of what we're going
to place here?
We're going to put
the this keyword.
That's right.
Because it needs to refer to
the owner object of the function
that's being called.
Additionally, since we're
building a function,
we now need to return
something from that function.
So we'll go ahead and
return our num Fish variable.
Magically, our
count Fish function
appears inside of
our aquarium object.
And when we call
aquarium.countFish, we get 3.
Awesome.
Let's take Dory out.
We'll establish a
poor Dory variable.
And we'll call
aquarium.takeOut on Dory.
Dory pops right out.
We'll scoot our
objects closer here.
And the delete that
happens inside of take Out
will return us a true.
And now Dory is held
inside of poor Dory.
If we were to now call
aquarium.countFish,
we appropriately get
2 because now there
are only two fish inside
the aquarium object.
And that is the end of
the Ocean of Objects.
Now we've got a
bunch more challenges
here for you to
really test the work
that you've done
with these objects.
Hope you've had a great time.
And we'll see you back
in the next level.
And that's what
gets [INAUDIBLE] -
[LAUGHTER]
We need to delete [INAUDIBLE] -
The colossal fail.