[SINGING] From the Labyrinth of
Loops to the Variable Valley,
we'll see the Cliffs
of Value first.
JavaScript's right
up your alley.
Built-ins Bluff, Files
Falls, Array Archipelago,
declarations in a
desert where you'll
find out how far you'll go.
Learn to program, take a ride.
Buy a ticket, step inside.
All aboard, you're
at the station
to increase your education.
Bon voyage and skinny
dip, as long as functions
you don't skip on this
the JavaScript Road Trip.
Whew, you made it out of those, huh?
I hope they weren't
too challenging.
But these might be.
So in this level,
we'll be looking
at the broad concept
of inheritance, which
is a very common object
oriented practice.
And specifically,
we'll be looking
at how it relates to JavaScript.
Periodically when
we code, we want
to build a program that has
a vast amount of objects,
all of which share
some small amount
of similar functionality.
Now, we don't
really want to build
that similar functionality
inside every one
of those objects.
Can you imagine the
memory storage issues
that might occur?
So instead,
JavaScript provides us
with a very nice
blueprint object
that will pass those
similar properties out
to every single one of those
objects that we have made.
So saddle up boys and
girls and grab your lasso,
because you've reached the
dusty and dangerous Plains
of Prototypes.
Watch out for twisters.
Welcome back.
This is a Level Five,
the Plains of Prototypes.
Surprise.
Guess what?
The objects we have built so
far have some secret properties
that we never saw
or talked about.
That's right.
Nemo, Bubbles, the book,
the box, the castle, Dory,
and the aquarium all have
a bunch of properties
that they were given just
as soon as we created them.
These are properties like
value of, constructor,
to Locale String, to
String, is Prototype Of,
property Is Enumerable,
and has Own Property.
Hmm.
Interesting.
Where did these come from?
All these objects have a
mysterious parent object
that gives them some
extra properties.
We want to remove
that mystery for you.
An object's parent is
called its prototype.
And all of these methods that
you see come from something
called the object prototype.
When a generic
object is created,
its prototype is going to pass
it many important properties.
So when we made that aquarium
object before and put
a whole bunch of stuff in
it, the object prototype
passed it tons of
extra properties.
A prototype is like
a blueprint object
for the object we
are trying to create.
JavaScript has a
set of properties
that it wants every
object to have.
And so the highest prototype,
the object prototype,
passes all those
properties to every object.
Passing down properties
is called inheritance.
Inheritance is a super important
thing inside of programming
and it goes a long way to
helping us avoid over coding.
It helps prevent building
multiple, multiple properties
and methods that are exactly
the same into similar objects.
In other words, it helps us
not have a billion storage
locations for the
exact same information.
So far all of the
objects literals
that we've made with
the curly brackets,
they inherit directly from the
very highest level and the js
hierarchy.
That's the object prototype.
Turns out though, that
all of the JavaScript data
structures that you
can think of will all
inherit their properties
and methods from their very
own prototypes, not just
the object prototype.
Let's take a look.
If I had an array and it has
a bunch of strings in it,
the array actually
inherits from something
called the array prototype.
So all of those array methods
that we've seen or used inside
of the previous
Road Trip course,
like length, pop and push,
and shift, and some others,
they all come from
the array prototype.
And those are passed down
into the array object
that we've created so that we
can call each of those methods
or properties on our my Array.
Same thing goes with strings.
If we established a
variable called my String
and we built a
string inside of it,
that string is secretly a
child of the string prototype.
And the string prototype
passes a whole bunch
of string properties and methods
to our my String variable.
That's how come we
can call the length
property on a
my String as well as
char At and various
other string methods.
Similarly, the number prototype
passes a few properties
into every number variable.
And lastly but certainly not
least, the function prototype
will pass a few properties
and methods to every function
declared or otherwise
that you create.
So are you ready for this?
Not only do all those values
inherit from their prototypes,
but the prototypes
inherit directly
from the object prototype.
That means that the array,
string, number, and function
prototypes as well as all
the other prototypes that
exist in JavaScript have
access to all of those object
prototype properties.
So coming back to
my String, which
inherits from the
string prototype,
not only does it get all the
string prototype methods,
but it also gets all of the
object prototype methods.
Because the object
prototype is an ancestor
of the string prototype
and thus the my String.
Now, inheritance is
really cool because it
avoids a whole bunch of
duplicate memory storage.
So instead of hard coding all
of those properties and methods
into every object we
could ever create,
instead they inherit from
one very nice location.
But it's really
important to recognize
that though properties
are inherited,
they're still owned
by the prototypes,
not the inheriting object.
So what does that mean?
That means that the properties
that belong to the object
prototype are actually stored
there and they stay there.
And that's good, because we want
them to only be in one location
so that every
object that we make
can inherit from
that one location.
For example, the
has Own Property
is owned by the
object prototype,
so that when we would call
it on my string what happens
is my string looks up to the
string prototype to say,"Hey,
do you have this has
own Property Thing?
Because I don't have it."
String prototype says no, and
so the search continues up
what's called the
prototype chain.
When the search gets to
the object prototype,
the object prototype
says, "Yes, I have
the has own property method.
And let's go ahead and
let my String use it."
Why?
Because object
prototype is an ancestor
of the my String variable.
Something to note
here is that my String
has access to the has own
property method without it
needing to be stored inside
the myString variable.
Pretty cool, right?
So the same goes with a
common string property
like chartAt, which
you've seen before
in Road Trips one and two.
my String looks up to the
string prototype and says,
"Yo, string prototype, do
you have a char At method?"
String prototype says yes,
"I have a charAt method,
and you are most
welcome to use it."
Since the string
prototype owns the char At,
the search is going
to stop right there.
The string prototype will
grant my String the access
to the function.
Inheritance is pretty awesome.
We're going to try to blow
your mind a little bit here.
What if we wanted
to add some base
values or some functionality to
all objects of a similar type?
Hmm.
Yes, we can add inheritable
properties to prototypes.
Let's say here that we
had a bunch of strings
in whatever program
we were working on
and we needed to be able to
count the amount of any letter
within each string.
For example, in
these strings, if we
wanted to know the
amount of A's we
could see that witch would have
one, Scarecrow four, Glinda
one, Dorothy one, Lion has
two, the wizard has four,
and the Tin Man has five.
Additionally, if we want
to know how many E's were
in these strings, we would
get three, five, seven, four,
three, five, five in
order for those strings.
Well, that seems
pretty easy, right?
Counting letters?
But since this functionality
doesn't actually
exist in the ready made
JavaScript string methods
we'd have to build that
functionality ourselves,
either in declared function
or a function expression
or something like that.
Turns out though that we can add
such a function to the string
prototype as a property.
And then all of the
strings that we build
will have access to that
property to use at any time.
That's inheritance.
That's pretty cool, right?
So let's try it.
We'll start to build a new
function inside of the string
prototype.
Now, this dot notation
that you see here
finds the prototype for all
string values everywhere.
To add our function directly
to the string prototype,
we're just going
to use another dot
and assign a new property
name called count All.
Because we're going to be
counting a bunch of letters.
By adding this to
the string prototype,
we've now made it
inheritable to all strings
everywhere, even ones
that already exist.
So we'll assign to it
a function expression,
and since we're
giving the function
to the overarching
string prototype,
we won't really need to
pass the function a string
because the string will be
calling the function itself.
All we need to give
it is a letter.
We need to make sure
we give it a letter so
that the function knows which
letter we're looking for.
Next we'll get a for loop going.
Check this out.
So inside we've got our
loop counter set up.
And we're only going to
run so long as we have not
reached the end of the string.
Now since the string
we are interested in
is going to be the very string
that is calling count All,
we want to use the very
important this key word
to refer back to
that caller string.
Now before you saw
that this was being
used to refer to an owner.
And that's because
the owner was actually
the caller of the property.
So here you can see
in a little more depth
that the this keyword always
refers to the calling object,
whether that caller
is the actual owner
of the property
being called or not.
Now here's where the money is.
This is the
conditional that checks
to see if we have found
the right letter as we
move through the stream.
Let's look at the left hand
side of this conditional.
We have this, which refers
to the string that's
calling count all.
And then we have char At
I. What's that doing?
You know what that's doing.
It's looking at a particular
letter inside of the string.
Then we have a dot to uppercase.
That's a very cool and
useful string method,
but how is that going to work
if we only get a character back
from the char At method?
Well, it turns out that
char At gives us back in fact
a string that just happens
to be one character long.
Now to uppercase will
take any string even,
one that is only
one character long,
and convert any alphabetic
characters inside it
to uppercase.
You can see here
that a lowercase "bam!"
with an exclamation point
becomes a Batman style bam when
to uppercase gets a hold of it.
Now why would we be doing this?
Well let's check out
the right hand side.
The letter dot to uppercase will
return whichever letter we've
passed in as an
uppercase letter.
What does this do?
It means that our
comparison is only
looking at capitalized
letters the whole time.
And that way we don't have to
have these complex conditionals
that look for lowercase
and uppercase altogether.
We've taken care of it
with one line of code.
Something to note about
the to uppercase method
is that if the letter
you're looking at
is already uppercase, it
will just stay uppercase.
So if we have a match, then
inside that conditional
we should adjust our
letter count to say yes.
We have found one of the
letters we're looking for.
At the end of our
function, we'll
just return the amount
of letters that we found.
Great.
We've added a function
to the string prototype
that all strings everywhere
should now be able to access.
First, let's try calling
count all on the witch string
and let's pass in I as the
letter that we are looking for.
You'll notice there's an
I inside aisle as well
as in little, for
a total of two I's.
Then we can call count
all on Scarecrow.
Notice this is a completely
different string.
That's because we added count
all to the string prototype.
If we pass in O to our count
all method on Scarecrow,
we find the O's in some,
people, without, do, lot,
of, and don't.
For a total of seven O's.
Similarly, if we call
count all on lion with K,
we would see the K in
junkyard for a total of one.
And if we called it
on tin man with N,
we would find the N's in
now, no, and breaking,
for a total of three.
Sweet.
Now you know all
about prototypes.
Well, not all about prototypes,
but a lot about prototypes.
And you also know how to add
functions into those prototypes
so that all of your objects
can use different functionality
that you've put
into the prototypes.
We're going to give you a few
challenges on these topics,
and we'll see you back
in the next section.