Welcome back.
Hope you enjoyed that
set of challenges.
You are now in section two
of the Plains of Prototypes.
In this section, the first
thing we're going to do
is take a look at a
second way to build
objects using object.create.
And it will tie-in very
importantly with prototypes.
Using inheritance, we
can create new objects
with our existing
objects as prototypes.
So here we're going
to go ahead and set up
a new object, a new shoe.
And we're going to give it
a size, property - a gender
property, as well as a
construction property.
If we wanted to create a
new object that used shoe
as a prototype, we'll create
a variable called magic Shoe.
And we will use the
object.create method
and pass in shoe.
Whatever you pass in
to the create method
will be the prototype
for the new object.
If we logged out
our magic Shoe now,
we would see that the object
is exactly the same as the shoe
object.
It inherited all
of its properties
from shoe, just like we'd
expect from our prototype.
Now, on this new object, we
could add a few properties.
Let's say jewels
would be "ruby".
We could say travel Action
would be "click heels".
Is this sounding familiar?
And then the actions
required would be three.
And then we would get a
ruby slipper out of it.
Fantastic.
If we log out the
magic Shoe now, you
can see that we have all
of the new properties added
to our object.
Just to show that our original
prototype object has not
changed at all, we
can log out shoe.
And we can see that everything
has stayed exactly the same.
Let's take a closer look
at the inheritance inside
of our new shoe set up.
We can actually use
an inherited method
from the object
prototype to demonstrate
our newly created
prototype chain.
Take a look at
this line of code.
It says,
Object.prototype.isPrototypeOf.
Do you remember
that property from
the
Object.prototype.isPrototypeOf?
What it will do is look
at the object on the left
and see if it's a prototype
of the parameter object.
So in this case, we're
asking, is Object.prototype
a prototype of shoe?
Since that is true - the
object prototype is, in fact,
a prototype of shoe -
we'll get a true
returned from that method.
Next, if we were to call
shoe.
isPrototypeOf( magicShoe), we will also get a true.
That's because we used shoe
as the prototype of magic Shoe.
That goes to show
that we don't always
get true from this situation.
If we called
magicShoe.isPrototypeOf( shoe
), we would see
that that is false.
That's because the
magic Shoe is not
at all the prototype of shoe.
Now, what happens if we call
Object.prototype.isPrototypeOf(
magicShoe )?
Well, you might think false
because object prototype is
way up there and magic Shoe
is way down there.
But actually, this returns true.
And that's because isPrototypeOf
looks all the way upward,
through the entire
prototype chain,
to see if the object that's
on the left-hand side
is ever a direct ancestor
of the object that's
passed in as a parameter.
In this case, it only
has to go two steps up
to find the object prototype.
And so we get a
true value returned.
Cool.
So now, what if there
were other kinds of shoes?
Could we use the same prototype
to create boots, sneakers,
sandals, or whatever that is?
Well, let's check
it out and see.
So here's our shoe
variable, right?
We've got a size six.
We've got a gender of "women".
We've got a construction
of "slipper".
If we've decided to make
a variable called "mens Boot"
and assigned to
it the new object
that comes out of object.create
on shoe, what do we get?
We get a men's boot with a
size of six, a gender of women,
and a construction on slipper.
That's no good.
That kind of sucks.
We're not really getting what
we were looking for here.
Hm.
What can we do about
that kind of situation?
Well, we might build
a prototype that
has just empty properties -
all of the properties
that we want that are empty.
Let's see what happens
when we do that.
If we make our
shoe variable have
all of those same
properties, but now set
all of those properties
to undefined,
well, so now we have a
prototype that's empty.
But what do we do with it?
Well, let's try making
a mens Boot variable
and assigning to
it the object that
comes out of
object.create on shoe.
What we get, then, is just
an empty shoe object, right?
And then we have to assign
all of the properties
their specific values.
We'd also need to do the same
thing with a variable called
"flipflop."
We could create a
shoe - an empty shoe -
and then assign all
of the properties.
Guess what?
This kind of sucks.
You could see, already,
how tedious this
would be if every time you
went to create a new shoe,
off the generic empty
shoe, you needed
to put every single property
in each one of those objects.
That would be kind of terrible.
And actually, all of
that is way more code
than it would take to just start
out by coding an object literal
and putting all
of the properties
in on your very
first object literal.
So we need a different way
that won't be so cumbersome
and that will automate
our property assignment.
Let's take a look.
Pretty cool.
First thing we need
to do: we need
to determine a whole bunch of
common properties of a shoe
class.
What's a class?
It's a set of objects
that all share and inherit
from the same basic prototype.
So size - we know that's one
that a shoe should have, right?
All shoes have a size.
How about color?
Yep.
That's All Shoes.
Gender?
Yeah.
Construction?
Sounds good.
How about lace color?
Well, some shoes don't
really have laces.
Look at the slipper, I
mean, or the flip-flop
doesn't have any laces.
So let's go ahead and put
that under Some Shoes.
How about the function lace Up?
Say, if we had a function
that laced up the shoes,
does that belong to All Shoes?
No, because not all
shoes have laces.
So we'll put that
under Some Shoes.
How about jewels?
Thankfully, not all
shoes have jewels.
What about bow position?
Well, no.
I don't imagine there's
many bows on work boots.
What about put On?
Well, yeah.
We could have a function for
All Shoes that puts on the shoe.
dimensional Travel, like,
say, for the ruby slippers.
I'm pretty sure
dimensional Travel is just
Some Shoes.
Don't quote me.
And take Off, take Off is
probably an All Shoes function.
Now, with a good set
of these properties
we can expect all of
the shoes to have,
we're going to be ready,
now, to build what's
called a constructor
for our class.
These other ones
we'd get to later.
So now we will build
a constructor function
for our shoe object.
A constructor is going to allow
us to set up an inheritance,
as well as assign
specific property
values for a specific
instance of the object.
That's pretty cool.
Looking down here, you can see
we've established a function,
and we've called it
Shoe with a capital S.
That's important because
capitalizing a function's name
sort of distinguishes
it, in JavaScript,
as a maker of an entire
class of objects.
Now, each of these
parameters that you see here
will be specific values for
a specific kind of a shoe.
The Constructor function will
construct a brand new shoe
and then pass these
specific parameters
into that particular
instance of the shoe.
Now, how will it do that?
How will it take the
parameters of the function
and put it into a
new shoe object?
Well, we will use the
this keyword, here.
And again, the this
keyword is very useful.
The this keyword is going
to have some unique behavior
inside of our function.
It's automatically
going to refer
to the new instance of
the class that is made.
So when we set this.size
equal to shoeSize,
as well as these other
assignments, what's happening
is the Shoe
Constructor is building
a new instance of a shoe and
passing all of these parameters
into that particular
object from the class.
We could also add some
functionality here.
Here's our putOn and
takeOff functions,
which we've assigned as
function expressions.
Inside one, we've got an alert
that says, "Shoes on!"
And then, in the
takeOff function,
we've got an alert that
says, uh, what's that smell?
The important thing to note
is that these functions
will be common to
all shoes everywhere.
Now we've got to
figure out how to use
the Constructor to actually
make the new shoe object.
Well, we've got a
new keyword here.
And it is new, in fact.
What we'll do is we'll establish
a new beachShoe variable.
And we'll assign
to it the object
that comes out of the
Constructor function.
How do we call the
Constructor function?
You can see there that that
new keyword asks the Shoe
Constructor to
make a new instance
with these particular
parameters,
meaning "10" and "blue"
and "women" and "flipflop".
If we go ahead and
log out beach Shoe,
we can see that we
get a Shoe object.
Notice that the front
of the object, its name
has changed from object to Shoe.
It's because we have a Shoe
object, and inside of it,
all of the exactly
correct properties that we
would expect, plus
some functions.
If we were to now
call beach Shoe.put On,
we'll get a pop-up that
says, "Shoes on!"
That's because the put On method
is accessible to any shoe
that we create at any time.
We could even add
properties that
are more shoe-specific, later.
For example, on a flip-flop,
there's two straps.
And we might want
to add that there
are two straps to
that beach shoe.
So we would say,
beach Shoe.straps is equal to 2.
And it would add it right in.
But wait.
Hold on.
Where is my efficient
inheritance?
Yeah, I don't see any.
There's not any here.
We've got an object builder,
but we haven't really
used the concept of
JavaScript inheritance
that we were promised
by the Constructor.
So far, it looks like
our Constructor just
builds an object with
a bunch of data values
and a bunch of functions.
In other words, all of the
properties that each Shoe has
belong to that Shoe.
They aren't stored
somewhere else
and then accessed by the Shoe.
That's really important.
We want to make sure that we
have a normal inheritance set
up here, so that we can have a
really efficient data storage.
Hm.
Do we see anything
about our shoe
that will be the
same for all shoes?
Hm.
Let's check it out.
Every single shoe is going
to have those two functions.
But why?
Wouldn't it be better to have
those two functions in one
object that every shoe
everywhere can access?
Yes, it would.
So let's try that.
First thing we need to
do is assign a prototype
to a Constructor.
That's right, a Constructor
is not a prototype, right?
Constructor's just a function.
And a Constructor
has a prototype.
So by setting a Constructor's
prototype property,
every new instance that
we ever make every time we
instantiate an object, it will
refer to that new prototype
we've made for all of these
cool, extra properties.
So here, with our
shoe.prototype,
we're going to go ahead and
build a new, secret object,
within the Constructor
function's prototype property.
This will tell every
created shoe to inherit
from that object.
You might notice
something else here.
We haven't drawn
attention to it yet,
but every time we've called
any prototype, at all, be it
Array.prototype,
string.prototype,
or the Object.prototype,
we have always
called it as a property of a
certain class's Constructor
function, using
the dot operator.
That's no different here.
We've got the shoe.prototype
ready to roll.
Inside our prototype,
we're going
to build two properties--
put On and take Off.
Notice they take a
property style now.
To put some values in those
particular properties,
we'll just build some
anonymous function expressions
that alert our desired messages.
Notice, now, that
our Shoe Constructor
gets considerably smaller.
And that means that every
object we instantiate,
every shoe we make,
will also be smaller.
That saves a lot
of data, especially
if you're running a
shoe store, right?
By putting both of those
functions in the shoe
prototype, we force
every Shoe object
to inherit those functions
when it needs them.
So let's come back to
our beachShoe variable.
We're going to create
it the same way.
And if, this time, we were to
console.log(beachShoe.gender),
what happens is beach Shoe just
looks directly within itself
for the "gender" property,
finds it, and logs it out.
And we get "women".
But then what happens when
we do beach Shoe.take Off?
Well, that's a method
that beach Shoe does not
find in itself.
So what it does is it
looks up to its prototype.
What is its prototype?
Well, that would
be shoe.prototype.
So it looks up there, and it
says, "Hey, shoe prototype,
do you have the take Off method?"
Shoe prototype nods and says,
"Yes, I do, and you may use it."
As a result, we get the alert
message, "Hh, what's that smell?"
If we were to call
beach Shoe.has Own Property
on the string "construction",
well, neither beachShoe
nor the shoe prototype own
that property, hasOwnProperty.
So what happens is we
go up even another step,
back to the object prototype, to
find the hasOwnProperty method.
And there it is.
And the object prototype
says, "Yes, beach Shoe,
you may use this
property, here you go."
But then what happens?
The has Own Property
function now looks
to see if beach Shoe,
itself, has the property
"construction", which it does.
And so we get a true value
out of that line of code.
Now, here's something
very useful.
Prototypes can actually refer
back to their instances,
to pick up some data.
Let's see about modifying
our message functions
with some of the data
in our shoe objects.
So let's go ahead and get rid
of our current alert messages.
So now on our new
function, we'll
say "Your", whatever style
the shoe is, "is on."
Inside the take Off function,
now our alert message
will say, "Phew,
somebody's size,"
and whatever the size
is, "are fragrant."
What's important here
is that the this keyword
will look back down to the
particular shoe instance that
called the function and pull all
of the property data from it.
So if we call now,
beach Shoe.put On
we'll get "Your
flipflops on!"
instead of just "Your shoes on."
And if we call
beach Shoe.take Off, we'll get,
"Phew, somebody's size
10's are fragrant."
And now you have a few more very
useful skills with prototypes.
And we will release you
to a few more challenges,
to see how you do there.
We'll see you back
in the next section.