Welcome back, folks,
to the last section
of the Plains of Prototypes.
Hope you had a great time
with all of those challenges.
And weren't they a doozy?
Yeah.
Let's turn to our next topic,
useful properties in the object
prototype.
Yeah, remember all of those
cool object prototype properties
that we saw at the
beginning of this level?
We're going to examine and
use a few of those now.
First one we're going to look
at is the value of property.
Let's say we had two
variables, x and y.
One gets assigned 4.
And the other gets
assigned the string 4.
If we call x.value Of(),
we'll get that property from
the object prototype, and we
get a 4 back, as a result.
If we call y.value Of(), we will
also get the string 4 back.
Now, why are we trying to
differentiate between these two
pretty obvious things?
We just want to make sure
you know that the value
in value Of() isn't looking
for numbers, necessarily,
but instead returns whatever
primitive type is associated
with the object.
That's going to come
in handy, pretty soon.
Now, if we try to
compare x.value Of() equal
to y.value Of(), we get a true.
Why is that?
We need to be careful here.
That's because the double equal
sign tries to help us out,
tries to be our friend by
using type coercion which turns
a number contained within a
string into that actual number.
So here, the 4 that
was in a string
actually got turned
into the number 4.
And so the double
equal sign said,
yes, these things
are exactly the same.
But we didn't want that.
Sometimes you might,
but not this time.
So why should it matter
to us that the number 4
is different from the string 4?
Well, up to now, in the
JavaScript Road Trip courses,
we have always known that
the two values that we'd
be comparing would be
exactly the same type.
That was to sort
of keep it simple
for you to understand
as we moved along.
But as you grow in your skills
as a JavaScript programmer,
you're going to
want to make sure
that the types that you get,
whether from files or from user
entry, match what
you're seeking.
And so we need a different
way to compare types,
as well as the values
contained within those types.
Enter the triple
equals operator.
The triple equals
operator does not
ignore the type of
the value in the way
that the double equals operator
will ignore the type for us.
So therefore, we get sort
of a truer interpretation
of the equality here.
And JavaScript
experts will often
prefer the triple
equals operator
over the double equals
operator for this reason.
Here, you can see, when we use
a triple equals on x.value Of()
and y.value Of(), we get a false.
value Of can be used on all
native JavaScript data types.
So here, if we established a
variable called a and assigned
to it an array that contained
3, and then "blind",
and then "mice", and
we called a.value Of(),
we would just get
the array back.
It's almost like
logging out the array.
Same thing with
the number object.
You can see the
number constructor
being called on 6, over there.
And if we logged out the value
of b, we would just get 6 back.
Now, you might look at all
of these responses and think,
they're just giving me
what the variable contains,
so why wouldn't I
just use the variable?
It's true, these
particular responses
are not very interesting.
What's interesting,
though, is when
you redefine the value of
method for a classes prototype.
Let's take a look.
What happens when we
call value Of on an object
that we make, ourselves?
Here, I've declared
a tornado variable.
And I have assigned it
a function expression.
Guess what?
Constructors can be
function expressions, too.
I'm going to pass in
a category - meaning
the severity of the
tornado - as well
as the affected
areas - that's going
to be an array of cities -
and then the maximum wind
gusts - that's going to be
how high the winds travel,
in this tornado.
Next, I'll need an array
of the affected areas.
We'll call that cities.
And inside that array,
there will be other arrays.
In those sub-arrays,
in the first index
will be the city, and
in the second index will
be the population of
that city, for use later.
Now, to create a
new tornado object,
we'll establish a
twister variable
and pass in F5 - very strong.
The city's array, as well
as 220 miles per hour winds.
If we were to call
value Of on our new tornado
object, twister, we would get
a return of a tornado object
with a list of all of its
properties and their values.
But look at the
location property.
It says, Array[3].
That just tells me I've got an
array with three entries in it.
It doesn't even
tell me that inside
that array is another array.
So I don't even know
what's going on there.
In other words, the
value Of is trying
to give me as much information
as it knows about this object.
But we have to be responsible
for making that value Of
method better.
How can we do that?
By overriding a
prototype's property.
Let's check it out.
So why might we override
prototyping properties?
Well, there are many
situations, as you might expect,
that require special
functionality that's
different from the
first available property
with that name inside
the prototype chain.
But we want to caution you
to think of safety first,
in this case, for overriding
because you want to make sure
that you don't
override a property -
let's say, in the object
prototype level - that
will affect all
objects everywhere -
shoes, tornadoes, boxes, books.
We don't want that, necessarily,
for what we're about to do.
We just want to override the
value Of method for tornadoes.
So we're going to do that
inside of the tornado prototype.
Let's take a look.
So therefore, to get a
more informative result
for the value Of
method on tornadoes,
we just want to modify
the tornado prototype.
So what would be a
good redefinition
of the value Of
property for tornadoes?
How about we make
it the sum of all
of the potential people
that are affected
by this particular tornado?
Let's try that.
Now, to make sure we only do
this in the tornado prototype,
we're going to call
tornado.prototype.value Of,
which creates a new property
inside the tornado prototype.
Next, we'll assign
a function to it.
And inside that, we'll
create a sum variable
that starts at zero.
And then we'll have
a loop that loops
over every array inside
the cities array.
Each time we get to a
new cell in the array,
we'll add the
population of people
associated with that
city to our sum.
And at the very end of
our value Of function,
we will return the
sum of those people.
So now, if we call
twister.value Of(),
we no longer get that big,
long list of properties
in the tornado object.
Instead, we get
641,647 people, which
is the sum of all of
the affected people
inside of our affected cities.
Take note that the
value Of is found, now,
in the tornado prototype.
And that comes before
the object prototype
in the prototype chain.
So therefore, the
value Of method that's
still in the object prototype
never gets even looked at.
What's cool about this
kind of overriding
is that our value
will even update
as the cities array is updated.
Say the tornado spreads its
damage to another location
and we need to add a city to it.
Let's try that.
If we tried to push a new
city into the cities array,
with a new population of
130,045, what happens now,
when we call twister.value Of()?
We get 771,692.
Why is that?
That's because since the
cities array was passed
in by reference, we'll
always get an updated
value for that sum every
time value Of is called.
How cool.
Moving right along to another
useful prototype property,
this one's called to String.
Now, the default responses to
the objects to String method
are often very
uninteresting, especially
on the JavaScript native types.
But overriding it can be cool.
Let's take a look at what
the to String method does.
Over here, we've got our
original x and y variables
with the same values.
And as you might expect,
calling to String on x just
turns the 4 into the string 4.
Calling to String on y doesn't
have much impact, just returns
the exact same string.
Looking at the array, a call
to the to String on array
will just stringify
and concatenate
all of the contents, but
separating each entry
by a comma, without
any white space.
So overriding to String
on the array prototype
is usually pretty desirable for
whatever you're trying to do.
Additionally, the
to String method
can come in handy on a function.
If we established a
new function here,
and assigned it to
variable, double,
and then called
double.to String(),
you can see that the entire
function is logged out
as a string, which can be
very useful if you ever need
to concatenate an entire
function as a string into some
formatted printout.
Now, let's go ahead and
override our to String method
inside of our tornado prototype.
We want to do something
cool with our to String
method in a tornado.
So let's bring back in our
tornado constructor, as well as
our cities and our
new twister object.
And down here, we're going
to override the to String
method inside the
tornado prototype.
You can then see here that
we assigned it a function
inside of which we'll
start a list variable that
is an empty string.
What this is going
to do is hold a list
of the affected
areas in the cities.
Then we'll loop over all of the
arrays inside the cities array.
Inside of our loop,
if we haven't yet
reached the last
city, then we just
want to add the name of the
city and a comma to our list.
But if we did reach the
very last city in our array,
we want to use the
Oxford comma style,
and have some good grammar,
and put and, the last city.
Notice here that the
cities are contained
in the zero index
of each sub-array.
Once the loop closes, we'll
know that our list variable
is complete, meaning
all of the cities
have been concatenated
correctly into one variable.
Then we will return this
rather large string,
here, that says, "This tornado
has been classified as an,"
and then we'll put the category
in for this particular tornado.
"With wind gusts up to," and
we'll put the wind gusts
in for this tornado.
New sentence.
"Affected areas are,"
and notice now,
we concatenate the
list variable in.
That will put all of
our cities in one spot.
"Potentially affecting
a population of,"
and now, this is
cool - we actually
are calling our overridden
value Of method on this.
So we will get the population
placed right there.
Let's check it out.
If we call
twister.to String() now,
we get a very cool
representation of all
of the data that's in our
twister tornado object.
It says, this tornado has
been classified as an F5,
with the wind gusts up
to 220 miles per hour.
Affected areas are Kansas City,
Topeka, Lenexa, and Olethe,
potentially affecting a
population of 771,692.
Cool, huh?
Next up, we're
going to try to find
an object's constructor
and its prototype.
And there are some inherited
properties from the object
prototype that
provide ways for us
to locate those nearest
prototype ancestors.
Let's check that out.
If we call
twister.constructor here,
we get the entire constructor
function back, as a result.
Now, next, if we call
the .prototype property
of the constructor function, we
will get the prototype object
associated with
that constructor.
Pretty cool.
So there, we can see both the
constructor function, as well
as the prototype object that
has our overridden value Of
and to String methods.
Something useful
to remember here
is that if a prototype object
is defined for a class,
meaning the class
uses inheritance
in some way, that
prototype will always
be a property of the
class's constructor.
And the constructor is just
another function object
of the properties.
Another way to access just
the prototype would be
twister.__proto__.
Kind of weird, but it will give
you back the exact prototype
object used for twister.
Now that you know how
to access the prototype
and the constructor,
let's take a look
at the has Own Property method
in the object prototype.
This method will
help you identify
the location of properties
where they are stored.
Searching the prototype chains
for potential overridden
properties is
something we do a lot.
And it becomes very
easy with this function.
What if we wanted to find the
owner of a particular property?
Well, we can build a
function to do that.
Let's check it out.
So what if we wanted to be able
to find a specific property
within an object's
prototype chain?
Hm.
We wanted to find which location
held a specific property.
Well, we can add that one
to the object.prototype.
That way, every
object, everywhere,
will be able to
find any property
that we want to look for.
So here you can see we're doing
object.prototype.find Owner Of Property.
And then we assign
it a function.
The function takes in, as
a parameter, the property
name that we're looking for.
The first thing we'll do is
establish a variable called
current Object which will be
the object within which we're
looking for the
property, currently.
And at first, we
will assign that
to this, which means
the calling object.
We want to start at
the calling object,
to see if the property is there.
Next, we'll hook ourselves
up with a while loop that
will keep searching
the prototype chain
until we've tried to go beyond
the object prototype which
has no prototype.
So if we tried to access
the prototype of the object
prototype, we would get no
because object prototype is
the highest prototype
that you can go.
Then we'll set up a
conditional in which
we check whether the current
object, has Own Property,
the property name that
we're looking for.
And if it does, we'll
return that current object.
Why?
Because if the current
object has the property name
that we're looking
for, that means
it is the closest object,
in hierarchy, to the calling
object, which means
that's where it gets
the method, or the
property, from.
Otherwise, if the currently
examined object does not
contain the property
that we're looking for,
then we need to proceed
up the prototype chain
to find that property.
Hm.
How do we do that?
Well, we say that the
current object should now
be whatever the
previously looked
at object's prototype was.
That helps us move up
the prototype chain.
Then, at the end,
if the loop exits,
we know we tried to get past the
object prototype and hit null.
What does that mean?
That means we never
found the property
in any of the prototypes
throughout the chain.
So we should go ahead and let
ourselves know that and say,
no property found.
So now, if we call the
find Owner Of Property on twister,
with the parameter
value Of, meaning
we're looking for
the value Of property,
well, twister looks inside
itself, as an object,
and doesn't see
value Of, so it goes up
to the tornado prototype.
And there it is, the
value Of function.
So our
find Owner Of Property method
returns the entire
tornado prototype to us
as the location of
the value Of property.
Now, if we call our function
on the go To Oz property, hm.
Well, we'll first check
the twister object.
Nothing there.
And then we'll head up
to the tornado prototype.
Nothing there, either.
Uh oh.
So now we'll trudge up
to the object prototype.
Still nothing.
Finally, we'll try to get
past the object prototype,
but that prototype is null.
Womp, womp.
But actually, that's cool
because our while loop will
exit, and we'll get
no property found.
So we see that trying to
find the go To Oz property
shows us that none
actually exists
for this particular tornado,
which, I have to say,
kind of sucks.
And that, ladies and gentlemen,
is the end of a level five,
the Plains of Prototypes.
Hope you've enjoyed it.
We've got a few more
challenges before the very end.
So take some time with those.
And we'll see you back for
more JavaScript real soon.
Take care.
For example, the -
[NONSENSE SYLLABLES]
I'm crashing is why.
I'm crashing.
Crashing, man.
Uppercase method.
- properties.
Well, uh, as -
[NONSENSE SYLLABLES]
I can't talk.
I just can't do it.
- method.
[FART NOISE]
Wah!
- all of that get
pa - if I could talk.
Don't put that in there.