My name is Carlos Souza.
And you're watching
Rails 4 Patterns.
In this level, we're going to
be looking at class methods
and scopes.
Let's look at the index action
in our PostsController
Here we're manually constructing
a query, which
returns the most recent
published posts and assigns it
to the post instance variable.
There are some problems
with the code, though.
First, it exposes implementation
details, which
totally breaks encapsulation.
Like we've seen in the previous
chapter, this code
should be placed inside
of a model.
It also produces unnecessary
duplication, which means that
every time that we want to
fetch the most recently
published posts, we're going to
have to rewrite this code
over and over again.
Lastly, it complicates writing
tests, because it forces us to
write controller tests as
opposed to unit tests, every
time that we need to
test this feature.
A better way to write this is
to move this code out of the
controller into our model.
Here we have our query
implemented as a class method,
which is similar to writing
a scope, named recent, and
passing a proc object
as an argument.
Back to our controller, we can
simply call the recent method
on our post class.
This way our model is properly
encapsulating
details about the query.
One question you might have is
whether class methods and
scopes are the same thing.
Let's take a look.
Here we have our post class,
with two class methods, by
author and recent, each one
with its own query.
These two can be chained
together.
In the first example, we're
calling posts by author,
passing in the author argument
as Carlos and calling recent
on the return value
from that method.
And we can see it's generating
the proper query.
But what if the argument by author
happens to be nil?
Say a user goes to a search box
and instead of typing in a
keyword, he simply
submits the form.
He might expect to
get back all the
posts from all authors.
But the query that this
generates will actually be all
posts where author is null,
which is obviously the
opposite of what we wanted.
To fix this, we go back to by
author method and add a
validation that first
checks to see if
the author's present.
Otherwise, it will return nil.
The problem with that is that
when we pass nil to the by
author method, it actually
returns nil.
But then we'll call recent on
nil, which will cause an
undefined method error
to be raised.
To fix that error, we go back to
the author method again and
add an else block
that returns all.
All in Rails 4 is a chainable
relation.
Now calling by author with
nil behaves as expected,
and we can just call recent on
the return value for that.
Our query runs fine now, but it
required a decent amount of
lines of code to be written.
Luckily there's a better way
to write this using scopes.
If we change the previous code
from class methods to scopes,
then we don't have to worry
about returning
a chainable relation.
Because scopes always return
a chainable object.
So now when you pass in nil to
the by author method, we don't
have to worry about it
generating the wrong query.
Here's some new code.
We have our comment class,
which belongs to a post,
and it has an approved scope
that returns all the comments
that were approved.
We also have our posts model,
which has many comments.
It has a scope called with
approved comments, which joins
with the comments table and
returns all of the comments
that were approved.
Now when we call the
with_approved_comments, this is the
query that it generates.
The problem here is that we
have the same query logic
duplicated in two different
places.
We can get rid of this
duplication by
using the merge method.
Merge facilitates sharing common
conditions between
multiple associations.
Using merge, here's what our
code would look like, which
generates the same SQL.
When we're using two scopes
that reference the same
database column, there's a huge
difference in behavior
between Rails 3 and Rails 4.
In Rails 3, the query
in the last scope
overrides the first one.
In this case, when calling
user.active.inactive, both
which reference the state
column, the last query would
override the first one.
In this case, it would
only query for
state equals inactive.
Rails 4, however, will simply
append the conditions and
generate a query that
looks for both
state, active and inactive.
If we want the same behavior
from Rails 3, we need to use
the merge method,
passing in the
second scope as an argument.
This way we can use the last where whens logic.
This way, in case there's a
common column between two
scopes, the last
scope will win.
We've reached the end
of this level.
So, get ready for some challenges
on class methods
and scopes.
I have no idea what I'm
going to say now.
Err.
Was that good?
Every time that we--
err.
Keep on doing that.
We'll make an outtake reel.