Your controller is getting bloated
and your models are fat.
The configuration files, we don't know we're they are at
and the views are awful dirty.
And your app needs a bath.
You lost all the defaults,
left the golden path.
But some best practices we have a prescription.
The encapsulation tool belt will cure your addiction!
Beyond the basics of learning Rails 4,
there's some patterns you'll need to explore.
I'm Carlos Souza,
and you're
watching Rails 4, patterns.
In this level, we're going to
be looking at concerns.
Here we have our post class,
which has many comments, which
is a polymorphic association,
represented here by the
comment class.
In the same way, we have an
image class with the same
comments association.
And both the post and the image
classes share the same
comments by user method, which
queries for comments from a
specific user.
When recalling these methods
from an object, either a post
or image object, they have
the same signature.
And their implementation
is exactly the same,
so there's definitely
some unnecessary
duplication going on here.
Let's see how I can remove this
duplication by extracting
the comment code
into a concern.
Rails 4 ships with a concerns
directory under your app/
models folders, which is a place
to put concern modules
that will be mixed
into your models.
So, let's create our concern
module and call it
"commentable."
Using the included hook method,
which is automatically
called by Ruby when we mix
this module into a model,
we'll dynamically add the
comments association to
whatever model includes the
commentable module.
We'll also move our
comments by user
method into this module.
And module methods become
instance methods
on the target class.
Then, we simply include the
commentable module in both the
post and image classes, and
the code behaves the same.
We can still call comments by
user on both the post and
image objects.
We can simplify our commentable
module by
extending from active support
concern, which was added back
in Rails 3.
This allows us to use the
included block to add our
associations.
Code inside of the included
block runs in the context of
the target class.
And if we happen to have a class
method that needed to be
both classes, for example
upvote, which takes a comment
as an argument, we could simply
extract that and place
it inside of the commentable
module inside of an inner
module called ClassMethods.
Active support concern
automatically includes methods
from the ClassMethods in the
module as ClassMethods on the
target class.
Concerns aren't just
for models.
Here we can see that our images
controller shares some
common code with their
videos controller.
Both of them are calling
file.basename, passing an
image path an argument and are
using that image path to
interpolate a string and assign
it to the thumbnail
instance variable.
Our controllers folder also
has a concerns directory,
which is where we place our
previewable module, which will
contain the duplicate code.
So for both the models and
controllers, we can extract
duplicate code into modules,
which Rails 4 calls concerns.
Now, to call our thumbnail
method from our controllers,
we simply have to include the
previewable module on both the
images controller and
videos controller.
So, we have the app /models/
concerns directory and the app/
controllers/concerns directory,
which is our common
place to put shared code.
We also have our active support
concern module, which
is a completely different
thing,
and it's just a tool
that helps you make
mix-ins a lot cleaner.
And there are two different
things, so don't let them get
you confused.
We've just unlocked another
tool in our
encapsulation tool belt.
The first one was non-active
record models, which are
classes that encapsulate unique
business logic out of
your ActiveRecord models.
And now, we've just come across
concerns, which help
extract duplicate code into
reusable modules that can be
mixed in multiple models
or controllers.
We've just reached the end of
this level, and good luck with
the challenges.
Don't let them too confuse
the [BLEEP]
out of your head, which your -
Err!