I'm Carlos Souza, and you're
watching Rails 4 Patterns.
In this level, we're going to be
looking at fine tuning your
Rails application to make it
more secure and faster.
So let's look at this
typical Rails query.
We're fetching the items
that are very
close to its due date.
Once the query is run, it
returns an active relation,
which is basically
a collection of
active record objects.
So when we call items.class, we
can see that it's an active
relation item, and the first
item in the collection is an
active record object.
However, our web page might not
need to display all of the
columns in the database.
In fact, we might only
need the ID.
In this case, we can use the
select method to reduce the
number of columns loaded
from the database.
As you can see, it generates a
SQL that only selects the ID,
and only the ID property is
set on the item objects.
This is a little bit more
efficient on the database
side, but still when we call
items.class, we're still
getting back an active
record relation.
And each element of the
collection is still an active
record object.
So, we're still creating
different item objects for
each row returned from
the database.
And this seems kind of
wasteful when all we
need are the IDs.
This is where the pluck method
comes in, which returns an
array of values instead of
active record objects.
So by looking at the SQL that's
generated, we can see
that it still reduces the number
of columns loaded from
the database.
However, notice the
return value.
It's actually returning an
array, and each element of the
array, instead of an active
record object, is just a
number, a fixed number.
And by avoiding the creation of
active record objects, we
were really able to
speed things up.
The pluck method has been
around since Rails 3.
In Rails 4, pluck is now able
to take multiple arguments.
As we can see here, we're not
plucking for ID and name.
So the SQL that's generated,
it's only fetching the ID and
name columns from
the database.
And now, it returns an
array of arrays.
So when you call items.class, we
can see that it's an array,
and items.first.class,
it's also an array.
So we're still avoiding
the creation of
active record objects.
So remember, the pluck method is
a great way to reduce your
application's memory footprint
and make your application
plucking faster.
Rails, by default,
filters passwords
from the log entries.
In this example, we're issuing
a post request to /users,
passing in an email
and a password.
Notice how we're not able
to read off the
password from the log.
However, passwords might not be
the only sensitive information
that needs to be filtered.
In the second example, we are
also passing the social
security number, which
you might not want to
record on your logs.
Let's see how we can
filter that out.
All you have to do is go to your
application.rb under the
config directory,
and look for the
config.filter_parameters option.
There, you can add social
security number or any extra
fields that need to be filtered
from the logs.
Now, when you look back at the
logs, you will notice that the
social security number is
also being filtered.
This might sound like a small
detail, but you'd be impressed
by the number of people
that overlook this.
When you created a new Rails app
and you fire up the Rails
server, you will most likely
be using WEBrick as the
application server.
WEBrick is the default
application server that can be
found in the Ruby standard
library.
However, WEBrick should not
be used in production.
First, it's very slow when
compared to other app servers,
and this is mostly because it's
written in pure Ruby.
Other rack servers might be
partly written in Ruby, but
also use languages like C and
C++ for critical parts, like
HTTP parsing.
WEBrick also lacks important
features that production apps
usually need, such as management
of multiple
application instances
and management of
processes or threads.
One alternative to WEBrick
is the puma server.
You can start using puma
by simply adding
it to your gem file.
Next time you fire up Rails
server, Rails will
automatically detect puma
and use that instead.
Or you can manually fire up puma
using the puma command.
And speaking of gem file, it's
also a good practice to
declare the version of Ruby that
your application uses on
your gem file.
This ensures that your local
development environment mimics
your production environment as
closely as possible and also
prevents other developers
working on the same
application from using different
Ruby versions.
When you specify the Ruby
version in your Gemfile,
bundler will automatically match
that against the Ruby
version that you're
currently running.
And it will raise an error if
those two versions differ.
However, bundler will not
install Ruby for you.
For managing different versions
of Ruby, check out
rvm or rbenv.
As your Rails application grows,
odds are that you're
going to start having to manage
different processes.
In this example, we have a Rails
server, a scheduler, and
a couple different workers.
And to get it running, you have
to type in a bunch of
different commands.
You might have to run the server
and run each worker
individually,
so the more elements that you
add to your stack, the harder
it is to get it all running.
One way you can solve this
problem is by declaring your
processes on a proc file.
Here's an example of a simple
proc file that has a single
processing named web which will
fire up a Rails server.
And the syntax for a proc file
is the process type followed
by a colon, followed by the
command to start that process.
The complete proc file from
our previous example might
look like this.
A process for web that fires up
a Rails server, a process
for worker that runs our worker,
another one for our
urgent worker, and another
one for a scheduler.
So how can we run our
proc file now?
Well, we can use foreman.
Foreman is a command line
tool for running
proc file backed apps.
Now, to run your application,
all you have to do is go to
your project folder and
run foreman start.
If you're deploying your
application to a VPS and
you're using something like
upstart or init tab to manage
your processes, then foreman
also exports to those formats.
Check out the GitHub repo
for more information.
We've reached the end
of this level.
Now, it's time for you to dive
into the challenges and fine
tune your applications to
make them rock solid.
Here with - blah.
I totally blanked out.
Why do I restart so bad?
What the -
[BLEEP].
Let's took at this typical
Rails query -
took a took, took a took.
Blah.
Mother plucking faster.
For a ruin - bah.