Your controller is getting bloated
and your models are fat.
The configuration files, we don't know we're they are at
and the views are awful dirty.
And your app needs a bath.
You lost all the defaults,
left the golden path.
But some best practices we have a prescription.
The encapsulation tool belt will cure your addiction!
Beyond the basics of learning Rails 4,
there's some patterns you'll need to explore.
My name is Carlos Souza.
And you're watching
Rails 4, Patterns.
In this level, we're going to
be talking about models.
When working with Rails and the
Model View Controller, or
MVC, you're probably used to
the fact that most of the
logic should go into
the models.
Well, let's see an example
of why that is.
Here we have an items
controller
in a publish action.
By looking at our controller,
we can see the logic behind
publishing an item, which
involves first checking if an
item is approved, then citing
the published_on property with
the current time, and
then saving the
model to the database.
This is an example of
a fat controller.
And code like this, it's
hard to work with.
All logic related to publishing
an item is exposed
in the controller.
And this will most likely cause
this controller action
to be highly accessed in the
future by other developers
every time we need to change
something specific to this
publishing feature, which
might cause potential
conflicts in the code base
and will make new
features hard to implement.
And here's an example.
Say one of our developers needed
to add an additional
validation to the publishing
feature.
A good sign that it's time to
re-factor your code into a
better design is when you have
something like this.
Notice how we have multiple
calls to the same object.
And we shouldn't be asking
your objects about their
internal state.
But rather we should be
telling them what
we want to get done.
One way to make this better is
to re-factor this code out of
our controller and into an
instance method into our item
model, where it belongs.
So, we create a publish method.
And the first thing we do is
check for pre-condition.
In this case, if the item is
either not approved or if the
user is Loblaw, then
we return false.
This is called the guard clause,
and it makes our code
easier to read.
If all pre-conditions are good,
then we set the publish on
property and then
save the object.
Notice how this is all
encapsulated in our model.
All our controller needs to do
is to call the publish method
on an item object.
One of the features from active
record that you might
be familiar with are callbacks,
which are methods
that get called at certain
moments in the
object's life cycle.
The problem is, they're
often misused.
So every time you create a user
object in the database,
the set token method is going to
be called, which depends on
the token generator model.
The problem with this code is
that every time that we create
a new user record in the
database, the set token method
is going to be called,
which depends on the
token generator model.
And referencing other models
in the callback introduces
tight coupling.
So every time that you create a
task for your user model and
it creates a new record in the
database, it will depend on
the create method from the token
generator class being
called, which might lead
to unexpected behavior.
And also, it affects the
object's database life cycle.
So if that method raises
an error, your
object will not be saved.
We can fix this by creating a
new method on our user class.
And let's call this
method register.
You can call it pretty much
anything you want.
And inside this method, we're
going to assign a new token
using our token generator class
in the create method.
And then we'll save
the user record.
And then inside of our
controller, we can simply call
that register method.
And this is better, because the
token generation is now
decoupled from the object;s
database life cycle.
So, when is it OK to use
a callback then?
Well, callbacks should only be
used for modifying the internal state
of the object.
Let's look at this example,
where we have a before create
callback called set_name.
So, what the set_name method does
is that it sets the name
property on the user based on
its log in if the name is not
already set.
And it's also a convention
to set your
callback methods as protected.
Notice how this callback doesn't
have any external
dependencies.
It's all within the
user model.
Let's take a look at some
additional code and see what
it's doing.
First, we grab a user
from the database.
Then we call the
suspend method.
It looks like a clean API
from the outside.
But let's take a look inside
of the user model.
Our user has many items
and has many reviews.
The suspend method starts off
with a transaction block.
Transactions ensure that all
enclosing database operations
are atomic.
This means that if any of the
lines here fail, the database
will roll back to its
initial state.
Then instead of the transaction,
we start by
updating the user model and
setting the is_approved
property to false.
After that, we loop through each
of the user's items and
set them to approve
false as well -
and the same thing
for reviews.
The problem with the suspend
method is that there's too
much logic cluttered into a
single method, which makes
your code harder to read
and to maintain.
The first step into re-factoring
this code is to
break it into multiple
methods.
Here you see we have disapprove_
user, disapprove_
items, and disapprove_reviews.
This is better, but
it's not great.
Here we have too much logic
inside of a single class,
which breaks the single
responsibility principle.
An object that controls too
many other objects in the
system is an anti-pattern
known as God Object.
What most people don't realize
is that not all models need to
be active record models.
In this case, not everything
involving a user needs to
necessarily go into
the user model.
So, let's create a user
suspension model and pass the
user to its constructure.
Then we'll create a create
method, and then we'll wrap
all the logic related to
suspending your user inside of
that method.
The create method is just a
regular instance method.
And the user suspension class
is just a plain old Ruby
object, or a PORO.
And the benefit of doing this
is that this class is
responsible for only
one thing.
Now, back in our users
controller, we use the users
suspension model that
we just created and
call the create method.
Creating new models based on
new abstractions is a great
way to keep your Rails
application modular.
Other frequent non-active record
models that you might
come across are models like
user registration, plan
subscription, credit card
charge, or shopping cart.
None of them have to necessarily
be active record
models or need to be persisted
to the database.
Throughout this course, we're
going to be looking at a
couple of patterns that we
can use to improve our
application's encapsulation.
This means moving code from one
place and putting it into
another, just like we saw now.
And the first tool in our
encapsulation tool belt is
non-active record models.
You've reached the end
of this level.
Now, get ready to work
on some challenges.
Rails form.
Rails porn.
Familiar, familiar.
Rails form patterns.