You're watching Rails
4 Patterns.
In this level, we're going to
be talking about decorators.
Here we have a post class with
a is_front_page method that
checks to see if the post
has been recently
published or not.
In our controllers, we're simply
fetching that record
from the database. And in our
show template, we're calling
the is_front_page method to
determine whether or not we
should display the image
for that post.
The problem with this is that
our is_front_page method is
only being used for view
logic, but it's declared in
our post model.
This makes our model
polluted with
view-related business logic.
This is where decorators
come in.
Decorators help us extract
view-specific logic from our
models into decorator classes.
In this example, we'll move our
is_front_page method out
of our post model into the
PostDecorator class.
This class will live in a
decorators directory that we
have to manually create, but
Rails automatically adds it to
the load path for us.
And the class states the
post as an argument.
Then, in our controller, we use
the post object that we
grabbed from the database, and
use it as an argument to the
PostDecorator.
You might notice that in our
show action, we're not using
an instance variable for the
post anymore, but instead,
we're using it for the
PostDecorator.
And this is because we want the
PostDecorator to be the
only way to reach out for
the contents of a post.
With this in mind, back in
our view, we want to call
postdecorator.image, but we
don't have that method yet,
and if we try calling it,
it's going to error out.
To fix this, we're going to
implement method_missing,
which will forward any undefined
method to the
wrapped object, in
this case: post.
And we do that by calling
post.send, and passing in all
the arguments from
method_missing.
So now, when you create a post
decorator using an existing
post, and you call the image
method upon it, it'll properly
forward the method using method_missing,
and we'll get
the post image back.
However, if we ask this object
if it responds to image, it'll
return false.
This is because it will not
search the object's ancestors
chain, and this can cause
unexpected behavior.
To fix that, we should implement
respond_to_missing,
and ask post if it responds to
the given method, otherwise
call super, which will invoke
the respond that's missing
from its parent object.
Now, if we ask a PostDecorator
if it responds to
image, it'll return true,
because it properly searches
the object's ancestors chain.
So remember to always define
respond_to_missing when you
override method_missing.
So to summarize, we want to
use decorators to attach
presentation logic to an
object dynamically.
So working with a decorated
class should be transparent to
clients, as the decorator
will simply wrap
the underlying object.
It will delegate most methods to
the wrapped object, and may
also add a couple of additional
methods of its own.
Here's another example using
a Rails view helper.
Here we have our PostsHelper
module, with the publication
date helper method.
This method takes a post and
formats the created update.
Rails view helpers are a great
starting point, but they're
really hard to evolve.
So, a couple of issues with Rails
view helpers is that
they pull the global name space
with methods that are
specific to one model, and they
also force you to use a
functional approach within an
object-oriented application,
which may look kind of weird,
and it allows you to use that
same method from other
templates.
For example, nothing stops us
here from passing a user
object to the publication_date
method, since the user object
might also have a
created_at view.
And a better place for the
publication_date method is
inside of our post
decorator class.
This way, we can call
publication date as an
instance method on our post
decorator object, which gives
us a more consistent object-
oriented approach
throughout the view.
Another way we can use
decorators is to output HTML.
In this example, we have our
PostsHelper with a post_classes
method.
This method takes a post and
constructs a collection of CSS
classes based on the
post's attributes.
Then in the view, we use the
output from the post_classes
method to determine the classes
for our article element.
And again, this is a great
starting point, but it doesn't
scale well, as your view
specific logic grows.
So, let's move our post_classes
method into our post
decorator, and simply
call it classes.
From inside of our method, we
have access to the post
attribute reader.
We don't have to pass any
argument to this method,
because we have access
to the posts via
our attribute reader.
And in our show template, we
can go back to using a more
object-oriented approach by
calling the classes method on
the post_decorator.
So we've now completed our
encapsulation tool belt.
To recap, the first one we
learned was how to use non
active record models to
encapsulate unique business
logic out of your active
record models.
Then, we learned how to use
concerns to extract duplicate
code into reusable modules
that can be mixed into
multiple controllers
or models.
And now we've just seen how
decorators helps us extract
presentation logic out of the
models by A, wrapping them, B,
providing a transparent API, and
C, adding a couple methods
of their own.
We have reached the end of this
level, and it's time for
you to work on some challenges
on decorators.
Out of a rec--
You can't say my name.
My name.
A--