Your controller is getting bloated
and your models are fat.
The configuration files, we don't know we're they are at
and the views are awful dirty.
And your app needs a bath.
You lost all the defaults,
left the golden path.
But some best practices we have a prescription.
The encapsulation tool belt will cure your addiction!
Beyond the basics of learning Rails 4,
there's some patterns you'll need to explore.
I'm Carlos Souza, and you're
watching Rails 4 Patterns.
In this level, we're going to
look at creating custom JSON
APIs using active model
serializers.
Many people use Rails to create
API applications that
respond to formats like JSON.
One way you can do that out
of the box is by using the
respond_to block and using
the format.json.
And inside of this block, you
can pass a couple of options
if you really want to customize
the JSON that you're
sending back to your client.
The problem with this code here
is that serialization
code should not be placed
in the controller.
A better way to do this would
be from your model.
By overriding the as_json
method, you can also customize
the JSON that is sent back.
However, placing serialization
code in the model breaks the
Single Responsibility
Principle.
Now, your active record model
is not only responsible for
persisting to the database and a
couple validations, but it's
also responsible for formatting
to custom JSON.
And that's where active models
serializers come in.
And they help you decouple
serialization
code out of your model.
There's very little
configuration needed.
They give you access to URL
helpers, and have built in
support for associations.
To start using active model
serializers, all we have to do
is add it to your Gemfile.
At the time of this course,
there's a couple of features
that we're going to be looking
at that haven't yet been
released to the Ruby gems.
So, make sure you point to the
GitHub repo if you want to use
these features.
You'll also want to remove
jbuilder from your Gemfile in
order to avoid conflicts,
especially when running Rails
generators.
After you've run bundle, the
first thing you'll notice is
that your JSON responses will
automatically have a root node
that's added by active
model serializers.
The items root node makes this
response compliant with the
JSON API hypermedia type.
Visit the jsonapi.org for more
information on the JSON API
hypermedia type.
So back to our controller, if
you want to use the Rails
built-in serialization,
there's nothing
that you have to do.
You can either use the
respond_to block with the JSON
format, or it also works
with respond_with.
Now, let's see how we create
custom serializers.
Active model serializers
gives us a generator.
So, when we call Rails generate
serializer, or Rails g
serializer, all we need to do
is pass in the model that we
want to create a
serializer for.
A serializer's directory
will be
automatically created for us.
And inside of that folder, a
serializer will be created,
named after your model,
in this case, an
item serializer class.
The newly created serializer
will start off with the ID
attribute, which is the only
attribute that will be
serialized.
Back in our controller, we can
still use the same render call
or respond_with, and
we'll have our JSON
sent back to the client.
By convention, active models
serializers will look for a
serializer class named after
the class that's
passed as an argument.
You might want to skip the
convention and provide your
own custom serializers.
If you want to do that, you
can either override the
convention by passing a
serializer as an option to
render, or specify your
serializer class by overriding
the active model serializer
method on your
active record model.
Here's an example of our custom
serializer that's being
used by our item model.
Notice, it's using both ID and
description as attributes.
As we've seen, by default,
when we add active model
serializers to our project,
it'll automatically
add the root node.
For backwards compatibility with
other clients that might
already depend on the response
type, you might need to remove
that root node.
So, here's how you can do that.
First, you can pass root false
to the render call.
Or, you can pass in a
custom serializer.
Here in our example, we're
calling it items collection
serializer.
And notice how our base class
is active model erase
serializer, which is the base
class for collections.
Then, inside of our custom
serializer, we set root to
false, which will remove
the root node.
Now, let's see how we can add
custom properties to our
serializers.
Here, we have our item
serializer that defines
attributes ID, name, and URL.
URL is not a property from our
item model, but rather a
method that we're going
to be defining now.
Inside of this method, we're
going to call the item_url
helper and pass in an object
as an argument.
The object method gives us
access to the object being
serialized.
In this case, it's an item.
So the output for the serializer
would be something
like this, an array of items,
the ID, the name, and the URL.
We've reached the end of this
first part on active model
serializers.
Now, it's time for
some challenges.
Use this -- blah.
There is -- here is?
Access to your hell--
your hell?
[You're hell] You are hell, your hell methods.
[LAUGHTER]
Serialization, serialization.
Serialization -
[BEEP]
Why did you have to
say that, man?
[LAUGHTER]