I'm Carlos Souza, and you're
watching Rails 4 Patterns.
In this level, we're going to
continue looking at active::model
serializers.
Let's start by looking at how
we can use associations from
our serializers.
Here, in our item serializer,
we've defined
ID, name, and URL.
Then, we have our URL method
that's calling a route helper.
For each item, we also want
to serialize its comments.
We do that by simply adding
has_many :comments.
This way, each element of the
association will also be
serialized.
When a custom serializer isn't
found, then the default Rails
serialization is used.
And here's what the
output looks like.
Child objects are embedded
inside of their parents.
In this case, comment objects
are serialized
inside of each item.
Instead of serializing the whole
comment object, we might
want to simply fetch their ids,
which gives us a huge
performance boost because it's
less data that we're
transferring down
to the client.
To do that, we simply pass
embed: :ids as an option to
has_many, which will return the
ids for the associations
instead of the entire object.
Here's what the output
looks like.
And you'll notice that we have
comment_ids property with an
array of ids.
Another way that we can specify
that we want all
association ids is by using
the embed class instead.
This will apply to all the
associations of the
serializer.
In this case, comments
and pictures.
You'll notice that in the
output, we have both comment_ids
and picture_ids.
In addition to embedding ids
for associations, you might
also want to side load the
objects themselves.
By side loading association
objects, you can reduce the
number of HTTP requests.
And you do that by passing the
include true option to your
embed method.
Up to this point, comments has
been using Rails' default
serialization.
But once we include side
loading, then we'll need to
create its own custom
serializer.
In this case, comment serializer
under the add
serializer directory.
Back in our controller,
nothing has changed.
We can still use the render or
the respond_with method.
And here's what the
output looks like.
Notice how we're embedding our
ids for comment_ids, and the
comments objects are also
included at the top level.
The comment_ids can used by
client side JavaScript
libraries to fetch the
side loaded comments.
In this case, because we're side
loading associations, it
has required the presence
of a root element.
Otherwise, we might see
an error like this.
Now, let's look at how we can
customize the records that are
returned by our associations.
Notice that inside of our
comment class, we have an
approved scope that returns all
of the approved comments.
We want our serializer to only
include the approved comments.
To do that, we override
our comments method.
Now, using the object method,
which again refers to the item
being serialized, we can call
comments, and then the
approved scope.
That way, we can override the
association methods to only
return the records
that we want.
So what if you want to add a
specific property based on
whether the current user had
a premium account or not?
How would you do that?
First, we override the
attributes method, which gives
us total control over the
data that's serialized.
We start off by calling super,
which will look for the
attributes that were defined
at the top level.
Then, we need to check
if the current user
has a premium account.
Out of the box, active model
serializer gives you access to
the current_user helper method
from the controller because
this is such a common pattern
in Rails applications.
So if the user has a premium
account, we want to set the
discounted_price property
and return the data.
Here's what the output
looks like for a user
with a premium account.
Notice it's showing the
discounted price.
For some reason, your
application might use a
different scope than
current user.
For example, logged_user.
If this is the case, then you
can tell active model
serializers to look for a
different scope either by
calling the serialization scope
method passing in the
name of the scope, or by passing
scope and scope_name
as options to the
render method.
We've reached the end of this
level, so get ready for some
serious serialization.
There's an alien inside of me.
Then, have our URL - we then -
then, we have our URL -
then, we have our UR -
Oh my god, this never ends.
Yes, it does.