Welcome back to Forging
Ahead with .Net MVC.
In this section, we're
going to use layouts to make
our views more consistent.
Some things we want
to do is we want
to be able to set the title
on our individual pages,
as well as the title and the
metadata in our search results
to be more useful
application wide.
Now, you'll notice,
as we've made changes
in our application, certain
parts of our pages have changed
and other parts haven't.
The navigation and the title at
the top, as well as the footer,
have remained the same.
However, the middle portion--
the body-- of our page
has changed depending on
what view we've returned.
This is thanks to the layout.
Now if you look in
our views folder,
we have a folder called Shared.
Inside this folder will be a
file that's _Layout.cshtml.
This file contains the content
that has been on our page
that has been remaining
static this whole time,
as well as it sets up the
layout for the content
we do add to our page.
We've got this layout
file that sets up
the header and the
footer of our page,
but exactly how do our
individual views know
to use this layout of file?
We have a file also in
our views folder called
_ViewStart.cshtml, which is
added to the top of any view
any time we use the
Return View method.
If you actually open the
_ViewStart.cshtml file,
you'll notice there's really
only one line of code here.
There's just at, curly
brace, and then layout equals
underscore at layout.
Layout is a keyword by Razor
that actually sets the layout
of a page, and then
we're setting that layout
to our _layout file.
Looking in the _Layout.cshtml,
you'll notice there is a lot
happening here.
So we're going to go
ahead and break down
some of the important
pieces that we care about.
Most of the rest of this is
just HTML we've seen before.
The first thing you'll see
that is unique to ASP.net
is the at view
data, which is going
to have a string in
brackets afterwards.
View Data is a
dictionary that allows
us to pass data from our
controller to our view,
similar to the model.
Now a model is actually
defining the structure
of the data on the
page. View Data
is something we would use
if we have like that one
off variable, or one off
field that doesn't really
fit into our model, but
we're going to need.
So the next thing you'll
notice that isn't standard HTML
are at render section, which is
followed by a string and then
whether or not it's required.
What Render Section allows us to
do is it acts as a placeholder
that we can define within
our view to pass content
into that location of the page.
So in this case, where we have
the in between our head tag,
if I want to reference an
additional style sheet,
I could just drop
that in on my view
and it would bring that in here.
You'll also notice we
have the at render body.
Now anytime in our view
we don't specifically
define a section we're
going to put the content in,
it'll end up being put
worthy at render body is.
That's the reason all of
our changes in our index
are details pages
have shown up here.
So let's put our layout to
use to try and accomplish
our goal of being able to
set the title on our page,
as well as to be able to set
the metadata for search results.
Now, we don't have to actually
do anything with the RenderBody
because that's been
working this whole time.
The way we would set our
ViewData for our title,
is we can just use it
like it's a variable.
We'll just have our
ViewData, our key,
and then we can set
that to characters
in our index section.
What this will do is it will
pass this characters value back
to the Layout page, and put
that in the title for us.
Now, you'll notice
we didn't have
to actually pass this ViewData
through our view method.
That's because this is handled
in the background where we'll
automatically map up that
ViewData in our controller
to the ViewData in our view.
So we don't actually have
to wire anything else up.
What this will end up doing is
taking that character's value,
bringing it to our layout
page, replacing that ViewData
in the Layout page
with characters
when it comes time to render.
That will make our
title characters
space dash space forging ahead.
The next thing we're
going to set up
is to be able to actually add
our metadata to our head tag
in our layout.
As you'll recall, we had
that at render section
header on our layout page.
If we go into our index view,
and add the at section space
header, anything we
put in the curly braces
after that will be populated
to that location on the layout.
What we're going to
do is pass a meta tag
with the attribute
description that's
going to have the basic
description of the page.
You'll notice at render
section, that first argument
is the name of the section.
So when we call
it from our view,
we're actually
just saying render.
We're using the actual
name of the section
to make that map up.
If we were to pull up the
index page at this point
and look at the results
of the changes we've
made to our layout,
we'll notice the title
on the top of our browser
will have our new characters
dash forging ahead, just
the same as if we were
to look in search
results for this page,
we would also see that
characters dash forging ahead,
as well as would have the
description from our metadata.
There are some conventions
to be aware of.
For example, the naming
convention of layouts
is typically underscore
then PascalCase.
That is, underscore and then
each word of the name of that
file to be capitalized.
All layouts typically
go in the shared folder.
Normal naming conventions
is for your section names
to be all lowercase.
And finally, if you
have content that's
only going to be on some
pages, you typically
don't want to put
that in your layout.
Now, it's your turn to
make changes to the Layout
page in the challenges.
Enjoy.