[SINGING]
Stoke the fire, fan the flames
our journey continues, starting today.
We'll traverse the database,
Entity Framework
on our side, ensuring
that our data is ace
and presenting our views with
pride. Routes help guide the way
to our success, I daresay.
For knowledge we shall seize
While Forging Ahead with
.NET MVC.
My name is Eric Fisher, and
welcome to Forging Ahead with
.NET MVC. In Try .NET MVC, we
learned the basics of MVC.
We put together an
application where we could
store characters and equipment.
The problem was, anytime
we closed this application
we lost everything.
So we're going to set
it up so we can actually
store this in a
database and we can
validate to make sure our
input is clean and correct.
Some specific things
we're going to do
is store our characters
and equipment
in a database so we can
reuse them between games.
We're also going to take steps
to make sure the data that's
entered is clean and valid.
There are two
versions of ASP.NET
that we need to be
concerned about.
We have ASP.NET Core
and ASP.NET Framework.
Now this course is going
to be using ASP.NET Core.
And while most of the
material between ASP.NET Core
and Framework are the same,
there are some differences.
In this case, we'll have
our using statements
that have the word
"core" in them,
and our startup.cs file will
be different between the two.
I wouldn't worry
about this too much.
Most of the material
you see in this course
is going to be the exact same,
regardless of whether you're
using Core or Framework,
with the only exceptions
of startup.cs and the
using directives that
have Core in their name.
In this section,
we're going to cover
data annotations which we'll
use to make our model smarter.
For storing our data long term,
we have two real options here.
We can either save
it to the file system
or we can create a database.
Now databases handle
relational data lot better.
And since the data we're going
to be using is relational data,
we're going to go
with the database.
In our Try .NET MVC course,
we cover model or view
under controller.
In our case, since we're going
to be doing data and business
logic, we're going to go ahead
and do that in our model.
We've created a new project
called ForgingAhead.
Inside our models
folder we're going
to go ahead and add
the character.cs file
to hold our character model.
In this file we're
going to add a bunch
of the properties such as
name, strength, intelligence.
To read and write
from our database,
we're going to use what's
referred to as a database
context, or DbContext.
So we're going to create a file
known as ApplicationDbContext
in our models folder.
So creating our
ApplicationDbContext file
is only the first
of many steps we're
going to have to do to set up
to be able to read and write
from our database.
In addition to this,
we're going to have
to reference
EntityFramework, we're
going to need to add a
property for our characters
in our
ApplicationDbContext, we're
going to need to
create a character
controller that loads
the ApplicationDbContext,
we're going to create a
character through the context
in our controller,
and we're going
to need to save our new
character in the database.
The first thing we're going to
do in our ApplicationDbContext
is we're going to go ahead
and set up a using statement
for EntityFramework.
That enables us to inherit
the DbContext class which
lets us teach
EntityFramework how
our database is going to work.
We'll set up a DbSet
collection, which
works a lot like a list the
difference is EntityFramework
will use this DbSet collection
to define tables and views.
The normal naming
convention for a DbSet
is to have whatever
object we're adding
to our DbSet singular, and the
name of our actual property
that is our DbSet to be plural.
So if I was passing in
my object Character,
I would then name it Characters.
Our ApplicationDbContext
is all set up
at this point to start
accepting and passing
back character data.
We're going to actually access
the data through our character
controller.
So let's go ahead and create
our character controller
in our controllers folder.
Just like before, we're
going to go ahead and add
using statements.
We're going to add a using
statement for EntityFramework,
a using statement to
get our collections,
and the using statement
for our models.
These classes will
give us functionality
we're going to need
throughout this class.
Next, we'll add a private
read-only context variable
to our character controller.
Let's break down each one of
these keywords individually.
We've seen public
before where we're
able to access a
method or a property
anywhere within our application.
Private, on the
other hand, makes it
so we are only able
to normally access
our method or property within
the context of that class.
Read-only is just
like it sounds.
It allows us to read
from the variable,
but not write to the variable.
You'll notice the
standard naming convention
for a private read-only variable
is underscore and lower case.
This is helpful
because that way when
we're looking
through our class, we
can very easily recognize
our private and read-only
variables.
Now let's add a character
controller constructor
to our character
controller class.
This will take an
input parameter
of ApplicationDbContext.
And inside of here we're
going to go ahead and set
our private context
variable to our passed
in ApplicationDbContext.
What we're doing here is
constructor injection.
This allows us to
inject an instance
of our ApplicationDBContext
without creating a new one
inside of our class every time.
ASP.NET is set up to use the
dependency injection design
pattern to loosely
couple our dependencies
for better testability
and adaptability
of our application.
ASP.NET will
automatically inject
the ApplicationDBContext when we
create our character controller.
This means we don't
have to actually
create a new
ApplicationDbContext
every single time we
access our controller.
Dependency injection
is built into ASP.NET.
The purpose of
dependency injection
is to establish
Inversion of Control.
Without Inversion
of Control, we have
to instantiate a new
instance of a class
anytime we want to use it.
With Inversion of
Control, we can loosely
couple our dependencies.
In ASP.NET we have a class
known as the ServicesCollection.
This will automatically
inject anything
we've placed into it
whenever we try and access it
through the constructor of
one of our other classes.
To make our injected class
accessible to the rest
of our current
class, we're going
to go ahead and set
our private variable
to be the injected class.
This makes it accessible
to the entire class
through that underscore context.
Now the first place
we're going to use
that context is in a new action
that we're going to create
called Create.
This action method will
accept an input parameter
of the Character object.
To add an object to our
Characters Collection,
we can just call the
add method like we would
with a list, passing in
our character object.
The one difference
we have to deal
with when dealing with our
context as opposed to a list,
is once we're done we need
to call the SaveChanges
method on our context
to actually commit
those changes to the database.
You don't have to call
SaveChanges every single time
you make a change.
You can make many changes,
and then save all of them
at once at the end by
calling SaveChanges.
To prevent the user from
accidentally resubmitting
this information
by hitting Refresh,
we're going to go ahead and do
a RedirectToAction to our Index
page.
The result of calling
our SaveChanges method
in our Create method
can be different
depending on our situation.
If we don't already
have a database,
EntityFramework will
create a database for us.
In the event we don't already
have a Characters table,
EntityFramework will create
our Characters table for us.
And finally, we'll
create a Character record
for the character
object we've submitted,
like you see over here.
EntityFramework is an Object
Relational Mapper, or an ORM.
ORMs EMS handle all
of the database stuff
so we can focus on our code.
Now it's your turn to
set up EntityFramework
in the Challenges.
Have fun.