Welcome back to Forging
Ahead with .NET MVC.
In this section we're going
to go through validation
using data annotations.
Looking at our data, we're
seeing lots of problems.
We're seeing characters with
levels that aren't appropriate.
They're either negative
or they're way higher
than the game allows.
We're seeing names that are
a single character long.
Just generally, a lot
of this data is messy
and it's going to cause
problems for the people playing
the game.
So we're going to set up
validation to try and get this
under control.
Using data annotations
we can actually
set up rules for our
properties using attributes.
Using the Required attribute
on our name property,
for example, when we
go to our front end
this will add data-val-required
on any inputs for our name
property.
Which will tell our
front end validation
that this is a required field.
They have to enter
something here.
Just the same, it
will actually go
to what's referred to our model
state, which is part of how
we do our back end validation.
And it will say if
the name property is
null or empty to add an error.
And finally, this will actually
go through Entity Framework
when it goes to create the
column name in our database.
And it will make it so that
column is not nullable.
Before we're able to use
our data annotations,
we're going to have to
set up a using statement
to System.component
Model.DataAnnotations
to give us access to them.
The first thing
we're going to tackle
is where our users are entering
characters of the same name.
The problem is, our
system doesn't really
have a good way of
handling it when
we do have multiple
characters with the same name.
We can disallow this behavior
using the Key attribute.
What this will do,
is in the database
it make this a unique key field.
This means there
can only ever be
one character with the
same name in the database.
So the next thing
we're going to tackle
is where users are
simply not entering
information, where
they're skipping entering
the name or any of the stats.
Our game does require
all of this information.
So we're going to
disallow this behavior.
We can do that by adding
the Required attribute.
What this will do is add rules
on the front end, back end,
and the database to ensure
that a name is entered.
From here, we're going to
tackle where some of our users
were entering names
like A and C and CC,
and other such short
names that just really
aren't great for the
way our game works.
So what we're going to do is
use the MinLength attribute.
And we use this by having
MinLength, parentheses,
and whatever length we want
to be the minimum allowed.
In this case, we're
going to use three.
This means any name
entered must be
at least three characters long.
From here, let's
handle where our users
were entering negative
and numbers that
were way too big for our stats.
We can do this using
the range attribute.
We do this by having
Range, parenthesis,
the minimum allowed,
comma, the maximum allowed.
What we're going to do
is use range 1 and 20.
This means we'll require those
stats to be anywhere from one
all the way up to 20.
At this point, our
data annotations
are entirely set up.
We can make sure that
they have a name.
We can make sure
that name is unique.
We can make sure that the name
is at least three characters
long.
As well as we can make
sure all of our stats
are within an acceptable range.
Now it's your turn to set up
your own validation using data
annotations in the challenges.
Have fun.