Welcome back.
In this section, we're
going to go over how
to present data in our views.
In the last level, we
set up our CRUD methods
to read from and
write to our database,
but we don't have any views
to be able to access those.
So what we're going
to go ahead and do now
is-- we're going to create our
index view and our create view
to be able to access
those actions.
Let's start with our
index dot cshtml page.
We've gone ahead and we've added
a bunch of the starting code
here for you.
We're going to go
ahead and create
a link to our Create action
directly below our heading.
We're going to do this
by creating HTML link.
Now we're going to add two
attributes to this-- asp dash
action and asp dash controller.
Our asp dash action we're
going to set to Create
and our asp dash
controller, we're
going to set to Characters.
The template will render the
URL based on the two attributes
we have provided.
If you were to look at the
rendered code in the browser,
you would actually see the href
equals character slash create.
From here, we're going to create
a link to our Details action.
Just like before, we're
going to use the asp dash
action only to
Details this time,
and the asp dash controller
to the Characters' controller.
The catch is--
our Details action
is expecting an input parameter
of the name of our Character.
We can do this by adding the asp
dash route dash name attribute
with the items' name property.
What this is going
to do is it's going
to add a query string for
the name that will map up
with our input parameter
of our Details action,
as you can see below.
From here, we're going to
create our Create page.
Now we've set up a
bunch of this code
already for you, as most of
this we've already seen before.
This may look complex,
but a lot of this
is just the CSS we're using
to make this page look nice.
One of the things
you will notice
that is ASP.NET
specific, is the asp dash
for tag helper,
which we're going
to set to Name as it's going
to tie to our Name property.
What this is going to do is
when we use it with Label,
it's actually going to set
that Labels' value to be
the Name of the property.
We'll also use asp
dash for on the input.
And what this is
going to do is it's
going to go a step farther
than it did with the Label.
It's actually going to
change the type of the input
to be whatever is appropriate
for the type of the property,
as well as set the ID and
the name of that input
to match the Name
of that property.
You can see the
resulting HTML here.
Well, that works great
for any of our properties
that names happen
to be only one word.
But an example of our
is active property,
we'd probably want to display
that as two separate words.
We can't do that with asp
dash for without going
a step farther and
adding data annotations.
So let's go back to
our character model,
and add in using statement for
system dot component model dot
data annotations.
The next step we would
take is on the line
directly above our
is active property,
we're going to add the
display attribute with name
equals to is active
with a space in it.
This will tell asp
dash for any time
it is to display the name
of the is active property,
to go ahead and add that space.
If you look at the rendered
output of our template
at this point, and you look
at the ID and Name attributes,
you'll notice that
they're all still
set to the is active
without the space, which
is necessary for them to
map up with the property.
However, in the label
where we're actually
returning the value to be
displayed to the screen,
it now has our space.
At this point
we've got our views
to read from and
write to our database.
Now it's your turn to
set up your own views
in the challenges.
Have fun.
All the code you're seeing
here is just a bunch of ahhh.
Partial with that
character's details--
I mispronounced it
all sorts of wrong.
I said feels.
That's not even a word.
Well, I guess it is a word.