Welcome back.
In this section, we're going to
go over front-end validation.
Front-end validation is
important for giving the user
the best experience possible.
You do want to make sure to
have both front-end and back-end
validation, though,
because you can't always
depend on front-end validation.
The important thing is front-end validation
keeps everything
on the client side,
so when they hit
the Submit button,
they instantly get a response.
They don't have to wait for a
server to interact with them
and respond.
To set up front-end
validation, we're
going to need a reference
two JavaScript libraries.
These are going to be
jquery.validate and
jquery-validation-unobtrusive.
These are actually already
in the MVC template.
We just need to add these
references to tell it
we want it on these pages.
The next step is to
go to a view that we
want to add front-end
validation to to create
a div with the
asp-validation-summary tag
helper with a value of all.
What this is going to do is
any time we have a validation
error, this div is going to
have an unordered list of all
of those errors presented in it.
As you can see here,
our front-end validation
is all set up.
If we were to enter our
information incorrectly,
such as make our name too
short or to give values
outside of the range
we're allowing,
we're going to get the summary of errors underneath our Submit
button.
And that's all there is needed
to set up front-end validation
in ASP.NET.
Now you're going to
go ahead and you're
going to actually set up a page
to use front-end validation
in the challenges ahead.
Enjoy.