Welcome back.
In this section,
we're going to set up
what is called
ModelState Validation.
This is back-end validation.
We need to set up
back-end validation
because you can bypass
front-end validation,
whether intentionally or not.
If I disable my
JavaScript, for example,
a lot of my front-end
validation is going to break.
Users can also sometimes
bypass our forms
to attempt to submit information
directly to our application.
In these cases, we want
to make sure we properly
validate the data coming in.
The ModelState is an object
that tracks the value submitted
to the server.
In addition to storing the
name and value of each field,
it also tracks the
associated validation errors.
From here, to set up
back-end validation,
we need to go to one of our
actions that is expecting data.
We can go to the Create action.
The first step will
be to add a condition.
If the ModelState is not
valid-- the exclamation
mark meaning not-- we're just
going to immediately return
the view with whatever
model was passed to us.
By returning the character
back to the view,
that ASP-validation
summary is going
to be populated by all
of the validation errors
we've received.
But let's try testing
adding the same name twice,
which is one of the things we've
set up validation to prevent.
The first time we added the
name Hux, everything goes fine.
We're taken to the Index
page, and the name is listed.
However, the second time
we try to add the name Hux,
we wind up on a blank page.
Exactly why is that?
Well, if we were to
look into our console,
we would notice that our key
attribute actually worked.
It's just it didn't
fail until the point it
went to save to the database.
Now this is occurring because
our application doesn't
know the name is
already in the database
until such time it actually
attempts to hit the database.
So what we need to do
is check for that name
before we attempt to save it.
And if the name already
exists, create a new error.
We can do this by using the Any
method on our DB set characters
and looking for any
character with the same name
as the name of the
character we are passing in.
In the event we do
find a character, what
we're going to do is call
ModelState.AddModelError.
And we are going to pass in
Name, which is the field,
and what error message we want
to be presented to the user.
At this point, our back-end
validation is working.
But there is one thing that
isn't quite the way we want it.
If we look at our
error messages that
are being returned
to our summary
from the back-end
validation, some of them
are not exactly the cleanest.
We have the Value
blank is invalid.
And that would be OK, if we only
had one or two fields to deal
with, you'd be able to
recognize what field is invalid
very easily.
But if it was on a form
that had 20 or 30 values,
it would be almost impossible
to tell which of these values
I'm getting an error from.
So we need to make our error
messages a little friendlier.
We can set the error message
for a validation error
by going to whatever attribute
is appropriate for that error
and then adding after
it, ErrorMessage equals
and whatever error
is appropriate.
Now if this attribute
already had parentheses,
we will add this as
the last parameter.
If it does not have
parentheses, we're
going to add the parentheses
to contain that error.
At this point, our validation
is entirely set up.
If we were to enter any
of the information wrong,
we would get the
appropriate error messages
from both the front
and the back-end.
But you might be thinking,
what about the database.
You mentioned that the
database is part of validation.
One of the beauties of
data annotations and entity
framework is all of this
has been handled for us.
They have structured
the table so anything
that isn't supposed to be
null isn't allowed to be null,
anything that requires to be
unique needs to be unique.
All of that is handled for us.
Now it is your turn to set up
your own back-end validation
in the challenges.
I'll see you at
the wrap-up video.
And that's all there
isn't-- (COUGHING).
[LAUGHTER]
I'll see you at
the summary video.
Wrap-up video.
Wrap-up.
Now does your-- the
slide that does it in.