Welcome back to Forging
Ahead with .NET MVC.
In this section, we're going
to go over data relationships,
and how we can actually make
data related to each other.
Before we can actually
implement our data structure,
we need to kind of plan it out.
We know that our
players are going
to have multiple characters.
We also know each
individual character
is going to be able to have
multiple pieces of equipment.
This would imply a one
to many relationship
between our characters
and equipment.
However, our equipment
isn't unique.
Multiple characters could have
a piece of equipment, "sword"
or "shield."
This means,
ultimately, we're going
to have a many to
many relationship
between our characters
and equipment,
as any character can have
multiple pieces of equipment
and any type of equipment can
be on multiple characters.
The way a database handles
a many to many relationship
is using what's referred
to as a union table.
This table maps
which characters will
have which pieces of equipment.
Fortunately, because we're
using Entity Framework,
it's going to handle all of
this complicated database
stuff for us.
We just need to know
what's happening, in case
we need to police
our records and make
sure everything's correct.
All we have to do to
create a relationship
between our characters
and equipment
is adding new property
to our character's class
that is a list of equipment.
And then Entity
Framework will take
care of all the rest for us.
Now you remember, for our naming conventions
for any type of list or collection,
we have the singular object that we're passing in.
Our name will be the plural of that object.
In this case, because the singular and the plural
for equipment are the same, we don't add an S, or anything,
onto it.
Now it's your turn to go
through database relationships
in the challenges.
Have fun.