Welcome back.
In this section, we're going
to go over partials, which
allows us to break our views
up into different parts
for reusability.
For end result, we
want our index pages
to have a little
section that outlines
what our characters details.
We want to also use
exact same outline
of details on our details page.
Now rather than implement
this section multiple times
in different places, we can
create what's called a partial
and share that
between the pages.
We'll create our
character sheet partial
inside our shared folder,
just like we would our layout.
It also has the same
naming convention
where it'll be underscore
character sheet, with character
and sheet capitalized.
Our character sheet
partial is just
going to basically be
all the information
we need to present the view.
We're not actually going to
go through it all because this
is stuff we've already learned.
What we're going to
do in this case, is
we're going to actually
add our model declaration
at the top for our
character object,
and then immediately
after that we're
going to do at html dot
partial parentheses and then
inside quotation marks the name
of our underscore character
sheet partial followed by model.
What this is going to
do, is when I actually
go to render this
page, it's going
to grab that character
sheet partial
and place it in place
of this at html partial,
and it's going to use that
model data in our partial.
Now, if we actually look at
our character details page,
if we were to compare this
from having that code directly
in the details page
versus the partial,
the should be indistinguishable
to the end user, which
is exactly how it should be.
From here let's go
to our index page
and set it up to use a partial.
Before, we were just
having a label placed,
with the actual character name.
For each item in the
list this at html partial
is going to be replaced by
the contents of that partial,
giving us the details for
each of our characters.
At this point, we're
going to set up
or index action to return only
the characters that are active.
Just like before, we can use
a lambda expression-- return
only those records-- and then
pass those through to our view.
At this point, both are
index and our details pages
are set up to use our partials.
If we look at both our
index and our details page,
the details about the
individual character
will be the same
between both pages.
Some conventions to
note-- you'll notice,
the naming conventions
for our partial
is the same as our layout where
it's underscore PascalCase.
Now, in our instance, we
actually put a partial
in the shared folder.
This is one of two very
common conventions for where
you put your partials.
Typically, you either
put all of your partials
in the shared folder,
or you put the partials
in whatever folder is
appropriate for the model
they're dealing with.
In that case, if I had
a character partial,
I would put that under
the characters folder.
Meanwhile if I had a partial
that either used a unique model
to itself, or it used some
combination of models,
then I would put that
in the shared folder.
Now it's your turn to set up
partials in the challenges.
Have fun.