Welcome back.
In the last section,
you got to play around
with a framework to actually
create a record in a database.
Now there is one thing we
went ahead and took care
of for you behind the
scenes that you'll
need to take care of yourself
when you do the project.
And that is, if you
noticed, we accepted
the ApplicationDBContext
that was injected
but we never did set
up to inject that.
So first thing we're going
to do in this section
is we're going to actually
set up that injection.
And then, we're going
to move on to setting up
your CRUD methods, create,
read, update, and delete.
If you recall, this is what our
character controller currently
looks like.
Now the ApplicationDBContext
will get injected
by the services collection.
The problem is we
need to actually add
ApplicationDBContext to
that services collection.
The place we'll
need to add this is
in our Startup.cs file,
which is right in the root
directory of our project.
This is how we're actually
going to configure our ORM.
Now the way we're
going to set this up
isn't unique to
this application.
This is the sort of
stuff you'll actually
do with any project
you make that's going
to be using EntityFramework.
So exactly what is Startup.cs?
Startup.cs is how we actually
configure an application to let
it know we're going
to use MVC, what we're
going to dependency
inject, how it's
going to host the web, routes.
All of that is handled here.
Just like before, we're going
to add our using statements.
In this case, we're going to
add EntityFramework core dot
infrastructure.
Now infrastructure
is going to let
us have an in-memory database.
If you were to want to use
SQL Server, MySQL server,
or an other alternative,
you would end up
changing that infrastructure
portion to whatever
the appropriate database is.
The place we actually set
up dependency injection
within our Startup.cs file is in
our configure services method.
As you can see here, we
already have services.AddMvc,
which is what's
enabling MVC to be
accessible throughout
our application.
To add EntityFramework to our
services, all we have to do
is call
services.AddEntityFramework.
This is a special method
just for EntityFramework,
whereas if you were to
inject other classes,
you'd have to go through a
little more complicated route.
To actually set up
EntityFramework,
we're going to need
to let it know what
DB context it's going to use.
In this case, we'll call
the method add DB context
and then pass in our
application DB context.
This method is
what's actually going
to make our application
DB context injectable
to our other constructors.
At this point, our
Startup.cs is fully set up.
We're able to do our
injection and we're
ready to move on to actually
creating our CRUD methods.
We'll have a create character
method, a read all characters
method, a read a specific
characters details,
read all active characters,
update a character,
and delete a character.
We actually don't need
to make our create method
because we already have
created that in section one.
Once again, we're going to
add our using statements
to our class.
In this case, we're
going to add System.Linq.
This is going to give us
access to lambda expressions
which we'll need for
our CRUD methods.
Our first action
we're going to set up,
will be our index action.
This is effectively going
to be our read all action.
We'll create a variable
model which we're
going to pass back to our view.
This variable, we're going to
actually take our characters
DB set and call
the to list method.
This will actually
change that DB
set into a list for
returning to our view,
as our index will be expecting
a list of characters as opposed
to a DB set of characters.
The next action
we're going to set up
is our get active action.
This is going to work a lot like
our index action with the one
difference of we're going
to go ahead and add a where
method before our to list.
This where method is
going to accept what's
known as a lambda expression.
And what this lambda expression
is effectively doing is saying,
any record in this collection
that is active true,
return that.
Lambda expressions
effectively let
us write for each loop
in a condensed form.
The e in our lambda is the
name of the variable that
will represent each record.
Followed by an equal
greater than that
looks like an arrow that'll
tell our method what to do.
In our case, our e
is active condition
will be applied to every
single record in the collection
through our for each,
and any records that
meet that condition,
will be added
to the returned collection.
Using a lambda
expression is much nicer
than having to write
a for each loop
every single time we want
to do something like this.
In addition, lambda expressions
can often be more efficient
than a for each loop.
Now we're going to create
our I action details.
This is going to return a
single specific record for us.
To do this, we're going to use
the first or default method
on our characters DB set.
This will return a single
character as opposed
to a collection of characters.
We're going to use a lambda
expression like we did before.
The difference being is
instead of our condition
being we're looking to see
if the is active is true,
we're going to actually see
if each one of our characters
records has the same
name as the end put name.
Now we're going to set up our
update action which will update
a character in our database.
To update an entire
character in our database,
we can call our DB
contexts entry method
and then provide it the
character we want to update.
We'll then set the state
property of that record
to entity state modified.
This tells EntityFramework
we have changed this record.
From here, we need to call
save changes to submit
those changes to the database.
And just like any
time we submit data,
we're going to want to go
ahead and redirect to action.
So we'll go ahead redirect
to action to our index again.
Let's set up our delete action.
Our delete action is going to
start just like our details
action began.
We're going to go ahead and
get the specific character we
want to actually work with.
At which point,
we're going to want
to make sure that we actually
got a character back.
So we're going to make sure
we didn't get a null there.
In the event we do
get a character back,
we want to call the remove
method on the characters DB set
and pass in the character
that we got back.
And then we'll have
to do our save changes
to commit that to the database.
At that point,
we're going to want
to make sure to do our redirect
to action to our index page
again.
At this point, all of our
CRUD methods are implemented.
We can create a character.
We can read all
of our characters.
We can read a
specific character.
We can read all of
our active characters.
We can update a character and
we can delete a character.
Now it's your turn to set
up your own CRUD methods
in the challenges.
Enjoy.
Intelligence.
Just like we had done
before on Try .Net NVC.
To set up our app-- the first
thing we're going to need
to do--
Welcome back.
In the lacks--