Welcome back to forging
ahead with .NET MVC.
In this section, we're going
to go over custom routes.
We can use custom routes to make
our URLs a lot more friendly.
For example, if we are to
access our details page,
we have to type in characters,
details, question mark, name
equals, and then the name of the
character you want to look at.
Most people aren't
going to remember this
and search engines don't
use this very well.
So instead, we would like
to access our details
page through characters, the
name of the character, details.
This will make our URL a
lot clearer to our end user,
search engines' algorithm will
find these URLs a lot easier,
and plus, it avoids
query strings.
So where do we want to actually
set up our custom route?
We actually have two
places we can do this.
The first being the
Startup.cs we've seen earlier.
Now the Startup.cs
is kind of when
you want to make a custom route
for your entire application.
For example, our
default route is set up
in the Startup.cs file.
That's why we can use the
controller then action
anywhere in our application.
However, we're looking
at changing this,
and we really want to only apply
it to very specific methods.
So what we're going
to do is we're
going to go to our
character controller
itself and set a route
directly on the method
we want it to apply for.
To create a per
action custom route,
we can just go to the action we
want that route to be set for
and directly above it
add the attribute route.
And then define the route
in the parentheses after it.
In this case, we're going
to do character, slash,
curly brace, name, curly
brace, slash, details.
Now the curly braces are going
to tell our route that this
is a parameter, which it will
feed into our action method's
name parameter.
You'll also notice we didn't
say controller and action
in our custom route even
though that was an option.
Because we're making an
action-specific route,
we want to make this as very
tight on to this as possible
to avoid the risk of conflicts.
Now we have a lot nicer URLs.
We can actually go in
and type in characters,
slash, the name of a
character, slash, details,
and that's going to
take us to the details
page for that character.
Looking at how our users
are accessing our website,
we're starting to see
some weird stuff happening
with our create action.
Our create action
is supposed to be
where the users
would go to a form,
they would fill out the fields,
and then they'd hit submit.
But we're starting to see people
putting these really long query
strings after
create, where they're
doing every single
one of the properties
as part of a query string.
And even weirder,
our application
is actually accepting this.
This is something we
really want to avoid.
If we were to set up any type
of validation or security,
our users would
be bypassing this.
This is something we really
don't want to happen.
Our users are able to create
characters because right now,
all of our actions are
accepting both GET and POST.
We really don't want this
to happen because URLs
have a limited length.
They can leak sensitive
data, you can accidentally
resubmit data, and URLs are only
meant to handle the GET verb.
An example where
this can go wrong
is let's say someone is using
query strings on our login
page.
That means we have actually
exposed both the username
and the password to
potentially being accessed
by someone not intended to.
GET and POST are
examples of HttpVerbs.
HttpVerbs define how we
interact with our data.
A GET request is
requesting information
from an application.
A POST request is submitting
information to an application.
By default, in ASP.NET
MVC, every action
will accept GET and POST unless we specify otherwise.
Some examples of actions in our
application that should be GETs
would be our index page or
details page and our edit page.
Since our index action
is supposed to be a GET
and it's currently able to
accept both GET and POST,
let's correct it so
it only accepts GET.
The way we can do this
is we can go directly
above our index action and
add an attribute, HttpGet.
By defining HttpGet,
we're making it
so this action can
only accept HttpGET.
So for some examples of
POST-- our create action
that actually
saves our character
to the database, our update
action, and our delete action
are all examples of POST.
Since our create action is the
one we're seeing as a problem
right now where users
are submitting data
through the URL, let's go and
correct that to be a POST.
The way or we can do this is add
the attribute HttpPost directly
above our create action.
And just like GET, since we
defined this specifically
to use POST, it will
only except POST.
Now if our users were to
go to our create action
with all of the fields
provided in the query string,
they would end up just
seeing our Create view.
That is because
at this point, we
have only one Create
action that is a GET
and that is the one
returning the view.
The question comes
up-- what verb should I
be using for my delete action?
There actually is an HttpDelete.
The thing, though, is
browsers by default
only know GET and POST.
In this case, POST is the more
appropriate verb to be using.
We also have to ask what we want
to use for our update action.
With our update action, there's
the verbs PUT, POST, and PATCH
are all available.
In our case, again,
since browsers only
understand GET and
POST by default,
we're going to use POST.
It also happens to be
the most appropriate
for the way we're
updating our record.
Now that we're using
the proper verbs,
we don't have to worry
about accidentally
leaking our information out
through our query strings.
It also helps prevent from when
search engines are actually
trying to find our
pages accidentally
submitting data to us.
And finally, by knowing
the proper HTTPVerbs,
we're in a better
situation for any time
we go to consume or
create our own services.
Now it's your turn to
set up your own custom
routes in the challenges.
Enjoy.