Welcome back.
In this section, we're going
to cover editor templates.
Now our players
are going to want
to be able to update their
characters at different points.
Maybe their character gained
a level or some stats changed,
so we're going to need to
set up something to do this.
At this point, we're going
to set up our edit action.
Our edit action is going to be
almost exactly like our details
action, with the
one exception of we
are just going to set the
title to be "Edit" and then
the character name, as
opposed to what Details had.
Now, in our Edit view,
for the most part,
this view is going to
follow the same structure
our Create view had.
It's going to have its heading,
it's going to have a form.
The differences
inside of our form,
instead of actually breaking
out each and all of the labels
and inputs, we're just going
to use @HTML.EditorForModel().
What this will do is when
we render the template,
it'll actually create all
of those labels and inputs
based on the properties in our
model, completing the form.
As you can see here,
the editor template
is taking all the properties
and creating the proper input
fields for them.
So our template works.
Unfortunately, it's really
not cosmetically as good
as it could be.
Our update but it's
kind of just smashed
against the bottom
of our input field,
and the spacing isn't
really consistent.
So what we can actually
do is we can override
parts of our editor template.
So what we're going to
do is override parts
of the template based on
the types: string, Boolean,
and int32, and integer.
To override parts of
our editor template,
we just need to create an
editor templates folder
inside our shared folder.
What we'll do here is create
three views: Boolean.cshtml,
Int32.cshtml, and string.cshtml.
What this will do is any time
the editor template finds
one of those data types to
create a label and an input
field for, it is going to use
what we put in these files
in place of its
automatically generated code.
In our string.cshtml
editor template,
what we're going to do is we're
going to set up our @model
to be of a type string.
Since the data type we are
going to be replacing is string,
we want to make sure it
maps up with our model.
The only thing we're going to
actually have in this editor
template is an input that's
going to have an asp dash for that
is our model, and we're
also going to add class equals
form-control.
So what we're actually
doing is we're
adding a class from
the Bootstrap framework
to just make our
input look nicer.
We're not going to
actually show going
into the int32 and
our Boolean templates.
Really, the only difference
between those templates
and our string template
is just that model
is going to be to the
appropriate data type.
With this, our players can now
update their characters.
In addition to this, our form
actually looks nice and clean.
Editor templates are a great way to set up our input styles
and layouts throughout
our application.
Some conventions to note.
The naming conventions
for editor templates
is to simply be a
PascalCase name.
Editor templates are always
located in a subfolder called
EditorTemplates.
Now, if you want
an editor template
to apply application
wide, you would put
that inside your shared folder.
However, if you wanted
an editor template
to only apply to
a specific area,
say for example, in our
characters templates only,
we can add an editor's templates
to our Characters folder
instead, and any
templates we put in
that folder is
only going to apply
to those views in that
Characters folder.
Now, it's your turn to
set up your own editor
templates in the challenges.
Have fun.
Attribute wrong,
attribute wrong.
--opposed to be
submitting information.
I paused there just to ruin it.
--only except HTP get.
HTP?
HTTP.
Yeah.
By defining HTTP--
get, as I ruin get--