[SINGING] She will clone and
fork your repos faster than
you can blink.
And then tag, push, and pull
requests while pouring a drink.
She's studied wikis and
pages to promote her skills,
but it's the branching
and the merging
which will pay all the bills.
Your only chance to find
her is to use her work flow.
Commit to her release, and
you can access control.
You'll be pushing past security
to join her at the club just
to catch a glimpse of
her mastering GitHub.
You're watching Level
One of Mastering GitHub.
I'm Peter Bell.
In this course, we're
going to be looking
at the process of using GitHub
to collaborate effectively
with your team.
GitHub is more than just a place
to store your Git repositories.
It's a place for
sharing your code,
discussing it with
your team members,
and even doing
lightweight code reviews.
There are lots of
different ways that you
can work with Git and
tools like GitHub,
but we're going to be
focusing on proven best
practices for using GitHub
to collaborate effectively.
We're going to make
some assumptions
at the start of this class.
We're going to assume
that you're already
familiar with the basics of
adding and committing files
to a git repository, using
feature branches effectively,
branching, merging, rebasing,
and dealing with conflicts
if you've got a merge
or rebase conflict.
So if you're not comfortable
with any of those things
or you feel like you
need a refresher,
make sure to check out the Code
School classes for Git Real
and Git Real 2 that
will run you through all
of that material
in great detail.
Let's start by making sure you
have your Git configurations
set up the way you need it
for the rest of this course,
and hopefully you'll learn
one or two tips or tricks
along the way.
As we go through
this course, make
sure to keep a
console window open
and follow along
with the commands.
That way you're going to be able
to get some hands on experience
plus the challenges are going
to be in the console, as well.
So you'll be there and
ready to complete them.
There are three different
levels of configuration in Git.
You can configure at a local,
global, or system level.
Most of the configuration
you're going to be doing
is at a global level for
all of the repositories
that you work on
in this machine.
But sometimes you might want
to set a local configuration.
For example, if you wanted to
override your email address.
If you're account leader in
most of your work for a company
but you're working on
one open source project,
you might want to
get git config --
local your user dot email just
for that open source project.
And occasionally you might
want to configure something
at a system level, which is for
all of the users of the system
irrespective of who
they're logged in as.
So, for example, you might
want to set the system color
UI to true for all of
the users of the system
because it's something
that everyone's
going to need to
have configured.
So let's start
quickly by checking
your global configuration.
If you git config --
global user dot name.
That's going to get and
return your username.
And if you git config --
global user dot email,
that's going to display your
currently configured global
user email.
If you're happy with those,
you can leave them as you are.
If not, you can actually
jump in and change them
just by using the same
command but by putting
a value on the end.
There are two ways you can look
at your global configurations.
You can certainly git
config -- global --
list to use git to list all
of your global configuration
settings.
But the other thing you can
do is you can actually just
look at the underlying
configuration file.
If you just cat to catalog
or output the contents
of the ~/.gitconfig file,
that will take this file from
your home directory and
show all of your global git
configuration settings.
And, in fact, you can even edit
this file using a text editor.
Let's look at an
example of that.
Here we're going in to
our global git config
and let's say we wanted to
change our email address.
You just go into that,
change it, save the changes
to your file, and
then when you look
at your git config at a global
level for your user email,
you will see that it
has now been changed.
Viewing local
configuration settings
is very similar to
viewing the global ones.
You could git config -- local
-- list to list them using git.
Or you could just look at
your local git configuration
file, which is in the dot git
directory in a file called
config.
And, again, this
is something you
could edit using a text
editor if you wanted.
Have you ever had the experience
that it looked like somebody
had changed every single line
in three or four different files
but when you looked
at the changes
they made they
didn't actually seem
to have changed
any of the content?
This can occur when
you have people working
on different operating
systems and perhaps you've
got line feeds at
the end of each line
and perhaps they were using
Windows and added carriage
returns, as well.
One of the most important
configuration settings
you can use is autocrlf, or
auto Carriage Return Line Feed,
which allows you to
solve this problem.
Depending on your
operating system,
these are the
commands you're going
to want to run to make sure you
don't run into that problem.
Another important setting,
especially if you're not
on Git 2.0 or later yet, is
configuring your push default.
Historically, the push
default was always
set to matching, which meant
that whenever you pushed
to a remote server
like GitHub, it
would push all of the
matching branches.
You might push changes
to three or four branches
without realizing
what you were doing.
You probably want to
configure your push default
to Simple, which
means it's only going
to push the changes on the
branch you're currently on,
which is a much more
intuitive choice.
And that's actually now
the default in Git 2.0.
Another important
configuration setting
is to configure
your pull default.
Often what people will
do is they will git pull
and because a pull is a
fetch plus a merge, what
it does is it creates these
merge commits where it's taking
their local commits with
whatever commits they
downloaded and adding
this spurious merge
commit that really adds
no useful information
to the repository's history.
You are usually much
better to rebase on pull.
So to do a git pull -- rebase.
The problem is it's
sometimes hard to remember
to do that on a regular basis.
And if you're not quite
sure what I'm talking about,
remember, we covered
this in Git Real 2.
So do check out that
Code School class
if you want more information.
So if you want to make sure
that you're pull defaults are
configured correctly so that you
always fetch and then rebase,
what you want to
do is git config --
global pull dot rebase to true.
And this means for all
of your repositories,
it will rebase when you
pull instead of merging.
One problem that
can occur is when
you need to resolve the same
merge conflicts multiple times.
Perhaps if you
are cherry picking
a commit to multiple long
running release branches
or perhaps if you are rebasing
regularly or merging in
and then backing out of merge
after integration testing.
Likely there's a
configuration option
that can save you a lot
of trouble doing this.
With ReReRe, or Reuse Recorded
Resolution, what you can do
is ask Git to capture every time
you resolve a merge conflict
and then in the future
if you have exactly
that same merge conflict, it
will remake the same change
but still give you a
chance to review it just
to make sure it's acceptable.
So I'd strongly encourage you
to configure ReReRe and enable
that and set that
to true so that you
can take advantage
of this feature.
Finally, if you're running an
old version of Git, 1, 8, 4,
or earlier, it's important to
configure at a global level
to set the color.UI to true.
This is what gives you the
green and red coloration in Git
so that you can see more
easily what's going on.
There are some very
powerful options in Git,
but some of them can
require a lot of typing.
Aliases allow you to
create your own custom
commands that do
just what you want.
And there's a couple
of aliases we're
going to recommended that you
use throughout this course.
The first alias we're going
to recommend is git s.
If you look at a
git status, you'll
notice that it takes up a lot of
space to show you information,
whereas if you do git status
-s, or silent mode,
it gives you just the
information you need most
of the time in much less space.
So if git config an alias
called S for status -s,
that will allow you to
output status in silent mode
just by typing git s.
Git log is a great command,
but by itself it doesn't really
give a very useful
output because it
takes lines and lines
of information just
to show you the last
two or three commits.
Wouldn't it be great if we had a
command like git lg, let's say,
which wouldn't be too much
typing that would show us
every commit on it's own line
that would decorate those
commits with things
like the head,
the branches, and perhaps even
tags, and that would show us
things like the graph as
well so we could see what
commits were made
on what branches.
Well, we can do that if we
create a git configuration
option with an alias of lg
that is a log with the one line
decorate all and
graph options set.
Git configurations are specific
to the machine you're on.
They don't get
shared when you push,
pull, or clone a repository.
Because of that, it's
important to figure out
how you do want to share some
settings between team members,
whether it's the same
aliases or making sure
that everyone rebases on pull.
There are two common
patterns for doing this.
One is to just put your
configuration options in a wiki
so people can cut and paste
them and run those configuration
commands whenever they
set up a new machine.
The other option is to create
a repository for your dot files
where you can put
your dot git config
and any other important dot
files and share them easily
between members of your team.
Now it's time for you to
jump into some challenges
and make sure you've got
your configuration set up.
I'll see you in
the next section.