Welcome back.
In this section we're going to
go through forking and cloning.
If you're already familiar
with both of those,
you might want to just skip
ahead to the challenges.
When you create a new
repository on GitHub,
the first thing you're going
to want to do is clone that so
that you're downloading
a copy of the repository
to your local machine.
And then you can make changes
locally and push those
back up to GitHub.
If someone else has
created a project on GitHub
and they've added you
as a collaborator,
again, you can just clone
a copy of the repository,
make any changes you want,
and push them back up.
Because they've given
you permission to do so.
However, if someone's created
a public repository on GitHub
and they've not added
you as a collaborator,
you can still clone
that repository
to make a local copy.
You could use the files.
You can commit and
make changes locally,
but you're not going to be
able to push your changes up
to GitHub because you don't
have the permission to do so.
So the question is, how do you
collaborate on a repository
that you don't have
permission to push to?
Well, the answer is, you
create a fork of the project.
When you create a fork,
you're creating your own copy
of the repository,
still up on GitHub,
but under your username,
or organization name
if you're running
an organization.
And what this does is it
creates a copy on GitHub
that you have full
permissions to.
So now you can then
clone that copy,
make changes locally, commit
them, and push them up
to your fork.
Notice that I'm looking
here at the dojo rules
repository, which is owned
by the deadlyvipers.
If I want to make a
change to this repository
I'm going to have to fork it
so that I have my own copy.
So let's look at that process.
I'm going to go click the
fork button in the top right.
Then I'm going to choose
where to fork it to.
In this case, I'm going to
fork it to my personal account.
Once the fork is made,
notice that now there's
a new copy of the repository
at my username slash repo name.
And now that I've
forked it, I just
need to clone it, to
download it to my laptop.
So I'm going to copy the clone
url, go into a terminal window,
and clone the repository.
And now I can go in
here and make changes.
I could open up a
file, and I could
make some changes
to edit that file.
Once I've made my changes I can
add and commit those to Git.
And because I'm
pulling from a fork,
I can now push my changes
back up to my fork.
And I'll see that when
I go back to the fork
and look at the list of commits,
I'll see my commit right there.
Now it's time for you
to go fork a repo,
and I'll see you
in the next video.