So you were trying to
collaborate on a repository
that you didn't have
permissions for.
So you made a fork so there
was your copy on GitHub.
You cloned that down to your
laptop, made the changes,
and pushed them
back to your clone.
But wouldn't it be great
if you could somehow
get the changes or
improvements you've made back
into that original project?
Well, you can and the mechanism
to do that is a pull request.
As we can see here,
this is a case
where there was an original
project, you made a fork of it,
you cloned it down
to your laptop,
and you've pushed
your changes back up.
When you send the pull request,
the owner of the original repo
is then notified so
they can go and check
the status of your pull request
and decide whether to accept it
or not.
You can think of a
fork as a branch.
So in this diagram,
you can see that we've
forked the Code School repo and
created our own copy of that.
And we've got our
master branch that we're
making certain commits to,
and then at the same time,
commits are being made to
the master branch or the Code
School repo.
The pull request
is us requesting
that the changes on
our master branch
get merged in to the master
branch in the Code School repo.
And if a pull
request is accepted,
that's exactly what it will do -
it will create a merge commit.
So let's look at the process
of creating a pull request.
In this case, I'm
going to request
that the changes I made to my
fork, my copy of the dojo rules
repository get pulled into the
original deadlyvipers repo.
So the first thing I do
is in the top right hand
corner there is a
"Pull Request" button.
So I'm going to click
that and then click
"New Pull Request"
when that appears.
You'll notice that I am
requesting the changes
for my master branch to be
merged in to the deadlvipers
master branch.
I click on the "Create
New Pull Request" button,
enter any information,
and then click
on the "Submit Pull Request."
And here we are with a
created pull request.
Notice that we're on the deadlyvipers
copy of the repository
because that's where the pull
request was created because we
are asking them to
accept the changes
into their copy
of the repository.
The next time that
deadlyvipers logs in,
they're probably going to look
through a list of the pull
requests they've
received, including ours.
On a public GitHub repo,
anybody can review and comment
on a pull request.
They can check your
branch, run the code,
and perhaps run some
tests against it
to make sure it's running.
And if they have
permissions, they
can then accept the pull
request and merge it
into their repository.
Let's imagine somebody comes
across your pull request
and they click on
the pull request
and decide to go
look at your code.
But this person thinks
you've gone too far.
What they can do is
they can actually
make a comment right in the pull
request suggesting that you've
gone too far and
submit that change.
When they do so, you're going
to get an email notification.
When you do that, if
you agree with them,
you can then go back into a
terminal window, edit a file,
and make a change
that seems to be
consistent with their feedback.
You can then add and
commit that change
and push it up to GitHub.
And because pull requests
point to a branch,
not a specific commit,
that will automatically get
added to the pull request.
So now your new commit
becomes part of the pull
request as soon as you
push it to your fork.
They can then look
at your changes,
and if they're
comfortable with them,
they can make a comment
saying that they're + 1
and that they think
you should ship this.
And when you get that,
depending upon the rules
that you use in your
team for maybe one or two
other members of your
team, you can then
click on the button to
merge the pull request.
And now we can look at the
commit history in the deadly
vipers copy of the
dojo rules repository
and see the commit
we made and the merge
commit that closed
the pull request.
And you'll notice
that the merge commit
even has a reference
back to the pull request
so we can link back
to the pull request
and see any discussion that
might have occurred while we
were working on
this functionality.
Time for you to
submit a pull request
and then we'll see you
back in the next section.