When you're collaborating
using forks,
it's important to
update your fork
to capture changes
that have been
made by other collaborators.
In this section, we're going
to explore how to do that.
Let's say that we
have two developers
don't want to collaborate on a
single repository using forks.
We're going to start with
the initial repository.
We're going to call that
the upstream because both
of the developers are going to
create downstream forks of that
so that they have their
own copy of the repository.
And then both of
the developers are
going to clone
those repositories
to their individual laptops.
They're going to do coding,
add and commit their changes,
and push those changes
up to their forks.
Then both of them are going
to submit pull requests
with their changes which
eventually will get accepted
and merged into the
upstream repository.
Well, the problem is,
each developer now only
has their changes.
They don't have a copy
of the changes made
by the other developer.
Because those changes are only
on the other developer's fork
and on the upstream repo.
So what they need
to be able to do
is they have to pull
from the upstream repo
to be able to get the
accepted pull requests made
by the other developer
to update their fork.
So to look at the commands
required to do that.
The first command is you're
going to add a remote,
using git, pointing to
the upstream repository
with the path to
whatever that repo is.
You're then going to fetch the
changes from that upstream repo
and merge the changes that
were in the upstream master
branch with your local
master branch in your laptop.
And then finally, you're
going to push those changes
to your fork so that it
has all of the changes made
by the other developer.
This is something
you're going to want
to do every time
a pull request
is accepted into
the upstream repo.
So let's see this in practice.
Let's imagine that somebody
comes to the deadlyvipers dojo
rules repository.
And they make their
own fork of the repo
and they decide
to make a change.
They go to view a file.
And notice here,
the Edit button that
allows them to make a
change right on GitHub,
and to commit that change.
They go into the
dojo rules file,
and they add a simple
commit message,
and then commit that change.
Then, they create
a pull request,
requesting that this change be
merged into the deadlyvipers
copy of the repository.
Now let's go in and look at the
pull request that they created.
Now, if I log in as a
member of the deadlyvipers,
I can go look at
their pull request,
look at the change they made,
and if I'm OK with that,
I can merge that
pull request in.
And I get the chance to
type a merge commit message
if I want to make it clear
what work I was bringing in,
or why I accepted it.
So we've merged their changes
into the upstream repository.
And we can see that
right here on GitHub.
So if we go back to our
console as our original user -
remember this is Peter Bell who
has a fork of the deadlyvipers
repo.
We git pull, but it
doesn't download anything.
And when we look at the
contents of the dojo rules file,
we see that it doesn't
have the change that
was accepted and merged
into the upstream repo.
So to fix this, what we need to
do, is we need to add a remote.
The convention is
we'll call it upstream.
And we've got to point
that to the deadlyvipers
copy of the repository.
And then what we need to do
is pull those changes down.
Now that we've pulled
those changes down,
you can see that we now have
the changed content for the dojo
rules file.
And the next time we
push up to our fork,
that will push the
changes to our copy
of the repository
on GitHub as well.
Time for you give this a try,
and I'll see you
in the next level.