[SINGING] She'll clone and
fork your repos
faster than you can blink.
And then tag, push and pull
request while pouring a drink.
She's studied wikis and
pages to promote her skills,
but it's the branching
and the merging
which will pay all the bills.
Your only chance to find
her is the user work flow.
Commit to her release and
you can access control.
You'll be pushing past security
to join her at the club just
to catch a glimpse of
her mastering GitHub.
Forked based
collaboration is great
for occasional
contributors, but if you're
working with a team
on a regular basis
you're probably going
to want to collaborate
using a single repository.
In this level, we're going
to look at how to do that.
Let's say you're working with
a team of three other people
and you're using a
fork based workflow,
you're going to
have your own fork
that you need to
set up as a remote
to pull from and push to.
You're also going to have to
set up the upstream as a remote
so that you can pull
any pull requests that
have been accepted from
other members of your team.
But in addition to
those two remotes,
you're probably
also going to have
to add three other
remotes for the three
other members of your team
to pull from their forks,
because if you don't
do that you won't
be able to pull from and
download a copy of any changes
that they're working on that
have not yet been accepted
as pull requests into
the upstream repo.
In practice this
is a lot to keep
track of so most teams instead
use a single repository
workflow.
With a single repository
workflow everyone
is working directly with a
clone of the same repository
on GitHub.
No folks required.
And because of that, it's very
easy to keep things updated.
You just have a clone of that
single repository on GitHub
and you can pull or push from
that to get all of the changes
that everyone is working on.
However, you have to
be careful if you're
working with
multiple contributors
on a single repository, because
if everyone commits directly
to the master
branch you're going
to run into conflicts
on a regular basis.
So instead what
you need to do is
you need to use a feature
branch strategy where everyone
is contributing on their own
separate feature branches
on that single
repository on GitHub.
This makes it easy for people
to contribute to other people's
work because all
you need to do is
fetch the changes from
the remote server,
look at a list of all your
branches doing a git branch -a
and then check out
any other branch
that any member of your team
has pushed up to GitHub.
And then once a feature is
done, any member of the team
can check it out, make sure
that the tests run well,
and then merge the work
into the master branch
and push that up to GitHub.
Pull requests add another
level of collaboration
to this process.
Rather than having
to check out a branch
and send emails to members
of your teams saying,
"I like this, but could
you make a change?"
With a pull request you can
have multiple developers
collaborating on a branch
and commenting on it directly
on GitHub
And this is the GitHub flow,
where every developer creates
their own feature branch,
or the developers work
on a single repository.
And then the developers,
when they're ready,
create a pull request requesting
that the rest of the team
review their work and
then eventually merge it
into the master branch.
So let's look at this in action.
Let's say we wanted
to add a new feature.
We would create a branch locally
and then go do some coding.
We might create a
file and populate
that with some content.
We then add that
change, commit it,
and push it up to
the remote server.
And the way we do that
is using a Git push
-u origin branch
name, which does two things.
It pushes the changes up
to a new branch on GitHub
with the same name, but it
also sets the default upstream
for that branch, which we can
see here in our docket /config
file.
So in future, if we want to
push or pull from that branch
we can do that.
Once we're ready to get
feedback on this branch then
we go into GitHub and
create a pull request.
We can select from a drop
down list of all the branches
to pick which branch we want
to create the pull request on,
which branch we're
requesting that we merge back
into the master branch.
Then we create the pull
request, and wait for feedback
from the rest of the team.
Why don't you go ahead and try
to create a pull request now.