Whether you are just proposing
a new potential feature,
or whether you think your
code is ready to merge,
there will usually be some kind
of discussion or collaboration
around most of the pull
requests you create.
When you're collaborating
on a single repository,
there's nothing to stop
you merging your pull
request in without any feedback
from the rest of the team.
But don't do it,
it's a bad idea.
Let's take one more
look at the workflow.
The first thing you
do is create a branch.
In this case,
we've called it F1.
And then you make at least
one commit on that branch,
and push it up to GitHub
Once you've got at
least one commit,
you can now create
a pull request,
to start to get feedback
from the rest of your team
on the code that
you're working on.
You can then get comments from
different people on the team.
And if you want to make
changes, you can simply
make those changes on the
branch, push them up to GitHub
and they will automatically
be added to the pull request.
Because pull requests point
to the head of the branch,
not to a particular commit.
Once at least one or
two people on your team
have approved the
changes, you or they
can then go ahead and
merge those changes back
into the master
branch, either by using
the web-based interface
to merge the pull request,
or by merging the feature branch
locally on the command line,
and then pushing those
changes up to GitHub.
There are three
types of comments
they could be made
on a pull request.
They could be made
at a high level
on the pull request itself.
I think this is a great feature.
They could be made
at a commit level.
"Oh, I'm not sure I agree
with the changes you
made to this code."
They can even be
made at a line level.
"I really don't think you
should have deleted line 12."
Let's look at collaborating
on a pull request,
and see how it works.
Anybody on the team can make
comments on a pull request.
Pull requests are designed to
make it easy to collaborate.
So one thing you should consider
is "at" mentioning members
of your team using
their GitHub usernames.
That way they'll get
notified by email
whether you're looking for them
to review some of your code,
or you're providing feedback
on changes they've made.
The pull request window
updates automatically,
so you could have a
close to real time
chat with other
members of your team,
as they're making changes.
Here, you can see that
somebody commented
on a specific line of code.
And if you see a comment
that you agree with,
you might want to go back
into the command line
to make the requested change.
In this case, to remove
Budd from the kill list.
And then as usual, you add
and commit your changes,
and push them to
the remote server.
And then, when we go back
into the pull request,
you see that your changes have
now shown up as another commit,
as part of the pull request.
And if your team
agrees with the changes
you've made, you can then just
merge the pull request in,
so that your changes become
part of the master branch,
and the pull
request gets closed.
So let's briefly look
at the commands we'd
use when reviewing
a pull request.
First thing we do is
git fetch, to download
all of the latest changes
and all of the branches,
to have a copy of everything
that everyone else has
worked on, and push to GitHub
Then we do a git branch-a
to show all the branches,
including the remote branches.
Then if there's
a branch that you
want to work on, that
relates to a pull request,
you can git checkout
that branch name,
and it will automatically
create a local branch,
pointing to your
remote tracking branch.
There you can make
whatever changes you want.
You can commit
them, and push them,
and now your changes will
be part of the pull request
that was created by
one of your team.
So far we've focused on other
people reviewing our work.
But often, we'll
want to review what
someone else has
been working on.
Let's say someone is
working on a feature
and we want to see
how it's going.
We can start by viewing
the pull request
and making some comments online.
But eventually,
we're going to want
to check out and run their code.
All we need to do is git pull
to download all of the changes
that people have
been working on.
Then we can do a
git branch-a to see
a list of all of the
branches that are there.
And we can see that there's
an equipment list branch.
So let's git checkout
equipment list,
so that we can go see and
make a change to that branch.
In this case, let's add a little
more equipment to the list,
just to make sure we're well
supplied for our next mission.
We add and commit the changes,
push them up to GitHub,
and then if we go back in to
GItHub in the pull request,
we now see the
change that we made
to a pull request
and a branch that
were created by somebody
else on that team.
Finally, we can make
comments, other team members
can make comments, and when
we are ready and comfortable
with the changes
made, we can then
merge the pull
request using GItHub.
So why don't you give
it a try, and we'll see you
in the next section.