Welcome back.
So far, we've looked
at the logistics
for working with pull requests.
In this section,
we're going to look
at three key
considerations that you
need to think about
every time you're
going to merge a pull request.
The three key considerations
are whether you
should use an interactive
rebase to simplify your history,
whether you should use a rebase
to create a linear history,
so it looks like you worked
from one feature at a time,
and/or whether you should
use fast-forward or recursive
merges when you're
merging feature
branches into your
master branch.
Careful use of
interactive rebases
can do a great job of
simplifying your history.
Generally when you're
working with Git,
you'll be committing
every 5-10 minutes.
And sometimes you
just don't need
to keep that granularity
of information.
So before you merge
a feature branch in,
you should absolutely go back
and look over your history
and see, are there any commits
that could be reordered?
Maybe where the commit
message could be changed.
Or even where you could
squash or fix up a number of
commits to simplify history.
If you're not familiar
with interactive rebase,
make sure to check
out Git Real 2.
It's important to avoid a common
anti pattern, which is just
taking all of the commits
on a feature branch,
and squashing them into one.
Occasionally, this
can make sense.
But most of the time, you want
to keep a more granular history
than that.
So just because you decide
to do interactive rebases,
does not mean you should
squash every feature
branch into just
a single commit.
The next question is whether
you should use a rebase
to create a linear history?
So instead of it showing
the truth where maybe you're
working on five, or six,
or 10 features at a time,
you history will look
like your development team
only ever started,
worked on, and delivered
one feature at a time.
It's not always truthful, but
it's generally much more useful
to use rebase in this
way to give yourself
a clean linear history
so that you can look back
on what you've done, and
other people can better
understand what your
team's been working on.
And to do that, you just
check out the feature branch,
and git rebase master.
Resolving any rebase
conflicts in the same ways as
you'd resolve merge conflicts,
if there are conflicts
between the changes on
your feature branch,
and the changes that were
made on the master branch.
Then the final
question is whether you
should use a recursive merge
or a fast-forward merge?
The benefits of a
fast-forward merge
are that you get less commits.
Because the commits
from your feature branch
are put straight on to the
master branch with no merge
commit.
The downside, is it's much
harder to tell what commits
were made on what
feature branch.
So generally, I recommend using
a recursive merge even if there
was no changes on master
because you've rebased,
and you would be able to
do a fast-forward merge.
If you want to make sure that
you have a recursive merge,
just check out master, and git
merge --no-ff,
no fast-forward
the feature branch
And that way, you'll be
guaranteed a merge commit,
which will make it
very clear what commits
were made on a feature
branch because they
won't be added to
the master branch.
And it will also give
you a single commit
that you can revert if you
want to remove this feature
branch from history.
To summarize, with
fast-forward merges,
you do get less commits, because
you don't get the merge commit
every time you merge
a feature branch it.
But I generally recommend
to use recursive merges,
because firstly, it
makes it very clear
that every commit was made on a
feature branch, not on master.
And secondly, it gives
you that single commit
that you could revert
to remove that feature
branch from your history.
Looking at these three
key considerations when
merging pull requests, generally
you should interactively
rebase to simplify your
history, but only removing
commits that don't
add value when
looking at how the
project was built.
You should definitely
consider rebasing
to create a linear
history, so it
looks like you only built
one feature at a time.
And finally, you should
use recursive merges
because they provide more
clarity about where commits
were made, and make it very
easy to revert a feature branch.
So let's look at going through
this process end-to-end.
We've got a pull request
here with a number of commits
that are a little confused.
So let's go into
a terminal window.
And we can see here that we've
got five commits on the action
plan branch.
And we probably
don't need that many.
So we want to rebase
interactive from the Gotta kill
Bill commit.
So let's check out the
action plan branch.
Have a look at the log now.
And we see now that our head
is at 2e03 on the action plan
branch.
So now, we can git rebase
interactive, HEAD~5
to rebase the last five commits.
Most of the time, you'd want to
keep a number of these commits.
Most of the time, you wouldn't
squash all of these commits.
But in this case, there really
was only one substantive thing
we did.
We built a simple list
of people to kill.
So let's reword the
first commit so that we
can change the commit message.
And then let's fix up
all of the other commits
to squash them into
that first commit
and discard their
commit messages.
When we're done with this,
it will throw us back
into our text editor
and give us a chance
to change the commit message
for the one commit we're saving.
We put the new
commit message in.
It continues with the rebase.
And now if we're to
look at our git log,
we see that there's just
a single new commit, d99e,
that is at the
head of action plan
that has all of our changes.
Now, we can push those changes.
dash f, we're going to force
push them up to GitHub.
And then when we go back
into the pull request,
we see that instead of
five different commits,
we now see just a single simple
commit for this pull request.
So we've done the
rebase interactive
and we see in the
file it's adding
all the content we wanted.
Now, we want to rebase this
against the master branch
because we can see that there
was some commits on the master
branch.
And we want to make it
look like we didn't start
working on the action plan until
those commits were finished
and merged.
So from the action plan branch,
we will git rebase master.
And that will replay our commits
on top of the master branch.
So now when we
look at the log, we
can see that the action
plan branch looks
like it was started after all
of the other commits on master
were finished.
And again, we're
going to have to git
push -f to
force this change.
Because we've changed the
sha1 hash of this commit.
And indeed we see when we
refresh the page in github,
that there is still only a
single commit on the pull
request, but now it has
a different sha1 hash.
Then finally, all we need to
do is git checkout master.
And then git merge, no
fast-forward our feature
branch.
We enter a commit message.
And then push those
changes to GitHub
And because pull
requests are closed
when the branch that
they point to gets
merged into the default branch
on this repository master,
on GitHub the pull request has
now been merged and closed.
I know that's a lot to
wrap your head around,
but it's important you get
used to working with these best
practices.
So why don't you give
it a try yourself?
And I'll see you
in the next level.