[SINGING] She will
clone and fork
your repos faster than you
can blink and then tag, push,
and pull requests
while pouring a drink.
She's studied wikis and
pages to promote her skills.
But it's the branching
and the merging
which will pay all the bills.
Your only chance to find
her is to use her workflow.
Commit to her release,
and you can access control.
You'll be pushing past security
to join her at the club,
just to catch a glimpse
of her Mastering GitHub.
Welcome back to
"Mastering GitHub."
In this level, we're going to
be looking at tags and releases.
So far, we've talked
a lot about how
we can use feature branches
to build new functionality.
But we haven't talked
at all about how
we can use tags or
release branches to manage
moving that functionality
to production.
Let's start by looking at tags.
The first question
people often ask
is, when should I create a tag.
And the answer is, every
time you push to production,
you should tag that commit.
The only exception to this is if
you have a continuous delivery
environment, where every single
Commit on your master branch
ends up in production.
It's important to tag
every production release,
so that you know
exactly what code
has gone to production
at what time.
There are three
different types of tags.
Lightweight tags
allow you to create
a simple, human-readable
title for pointing
to a particular commit hash.
Signed tags allow you to
cryptographically sign a tag,
so you can prove that it
was you that made the tag.
But most of the time you're
going to use annotated tags.
What they allow
you to do is give
a name to a particular
commit but also to capture
who created the tag, when
they created the tag,
and in the description
field, explain
why they created the tag.
So let's look at how
we'd use annotated tags.
The command you use is git
tag -a, to make it annotated.
And then you give it a
name, in this case, v1.3.2,
which is version 1.3.2 with a
-m message of whatever the tag
message should be.
If you leave off
the -m, it will just
throw you into you
default text editor,
and you'll be able to create
a more comprehensive message
there.
Once you've created
the tag, you then
want to push it up to GitHub.
This doesn't happen
automatically with a push.
So you have to do
git push --tags,
to upload any or all of the
tags you've created locally
to your GitHub repository.
A common best practice
for naming tags
is to use semantic versioning.
So you might start
with a v and then
follow it by three
numbers - the major release,
the minor release,
and the patch version.
The major release is to
identify substantial changes
to the application,
often ones that
will break backwards
compatibility.
Minor releases are to capture
new user-valued functionality.
And patch releases are
used for simple bug fixes.
Well, let's look
at this in action.
If we go to the terminal window
and check out our git log,
we can see that there was
a previous release - ccbc2.
And let's say that we
wanted to tag that.
So the first thing we do
is we would git checkout,
to check out that SHA1 hash.
And of course, we're in
a detached head state,
because we are not
on a commit that
has a branch associated with it.
Then what we can now do
is create a tag here.
So we just git tag
-a, give it a name.
And then we can either
-m to give it a message,
or in this case, go
into a text editor,
to create a more comprehensive
message for the tag.
When we go back to
the log, we can now
see that tag against
the SHA1 hash.
But when we go up
to releases and look
at the list of releases,
the tag isn't there.
That's because we've
not pushed it up yet.
So we go back to the command
line, git push --tags,
to upload any of
our tags to GitHub.
And now when we
look in GitHub, we
can see that tag under
the "releases" tab.
If you want more information
on naming your tags,
a great place to go
is the semver.org,
SemanticVersioning.org website,
that has a lot of information
on best practices for
using semantic versions
for your version numbers.
Time for you to go
start tagging some code.