In the last section, we
looked at release tags.
In this section, we're going
to take a little bit of time
to look at where and
when it makes sense
to use release
branches, as well.
Whatever happens, you'll want
to create release tags whenever
you push to production.
And most of the time
that's all you need.
But occasionally, you also
need release branches, as well,
where you need to make changes
to a particular release
without affecting
your master branch.
That's where release
branches come in.
Release tags point to a
single commit, which is great.
But what happens if you need
to make changes to that commit?
Let's say, you need
to make a hotfix,
because you found in
your manual QA process
that there's a bug in
your production release.
In that case,
you're going to need
to support a release branch
that will allow you to make
the additional commits to fix
any bugs that you might find.
So we can see here on the left
that we have the master branch
with a number of commits.
It looks like we've pushed
two of them to production.
And we've created release
tags for those two commits.
A version 1.0.0, and
then a point release
for a hotfix, version 1.0.1.
On the right, we
can see that we also
have a master branch
with a number of commits.
But in this case, we've
created two release branches,
one for the 1.0 branch,
and one for the 1.1 branch.
And in both cases, we will
make changes and then create
release tags for
the various hotfixes
we end up pushing to production.
There are three
key reasons why you
would choose to create
a release branch.
The first is, if you
have a lot of manual QA.
The second, is if you
have long running releases
that you need to support
and update over time.
And the third, is just
creating them on demand,
when you need them,
when you have hotfixes.
Let's look at each
one of those three.
If you have a manual QA
process, and you almost always
have a number of hotfixes
to every production release,
it probably makes
sense to start off
by creating a release
branch every time
you choose to push
to production.
That way, your QA team can
work on the release branch,
provide feedback
to your developers,
they can create a
number of hotfixes,
and then you don't need to
tag and push to production
until the release
branch is ready to go.
Here, you can see
a case where we
have a release branch
that we created.
And we made a couple
of hotfixes on it
before we finally decided to
create a release tag for it.
And then, once we've
made those changes,
we needed to get the hotfixes
back into the master branch,
so we merged them
back into master
after pushing to production.
Another reason to
create a release branch
is, if you have a
long running releases
that you need to
support over time.
So for example, if
you've got customers
paying you to support version
1, version 2, and version
3 of your code for a
number of months or years,
you're going to have to keep
those release branches so
every time you have
security updates,
or other critical
patches, you can
patch each one of
those release branches
and then send them off to
the appropriate customers.
For many teams,
if you don't need
to support long running
feature branches,
and you don't have an extensive
manual QA process that often
finds bugs in your
code, you may not
need to start with
release branches at all.
Instead, what you should do is
start with the release tags.
And you can see here we have
release tags, release 1,
and 1.1.
So what happened
here was, we started
by just creating release tags.
But then we realized
that we needed
to make a hotfix to release 1.1.
So we checked out the tag.
We created a new branch,
called release branch 1.1,
and then we made the
hotfix on that branch,
so it didn't get
confused with changes
we were making on
the master branch.
Then what we did was we tagged
that hotfix as a release 1.1.1
and pushed that to production,
merged the changes back
into master, and then
deleted the release branch.
So it's possible to just
create your release branches
on the fly, after the fact,
if and when you need them.
And that's often
the best strategy
for the majority of teams.
So now it's your turn to create
a release branch on the fly,
and I'll see you back
here when you're done.