In this section, we're going
to look at releases, which
are a GitHub-specific feature
that allow you to add more
information and
functionality to your tags.
There are two key
benefits to releases.
The first is that they
allow you to share binaries
with your users through
GitHub without having
to check the binaries into Git.
The second benefit is that they
provide you with the ability
to put extended release
notes in a way that's
easy to share with
anybody who's using
your code or your project.
There are two ways to
create releases on GitHub.
The first is to
select an existing tag
and to add binaries, notes,
or additional information.
The other option is to
go into the Releases tab,
and create a new
release from scratch.
And it will automatically add
a tag as part of the process.
One other benefit of releases
is that they allow your users
to be able to download a
copy of your source code
from a zip file without having
to clone the repository.
So within the Release tabs,
one of the things you can do
is edit a tag.
And when you click on that, it
allows you to, in this case,
we're selecting an existing
tag, and we're just
adding an additional
description to the tag.
You could also just drag
and drop binaries here
to attach them to the release,
making it very easy for people
to download executables
or other compiled source.
If you want to, you
can also highlight
if this release is a prerelease
version and something
people should be wary about
when downloading or using.
When you're done
with making changes,
you can click on the
"Publish release" button,
and it will save and
publish your changes.
The other way you can
create a release on GitHub
is to actually go
and find a commit
that you want to
add a release to.
As we look through
our commit history,
I see that there was a pull
request for the kill list.
And at the moment, we
don't have a tag for that.
And it seems like
that's probably
a release we'd want to tag.
So go to the "Releases" tab and
click on "Draft new release."
We have no tag version, but
if you go to the target,
and select "Recent Commits,"
you can then scroll down
to find the commit that
you want to select.
You can then give
it a tag version.
We'll call this 1.0.0.
And a release title
describing the release.
And then you can add longer
release notes explaining
the purpose of this
particular commit.
Again, if you want
to, you can highlight
that it was a
prerelease And then
you can publish this release.
And now, when we go back
to the releases page,
you will see that we can see
both of these releases, one
of which was created by a
tag on the command line,
and then enhanced through
GitHub, and the other of which
was created in GitHub, adding
the tag after the fact.
And now it's your turn
again - in this case,
to create some releases.
See you after the challenges.