[SINGING] She will clone and
fork your repos faster than
you can blink.
And then tag, push,
and pull requests,
while pouring a drink.
She's studied wikis and
pages to promote her skills,
but it's the branching
and the merging
which will pay all the bills.
Your only chance to find
her is the use her workflow.
Commit to her release and
you can access control.
You'll be pushing past security
to join her at the club.
Just to catch a glimpse
of her Mastering GitHub.
You're watching Level
Four of Mastering GitHub.
In this level, we're going to
cover GitHub issues, the GitHub
wiki functionality,
and GitHub Pages.
Let's look first
at GitHub Issues.
There are a couple
of main reasons
why you might choose to use
the issues functionality that's
built into GitHub. The first
common reason is if you've
got bugs that you
want to keep track of,
it often makes
sense to keep track
of those right in the
repository with the code
and with everything else.
The other use case is
it often makes sense
to use GitHub Issues to track
stories or units of work
that you need to deliver.
And in fact, some
teams even put both
of those into GitHub
issues, just using labels
to differentiate new
features from bugs.
If you want to enable issues for
a project, it's really simple.
Just go to Settings,
Options, and you'll
notice that there are
three check boxes.
And the last one is a
check box to allow you
to enable or disable Issues.
By default, it's enabled.
Don't worry if you've
got a bunch of issues
and you uncheck the box
and save it by accident.
GitHub still keeps
the issues, it just
doesn't allow you
to access them.
So just re-enable the check
box, and all of your issues
and all of their comments
will still be there.
If you're working on a project
that's publicly accessible,
anybody can create new issues
or comment on the issues.
If you're creating a
private repository just
for the members of
your team, it'll
only be collaborators
with access
to the project that can
view and create issues.
Click on the Issues tab
in the right-hand nav bar,
and you'll see a list
of any issues that
are being set up for
a particular project.
If you want to see what
work's outstanding,
have a look at the
list of open issues.
If you'd like to get a sense
of what the developers have
delivered recently, look at
the recently closed issues.
When you look at
the list of issues,
you'll see that you can see
everyone's issues, issues that
have been assigned
for you to work on,
issues that you created for
other people to work on,
and issues that have
mentioned you; either
in the original issue, or
somewhere in the comments,
with an 'at' mention of
your GitHub user name.
There's also the ability
to filter issues by labels.
One common pattern is to have
labels for features and bugs,
so you can quickly
see what functionality
needs to be built,
and what issues
you have with the functionality
you've already delivered.
You can even filter
by multiple labels.
Let's say you find
a bug in a project.
You can create a
new issue to notify
the team that there's a problem.
Just go to the Issues page, and
in the top right-hand corner,
click on the "New issue" button.
When you do that, you're
going to get a form.
The form first asks for
a title for the issue,
to briefly describe
what it's about.
It also gives you
a larger area where
you can give a more
comprehensive description.
And then, if you know who
should be working on it,
you could also select from
a drop down list or type
in any GitHub user name
to assign the issue
to a particular person.
There's also the option
to assign the issue
to a milestone, if it needs to
be done for your 2.0 release.
And you have the ability
to add one or more labels
to determine, is this
a feature or a bug?
And what functionality
does it relate to?
If an issue is assigned
to you, or if you
get mentioned in an
issue, either in the body
of the original issue or
in any of the comments,
you're going to start
getting notified
of any other changes
that occur on that issue.
Any other comments that
are made, or any other
commits that
reference that issue.
Sometimes that can be annoying,
if it's a long running issue
that you don't have any
ongoing relationship with.
So if you use the button towards
the bottom right-hand corner,
you can unsubscribe
from an issue,
to make sure that you
don't keep getting
notified about what's going on.
Equally, if there's an issue
you haven't been mentioned in,
you can just click on the
Subscribe link on any issue,
and you will start getting
notified anytime there's
activity on that issue.
You can also respond
to an issue just
by replying to any
email notification
that you get about that issue.
So it's really easy to
respond to issues, even
from a mobile device.
Issues integrate really well
with commits and pull requests.
You could reference
an issue in a commit,
and that will make the commit
appear in the issue history.
And it will notify anyone
who's subscribed to the issue.
Also, if you use
certain words like fixes
or closes or resolves,
and follow that
by an issue number, a
pound sign, and the number
of the issue - if you put that
in a commit message, when that
commit is merged into
your default branch -
for most people, the
master branch - that
will close the
issue automatically.
Issues also support a wide
range of keyboard commands
for navigating quickly.
So especially if you're dealing
with a lot of bug reports
on a regular basis, you
can use the keyboard
to speed up your workflow,
using GitHub issues.
So let's see this
work in practice.
We're going into this
project, and we're
going to create a new issue.
We click on the
New issue button,
and we put in some kind of
title to concisely describe
the issue that we're having.
We can select from a drop down
list of developers, which,
by default, will be anybody
who has been involved
with the project to date.
And we can either select
from an existing milestone,
or if we wanted to, we
could create a new milestone
to assign this issue to.
So in this case, let's create
a new milestone for the issue.
And then, let's take a
moment to put a little more
of a description, so whoever
needs to work on this
understands what
we want them to do.
And then we submit the issue.
Now let's go into
a terminal window
and see how we could
work with that issue.
Let's open up the file, make
the change that was requested,
and then we're going to add
and commit those changes.
But in the commit
message, we're going
to make sure to say that
it fixes number 9, which
is the issue number
we just created.
Then we can push those
changes up to GitHub,
and go look at the issue.
And we see that it's
automatically been closed,
because it automatically
identified that there
was a commit on
the default branch
that mentioned the issue.
And because it used
the word fixes,
it knows that the issue should
be closed automatically.
Up to this point,
we've just been
looking at issues
on a small project.
But sometimes it's
good to see how
issues are used by large
open source projects.
Let's go look at Rails, and
see how they use GitHub issues.
As we go to the
Rails project, we
can see that in the
Issues tab, there's
a list of outstanding issues.
We can filter the
issues by milestone,
so that we just see the issues
for an upcoming milestone.
It looks like the latest
milestone had no issues.
But as we go to a milestone
further in the future,
we can see there are a
number of outstanding issues
to resolve before
that goes live.
We can also filter by labels.
Let's say that we
just wanted to see
the issues that related
to active record.
We can do that as well.
So we can filter, for
example, by the issues
within a particular milestone
that relate to active record.
Now it's your chance
in the challenges
to work with issues on GitHub.