Welcome back.
It's always a best practice
to create a README.md
file in the root
directory of your project.
It allows you to tell people
what the project's about,
why they should use it,
and how to install it,
and even how to
contribute back to it.
But as your project gets
larger and more complex,
eventually the
README file is going
to get a little too
large to work with.
When that happens,
you should consider
setting up and GitHub Wiki
to provide more information
about the project you've built.
You may have noticed
earlier, enabling
wikis for a project is
done on the same page
as enabling issues.
You just go to
Settings, Options,
and under Features make sure to
check the box next to wikis.
There's an extra
option for wikis which
allows you to restrict editing
on a public repository only
to collaborators.
So if you don't want everyone
changing the documentation
for your project, make
sure to check that box.
Let's say you want to add
a wiki to your project.
Start by clicking on the
Wiki tab on the right.
And you'll see that it gives
you a welcome page to the wiki,
and asks you to click a button
to create your initial page.
When you click that button,
it'll give you a form.
By default, it'll set the
title for the page to Home,
but you can change
that if you want.
And then it gives
you a text area
where you can enter the
content for that initial page.
Creating links is really easy.
You just click on
the Link button.
And then insert the
link text, which
can be any description you want,
and the URL, which is either
going to be the name of another
page on the wiki or a full URL
if it wants to be a link to
something outside of your wiki.
There were a number of
buttons above the text area
when you're entering content.
You can use these to create
headings, links, bolds,
italics, and the like.
But this isn't a WIZIWIG editor.
All it's going to do is
generate Markdown for you.
So instead, use these if you
can't remember the Markdown.
But once you've used
them a few times,
you'll probably just
start typing the Markdown
straight into the text area.
The Markdown we work with in
README files and in the wiki
is GitHub Flavored Markdown.
If you're new to
Markdown you'll obviously
want to learn the
basics of this.
But even if you've been using
Markdown for a number of years
in other projects, take
the time to go to the URL
at the bottom of this
screen and learn more
about GitHub Flavored
Markdown, because there
are a number of
specific differences,
compared to other flavors
of Markdown that exist.
One thing you might want to add
to your wiki is status badges.
Here's an example in
the Rails Arel Project,
where we're seeing
badges to show
that the build is currently
passing in Travis CI,
and that the dependencies
are all up to date,
according to Gemnasium.
We're really just
putting images in here.
But those images get
updated by those projects.
So it's a really easy
way to dynamically show
the state of your
project in your wiki.
This is a general feature
of GitHub Markdown.
And it can be used in
wikis or in README files.
In fact, the example,
we're using here comes
from the Arel README file,
rather than its wiki.
So let's look at the
process of building a wiki.
The first thing we do is
click on the "Wiki" tab,
and it's going to say,
Welcome to your wiki.
Create the first page.
Click on the link,
and all you need to do
is go into the content area
and add some information.
Once you're done with
that, click on "Save Page."
And notice the little
metadata is stored here
about who made the change
and when it was made.
Now let's add a new page,
because the whole power wiki's
is linking across
multiple pages.
We can give it a title,
enter a description,
and when we're
done, save the page.
Now let's go back
to the home page
and create a link
to our new page.
And to do that,
all we need to do
is type the text before the
link, click on the link button,
and enter the description we
want for the link and the page
it should link to.
And notice, we can just go in
and change that description,
for example.
It's just a text file.
Now when we go to the home page,
after saving that page,
we can click on
that link and see
that it takes us to
our new Rules page.
You'll also notice that
all of the pages we add
are added to a navigation box
on the right of the wiki page.
So have fun playing
with you wikis
and I'll see you in
the next section.