Have you ever wanted to host a
simple static website relating
to a project or an organization
you're involved with?
GitHub Pages can
allow you to do that,
adding it to an existing repo
or an organizational account.
There are two main use
cases for GitHub Pages.
The first is to add richer
documentation and information
to a specific project.
The other is to create a page
either for a user on GitHub
or for an organization.
Let's say you wanted to create
a web page just for yourself.
Well, the first thing
you'd want to do
to do that using
GitHub Pages is create
a repo for your
username.github.io.
It's important you follow that
convention when naming it.
Then you can go
into the settings,
scroll down to the
GitHub Pages area,
use the auto page generator,
write your content,
pick a theme, and publish.
Let's look at how that
works step-by-step.
In this case, we want to create
a page for deadly vipers.
So it's an organization
rather than a user.
But it's exactly the
same process either way.
You start by clicking on the
link to add a new repository,
and you name the repository
as user or organization name
.github.io.
When you do that it'll
create the standard page,
and you'd usually expect
to have to push content up.
We're going to do
something different.
Just click on "Settings,"
scroll down the page
to the GitHub Pages section,
and click on the "Automatic page
generator."
That will then give
you the very first page
and you can start by putting
some content in as a title
and by updating the description
to describe what you want
about your organization
or your user account.
Click the button at the
bottom to save the content,
and then you get
to select a theme.
Don't worry.
You can create
custom HTML and CSS.
This is just to give
you a starting point
so you can make
something that looks
fairly attractive quickly.
Once you've selected a theme,
click on the "Publish" button
and it will take you to a
page showing all of the HTML,
CSS, and other content
that was generated.
And at the top of
the page it tells you
the URL you will need to
go to to view this page.
If you go to that
page immediately
you'll probably not
see anything at all.
But if you give it
about 10 minutes
you will then see
that the site has
been pushed live to that URL.
And in general, changes
take about 10 minutes
to get pushed up.
If you want to create
GitHub pages for a project,
this is often
something you would do.
You started with a README
file, you upgraded to a wiki,
but eventually you
want not just room
for more content but also a
more attractive look and feel.
If you want to do this it's
basically the same process
as you'd do if you were
creating a new site
for a username or
an organization.
The difference is
that you're not
going to create a
new project, it's
going to create a new branch
within an existing project.
So you just go into settings,
select the GitHub Pages
Automatic Page Generator, write
the content, select a layout,
publish it, and the
content you created
will now be in your
gh-pages branch.
Let's go through this process.
So we've got an
existing repository.
We click on "Settings."
Scroll down to "GitHub Pages,"
and click on the "Automatic page
generator."
It then gives us a form for
entering our initial content.
We change the title,
replace the description
with the content we want to
share, and save the page.
We then pick a theme.
And once we're done with that
we click on the "Publish" button.
For a user or organization page,
the URL is going to be the user
or organization name .github.io.
For a project page
though, the default URL
is going to be
username.github.io slash
repository name.
So for example,
in this case, it's
deadlyvipers.github.io/dojo
rules.
If you want to be able to
access your GitHub Pages
content at a custom
domain name, you
can set that up really easily.
You just create a
file called "CNAME"
that is in the root
of your repository.
And of course, it's got to
to be on the same branch
as your GitHub Pages content.
And then all you need
to do is configure
that CNAME with your DNS host.
So let's look at the process.
Here we're going to
create a custom URL
to get to the deadly
vipers homepage.
Firstly, we go to the
pages repo that we created.
So we're working here
in the master branch.
Then we want to add
a file called CNAME.
We could clone the repository,
download it, and make changes
locally, but let's
just make the change
by clicking to add a new
file right through GitHub.
We'll name that file "CNAME."
All we need to put in this
file is the domain name
that we want to point to
this GitHub Pages site.
We need to put a commit message
in and save this change.
Next, we need to go to our DNS
provider to add a new record.
And all we need to do
is find the domain name,
look at the host records, and
add a new CNAME for whatever
subdomain we want, in this
case pages.deadlyviper.com,
and point that to the
username.github.io.
So in this case,
deadlyvipers.github.io.
Let's see what that's done.
Well, if you go to
the original URL,
you see that the
content is here.
But if we go straight to
pages.deadlyviper.com,
you see there's nothing here.
And in fact, you'll
have to wait usually
10 or 15 minutes for the DNS to
propogate to get to the point
where you can see the content
at pages.deadlyviper.com.
We're done with this section.
You might want to create a
GitHub Pages for your username
or even for an organization.
Have fun, and we'll see
you in the next level.