[SINGING] She will clone and
fork your repos faster than you
can blink, and then tag,
push, and pull requests
while pouring a drink.
She's studied wikis and
pages to promote her skills,
but it's the branching
and the merging
which will pay all the bills.
Your only chance to find
her is the user workflow.
Commit to her release and
you can access control.
You'll be pushing past security
to join her at the club,
just to catch a glimpse
of her Mastering GitHub.
There are a number of
options available when
you configure a new repository.
Most of them you'll be
familiar, with but there
might be one or two that
you've not encountered before.
Once you've created a
repository, go into Settings
and click on the Options tab.
There are a couple of
interesting settings
under the Options tab.
One of the first is
the ability to change
the name of your repository.
And the best part is,
if you rename your repo,
any existing links to
it will still work.
They would just get
forwarded right along.
Another interesting
option is the ability
to change the default
branch from master.
Most of the time,
you wouldn't do this,
but let's say that you
had a whole bunch of users
very comfortable
with subversion.
If you wanted to, you could
create a new branch called
"Trunk" and make that
the default branch.
Why does the default
branch matter?
Well, it's used for
a number of things.
One example would be when you
close an issue using a commit,
the issue won't be
closed until that
commit is merged into
the default branch.
So it's important to think
what default branch you
want and configure
that correctly.
Of course, you can also
configure wikis and issues,
switching them on and off, as
we saw in earlier sections.
And, you can configure GitHub
pages to use the Automatic Page
Generator to create
your GH pages
branch with some content
for showcasing your project.
There are a few options you
need to be careful about.
You can take a repository and
change its status from public
to private, or vice versa.
You can transfer the
ownership to any other user
or an organization that
you're responsible for,
or you can delete
the repository.
Under the "Collaborators"
tab, you can
add new people, based on
their GitHub username,
to collaborate with
you on a project.
If it's a private repository,
you need to do this for them
to be able to see it at all.
If it's a public repo,
you're giving them full
read and write access.
But you're not giving them
administrative access.
So, for example, they can't
change settings for the site
or add new collaborators
themselves.
There are settings for
managing webhooks and services
and deploy keys, but we'll be
looking at those little later
in this course.
Let's quickly go
through the process
of configuring a new repository.
In this case, we're going
to add a new repository
to this organization,
to deadlyvipers.
We're going to give it a
name, make sure it's unique,
and, optionally, give
it a short description.
And in this case,
we're to initialize it
with a README file
so we don't need
to create files locally and
push them up to the server.
We do that, and now we
have a new repository
with a README file.
Now let's go into Settings.
And in this case,
we want to limit it
so that only collaborators
can add and change content
on the wiki.
And let's rename the
project, as well.
Now, let's talk a little
bit about managing
a project using GitHub.
Let's say you were getting
started with the Rails Project.
Well, the first thing you want
to do with any new project
is look at the README file.
It should give you information
on the goals of the project
and how to download
and get it configured
so you can get it
running locally
and start to run the tests.
Next, you might want
to see what people
have been doing on
the project recently.
And a good way to do that
is, on the right-hand side
of the screen,
there's a Pulse tab.
If you click on that,
it's going to show you
an overview of the
recent activity - what's
been going on in the last
few days, weeks, or months.
Let's look at the information on
this page one piece at a time.
Firstly, you can look at an
overview of pull requests,
showing the number
of merged pull
requests, how many features
are being completed
over the period of
time, and then secondly,
looking at the proposed
pull requests -
how many new features
have been added
to the project in the
last week or month.
You can also see some
statistics around issues
to see how many
issues were closed
and how many new
issues were added.
Most of the time,
hopefully the first number
will be bigger than the second.
You can also get an
overview of who's
been doing what to see
the number of authors,
how many commits they've
made, and how many additions
and deletions there have
been to the code base
in terms of lines of code.
As we scroll down
the Pulse page,
it shows us a listing of
the pull requests that
were merged and proposed.
This is a great way to just
get a sense as to what people
are working on
and talking about.
As we go further
down the page, you'll
see that there's
an issue listing,
as well, so you can see
the specific issues that
have been closed
and opened recently.
This is a great
way to get a sense
of what kind of functionality
you're having trouble with
and what kinds of things you're
successfully clearing out.
Another important
part of the Pulse page
gives you the
conversations listings.
Now, these are
conversations that
occurred on old issues or pull
requests that aren't closed yet.
It's a good way to pick up other
bits and pieces of activity
that might have been reflected
under issues or pull requests.
An important thing to
realize about Pulse
is that it's showing deltas.
It'ss showing you how many
pull requests were merged
or proposed, or how many
issues were opened and closed.
But what it's not showing
you is the total number
of pull requests
that are outstanding
or the total number of
issues that are still live.
So Pulse is a good
tool for getting
a sense of the directionality
of the project,
but the next thing you're
going to want to do
is look at some
absolute information.
For high-level information,
it's also worth
checking out the Graphs section.
There are four graphs here for
Contributors, Commit activity,
Code frequency, and a Punch card.
Let's look at what
each one does.
The Contributors
graph allows you
to find your most
valuable developers.
It allows you to see
who's been doing the most
work over a period of time.
By default, it will show
you the number of commits.
But if you want, you can
see the most active people
based upon the number of
additions or deletions
to the code base.
And you have the ability to
easily select a period of time.
You just drag your mouse
over a part of the graph,
and you'll be able to see
who the key commiters were
in that period of time.
The Commits graph shows the
busiest days and the busiest
weeks.
At the top, it shows
you a series of weeks
so you can see how activity
has changed over time.
And at the bottom, it
shows you the number
of commits per day of the week.
So it looks like
Wednesday is a great day
to code on the Rails Project.
The Code frequency graph is
particularly interesting,
because what it allows you to do
is see the number of additions
and deletions over
a period of time.
So for example, we
can see that there
was a point towards the middle
of this graph where there was
a lot of refactoring
going on in the code base,
even though the
number of commits
might not have been that much
greater than steady state.
And finally, the Punch card graph
allows you to get a sense what
times of day and days of the
week are getting the most
commits.
It's a function of the number of
commits made over the project's
life during any given
hour of any day.
The Punch card graph
gives you an idea
of the most productive times of
the day and days of the week.
Each punch is a function of
the percentage of the project's
commits, over its
lifetime, that have
been made on a particular
hour in a particular day.
So it just gives you
a quick, easy view
of what days and
hours people have
been committing most frequently.
Next, you probably want
to look at that absolute
state of the issues.
How many issues are
there outstanding,
and what are they about?
And as we saw earlier
in the course,
you can filter these based
upon whether they relate
to you or particular
labels or milestones.
And you're also going to
want to look at the absolute
state of pull requests to
see how many outstanding pull
requests are there and
what are people working on.
This is the best
screen for seeing work
in progress for the team.
Finally, it might
be worth looking
at the absolute state
of branches, too.
It will show you how
many different branches
you have in the repository,
irrespective of whether or not
they're connected
to a pull request.
Most of the time, there will be
a correlation between branches
and pull requests.
But, if somebody's doing a pull
request from a remote fork,
there won't be a branch.
And if somebody's
been doing some work
and has shared it on
GitHub but has not yet
started the conversation,
the pull request,
you may have a branch
without a pull request.
Time for you to take a look
at some of these graphs,
and I'll see you in
the next section.