In this section,
we're going to look
at some of the authentication
and authorization options
in GitHub.
It's important to realize
that other than signed tags,
Git doesn't have a native
concept of authentication
at all.
You have to identify yourself as
an author based upon your name
and email, but you can put
any strings into those fields
that you want.
GitHub doesn't do much
about authentication either.
For example, what GitHub does
is it identifies committers
based on their email address.
So let's say you wanted
to get David Heinemeier
Hansson to commit to your repo.
It's easy.
All you need to do is configure
your global user email
to david@basecamp.com.
Make a change, add it, commit
it, push it to your repo,
and as you see on
the screen here,
you too can get David to
contribute to your open source
project.
GitHub follows
the Git philosophy
of trusting your team.
And because of that,
there's fairly limited
access control functionality
built into GitHub,
deliberately.
Owners on a repository
can do anything they want.
And if you add somebody
as a collaborator,
they have full read and
write access to the repo.
They can make any changes
they want to any branches,
and there's nothing you
can do to stop them.
There are, however,
easy things you
can do to undo any changes
that they chose to make.
If you've really got people
working with your project
that you don't want to provide
full read and write access to,
just ask them to create a fork.
Folks are effectively
the main unit
of access control on GitHub.
Another common
pattern is to have
all of you developers working
on the same code base,
but then have a
separate repo that you
send pull requests to that only
your operations manager or team
lead can accept.
Even though permissions
in GitHub are very
coarse-grained - you either
have access to a repo or you
don't - with Git, you often have
a large number of repositories.
And if you also have a
large number of developers,
it can be hard to
manage that mapping.
As you hire a new
developer, making sure
that they have access
to the 30 repos
they should can be
a chore to maintain.
So what you will often do is
use organizations to own code,
either for a company or
for an open source project.
And then, use teams to
provide easier management
of permissions, because you
can add a developer to a team,
and then give team access
to the 30 repos it requires.
It used to be that SSH was the
preferred way of connecting
to GitHub.
Now, both HTTPS and
SSH work just fine,
but generally
HTTPS is preferred.
The only thing you're
going to want to do
is make sure to use
a credential helper,
so you don't have to keep
typing your password every time
you connect.
The other thing
that's worth doing
is upgrading to two
factor authentication.
So every once in a while,
you'll get a text message
from GitHub giving
you an access code
to make sure that if somebody
else gets your password,
they can't access and
change all of your repos.
Access tokens can be
used instead of passwords
for working with Git over HTTPS.
They can also be used to
authenticate to the GitHub
API over basic authentication.
There's a number
reasons why you would
choose to use access tokens.
Firstly, if you've configured
two factor authentication,
your password won't be
enough to connect over HTTPS,
and it won't ask you
for the second factor.
So you need to create
a personal access token
to be able to connect
to GitHub over HTTPS.
And make sure to enable
password caching,
so you don't need to remember
the contents of that password
token.
The second reason you might
want to create an access token
is if you have an application
that you want to provide access
to your GitHub repos, either by
pulling and pushing using Git,
or via the GitHub API.
If that's your use case, you
should create an access token
for that application.
You should treat those
access tokens the same way
as you would passwords,
and make sure never
to commit them to
your code base.
To create an access
token, just go
to Edit Profile, Applications,
and click on Generate New
Token in the Personal
access tokens section.
Give the token a name
that will make it clear
why you created it, command-
line interface for my Mac
or access for the
widget generator.
And you're going to limit
the scope for those tokens.
By default, they have
repo, public repo, user,
and gist scopes.
So that allows you to access
private and public repos,
update user information,
and create gists.
There are a number of
other scopes available
though, depending upon
what you want to do.
So take the time to learn
and see what the scopes are,
and which ones necessary for
the application you're building.
There are a number of different
strategies for connecting
deployment scripts and automated
scripts to your GitHub repo.
There are four common approaches
to providing deployment scripts
with access to your GitHub repo.
You can use SSH agent
forwarding, OAuth access
tokens, deploy keys,
or machine users.
With SSH agent
forwarding, you log
in to the machine that
is running the script,
and you can configure
forwarding so it
will use your SSH credentials.
That's fine, but it
doesn't work if you
want the script to run
when you're not there.
OAuth access tokens can
be a good next step.
They allow you to create
a personal access token
and provide that to the script.
This allows the script to
have the same access you do.
So the good news is it's
very easy to configure.
The bad news is it will have
access to all of your Git
repos, not just the one
you're working with.
The next step is to
create a deploy key.
This allows you to
create something
like a personal
access token, but just
for a single repository,
reducing your security
footprint.
And then, the final
option is, let's
say that you've got a script
that needs access to 20 Git
repos, but you've got
access to 60 Git repos
and you don't want
to share that.
You can just create a
new username on GitHub
just for that
script, and give it
access to only the
repositories that it needs.
Under Edit Ppofile,
security, it's also worth
looking at the Sessions section.
It will show you the
different devices that
have connected to GitHub
as you, and the last times
they connected.
As you scroll down
the page, you can also
see a security history
of the important things
you've done on GitHub.
And it's worth logging
in here every once
in a while to make sure
that somebody else hasn't
been making changes
to your account.
One of the most
important things you
can do to improve the security
of your GitHub account
is to enable two
factor authentication.
So I'd recommend you go
ahead and do that now,
and then we'll see
you in the next level.