Welcome back.
In this level,
we're going to look
at various ways of enhancing
your GitHub experience.
Everything from integrating
third party applications,
to working directly
with the GitHub API.
There are a range of pre-built
services available for easily
integrating well-known
applications like Basecamp,
CircleCI, or Asana
into your repository.
There's a list of
all of the supported
services along with
documentation explaining
what the integration is, and
how to use it in the Git hub
services repo in
the Docs directory.
If you want to add an existing
service to your GitHub repo,
just going to the Settings
tab for your repository,
click on the Webhooks
and Services option,
and then select a service
from the drop down list.
So let's go through the
process of adding a third party
service to a GitHub repo.
Start by clicking on Settings.
Then click on the Webhooks
and Services tab.
And then, after
clicking add services,
you can start to type
the name of the service
you want to integrate.
In this case, we're going to
use Code Climate as an example.
It may ask you
for your password.
And then, once you've
entered that you just
need to follow the
install notes that
are specific to the application
you're working with.
And once you've done
that, click on "Add service"
and you see the service
listed under your services.
And it's easy to add
multiple services.
Let's take a moment
here and add Basecamp
And you would enter the
information it asks for,
add service.
And it'll add it to your list.
It's equally easy
to remove services
just by clicking "Delete "next to
the service you no longer want
integrated with this repository.
Most of the popular
projects you work with
should already have
a service created
for integrating with GitHub.
Each one has
different behaviors.
For example, if you use
the Basecamp or AgileZen
integration, it'll just
add a list of your commits
to the progress page.
That's all it currently does.
Whereas if you something
like JIRA integration,
you can actually resolve
issues in the same way
as you're doing
GitHub issues just
by adding the appropriate
text to your commit messages
and merging them into
your default branch.
Another common
type of integration
is with a continuous
integration tool -
Jenkins, Travis CI, CircleCI,
something like that.
And those will allow your
tests to automatically
be run every time you make
commits to the repository.
With CircleCI, you just sign
up a CircleCI with your GitHub
credentials, and
you don't even need
to configure the
settings in GitHub.
It will automatically
run your tests every time
you push changes to
your GitHub repository.
We've seen how we can integrate
existing services work
with GitHub.
But it's also possible to use
custom webhooks to integrate
your own applications with
your GitHub repository.
In GitHub, you can
create webhooks.
These are HTTP calls that
will notify your application
every time a specific event
happens within a repository.
These hooks can be
used for anything
from updating an
external issue tracker,
to triggering continuous
integration builds,
or deploying to a
production server.
It's basically a post-request
that will get sent to a URL
that you provide to
GitHub in the next screen.
When you add a webhook,
you need to start
by entering the payload URL.
This is the URL
that you want GitHub
to call every time a
notification is fired.
You can select the
content type, usually
you'll use application JSON.
And if you want, you can
provide a secret so you
that the call is
coming from GitHub.
Then finally, you can decide
what should your application
be notified about.
It can just be notified
about push events -
when somebody pushes
changes to GitHub.
It can be notified of
every kind of event that
occurs relating to
your repo, or, you
can select the individual events
that you want your application
to be notified about.
So why don't you
create a webhook,
and we'll see you back
in the next section.