Welcome back.
If you want to integrate your
custom application with GitHub
sometimes a webhook's
all you need.
If you want to get notified
every time somebody pushes
new commits to get up, a
webhook would do that fine.
But what happens if you wanted
to see the history of all
of the commits in a repository?
Or list of all the users who've
committed to that repository?
In that case you'd need
to do something different.
And that's where the
GitHub API comes in.
You'll probably end up working
with a GitHub API using
a programming language
of your choice.
But let's use curl
and the command
line to see some of the kinds of
commands that the API supports.
Let's start with the
simplest possible request.
Let's just use curl to
call API.GitHub.com.
And as you see that,
returns a discoverable list
of all of the API calls
that are available.
You can even do things
like see a full list
of the emojis supported
by GitHub by curling
https://api.GitHub.com/emojis.
Let's try to get a little
publicly accessible information
about a particular user.
We just curl
API.github.com/users/username.
And now let's run
it with the -i flag
so that we can see all
of the header information
as well as just the response.
And you want to notice in
particular here, the RateLimit
limit, and RateLimit
remaining headers, which
show you how many more requests
that you can make, typically
within the next hour.
We can also do things like
getting a list of the publicly
accessible repositories
for a user by using curl
API.github.com/u
sers/username/repos.
If we're going to do anything
more interesting than this,
we'll probably need
to authenticate.
The best way to do that is to
create a personal access token,
and to use that for
testing the API.
Easiest way to do that
is through the website,
and then you can take
that token and use
that to make
authentication course.
So let's say I wanted to get
more information about my user
account.
I could run the
following command.
I'm going to curl -i
to get the headers, -h.
And in the header, I'm going
to ask my authentication token.
And I'm going to call
api.github.com/user to get
my user information.
And it will return
all the information
that's available
about me as a user.
If I want to create
a repository,
I can do another curl command
where I pass the authorization
token, and with -d, put the
name for the repository,
and go to
api.github.com/user/repos.
So I'm posting information
here to add a new repository.
How about adding an
issue to that repo?
Well, if I just type a slightly
different command here,
and now I'm going to create
a title, a body, and let's
say a label of critical.
And I'm going to send this
payload to api.github/repos
/myusername/thereponame/issues.
And by doing that, as you can
see, it creates a new issue.
And if we go to
the website, we see
that that issue has been
created successfully.
But API supports providing
information on activity,
it allows you to create
gists, it provides access
to read and write
more git objects,
so you could really
get into the git db.
And it allows you
to implement any git
functionality via the API.
It also supports working
with issues, organizations,
pull requests, repos,
search, and users, as well
as some miscellaneous
bits and pieces,
like listing the
emojis, or getting
more templates, or
things like that.
Not everyone needs to
use the GitHub API,
so we're not going to
create a challenge on that.
But it's important to understand
the functionality is there,
if you ever need it.
See you in the next level.