[SINGING] She'll clone
and fork your repos
faster than you
can blink, and then
tag, push, and pull
requests while pouring a drink.
She's studied wikis and
pages to promote her skills,
but it's the branching
and the merging
which will pay all the bills.
Your only chance to find
her is to use her workflow.
Commit to her release and
you can access control.
You'll be pushing
passed security
to join her at the
club just to catch
a glimpse of her
Mastering Github.
Welcome back.
In this level,
we're going to look
at hub, which is a command-line
tool that allows you to access
a lot of the
functionality of GitHub
without having to use a browser.
GitHub's great,
but it's a website.
And so because of that, every
time you want to do something,
you're testing your
hand-eye coordination
by using a mouse
to click through.
Whether you're working with
issues or pull requests,
wouldn't it be great
if there was a way
that you could create those and
work with them from the command-
line?
Well, that's exactly what
hub allows you to do.
And it also gives you
a number of superpowers
to get so that you can more
easily clone, fork, and work
with various GitHub-based
repositories.
So the first thing you'll need
to do is get hub installed.
On a Mac, the
easiest way to do it
is to use the Homebrew package
manager and just brew update
to make sure it has
the latest recipes,
and then brew install hub.
If you're on another
operating system,
you're going to want to clone
the GitHub hub repository.
cd into that, and then you're
going to have to rake install.
So you're going to have to
make sure that you have Ruby
installed on your machine
to make this work.
There are two ways of using hub.
The first way is you can use
the hub commands directly.
So if you want to use the
clone or fork functionality,
you can type hub
clone or hub fork.
The second option is
to alias hub as a git.
You can literally just type $
alias hub=git, or more likely,
you're going to want to add
this to your terminal profile.
Then, you can run commands
like git clone or git fork,
and it's going to start by
using the hub functionality
and then just degrade naturally
to using git functionality
if you don't need hub.
There's a couple
of important points
to bear in mind when
working with hub.
The first is, if
you're on Windows
and you're using msysGit,
which is what I'd recommend,
you do not want to
alias hub as git.
It will slow down your
command prompt way too much.
The second, is if you use
Bash or Oh-My-Zsh shell,
you're going to want to
implement tab completion.
I've added a couple
of links to the slide
here that you can use to
download those scripts.
So let's try the basics here.
Let's say we wanted to
create a repo using hub.
How would we do that?
Well, we would git
init, as we usually
would to create a local
repository on our laptops.
Then, create some content
and add and commit that
to the local git repository.
But now here's
where things change.
Instead of having to go
to a browser, go to GitHub
and add a new repo, you
can just type git create
to create a new repository
for this project on GitHub.
Then, just git push -u to set
the default upstream origin
master, and you can even use
git browse to open up a browser
and see this
repository in GitHub.
So let's say we wanted to
create a pull request using hub.
Well, we'd git checkout -b to
create a new branch locally,
create some new code, add
and commit that, and then git
push -u origin new branch
name to push the new branch up
to GitHub.
We need to have a branch before
we can create a pull request.
But then again, instead of
having to go to the browser,
all we need to do is
type git pull-request.
It will throw us into
our default text editor
and allows us to create a title
and description for that pull
request, and it will generate
it for us automatically.
Even cloning is easier with hub.
Instead of having
to type git clone,
HTTPS://github.c
om/username/project,
we can just git clone repo
name if it's our repository.
If it's a repository
owned by somebody else,
we just git clone, username,
or organization , slash repo,
and that will clone the
repository automatically.
Forking a repo is also
much easier using hub.
We would start by cloning
the repository so that we
have a copy of the repo locally.
So let's take the
deadlyvipers/dojo_rules
and clone that.
Then you cd into the directory
and just run git fork.
And that will create your own
fork of this project on GitHub.
Now, the only problem
is if you want
to use things like git
pull-request, at the moment,
origin is still set to
the deadlyvipers fork.
So what you have to do is go in
and edit your .git/config file
to change origin and
the fork of the repo -
to change those names around.
And let's see all of
this in a screencast.
Let's start by creating
a new repository.
We'll initialize it,
create some content,
add, and commit that locally.
And now we can use hub to
create a repository on GitHub.
And then we can push our
changes up to that repo.
Now, let's create a new
branch, and some code to it,
and push that branch
remotely as well,
setting a default upstream.
Now we can use hub here
to git or hub pull-request
to create a pull request.
We enter the title
and description.
And now, if we run hub
browse, we can go to the repo
and see that under
"Pull Requests,"
there is a new
pull request that's
been added and associated to
the branch we just created.
We can also easily
clone a repo just
by entering either the name of
the repo - if it's one of ours -
or the username organization
name and the name of the repo
if it's somebody else's project.
Let's say we want to
fork that project.
Well, if we do that, then pull
request isn't going to work,
because the remotes
are going to be wrong.
So the easiest way to fix this
is just to rename the remotes
in the dot.git/config.
We could create a branch.
Let's add some content
and commit that.
And now we can push
the branch successfully
and we can use git pull-request
to create a pull request,
enter a title and description,
and git browse to see that
on our fork of the repository.
So hub allows you to
do a lot more than just
cloning, forking, and creating
pull requests more quickly.
Let's have a look at
some of the other ways
that you can use hub to
more effectively collaborate
with your team.
Let's say that you're using a
fork-based collaboration model,
and you've got a new
collaborator on your team
that you want to pull
some changes from.
Well now, all you need to do
is git remote add username,
or even just git
fetch username, and it
will add them as a remote
and fetch their changes
so you can see what
they've been working on.
Let's say that there's
a fork of a repository
that you're working on
has a commit you need,
but you're not
collaborating with that fork
on a regular basis.
No problems.
Now you can use git cherry
pick to cherry pick any SHA-1
hash for a commit from any fork
of a project you're working on.
All you do is type $ git
cherry-pick username @ SHA-1
hash, and it will pull down that
commit from that fork and apply
it to your local branch.
Another common
problem is when you
want to check out
a pull request,
but it's a fork that you've
not worked with before.
You don't have it
set up as a remote.
With hub, that's
no problem at all.
You just git checkout, the
URL of the pull request,
and then the name
of the custom brunch
you'd like to create locally.
And it will go find the
fork, find the branch,
and create that as a
custom branch for you
locally that you can then run
the tests and see how it works.
Let's say that somebody
has created a pull request
and you want to merge it in.
But again, you don't have
their fork set up as a remote.
No problem at all.
With hub, all you need to do
is type $ git merge and give
the URL of the pull request,
and it will automatically handle
the process of finding
the appropriate branch
on the necessary fork
and merging it in.
Once you've done the merge,
you've then got two Options.
If you like what you see,
you can push the merge
back up to GitHub.
If it was just for
test integration -
maybe you were just trying
to test what it would be like
to integrate somebody else's
feature banch with your own -
you can just $ git reset --hard
HEAD~1 to throw away the merge
and continue with your work.
So let's try a
couple of scenarios
right here on the command line.
Let's first start
by using git fetch
username to pull from
a fork and to view
what somebody else on our
team's been working on.
We could even cherry pick.
How about we look
at a fork that we
don't have a copy
of locally and that
we don't have set
up as a remote?
And let's find a commit on it
that we'd like to work with.
So now we can just git
cherry-pick with the username
and the SHA-1 hash
for that commit,
and it will pull that down
and add it to our branch.
And let's say we
want to merge a pull
request from
somebody else's fork.
We can just git merge
and then provide
the URL for the pull request,
and it will merge it,
creating a merge commit,
on our local master branch.
And then if we're happy with
that and the tests run well,
we can push those
changes back up to GitHub
to close the pull request.
Why don't you have
a play with hub?
We've created some
challenges that you
can use to get some hands-on
experience working with this.
I'll see you in the outro video.
Let's start with just
a little bit of theory.
Let's not do that.
[LAUGHTER]
Let's imagine there's an
impossibly complex diagram
with way too many
lines and arrows.
[LAUGHTER]
--called deadlyviper.com--
If you had a whole bunch of
people moving [MUMBLING].
[LAUGHTER]
That have ever been in
made within a repository.
Yeah.
Ever been in made.
Ever been made.