[SINGING] 4:30 in the morning,
coding front-end on your site.
Console errors warning —
you don't know how to fight.
Reusable and flexible
directives are what you need.
Link and scope are sensible
in reliant apps with speed.
Services will be okay
to craft your own Note Wrangler.
You are on your way to
Staying Sharp with Angular.
Welcome.
My name is Alyssa Nicoll
and you're watching
Staying Sharp with Angular.js.
In this course, we'll be
furthering our Angular skills.
The app we're going to build
is called Note Wrangler,
and it uses Angular to
create and manage notes.
We'll be learning about
the route provider
and how to create flexible
directives and services
that will be reusable across
our Note Wrangler application.
Let's get started with routes.
In this first section, we're
going to be wiring together
our views.
We want to start this
Angular app from ground zero
so that you guys can see the
process as we go through it.
Here you can see we have all of
these static HTML and CSS files
from our designer.
Our goal now is to take this
and build it into a living
and breathing Angular app.
To get started, we're going to
create a few new directories
to organize our code.
Out in the wild, you might
see some applications
that put all of their
controllers and services
in one massive file.
We think it's best to
encapsulate each controller,
service, filter, or
directive into their own file
and give them their
own directory.
Inside our controllers
directory you'll
see that we have a separate
file for each controller.
So for notes index,
edit, show, et cetera,
each one gets their own file.
Now let's look at the HTML.
In the notes-index.html
and users-index.html,
there's a lot of redundancy.
They both start with the HTML
tag and end with HTML tag.
Let's take a look
inside those files
and see what's
actually repeated.
Here's the notes index.
As you can see, there's quite a
bit of code that's duplicated.
The only unique code
that exists is inside
the div that has the
class of main-wrapper.
If we go ahead and bring our
users index onto the screen,
you can see that
inside of that div,
called main-wrapper
as well, is the only
unique chunk of code for users.
So what we're going to do
is take those two pieces
of unique code and
separate them out
into their own template files.
We're going to place these
files into their own templates
directory with a pages
directory inside of that
and then a notes or users
directory inside of that.
But you might
notice there's still
some duplication going on.
Having a notes index file
inside a notes directory
is a little redundant, so we can
go ahead and remove the notes
or users prefix
off of those files
since they live inside
of their own directory
that tells you that information.
Remember all of that
duplicate HTML code
that we just pushed
to the side earlier?
Well, now we're going to take
it and just have one copy of it
in our main index file.
And then at the very top in
the HTML tag, you guessed it,
we're going to have an
ng-app attribute that labels
our application Note Wrangler.
Inside of our main-wrapper
you can also
see that it's empty
because that's
where our unique content
was removed from.
If we open our application
in the web browser,
you can see that our main
layout from the index file
is being loaded in,
which is awesome,
but nothing else is displaying.
So if we go to the URL
with /notes at the end,
what do we expect to happen?
Well, I would anticipate
a list of notes
being shown, the note index.
But how do we include that
template in this spot?
We can include that template
by simply defining an Angular
route.
Angular is going to
look at the /notes URL,
look into the routes.js file,
and find what template it needs
to include.
In this case, that's
the notes index.
There are four steps to
using routing in any Angular
application.
Let's go ahead and
list them out now.
First you're going
to use ngView.
Then you'll load
the ngRoute library.
Third, you're going to
import ngRoute module.
And then last, you get to
define the actual route itself.
Let's go ahead and implement
each of these steps together.
So the first step to routing happiness: ngView.
You need to use the ngView attribute
where you want to tell Angular, "Load in the template here."
In our case, that would be inside the div main-wrapper
where we took out the unique code.
The next step, loading
the ngRoute library,
used to not always be required.
The route library used to be
a part of the Angular core.
But in order to slim down, they
stripped that out and now we
have to include it in our app
if we want to use routes.
So here, in our main
index file, we're
going to include the script to
our js/vendor/angular-route
file.
Now that we've
loaded ngRoute, we
can include it in our
main application module.
We'll create an app.js
file, declare angular.module
name it NoteWrangler,
and go ahead and include
our ngRoute dependency here.
Now we can start declaring our
routes in a routes.js file.
We'll say angular.module
NoteWrangler again
at the top of the file,
and then in the application's
config function, we'll
include route provider.
This will allow us to
specify our routes.
You might be wondering
why we're not
creating an app variable like we
did in Shaping up with Angular.
We said var app
equals angular.module,
and then we reused that
application variable
over and over again any time
we wanted to attach something
to our application module.
This is a bad
practice for reasons
that we're not going to
get into in this course,
but just note that re-declaring
angular.module each time is
better.
Finally, the moment you've
all been waiting for.
We actually get
to define a route.
So with that route provider
that we just got access to
we have a couple of methods
that we're going to use.
There is .when, which will
allow you to add a new route
definition to the route service.
And there's .otherwise.
This method will allow
us to define a route
when no other route is matched.
Now we get to define
our first route.
We're going to say
routeProvider.when,
and then pass in the path,
which, in this case, is /notes.
Next, we specify
the template that we
want to load in by
passing in an object
with a template URL
property and the path
to the template as the value.
Now when we go back to
our application to /notes,
you can see that all the
notes are being loaded in with
the notes index template.
Next, we're going to
define our users route.
So when /users is visited, we
want the users index template
to be loaded in.
Notice we're not re-declaring
route provider each time.
We're just chaining on
the when methods as we go.
If we go /users in
our Note Wrangler app,
you can see now that all of
the users are being loaded in.
When you go to the root of
our application, simply /,
you'll see that it's just our layout.
Nothing else is being displayed.
So we can go ahead and declare
another .when method and say
when / load in the template
URL for the notes index.
The last route that we're going
to declare in this section
is a catch-all route.
It's basically saying,
"If nothing else matches, do this."
So we're going to use
our .otherwise method
that we talked about earlier.
We'll simply say .otherwise.
And then we'll
redirect to the root.
If we head on back
over to the browser,
you can see that our templates
are wired up now and working
with the navigation.
If we click on Users,
the Users page loads in
and they're all listed out.
Click on Notes.
The notes index
template comes in.
And then if we go
to the root, you
can see that also the notes
are being loaded in there.
If you look closely
at the URL, you
might be wondering why I have
app-level-1 in my path.
Well, you can't just
open an index file
for an Angular application and
expect it to work statically.
You need something on the
back-end to serve it up.
Sometimes people will use
Brackets, an application
that does this for you.
Other people will use Node.
I personally used Rails here
and put all of the levels
inside of one public folder.
So now if I change to
Level 2, 3, 4,
you can see the app in
its different states.
I'll provide you the link
at the end of the course
so that you can go and download
all of those if you would like.
Let's get started on challenges.