In this section,
we'll be covering
the logic in our routes and
building out our app further.
Remember the $http service
from the first Angular course?
This is a service
that can be used
to get or put, grab
data, manipulate
data, from an outside source.
$http has a get, post, put,
and delete method, which we'll
be using in our application.
It also gives us the ability
to pass in an object.
For instance, when
you're creating data.
Back into our routes.
Not only can routes have
templates associated with them,
but we can also
have controllers.
So for instance, when the /notes
request comes in, we can say,
"Listen to this controller
and load in this template."
The same thing with users.
There are two ways to link
a controller to a route.
The first is inline.
So back into our routes file
inside of the notes route,
we're going to
define a controller
and put the function right here.
That can get a bit
lengthy, though.
If we look back at
our application tree,
you can see we've
already set aside
different files for
each controller.
Inside the notes
index controller
let's go ahead and re-declare
our Angular module.
And then we can declare
our notes index controller.
Now back inside routes.js
in our notes route,
we'll specify this
notes index controller
and we'll also give it an
alias with controllerAs.
Back inside our notes
index controller,
we're going to use
the $http get method
in order to actually
grab some note data.
So here we'll say $http,
specify the get method,
and give it the URL
where it's going
to go and grab the data from.
If this $http call is successful,
we'll assign the returned data
to this.notes.
Now our template will have
access to this list of notes
and we can use ng-repeat
to loop through them.
We'll say ng-repeat equals
note in our alias index
indexController.notes.
For each note, we're going to
display its title and icon.
All of this markup
should look familiar.
Back in the browser, we
see that all of the notes
are loaded dynamically and their
icons and titles are displayed.
What if we wanted
to click on a note
and be able to view more
information about that note
like you see here?
How could we accomplish this?
So let's walk through the logic
of what we want to happen.
First, the note is clicked.
Next, the route changes
to /notes/ the note id.
And then lastly, the route loads
in the view with that note's
information.
In order to accomplish
this, first we'll
give each note anchor an ng-href
that will plug in the note id
to the path.
Then in our routes, let's
define our notes id route.
We'll say .when
/notes/:id.
The :id is specifying
that a route parameter is here.
After that, we'll pass
in the template URL
and controller for notes
show and give that controller
an alias.
You might be
wondering, though, how
do we get that id
out of the route?
Dun dun dun.
Route parameters.
You can use route
params in order
to grab that note
id out of the URL.
So back inside our
notes show controller,
we can pass in $routeParams
into our function
and then we can create
a get method and append
that $routeParams.id
at the end of it
to fetch the data
for that single note.
As you can see, we're attaching
this to var controller
outside the success callback.
Then, inside the success,
we're saying controller.note
and setting it equal to data.
This keyword inside the
callback no longer references
the controller, so we
have to do it this way.
Lastly, we'll create
our notes show
template that will display
the information for that one
single note.
As you can see in our application,
each individual note now displays a note show page
when you click them.
Let's go ahead and flesh
out one last controller.
We'll do the notes
create controller.
If you think about
it, our notes create
controller is going to need
a method that our form can
call to save a new note.
Inside our note
create controller,
we're going to attach
a saveNote function.
Inside that function's
parameters, we'll pass it note.
That note is the
note data that we're
getting sent from our form.
Then we'll make an $http
call with a method of post,
give it the URL that
we're sending our data to,
and lastly the note
object, which contains all
of the new note's information.
What if our $http call fails?
We need to be able to give
this feedback to our user.
So let's go ahead and create a
this.errors variable and set
it equal to null.
Currently there are no errors.
Then we'll declare the catch
callback, which will only
be called if there's an error.
And we'll assign that error to
the variable we just created,
this.errors.
If you wanted to display
this in our template,
we could use an ng-if there's an error, then go ahead
and display that error.
You might have noticed that
we're making calls to a server
to get or post data.
We're not going
to talk about how
to configure a back end in this
course, but you're in luck.
Code School has a
ton of courses that
cover that, all the
way from Ruby on Rails
to an Express course
that just came out.
This concludes Level 1.
Good luck on those challenges.
Wrangler app.
Wrangler.
Users in our note wrangular app.
Our note wrangular app.