[SINGING] 4:30 in the morning,
coding front-end on your site.
Console errors warning —
you don't know how to fight.
Reusable and flexible
directives are what you need.
Link and scope are sensible
in reliant apps with speed.
Services will be okay
to craft your own Note Wrangler.
You are on your way to
Staying Sharp with Angular.
You're watching Staying
Sharp with Angular.js.
And my name is Alyssa Nicoll.
This is Level 2.
And we'll be jumping into
more advanced directives
and talking about
$scope in this section.
Here's our application
where we last left it.
If we jump into
our notes.html, you
can see that each time
we create a note card,
we're reusing the same
chunk over and over again.
Well, as you learned in
the last Angular course,
we can just take this
duplicated HTML out
and put it into a
template-expanding directive.
We're calling this
directive nw-card.
The nw, of course, stands
for "note wrangler,"
the prefix of our application.
So here in our
notes.html, you can
see we're using this
new directive we just
created — nw-card.
And then we'll define our nw-card directive.
Inside of that function, we'll return an object
with a restrict property set to E for "element"
and a template URL pointing to our HTML.
Say we want to set a
header on our note cards.
We'll go ahead and
create a controller
where we can do
that functionality
and give that controller an
alias with controllerAs.
Inside the controller,
we then can
say this.header
equals a string.
And we'll just say "Note Title" for now.
Then inside the template,
we can print this
to the screen using
an expression,
we'll say bracket,
bracket, card.header.
If you see now, we actually have "Note Title"
being printed on the page.
There's another way
we can implement
this using the $scope variable.
You've probably seen
this before in tutorials
or in other Angular
applications.
So inside the controller
function, we'll pass in $scope.
And then we'll attach header
to $scope instead of this.
Now that we're
attaching to $scope,
we no longer need the alias.
So you get rid of
the controllerAs line
in our directive.
And then inside of the HTML, you can get rid of the card alias.
And the directive still
works as expected.
Let's compare the two
syntaxes side by side.
This is attaching
to $scope behind the scenes.
Whereas with just $scope,
we're attaching it directly
to the controller.
We don't need the card alias.
So both syntaxes lead
to the same result.
We're going to use the $scope
syntax from here on out,
but either are fine.
$Scope is a large part of
Angular as a language.
So why don't you go
get comfortable with it
in a few challenges,
and we'll see you back
in the next section.