Welcome back.
In this section, we're
going to be covering scope,
the config object.
Here's our current directive
code where we left off.
We're attaching a
header to the scope
and setting it to a
string of "Note Title."
What if we wanted to add
numbers to our notes,
though, so they each printed
out Note Title 1, Note
Title 2, so on and so forth?
One way we could try
to accomplish this
is to create a num variable
outside of the return.
We'll go ahead and
set it equal to 1
and then append it
to the $scope.header
inside the controller.
This will go ahead and
increment the number
as each note is created.
In order to understand
scope better,
we simplified our note
card example, like so.
If we look back at the browser,
though, we have a problem.
The notes aren't
incrementing as expected.
Instead of Note Title
1, Note Title 2,
they're just all Note Title 4.
What's happening here, though?
Well, it turns
out the directives
by default inherit
their parent scope.
Well, who's our
parent in this case?
Turns out it's
just the div that's
wrapping all of the note cards.
So each time scope.header is being set,
it's being reassigned on the parent.
That's why we have this
weird number issue.
Each time the
header is being set,
the numbers are being
updated on each of the notes.
In order to fix
this, we no longer
want to use our parent scope.
We want each directive to
have their own isolate scope.
To do this, we simply say
scope and then pass it
an empty object.
Woo!
Now we have an isolate scope.
With that one line,
each directive
now has an isolate
scope, so $scope.header
isn't overriding itself
every time a directive is
added to the page.
Let's review scope.
By default, directives
have their scope
set to false, which means they
inherit from their parents.
So if we set a header variable,
let's say, on the child,
it's actually being
set on the parent.
If we choose to isolate
the scope by passing
an empty object, and we set a
header variable on the child,
it's isolate to that child
and it no longer has access
to anything from the parent.
As we just saw, you can
isolate a directive scope
by passing it an empty object.
This means that
the child no longer
has access to anything on
the parent scope, which
can be problematic.
Remember back in
the notes HTML where
we repeat for each note
in the notes array.
And then the card directive
is going to need access
to that note information.
With our isolate scope that
we just created, however,
it no longer has access.
Inside of our notes HTML,
in the nw-card directive,
we're going to pass
header = note.title.
That's what we want to
pass into this directive.
Then inside the
directive, you'll
simply display header
with an expression.
There's one more thing we need to do in order
to make this work.
Let's jump back
into our directive
and go ahead and get
rid of the controller.
We need a way to let the
directive know it might
be receiving a header variable.
And, if so, bind it to scope.
We need to add a
little configuration.
Inside of our scope object,
we'll say header and then
set it to the @ character.
This tells our
directive that we're
going to be passing
in a string and we
can use that for header
inside of the template.
There are three options when it comes
to binding data on a scope.
You can use the @ character, which we just learned.
You can also use = or &.
If we set header to
= instead of @,
it would use a
two-way binding, so
if the variable
changed in one place,
it's going to change in another.
If we use the
=, we no longer
need the expression
around note.header.
We can remove those brackets.
Our note cards display more
than just the header, however.
We might want to pass
in an icon, for instance.
So you can do this by
simply saying icon =
and pass in as many bindings
as you need into that object.
Now our directive will
be expecting an icon,
so let's go ahead and say
icon = and set it
to note.icon in the directive.
And then inside the template,
we can use the icon.
The wonderful thing about
isolating a scope is now
your directive is flexible.
You can reuse it in
multiple situations.
So, for instance,
in our first situation,
we were using it
to display notes.
But what if we wanted to
display our users using
the same nw-card directive?
Instead of the note title, we
would just pass in a user.name.
Instead of an icon, we could
pass in a user's image.
With flexible directives, the
possibilities are endless.
If we take a look
in our browser,
you see that our notes are
displaying with actual titles
and icons.
Before we go into
challenges, I want
to talk about the
difference between the scope
object and $scope.
It can get a little confusing.
The scope object is used to
isolate a directive scope,
whereas $scope
in our controller
is used to set values or
functions on the scope.
Why don't you jump
into the challenges,
and I'll see you in the
last section for Level 2.