Howdy, howdy.
In this section, we're
going to be covering link.
Here we have our application
in its current state.
But wouldn't it be nice if
we could add a little bit
more information for each note?
What if we clicked
on each note card
and it could display
the note description?
Inside the card
template, we have
a description being displayed,
but it has a class of hidden.
We're going to add
some CSS that will
make that class of
hidden display none.
And when someone
clicks on it, we
want to toggle this
hidden class on and off.
To add this click behavior,
we'll use some jQuery.
We're going to listen for the
click on event on the div,
and then toggle the display
class on the paragraph.
But where does this
functionality go?
One place we can put this
jQuery is inside the controller,
but this isn't a best practice.
The jQuery selector is
searching the entire DOM.
And the controller may run
before the HTML is even
rendered.
If we're not going to put this
in the controller, where then?
Well, it turns out that each
directive has a link function.
The link function runs
after the directive has
been compiled and linked up.
This is the best spot to do
any DOM manipulation or logic
functionality.
If you'll notice,
though, we're still
searching the entire
DOM, which is bad.
It's not the best
for performance.
Luckily, link has an
element parameter.
The first parameter
for link is scope
and the second is the element.
The element refers to
the outermost element
for the directive,
which in this case
is the div with
the class of card.
Here's what our jQuery looks
like now using the element
selector from the link function.
We're no longer
searching the entire DOM.
Link has an additional
attrs parameter,
which allows us to access any
of the attributes that are
set on the directive's element.
So here, in our nw-card directive,
we have header and description that we
can pull out from attrs.
If we wanted to do a little debugging,
we could log header with console.log,
and then attrs.header.
If we look at our cards
now, we are successfully
displaying the description
when they're clicked,
which is awesome.
It's what we wanted.
But if you notice the
markdown, it's not quite parsed
how we expected.
So if you see, it says markers
on an asterisk asterisk DOM
element asterisk asterisk, which
in all reality that should just
be bolded and the asterisk
should not be showing.
One way we can do this is to
download an external JavaScript
library.
We found markdown.js out there
on the interwebs, moved it
into our Vendors
folder, and then we
included it with a script
tag in our index.html.
A good place to use
this external library
is inside our Link function.
As we just learned
earlier, the link function
is the perfect place to
manipulate DOM elements.
So as you see here
in our link function,
we're going to access
the body through scope.
So we'll say scope.body equals,
and we'll call our markdown
library method.
So it's markdown.toHTML.
And then we'll pass
it the scope.body.
If we look back at
our note cards now,
we see that it's working.
It's translating the
markdown to HTML,
but it's not actually
rendering it on the screen.
It's just printing out the tags.
Why is this happening?
Well, it turns out you
have to tell Angular
that it can trust
this and actually
render it to the screen.
We need to tell
Angular it's safe HTML.
And we'll use two
things to do this.
One, ngBindHtml and two, $sce.
If you ever try to insert HTML
with an Angular expression,
you'll notice that it doesn't
work, like we just saw.
In order to render
HTML onto the page,
we need to pass it into the
element with ngBindHtml.
Now we need to tell
Angular the HTML
we're about to pass to it
is safe and okay to render.
We'll use $sce to do that.
$sce is a Strict Contextual
Escaping service.
It's saying, "I
trust this as HTML.
Don't worry about escaping this.
Go ahead and render it."
If we head on over
back to the browser,
you can see that each
note card, when clicked,
displays their description
without all of those HTML tags
flying around.
As you can see,
the link function
is a perfect place to do DOM
manipulation and any logic
functionality you might
need in your directive.
So go practice it
in the challenges,
and I'll see you
back in Level 3.
—this array.
Has allowed us.
I don't know how
to go into link.
You might not know
this, but this-- yeah,
he may not know this, but this.