[SINGING] 4:30 in the morning,
coding front-end on your site.
Console errors warning —
you don't know how to fight.
Reusable and flexible
directives are what you need.
Link and scope are sensible
in reliant apps with speed.
Services will be okay to
craft your own Note Wrangler.
You are on your way to
Staying Sharp with Angular.
You're watching Staying
Sharp with Angular.js.
My name is
Alyssa Nicoll, and this
is Level 3, where we're
going over services.
Back inside our
application, you can
see that we have a
controllers directory.
In there, you'll find a
notes edit controller.
Inside our notes
edit controller,
you'll see that we have
an $http put method call.
It's saving our note
object up to the database.
This code is fine,
but it's not reusable
across our application, and
it's also harder to test.
This is where services come in.
Services hold functions that
are responsible for getting
and connecting data, and sharing
it across our application.
So if we create a
service, we can then
use that service inside of a controller, a directive,
a filter, and even another service.
To get started with our
service, first we'll
create a note.js file inside
of our services directory.
Then inside the
index.html, we'll
include it with a script tag.
To define a service,
there are five recipes
you can choose from.
The two most
popular, and the ones
that we'll be using
in this course,
are factory and provider.
Factory, the most
commonly used one,
is used to share functions and
objects across an application.
Provider is used for
the exact same thing,
but it also allows
for configuration.
Inside our note.js
file, we're going
to define a service
using the factory recipe.
So we'll say angular.module
at the very top.
We'll define our service
with .factory.
We'll then name
our service "Note,"
and then give the
function, the service name,
plus the recipe name — in
this case, NoteFactory.
That's a commonly
used convention
that you'll see
throughout this course.
So you can refer back to
it during the challenges,
we've placed the
factory recipe below.
Remember, the reason we're
creating a factory service
is to encapsulate some
of these $http methods.
So later on in
our service, we're
going to make an all
and a create method.
The all will encapsulate
this $http get method
to grab all of the notes.
So back inside our service,
we need to return an object.
Inside that object, we'll
create an all property
that has a function value.
That function will return
the $http get method.
We'll also define
a create property,
which will have a function
value that will take in a note.
This note will be used
in our $http post call,
and the result of
the call is returned.
Now back inside our
notes index controller,
it's still using
the old $http call.
It needs to be using the
notes factory we just created.
To use the factory, we
need to first inject it
into the function.
Then we can call
it, saying note.all,
and attach it to our success.
We obviously still
need to finish wiring
up the create method, but
I'll leave that up to you.
Good luck in the challenges,
and I'll see you back
in the next section.