Hello.
In this section, we're
covering another factory.
The next feature we want to
implement in our Note Wrangler
app is having a glamorous
photo for each of our users.
Maybe a puppy, too, but
we'll get to that later.
A solution to this is to
use the Gravatar service.
Gravatar is a very helpful web
app that allows people like me
or you to upload
images associated
with an email address.
Then we can use,
in our application,
that email address
to grab those photos.
In order to use someone's
Gravatar in our application,
there are three steps.
First, you need to hash
their email address.
Then, you append their
hashed email address
to a Gravatar URL.
Lastly, use this
URL in the template
with an ng-src attribute.
Hold on.
This sounds like
shared functionality
across our application,
which makes
me think it's service time.
Let's create a service
for this that we can then
use in the controllers
and then in the templates.
[SINGING] We need a Gravatar.
Make a service.
We need a Gravatar.
Fade out to black.
So as expected, in our
services directory,
we'll create a gravatar.js file.
And then we'll use the factory
recipe to define our service.
We'll name it Gravatar, and
then the function, of course,
will be named GravatarFactory.
Before we create the
meat of this factory,
we're going to need some
reusable variables that we can
define outside of the return.
We'll say var
avatarSize = 80,
which is setting a default
size for our avatar images.
This avatar size variable
will be used later
in the URL, which will return
us different sizes of the image
we're requesting.
So as you see here,
if we say size 100,
it'll give us an
itty-bitty picture,
whereas if we say
size 500, it'll
give us a massive picture.
Along with a default avatar
size to append to the link,
we'll need a reusable link
variable for the Gravatar size.
So we'll say var avatarURL
and we'll give it the default,
http://gravatar.com/avatar/.
That will be used
at the beginning
of each of these URLs.
Now we need to go back
to these three steps
and make some magic happen.
So first off, hashing the email.
How do we hash-ify something?
Well, there's a fun
thing called CryptoJS.
Stay with me.
CryptoJS is a simple
JavaScript library
that has an .MD5 function.
You can pass this
function a string,
and it will return
that string hash-ified.
In our index, in order to
have access to CryptoJS,
we'll need to include
this script tag.
The next step — we'll need to
add this hash onto our Gravatar
URL.
So back into our service.
We'll create a generate
property with a function
that takes an email.
That will return an avatar
URL plus the CryptoJS
hash-ified email, plus the size.
And if you'll notice,
we have to call
toString on that avatar
size, because it's currently
a number.
Here is our beautiful and
complete Gravatar service.
In order to call it, we need to
first inject it and then call
the generate method off
of it, like you see here.
[LAUGHS]
We can actually
simplify this code.
If your service only contains
one function, instead
of returning an object
with that one function,
you can just return
the function, like so.
And then to call the service,
you simply call Gravatar.
Inside our users index
template, our nw-card directive
now needs an image attribute.
We'll set that image attribute
to call the gravatarUrl method
we just made.
To make this work,
we obviously need
to go back into the
directive and configure
image in the scope.
We'll two-way bind it
with the = character.
Now we can go back into
the nw-card template
and use ng-src to display
the Gravatar image.
And all of our users
have glamorous photos.
Let's go through the five
different service recipes,
just so you're aware of
them as you're building out
Angular apps on your own.
First there's Value,
which is used often.
It's the simplest
service recipe,
and it's used for sharing just
a value throughout your app
repeatedly.
Then there's Factory, which
is used for sharing methods
and objects, like we
learned previously.
Next there's Service.
Yes, it is a Service
service recipe.
It's used for sharing instances
of methods and objects,
instead of the actual
method or object.
The fourth recipe is Provider.
It's used for sharing methods
and objects like a factory
but allows for configuration.
The last recipe is Constant.
It's used for sharing a
value within an application
configuration.
No worries.
There won't be a pop
quiz on all five recipes.
Just go practice
using Factory again,
and I'll see you back
in the third section.