Welcome back.
In this section, we're
talking about Provider.
In the last section,
we used a factory
to generate a Gravatar URL.
The problem with this is that
our avatarSize variable was
hard set, and not configurable.
So if we wanted to be able to
change that size, you can't.
You're basically stuck
with 80 for your life.
So the solution is simple:
We can use a Provider recipe.
If you remember before
when we mentioned it,
it's used exactly
like a factory,
but it allows for configuration.
The main difference between
a factory and a provider
is that we have to use
this $get function.
All providers have this.
This $get function is where
you can inject services
that your Provider might need.
However, providers run
before everything else,
so the only thing
you can inject right
at this top level of the
provider is other providers.
So now for the nitty gritty
task of refactoring our Gravatar
service from a factory
into a provider.
The first step of
this, of course,
would just change
.factory to .provider.
The next step is
to wrap the return
with an anonymous function,
and set that equal to
this.$get, because
remember, all providers
have a $get.
Our Gravatar
provider is currently
only returning one function.
But remember, you can return an
object with multiple functions,
and all of that
would be surrounded
with the $get function.
To call the provider, it's
just like calling our factory.
Back inside of users
index controller,
you just inject Gravatar
and call the service.
But how do we do the
configuration bit,
the entire point of
using a provider?
To do this, we need to
define a method for each item
that we want to configure.
Well, we just said we want
to do the avatar size.
So let's create an
anonymous function,
and set it equal to
this.setSize.
Inside of the function, we'll
set avatarSize = size
that we passed in.
Now we get to use
the configurable part
of a provider.
So back in our
app.js file, we'll
define a config method
on our main app module,
and we inject the
Gravatar provider.
We'll then call the GravatarProvider.setSize method,
and pass it whatever size
we want to configure —
in this case, 100.
Notice that the config gets
passed GravatarProvider, not
just Gravatar.
This is important, because
if you pass it Gravatar
it won't work.
You need to pass it the
function name, GravatarProvider.
If you go back in the browser
now, and look at the users
index page, all of the
cards have glamorous photos
for each of our users.
So why don't you go
practice using Provider
in the challenges, and I'll see
you back in our last section.