Welcome back.
In this section, we're
covering $resource.
So far, we've only been using
the built-in $http service
to grab or change data, as you
see here in our note.js file.
It's pretty common in
web apps that you'll
have code that
calls web services,
and they reuse a lot
of these methods.
If only there was a
way to simplify this.
I mean, all this code that's
being reused in so many apps?
Well, it turns out
there's a thing called
$resource that includes
all of these by default.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
The first step, as with
most external things,
is to install ngResource and
put it in our Vendors folder.
We're also going to include it
with a script tag in our index
file.
We need to give our main
application module access
to ngResource so we can
use it across our app.
So as you guessed, back
in the app.js file,
we're going to
inject ngResource.
Back inside our note factory
that we want to clean up,
we're going to inject
$resource and then call it,
sending in the URL
for the API that we're
going to call for the data.
This one resource line
returns similar functionality
to all of these $http calls.
Isn't that nifty?
It also simplifies what
we need to do in order
to call the $resource.
So what about calling these
resources from the controller?
How does it differ from $http?
Well, let's go back into
the notes show controller.
Instead of saying Note.find
and passing it the $routeParam,
we'll now do Note.get and
we'll pass id: $routeParams.id.
These do the same thing.
In the notes index controller,
instead of calling Note.all,
we will call a
Note.query method.
Same thing.
Just shorter.
In the note create controller,
instead of calling Note.create,
we're going to call Note.$save.
Notice that our catch
and finally from earlier
can still be used.
We haven't created a delete
functionality thus far.
But if we wanted to, we could
create a note edit controller,
and then inside of that, make
a function for deleting notes.
We could then use resource yet
again with a $delete method.
This would probably be used by
creating a Delete button, maybe
on the notes themselves,
and from there you
could call ng-click deleteNote.
There's also a substitute
$remove method.
It does the same thing, but
it's helpful for IE browsers
because delete is
a reserved word.
So to sum up, look at
all the awesome things
we just did with $resource.
It's allowed us to
shorten our code
and do things like
get a single resource,
get all the resources,
delete a resource,
and create a new resource.
But what about update?
There isn't an update
method, but resource
has the handy-dandy
feature of being
able to add custom functions.
So we'll just add
our own update method
and set it equal to method PUT.
Now in order to call the
custom resource method we just
created, we could go into
note edit controller, call
update on the instance
of the note passed in.
That's it for $resource.
Go practice in the challenges,
and I'll see you back
in Level 4.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Avatar service factory thing.
[LAUGHTER]
And don't reach so far out.
Because I'm a bird?
No, 'cause then your
hands'll be gone.
[LAUGHTER] Sorry.
I was imagining
myself without hands.
[LAUGHTER]
No?
I was just going to fade
to black while I'm dancing.
[LAUGHING]