[SINGING] 4:30 in the morning,
coding front-end on your site.
Console errors warning —
you don't know how to fight.
Reusable and flexible
directives are what you need.
Link and scope are sensible
in reliant apps with speed.
Services will be okay
to craft your own Note Wrangler.
You are on your way to
Staying Sharp with Angular.
You're watching Staying
Sharp with Angular.js.
My name is Alyssa Nicoll,
and this is Level 4 —
we're covering reusable directives.
Our notes index
page is currently
displaying a list of all
our notes, which is great.
But wouldn't it be
even better if we could
sort notes by categories?
What if we had this
sidebar over here that
had a list of the
categories available
and when you clicked
on it, it would then
filter through the
notes and display them
based on the category?
We're going to start
off by creating
an nw-category-select directive.
Inside the returned
object, we're
going to set replace to true,
restrict to E for element,
and then pass in
the template URL.
Our category-select needs
access to a list of categories.
So let's use a category
service to make this happen.
Should we do this
in the controller
or the link of the directive?
What do you think?
You guessed it!
Our link function is where we
should access the data from.
So inside the link
function, we're
going to call the
category service.
We'll say category.query and set
it equal to scope.categories.
Time to mock up
the templates now.
We have a list of
categories, but we
need to display them
somewhere with the markup.
So we could put all of it in
nw-category-select template,
but the children, the
nw-category items,
are going to have
additional functionality.
And so that's what we want
to split this out now.
So each of our categories
will have their own directive
and template.
So if we start coding out
the HTML for our select,
here's what it would look like.
Pretty standard stuff.
Inside the card div
is where you would
expect all of the category
items to be listed out.
So here we'll use the
nw-category-item directive,
and we'll use an
ng-repeat to loop
through each category
in categories.
For each one, we need to
pass in the category variable
because each directive
will have an isolate scope.
So now building out the
markup for the category item,
we're going to make sure
and show the icon, the name,
and the count of each category.
The count, as you
probably guessed,
is just the number of
notes in each category.
Now it's time to create the
category item directive.
So we'll name it
nw-category-item, as expected,
return an object that's
restricted to E for element,
and give it the template URL.
As we mentioned
earlier, we're going
to isolate its scope and
two-way bind category.
If you go back to
the notes index,
you'll see that all the
categories are displaying
and we even added a CSS select
so that on hover, the style
changes.
This is great, but
a couple of things
need to happen before
it's fully finished.
We need to keep track of which
category is set to active,
and then we need to filter
based on that active category.
First things first.
We need to decide where to keep
track of the active category.
So when a category
is clicked, it
needs to be set
as activeCategory
and there can only be one
active category at a time.
If that category is active,
it needs to change styles.
To solve this, we're going
to have nwCategorySelect keep
track of the active category.
So a sample value of
the active category
could be testing or
question or code snippet.
Each category item needs
to know which category
is active for two reasons.
One, it needs to
know if it needs
to be styled as an active
category — "Am I active?"
And two, it needs to be able to
set the active category if it
is clicked.
We could pass activeCategory
around and share a value
with everyone, however that's
not good object-oriented code.
Instead, we're going to let
the CategorySelect manage
the active category and
allow the inner category
items to get or set the active
value when they need to.
So first, CategorySelect
needs a function
that will allow other
directives to call and set
the activeCategory.
Let's semantically name
it setActiveCategory.
We'll pass in the
category and we'll
say scope.activeCategory
is equal to this
passed in category.
So logically as you're
thinking through this,
each category is
clicked and they
should be able to
have access and call
this parent setActiveCategory
method we just made.
But how do we give these
child directives access
to their parent's methods?
We have each child require
their parent directive.
We just say require:
^nwCategorySelect.
And this ^
character is letting
it know that you're looking
for a parent directive.
By doing this, our child will
now have access to its parent's
controller.
So how do we use the parent
directive's controller?
The first step, if
you haven't already,
is to define your link function.
Now link has a
fourth parameter that
can be named whatever
you would like.
And this is the
parent's controller.
Now inside of the
link function, we're
going to declare
a function and set
it equal to scope.makeActive.
Inside of the
makeActive function,
we'll call the controller's
setActiveCategory method.
We'll then pass
in scope.category.
We want to call this
makeActive function when
a category is clicked.
So inside of our category item
HTML, we'll add an ng-click
and call makeActive.
So if you go back in the browser
and you click on each category,
you'll notice that
nothing's happening.
And that's because we are, in
fact, setting activeCategory.
But we're not telling it to
do anything based off of that.
So let's go fix that.
So back inside our parent
category select directive
we're going to create a
function and set it equal
to this.getActiveCategory.
We'll have that function
return scope.activeCategory.
Back in the category
item child directive,
we're going to need
a function that
will check to see if
the active category is
equal to our category.
So we'll create the
function and set it
equal to scope.categoryActive.
Then we'll check to see
if the active category is
equal to our category.
Here's the category item
template how it currently is.
We need to assign a class
based on the return
of categoryActive.
So we'll say ng-class =
active: categoryActive.
So if you look back
in the browser,
you'll see that as you
click on a category
it stays active,
which is awesome.
That's what we wanted.
But the notes aren't filtering
based on that active category.
That's okay.
We'll work on that
in the next section.
For now, go have
fun practicing this
and we'll see you back soon.