Howdy again.
In this section, we're
talking about filters.
So back in our application,
we have categories showing up
and activeCategory being set.
The only thing left is to filter
based on that active category.
So you remember filters from
Shaping up with Angular.js?
There was date,
lowercase, uppercase,
limitTo, and orderBy.
Well, there's also another
thing called the filter filter.
And we're going to use that now.
The filter filter will
take a large array
and filter down that
array and return
you back a smaller
one of just the subset
items you were looking for.
So for example, here we
have an array of strings.
Let's say, filter by "a."
So this will select all
the words containing "a."
Filter filter will then return
us an array with "Alyssa"
and "Angular" in it.
The filter filter
can also help us
sort through arrays of objects.
So here we have our notes
array, which this data should
look familiar to you by now.
And we want to sort
through this notes array
based on the category.
Well, we would
filter it like this.
You specify the filter,
and then you say
category name question.
As with all other filters, we
will separate it by a pipe.
So we'll say ng-repeat
for node in notes, pipe,
and then put our filter.
So this filter would go
through our notes array
and return back an
array of only ones
with category of name question.
We obviously should filter
through the notes dynamically,
though.
So back in our
index.html, we're going
to use a new variable,
activeCategory,
that we need to two-way bind to our scope.activeCategory.
So obviously,
we're going to want
to filter this dynamically.
So instead of passing
a string of question,
we can pass it a variable
of activeCategory.
And we're going to want to
bind this to our category
select's activeCategory variable.
Remember how to do that?
In the nw-category-select
tag, we'll
give it an activeCategory attribute
and set it equal
to activeCategory.
Then back in the
directive, we'll
give it the equal sign
for two-way binding.
If we go back into the browser
on the notes index page,
and you click on a
category, now everything
is working as expected.
It's filtering through the
notes based on the category.
There's another thing that
filter filter can help us with.
And that's searching.
So if we wanted to add a
search box like this and filter
through the notes based on what
we're typing into the search
input, well, filter filter
can help us do that.
At the top of the index.html
page, we'll create an input.
We'll set the ng-model of
that input to search.title.
Then inside the repeat
for note in notes,
we'll say pipe specify the
filter, which is "filter",
and then we'll say "search."
So what this is going to do now, as you see,
I'll type into the input, and it's
searching through the titles of each of the notes
and only displaying the ones that match what I'm typing.
What if we want to search all
the properties on the notes,
not just note title?
Well, you can use the
$ character
to accomplish this.
So we'll simply say
ng-model = search.$.
And now, as you can
see, we're not just
filtering through note titles,
but we're searching all of it,
whether that's the
description or what have you.
What it we want
to do both things:
filter based on the category
and the search input?
Well, we can do this by
just adding another pipe.
So here we can say
filter:active category.
And then chain on another
pipe and say filter:search.
Now, both the categories and the search input
are filtering through the notes.
Go have fun with filters
in the challenges,
and I'll see you back for our
very last section of Staying
Sharp with Angular.js.