Are you ready for
the last section?
In this one, we're talking
about external libraries.
A lot of times we use external
libraries in our applications.
In an Angular app, it's best
to wrap that external library
in a directive, and then
reuse that directive
throughout your application.
So for example, look
at this tooltip.
It's kind of ugly.
We could replace this tooltip
with a prettier Bootstrap one
using directives.
Let's go ahead and find
out how to do that.
First, we want to
get the library
we want to use — Bootstrap,
in this case — put it
in the vendor directory, and
include it in our application.
Now we're ready to
create our directive.
We're going to
name this directive
"title," without any nw prefix.
This is because we want to
override the default HTML title
attribute.
This directive is going to
be an attribute directive.
And all of its
functionality will
be inside the link function.
Directives by default
are restricted to A,
so we don't need
to specify that.
If your directive is only
returning a link function,
there's an alternative
syntax for this.
So instead of return object and
then specify the link function,
you can just return
an anonymous function.
Now inside of our anonymously
returned link function,
we can call the tooltip
method from Bootstrap.
So we'll say element.tooltip,
and then pass it
a container body.
We're already specifying
the title attribute
inside of our card.
So now all we have to do is
go and load in the browser,
and you'll see that our
tooltip is being replaced
with the Bootstrap tooltip.
However, the tooltip
isn't working.
It's showing up,
but it's no longer
interpolating the expression.
It's just saying
bracket, bracket, header.
This is because the link
function only runs one time.
And when our link
function ran, Angular
didn't have access to
the header variable,
so it just set it to
bracket, bracket, header.
A simple but kind of
janky fix for this
is surrounding it by a timeout.
This will cause Angular to run
through an entire event loop
before replacing the tooltip.
By that time, the
header value will exist,
and our title directive
works as expected.
Our tooltip now works,
but as a best practice
we need to clean up
after our directive.
We can do this by listening
for the destroy event.
So we can just say
scope.on $destroy,
and then inside of that say
element.tooltip destroy.
This will clean up after
our directive nicely.
You might be wondering, after
seeing all the things we've
done in the link
function, "When should I
use the controller
inside a directive?"
Just remember, if you
need to share something
between directives, do that
logic inside of a controller
and use the require property.
Otherwise, it's your best
bet to use the link function.
Have fun making some external
library directives of your own,
and I hope you
enjoyed this course.
[BEEP]
Or, we'll—
—Ahh!
[LAUGHTER]
[BEEP]
We're going to make it
through this course.
We will survive.
[BEEP]