[SINGING] Store
documents in collections,
conjure them with projections.
Update, Remove,
Insert, and Find.
It's schemaless,
keep this in mind.
NoSQL looks like wizardry in
the Magical Marvels of MongoDB.
You're watching the
magical marvels of MongoDB.
I'm Joel Taylor.
In this level, we'll talk
about some query operators
and how to customize
our results.
We've decided to add some
filtering functionality
to our application to make it
easy to find specific potions.
In this example, we
want to find potions
by the vendor Kettlecooked
that are only the strongest,
with a strength of 5.
To do this, we can pass multiple
queries to the find method.
First, we'll query for a
vendor of Kettlecooked.
Add a comma, and
then we'll query
for ratings.strength of 5.
As you can see, we matched the
two first documents, but not
the third because it only
has a strength rating of 4.
Most of the time,
we can get away
with finding potions
based on equality,
but sometimes we want to use
queries with comparisons.
It's about time that we
allow our users to search
for potions based on the price.
So here we want to find
potions that are less than $20.
In order to perform
complex queries,
we can make use of the
comparison query operators.
The most common are
greater than, less than,
greater than equal to, less
than equal to, and not equal to.
Let's see how we can
put these to use.
Let's filter these
documents down
to only match documents that
have a price of less than $20.
Using the find
collection method,
we'll specify the
field price as usual.
But this time, we'll
pass it a field value
pair with it, $lt query
operator and the value of 20,
to find potions less than $20.
If we run this code, we'll see
the proper potions get matched.
Let's make our
filter more advanced
and allow for price ranges.
Here we want to
query for potions
that are greater than
$10 but less than $20.
Just like we did before,
we'll use find, specify
the field price,
but this time we'll
use multiple field value pairs.
First we'll add the
greater than criteria
by using gt and a value 10.
Add a comma, and then query
for prices less than 20
by using the $lt operator
and the value of 20.
If we run this query, we'll see
that we matched all documents
with a price greater than
$10 but less than $20.
The vendor Brewers recently
made some pretty risky comments
in the news.
We want to allow users to
be able to select potions
that are not made by Brewers.
Using find, we'll
specify the field vendor,
supply the field value with
an $ne operator and the value
Brewers to find all potions with
a vendor not equal to Brewers.
We've added a sizes
field to our potion
documents that contain the
sizes that each potion comes in.
We want to allow users to find
potions between certain sizes.
For example, we
want to allow them
to find potions that are
greater than 8 but less than 16.
We can use the element
match query operator
to only match arrays that have
at least one value that matches
all of the query criteria.
Let's give this a try.
We'll specify the field
sizes, pass element match,
and give it a range criteria
for values greater than 8
but less than 16.
As you can see, the
Luck potion matches
because it has a size of 10.
The reason we'd rather use
the element match operator
is because arrays act
differently with range criteria
than normal values.
For example, if we just did
a normal range criteria,
we'd actually match the
Love and the Luck potion.
The Luck potion makes sense
because it has a value of 10.
But the Love potion
doesn't have a value
that matches the criteria, so
why did that actually match?
When running a
query on an array,
each value is
checked individually.
If one value matches
each criteria,
then the document is
considered a match.
For instance, here we have
the sizes 2, 8, and 16.
The 16 matches the
greater than 8,
and 2 and 8 match
the less than 16.
Both criteria are met, which
makes this document seem
like a match.
Let's take a look
at another example.
Here we have an
invisibility potion
with the values 32, 64, and 80.
All these values match the
criteria of greater than 8,
while none match the
criteria of less than 16.
So this document is
not considered a match.
This is some strange behavior.
And the lesson here
is that whenever
you're dealing with
the ranges in an array,
you should use an
array query operator.
Now it's time for you to
go try some comparison
queries in the challenges.