Welcome back.
In this section, we'll
look at how to query data,
and we'll talk
about types of data
we can store in our documents.
Let's look at the potion
we stored earlier.
Since we didn't specify
the underscore ID,
Mongo created one for us
using the object ID data type.
While we can set
the ID ourselves,
generally, it's better to let
Mongo handle that so we don't
have to worry about unique ID
generation in our application
code.
We can use the Find method to
query for specific potions.
To do this, we'll pass the
document to the find method
with the field "name" and
the value "Invisibility".
This is saying that we want to
find a document with the name
Invisibility within
the potions collection.
It's referred to as
a query of equality.
Find returns the
entire document,
not just the field
that we queried for.
So what would happen
if our query matched
multiple documents?
Here we're going to query
for all documents that have
the vendor of Kettlecooked.
As we can see, find returns all
documents that match the query.
And here we've been returned
two separate documents.
It's important to remember
that queries of equality
are case sensitive.
So if we had a
vendor Kettlecooked
with a lowercase k, it
wouldn't match for this query.
Now that we've learned about
the queries of equality,
let's take a look at what
we can store in MongoDB.
Documents are JSON-like objects,
but more specifically, they're
saved in a format called BSON.
And BSON built
upon JSON, so that
means we can store values in
the same way, like strings,
numbers, Booleans, arrays,
objects, or even null.
But in addition, we
can also set values
like ObjectID and ISODate.
To learn more about BSON, you
can check out the documentation
using the link below.
Now that we know
what types of data
we can store, let's build out
our potion document with all
the important data, like the
tryDate, the Price, Score,
Ingredients, and the Rating.
We have the name and the vendor
information for the potion.
Let's add the price
and the review score.
We'll add the price of
$10.99 and the score of 59.
MongoDB will preserve the
precision of our integers
and floats, so we don't have
to worry about losing any data.
Next we'll add the date that
we first tried our potion.
We'll add our tryDate field
with the value as a new Date
JavaScript function.
This date reads as
September 13, 2012.
Even though we refer to
September as the number 9,
JavaScript starts months
off with the number 0,
which makes so much sense.
So instead, we have to
specify the number 8
to represent September.
With normal JSON, we have to
save the date to a string.
But when this gets
saved to the database,
MongoDB will convert
the date to an ISO format that
gives us great functionality.
Time to add the
list of ingredients
to our potion document.
We'll specify the
field ingredients
and then assign it the values
newt toes, the number 42,
and laughter.
Which is great, because
we can store any data
type within an array.
We'll be giving each
potion some ratings.
Each rating will consist
of strength and flavor.
Here we have a strength
of 2 and a flavor of 5.
Luckily for us, MongoDB
supports embedded documents,
so we can take this
document and simply
add it to our existing potion.
Here we've added a ratings
field with the value
of the document containing the
flavor and strength scores.
Embedded documents
don't require an ID
since they're just a child
of the main document.
We finally finished creating
our new and improved potion.
Now let's get it
saved to the database.
In preparation, we completely
erased our database
and reset it to make
room for this new potion.
We'll insert using db,
the potions collection,
and the insert method.
We'll pass it the new
document that we've created.
And there we have it.
We successfully
saved the new potion.
Let's see what queries we can
perform on this new potion.
Let's say we wanted to
find a potion that contains
the ingredient laughter.
Well, it turns out
that array values
are treated individually, which
means that we can query them
by specifying the field and
value that we want to find,
just like a query of equality.
To do this, we'll first specify
the field ingredients and then
the value laughter.
With this, we'll
return any documents
that have laughter in
the ingredients array.
As you can see here, this potion
has the proper ingredient.
Sometimes we only
want to find potions
that taste the absolute best.
Let's find a potion
with the flavor rating
of 5, the highest rating.
To perform a query of equality
on an embedded document,
we can use dot
notation to specify
the field we want to search.
So to find the strongest potion,
we use ratings.strength.
To find the best tasting
potion, we use ratings.flavor.
Using dot notation,
we can easily
query embedded documents.
So to find the best
tasting potion,
we can query using
ratings.flavor
with the value of 5.
While inserting a
document, we got
a bit distracted and set
the price value to a string
saying Ten dollars.
And while this is
invalid data to us,
Mongo doesn't really care.
And to our dismay,
the document still
gets saved to the database.
Why did this happen?
Turns out that Mongo doesn't
enforce many validations.
In fact, there's
only a few criteria.
For instance, Mongo will check
that the ID field is unique,
that there aren't any syntax
errors, that the document
size is less than 16 megabytes.
Currently, this document
passes all the validations.
Both IDs are unique.
The structure's good.
The document is a small size.
But let's say we
forgot the end curly
brace on the first document.
That would break the no syntax
errors and this document
would error out.
Now, if we try to add a
document with the ID of 1,
when there's already a document
that exists with that ID,
Mongo will raise an error
about duplicate IDs.
All this means is that
it's our responsibility
to make sure the data is valid
before sending it to Mongo.
You've learned how to
perform queries and create
rich documents.
Now go try it out
in the challenges.
[BEEP]
Place to right con--
Setup of-- ah, who-oo.
[SNAPS] You've learned--
[BEEP]
Smile.