[SINGING] Store documents
in collections,
conjure them with projections.
Update, Remove,
Insert, and Find.
It's schemaless,
keep this in mind.
NoSQL looks like wizardry in
the Magical Marvels of MongoDB.
You're watching the
Magical Marvels of MongoDB.
I'm Joel Taylor.
And throughout
this course, we'll
be interacting with the
potion review application.
We'll be using MongoDB
as a back-end database
to store and
retrieve our potions.
These reviews will consist
of the strength, the flavor,
and the grade.
This course consists
of five levels.
First, in conjuring
MongoDB, we'll
look at the basics of Mongo and
learn how to insert and find
our documents.
Next, we'll look at how to
update and remove them, perform
advanced queries, learn some
best practices for storing
our data.
And lastly, we'll see
how we can combine
data for interesting reports.
So get ready, sit back,
relax, and enjoy the course.
To start off, let's
first answer the question
of what is MongoDB.
Well, Mongo is an
open-source NoSQL database.
Now, the term NoSQL to be a
little difficult to define.
But for this course,
we'll refer to it
as databases that generally
aren't relational and don't
have a query language like SQL.
Mongo is document-oriented.
And it's great for unstructured
data, especially when we
have lots of it.
MongoDB first came
into being back
in 2007 when it was developed
by a company called 10gen
as a part of their product.
Unfortunately, they didn't
generate as much interest
as they wanted to.
But instead of
scrapping everything,
they thought their
database was really great.
So in 2009, they
open-sourced it.
And since then, it's gotten
so popular that in 2013, 10gen
renamed themselves to MongoDB.
You might be wondering, where
does the name Mongo come from?
It actually stems from
the word humongous.
MongoDB shares a
lot of similarities
with the SQL database.
At the lowest level, they both
store their data in a database.
In SQL, the database
is made up of tables,
whereas MongoDB is
made up of collections.
Tables are made up of rows.
But in MongoDB, collections
are made up of documents.
So for SQL, data
is stored in a row
that gets placed in a table,
which is saved in the database.
For MongoDB, documents get
grouped in collections.
And collections are
stored in the database.
So what's the big difference?
Well, SQL is relational while
MongoDB is document-oriented.
Let's take a closer look at
what it means to be relational.
Let's imagine we have a
love potion that costs $3.99
and is made by a
company called Brewers.
To store this in SQL,
we'd have a potions table
with the potion ID, name,
price, and a vendor ID column.
Then we'd have a vendor's table
with the vendor ID and name
column.
You'll notice that the
love potion has a vendor
ID of 2, which
creates a relationship
with the vendor and the vendor's
table that also has an ID of 2.
On the other hand,
document-oriented databases
would take the information
about the potion and group
it all together in
a single document.
All those documents then
get grouped together
in a potions collection.
You can think about this
like you're filling out
a form that contains
everything you
need to know about the potion.
So you've learned that
collections are just
groups of documents.
And documents exist
entirely on their own.
This means we can store
completely different documents
in the same collection.
For instance, here's
our potions collection
with three potion documents.
You might have one that
has the name, price,
and vendor information.
Another with only
name and price.
And then one with name, price,
and even danger information.
This is referred to
as a dynamic schema,
which means potions can
have different data.
This is why MongoDB is great
for unstructured data that's
still related.
Now that we've covered
the fundamentals,
let's break into some code.
One place to write
Mongo is in the shell.
To do this, in the
command line we type
Mongo, which then
puts us in the shell.
We can write our commands
after the greater than sign
to interact with our database.
We'll be providing the shell in
the browser during challenges.
But if you want to set up
Mongo on your local computer,
you can head over to their
installation instructions
online.
As we just saw, all instances of
Mongo come with a command line
app called the
shell, which is just
a JavaScript interpreter that
let's us write JavaScript code.
As you can see
here, we can perform
basic variable assignment,
access the variable
to see the contents,
and get a response back.
This is all just
normal JavaScript.
Documents, which is where
we store data in Mongo,
are just JSON-like objects.
These objects are surrounded by
curly braces, consist of field
value pairs.
In this example, we have a
field with the string name
and a value with a
string invisibility.
Then we have a field with the
string vendor and the value,
with the string Kettlecooked.
We can have as many field
value pairs as we like.
All we have to do is
separate them with a comma.
Let's look at a few
basic shell commands.
MongoDB comes with a
number of helper methods
to make it easy to
work with our database.
We'll be using a
database called reviews.
To get started, we can
select which database
we want by typing use reviews.
We'll get a response back saying
that we switched to the database
reviews.
If that database
doesn't exist yet,
it'll get automatically created
for us when we write to it.
To check which database
we're currently using,
we can simply type db,
and we'll get a response
back saying reviews.
If you ever forget
a command, you
can always type help,
which will give you
a list of helpful commands.
For instance, show
dbs will give us
a list of all the databases
and their names and sizes.
Here's our potion document.
Now, we can't just store this
document in the database.
If we did that, it would
be a complete mess.
First we have to store the
document in a collection,
and that collection gets
filed in the database.
So we're going to create a
collection called potions.
We'll put that potion document
in the potions collection,
which then gets persisted
in the database.
We can use the Insert method
to save our potion document
in the potions collection.
First, we type db.
Whenever we interact
with the database,
we always use db first,
followed by the collection name.
In this case, we'll put
the collection potions.
What's cool here is
although we haven't actually
created this
collection yet, it'll
be created when we insert
our document into it.
So next we have insert
with parentheses.
We'll then pass the parameter
of our potion object.
When we run this
code, we get back
a response that has
the words WriteResult.
But we didn't
conjure this, did we?
Well, it turns out that
whenever we create, update,
or move a document, we
always get a WriteResult
back to let us know if the
operation was successful
or not.
In this case, we
have nInserted, which
stands for the number
of documents inserted
and the value of one.
This lets us know that one
document was successfully
inserted into the
potions collection.
In order to retrieve
our document,
we'll use the find method.
Just like we do with
inserting, we'll
first type db followed by
the collection potions,
and then the find method.
Even if we don't pass any
parameters to a method,
we always end them
with parentheses.
Let's give this a try.
And just as we expected,
we successfully
retrieved our potion document.
But wait a second.
What's the _id field with
the weird object ID value?
MongoDB requires that each
document has a unique ID.
Since we didn't specify
one, it automatically
created one for us.
The find method will
return all the documents
in the collection.
To see this, we'll
add two more potions.
So you can see, we have two
successful WriteResults.
Running find again will
return all three documents.
Now that you've learned
the basics of MongoDB,
go try creating and
finding your own documents
in the challenges.