Welcome back.
We've only scratched the
surface of aggregations.
In this section, we'll be
covering the aggregation
pipeline.
Unfortunately, it turns out
that potions containing unicorn
and their ingredients
aren't permitted,
because unicorns are majestic.
We need to do a
quick audit to get
an idea of how many
potions per vendor
contain this
horrific ingredient.
First, we'll query for
potions containing unicorn.
Then, we'll group the
potions by vendor.
And finally, we'll count the
number of potions per vendor.
The aggregate method
functions like a pipeline.
Instead of just adding
one stage operator,
we can add multiple ones
for data to pass through.
We've already been working
with stage operators,
like this group one
we did in the last section.
Let's explore a few other stages
we can pass our data through.
The aggregation pipeline
works by passing data
from stage to stage and
modifying it along the way.
For instance, the
pooling numbers we want
will perform a
query of equality,
and pass only documents that
match to the group stage.
This functionality allows us
to manipulate data efficiently.
The first step we
need to take is
to query for the proper potions.
We can do this by using
the match stage operator.
We'll pass it the
filled ingredients
and the value, unicorn.
Now match is a lot
like find, so we
can use the same kind
of query for equality
to find the correct documents.
It's good practice to use the
match stage operator as early
as possible to reduce
the number of documents
that we pass through
the pipeline.
You can even use
match multiple times
to continually remove data.
Now that we've
limited our potions
to those containing
unicorn, let's go ahead
and group them by vendor
and count their potions.
In order to use multiple
stages, all we need to do
is add the next operator,
separated by a comma.
So next we'll add the
group stage operator,
and we'll group
potions by their vendor
and sum the total number
of potions per vendor.
Let's look at an
example where we'd
have a complex query
that we can make
simple by using aggregation.
In this example, we're
going to find the top three
vendors with potions under $15.
First, we're going
to query for potions
with a price less than 15.
Next, we'll group
our potions by vendor
and average their grades.
Then we'll sort results
by grade average.
And lastly, we'll
limit our results
to only the top three vendors.
Here, we'll use
match to only pass
on documents that have
a price of less than 15,
using the $lt query operator.
Again, it's good practice
to use match early on.
Now that we've got the documents
filtered, let's group them
and get their average grade.
We'll do this by using
the group operator,
setting the group key to
the vendor field path,
and then we'll create a
field called average grade,
and then use the average accumulator
with the grade field path
to get an average of the
potion grades per vendor.
Next up, we need to sort our
potions by their average grade.
We can do this by using
the sort stage operator.
Then we'll use the average grade
field with the value negative 1
to sort the grades
in descending order.
The last stage is to limit
the number of documents
that we return.
There's no need to
return any extra data.
We can do this by using
the limit stage operator
and passing it the value of 3.
Well, our code works just fine.
We could still
improve its efficiency
by making sure we're
only passing the data we
need through the pipeline.
After the match, all we
need from the documents
is their vendor name
and their grade.
While the other filter
unused and are just
bloating the pipeline,
let's look at how
we can trim up our documents.
In order to slim
down our documents,
we can use the
project stage directly
after match, which takes
the same values as we'd
use if we're projecting
with the find method.
It's good practice to
project as soon as possible.
We'll set the
underscore ID to false
since we don't really need it,
and the vendor ID and grade
fields to true.
With this last touch, we have
an efficient and working
aggregation.
Again, it's common to see
match and project used together
throughout the pipeline
to continue trimming down
our data.
This becomes
critical when dealing
with large amounts of data.
Now let's take a
look at our results.
As you can see, our results
have exactly what we want,
the group key with the
vendor name and average
grade per vendor.
Now it's your turn to try
the aggregation pipeline out
in the challenges.
Fortunately, it turns
out that potions
with unicorn in their
ingredients aren't permitted,
because unicorns are
******* majestic.
As it turns out, who knew?
You can't grind up a unicorn
and put it in a potion.
An idea of how many
potions per vendor contains...
[LAUGHTER]