[SINGING] Store documents
in collections,
conjure them with projections.
Update, Remove, Insert and Find.
It's schemaless,
keep this in mind.
NoSQL looks like wizardry in
the Magical Marvels of MongoDB.
You're watching the
Magical Marvels of MongoDB.
I'm Joel Taylor,
and at this level,
we'll be talking about
common aggregations.
We've been tasked with
finding the number of potions
per vendor, so
that we can perform
an audit on potion reviews.
We could query for
all the potions,
project the name
and vendor fields,
and then use something like
Excel to group our data,
together but that's
masochistic, MongoDB already
has all the tools
we'd need to perform
this operation efficiently.
MongoDB comes with a powerful
aggregation framework
that allows us to manipulate
our data before retrieving it.
To use it, we can simply
call the aggregate method
on our collection.
The term aggregate is just a
fancy word for combining data.
First, we'll add our
aggregate method.
Aggregate takes an array
as a parameter, in which we
can place our stage operators.
And the first step we
want to do is to group
our documents by vendor.
To do this, we can use
the group stage operator.
Just like an update
operator, stage operators
start with a dollar sign and
have a similar field value
format.
The group requires us set an _id
to the field name that we want
to group by.
In this case, you want
to group by vendor.
But instead of
just adding vendor,
we need to add a
dollar sign in front.
This makes vendor
a field path that
points to the value
of the vendor field
so that the group knows what
values to group the documents
by.
The _id field is known
as the group key,
and it's required by the
group stage operator.
If we run this code, it
will return a result object
containing a list of
unique vendor names
in our potions collection.
We have three _id fields that
each have a unique vendor name
as their value.
These are the group
keys that we set above.
The next thing we
want to do, is to get
to a count of the number
of potion per unit vendor.
Now, everything that
comes after the group key
is considered an accumulator.
Accumulators can be
assigned to any field name
and take an expression
that will be computed
on each document in a group.
We'll start off by
adding a field total
and use the sum accumulator
with the value of 1.
The sum accumulator will add 1
for each document in the group.
If we run the code above, we'll
see that we have each group
key, the field called total,
and the number of documents
within the group.
We're starting to get a lot
of dollar signs in our code,
and it could be a bit confusing.
A good rule of
thumb to remember is
that when the fields
begin with a dollar sign,
they'll perform some sort of
task, like grouping or summing,
but if a value begins
with a dollar sign,
we know it's a
field path that is
pointing to the value
of the specified field.
The sum is useful for
counting as well a summing
all the values of
fields in a group.
For instance, if we want
to get the total grades
of all potions per
vendor, we can simply
add another accumulator.
This time, we'll add a
field called grade_total,
and pass the grade
field path with the sum.
This will cause the
grade of each document
within a group to be summed
up into one single total.
Looking at the
results, we can see
that each document has
a grade_total field
with their total score.
This is cool and all,
but what we really want
is the average grade per vendor.
Let's calculate the average
potion grade for these vendors.
We can do this by using
the average accumulator.
To start, we'll group by vendor.
We'll have the field as
average, and then we'll
pass in the grade field
path as the value.
As you can see, we'll return
the average grade per vendor.
Finding the max
grade per vendor is
as simple as putting max
in where we had average.
As you can see, we now have
the max grade per each vendor.
We can even use max and
min accumulators together
to generate useful reporting.
And as a result, we get back a
single report with both the max
and min per vendor.
Now it's time for you
to try to aggregating
some data in the challenges.