Welcome back.
In this section, we'll be diving
deeper into updating documents.
During development,
we were a bit rushed
and made some bad
code decisions.
Luckily, we kept a To Do list.
In order to accomplish these
To Do lists, all we need to do
is use some more
update operators.
The first item of action is
to remove the color field.
While we initially
thought people
cared about the color of
our potion, it turns out,
no one's trying to make
a fashion statement
with their potion.
To remove a field, we
can use $unset operator.
Here we're going to call update
on our potions collection,
but this time for
our query parameter,
we're going to pass
empty brackets.
This will select
all the documents
in our potions collection.
Next, we'll pass $unset.
We'll specify the field color
and then an empty string.
This might seem a bit weird,
but when using $unset,
the value we pass
really doesn't matter.
And the empty
string communicates
what we're trying to do, which
is remove the color field.
Lastly, we'll set
multi to true in order
to apply this update to
all of the documents.
If we run this code,
we'll see that the colors
in the documents
slowly fade away.
The next task on our
list is to rename
the field "score" to "grades".
We can do this using the
$rename update operator.
Looking at the code we'll
will use the same kind
of query parameters you did
previously with empty brackets
to select all the documents.
Next, we'll pass in the
$rename update operator, then
the field "score",
which is the one we
want to update to the value
"grade", which is the new field
name we want.
In addition, we'll set
multi to true to change all
documents.
Looking at the code
above, we successfully
renamed our documents field.
We've received urgent notice
from the Magical Council
that we can no
longer have secret
as an ingredient in our potions.
So we need to change it.
Here we have a potion document
and ingredients hippo, secret,
and mouse feet.
Now, we can try to
update this by first
querying for ingredients
that have secret,
and then setting
ingredients to 42.
But if we do this,
we'll actually
end up updating the
entire ingredients
field to the value 42.
But instead, we just want to
update the single value, not
the entire thing.
You can reference arrayed
values using dot notation
and update them individually.
First we specify the field
name ingredients and then
the index of the value.
So in this case, we have
ingredients.0, ingredients.1,
and ingredients.2.
And since we want to
update the secret value,
we'll be using ingredients.1.
First we'll query
for the proper potion
using a query of equality.
We'll set name to Shrinking.
Then we'll put
$set with the field
ingredients.1 to
the value of 42.
As you can see, we matched
and modified one document,
and now the ingredients says 42.
Our previous update
will work when
we know the location
of the value,
but sometimes we're
not going to know
where the secret ingredient is.
For instance, one
might be ingredients.1,
while another is
ingredients.0, and then
another in ingredients.2.
We need a way to update
multiple documents
without knowing the location
of the secret ingredient.
We can this with something
called a positional operator.
First, we'll query for
potions with the value
we want to change.
We'll set ingredients
to the value of secret.
Next, with our update parameter,
we'll $set with the field
ingredients, but
instead of specifying
the location, this time
we'll use a dollar sign.
And that's a
positional operator,
and it acts as a placeholder
for the index of the value
that we're querying.
So if our query
matches the document
with the secret at the
index 0, the dollar sign
will then turn to 0.
If it's at an index of 1, the
dollar sign then becomes a 1.
Lastly, we'll set multi to true
to apply this update to all
documents.
It's important to note that
the positional operator only
applies to the first
match per document.
So if we had secret
multiple times in the array,
it only applied to
the first value.
Let's see the position
operator in action.
When we run this
update, the dollar sign
will be replaced with
the index of the secret.
So for the first
document, the update
becomes $set with ingredients.1.
For the second
document, it becomes
$set with ingredients.0.
And the last document becomes
$set with ingredients.2.
And there we have it.
All the potions have been
successfully updated.
We recently tried out
a new shrinking potion.
And originally, we didn't
think it worked very well,
so we gave it a strength of 1.
But when we woke
up this morning,
our pillow was the
size of our house,
so now that we're
full size again,
we're going to update
that strength to 5.
We can do this
using dot notation.
Since we want to update
the strength field,
we'll be using ratings.strength.
Then we'll update the potion
with the name Shrinking
and set ratings.strength
to the value 5.
From the WriteResult, we can
see that we successfully matched
and modified our document.
MongoDB comes with
a few operators
that allow us to perform
complex operations.
For instance, we
have $max, which
allows us to update
a value only if it's
greater than the current value.
$min if we want to update
only if the new value is
less than the current value.
And $mul, which allows us to
multiply the current value
by the value we supply.
Now, that's a lot of new
operators, but don't worry.
MongoDB has great
documentation and you
can read about them
using the link below.
As you continue
learning MongoDB,
the documentation will
be a loyal friend.
Arrays are a common way
to store data in Mongo.
Here we have our
shrinking potion
where we've added the
categories array with the values
tasty and effective.
Let's see how we can
modify this array.
Let's say we wanted to
remove the last value
in the categories array.
To do this, we can
use the $pop operator
to remove either the first or
the last value in an array.
We simply specify the
field "categories",
and give it a value of negative
1 for the first element
or 1 for the last element.
Since we're removing
the last element,
we'll give it a value of 1.
Now our categories array
only has the value tasty.
Now, keep in mind,
the $pop operator
only modifies the array.
It doesn't actually
return the value.
We can use the $push
operator to add values
to the end of an array.
For this example,
we'll use $push
with the field categories,
and specify the value budget.
So we can see, budget
is now at the end
of the categories array.
To keep things neat
and tidy, we only
want to add unique values
to the categories array.
To do this, we can use
the $addToSet operator,
which will only add the
value if it doesn't already
exist in the array.
So here we have $addToSet,
the field categories,
and the value budget.
So you can see, the
categories field
only has tasty and budget.
It didn't add budget
a second time.
We've learned how to add
elements to an array,
but what about removing them?
To remove values, we can
use the $pull operator.
The $pull operator removes
all instances of a specified
value from an array.
By using $pull in categories
with the value tasty,
you see that tasty
has been removed.
It's really
important to remember
that $pull will remove all
instances of a matching value.
So if your value's
not unique, they
will all be removed
from the array.
Now you're equipped
with some operators.
Go give them a try
in the challenges.
[BEEP]
Let's start from the top.
That's a fake smile.
[LAUGHTER]
[BEEP]
That was good.
Mystical--
[BEEP]