[SINGING] Store documents
in collections,
conjure them with projections.
Update, Remove,
Insert, and Find.
It's schemaless,
keep this in mind.
NoSQL looks like wizardry in
the Magical Marvels of MongoDB.
You're watching the
Magical Marvels of MongoDB.
I'm Joel Taylor.
And in this level, we're
going to learn about how
to best model our data.
We've decided to allow users
to sign into our application.
We'll be giving
them a basic profile
to add their name, email, and
top three favorite potions.
Users and their favorite
potions go hand in hand.
Whenever we visit
a user's profile,
we'll always be displaying
their favorite potions.
Because of the
strong relationship,
we can add a favorites
field to the users document
with an array containing the
names of the favorite potions.
Next up, we'd like to add
more vendor information
for each potion so that
users who will know more
about a vendor can
easily find necessarily
information, like their phone
number or if they're organic
or not.
Let's try modeling
this the same way
we did a users favorite
potions and embed it directly
into the potion document.
If we take a look
at our potions,
we'll notice that there's
a lot of duplication.
When we see this
kind of duplication,
it's a good sign that we need
to step back and take a look
at how we're modeling our data.
The reason we want to
be cautious about having
duplicated data
is that it can be
difficult to keep
data consistent.
This is known as data integrity.
One day, we might get a
potion in from a vendor that
says that they're not organic.
If we update that for this
potion but not the others,
we're going to have
inconsistent data.
And this is bad.
What can we do about this?
Instead of embedding
vendor information directly
in the potions document,
we can split it
into two collections, the
potions and the vendor
collection.
In the potions
collection, we'll have
a vendor ID that references
the vendor and the vendors
collection.
If you're familiar with
relational databases,
this is a step in
normalizing our data, which
allows us to reduce duplication,
which in turn reduces
inconsistencies.
For example, in the
potion document,
we have a field called
vendor_id set to Kettlecooked.
In the vendors collection,
we have a vendor document
with the ID set to Kettlecooked.
We're using the
vendor's name as the ID
since they're unique and
rarely change, unlike the rest
of their information.
This actually ends up being a
better fit for our use case.
Most users only want to
know a vendor's name,
but then there are those
who want to know more.
Let's see how we insert
this in the database.
First, let's add a vendor
to the vendors collection.
Now, this time, we're
going to specify the ID
and use Kettlecooked
as the vendor ID.
Next, we'll insert a potion
with the normal details.
But this time,
instead of vendor,
we'll have vendor ID
with value Kettlecooked.
And there we have it,
our potion document
references the vendor document.
Document references
are manual,
and we're required to make the
connection between documents.
Mongo doesn't see anything
besides field and value pairs.
In order to pull a potion
document and all of its vendor
information, we must first
query for the potion.
Then using the vendor
ID from the potion,
we must perform a second query
on the vendors collection
in order to get the
correct vendor document.
Now let's look at the
differences between embedding
and referencing documents.
Embedding documents comes
with some great features.
For example, when
we perform a query,
we only have to
perform one query
to get all the
data that we need.
In this example,
for users, we can
get the email and the
favorites with a single query.
In addition, we
get atomic writes.
What this means, if we were
to update the user's email
and add a new favorite, either
all the operations would occur
or nothing would happen at all.
Let's take a closer
look at what this means.
Let's say we're
updating a user's email
and adding a favorite potion.
If during that update
there's a power outage that
happens at our data
center and we've only
got a partial update,
nothing will actually
happen to that document.
It won't be changed.
This prevents impartial
writes from happening.
Imagine how that would be to
only have a partial update
occur.
On the other hand, when we
get a write result back saying
that we updated one document,
we know without a doubt
that everything got updated.
Now let's compare that
to reference documents,
which are completely different.
Documents that are referenced
are independent documents.
This means that they exist
completely by themselves.
This is ideal for data that
sometimes gets used together,
but sometimes also gets
used independently.
What's great is we only
have to update our vendor
information in one place.
This helps reduce the
risk of inconsistencies.
Unlike embedded documents,
one factor to consider
is that we can't atomically
write to multiple documents
at once.
If you come from
relational databases,
this is called a transaction,
and Mongo does not
support that by default.
To understand the
implications of not having
default support
for multi-document
write operations, imagine that
we received a new potion
from a new vendor.
If we tried to enter both
documents at the same time
and the potions document
writes successfully,
but the vendor document runs
into some kind of error,
there wouldn't be any
sort of roll back.
The potion document
would get written
regardless of the vendor.
So what's the big
deal with that?
Since MongoDB doesn't
acknowledge relationships,
we'd end up with a
potion that has a vendor ID
of a vendor that doesn't exist.
So you want to be really
careful when working
with reference documents.
Now head over to the challenges
and try out your hand
at modeling some data.