Welcome back.
In this section, we'll be
talking about some concepts
to help guide us between
referencing and embedding
documents.
Data modeling is no easy task.
It can be really difficult
to decide when to embed,
versus reference a document.
In order to make
the best decision,
we have to really
think about our data
and how it's used throughout
the life application.
As a quick review,
we have two options--
embedding and referencing.
With embedding we can
perform single queries
to get all of our data,
but with referencing we'll
need two queries.
Embedding means that documents
only exist within their parent,
but reference documents
exist independently.
Embedded documents
have atomic rights,
but reference
documents don't support
multi-document operations.
We decided we want to
allow users to comment
on our reviews,
and in this section
we're talking about how to
best model this decision.
So we'll have potions
that will have comments,
and those comments
will belong to users.
Whenever we need to
decide between referencing
and embedding documents,
we need to ask
ourselves a few questions.
The first question is,
how will our data be used?
If you have data that's
always used together,
you're most likely
safe embedding it,
and you'll benefit from faster
read and write performances.
With referencing, it would
require two queries every time
we need that data
that's always used,
and that's just inefficient.
When data is either sometimes
or rarely used together,
it can either be
embedded or referenced,
as it will depend on
some further questions
that will narrow
down the decision.
The data isn't
always needed together,
then the cost of performing two
queries to get the data when
needed has minimal overhead.
As you can see, most the time
embedding is the best option.
Let's take a look
at our example.
Here's a potions view page
with the potion review
details and some comments.
As you can see, whenever
we display a potion,
we'll also be displaying
their comments.
And for each comment we'll
be displaying the author.
In this case, embedding comments
and users in a potion document
makes the most sense.
Referencing would
require us to query
for the potion, a query for
the documents, and then a query
for the users, and
that's too many queries.
The next question
we'll need to ask is,
what is the size of the data?
As this can significantly
impact our decision.
Generally, if the expected
size is less than 100,
then the data can be embedded.
Whereas, when there's more
than a few hundred documents
in a relationship,
referencing presents itself
as a stronger option, as it's
easier to manage the data.
Let's head back to
our application.
Our site is growing
in popularity,
but we don't really expect
to have a ton of comments.
Maybe we'll have 50 per
potion, and each comment
will only have one user.
This data's small enough
that we can easily
manage it with embedding.
Whenever the data gets
to the hundreds mark
is when we really want to
start considering referencing.
Our last question is,
will the data change often?
As it's important to understand
the life cycle of the data.
If our data never or rarely
changes, it's safe to embed it,
even if there's
some duplication,
since it'll be easy to manage.
When the data might
change occasionally,
we can either
embed or reference,
as it will depend
on whether or not
we want the overhead of
managing duplication.
Lastly, data that is
constantly changing
is better to be referenced, as
it will prevent inconsistencies
when there's duplication.
It's much easier and performant
to write in one place
than hundreds all the time.
This question changes a few
things for our application.
Let's take a look
at the relationship
between potions and comments.
Once a comment is
written, we don't really
expect it to change that often.
There might be an
edit here or there,
but it's not going to
happen all the time.
With this, we can safely
still embed comments
within our potion.
Now let's look at a
comment and users.
Users might change their email,
or add a few favorite potions,
and this would be
an absolute pain
to update through
all the comments.
And that's a lot of duplication,
and our users surely
wouldn't appreciate
having messed up data.
For comments, it looks like
referencing is actually
the better decision.
We've chosen to embed our
comments in the potions,
since the data is
strongly related.
Every time we show
a potion, we're
going to want to show
the comments as well.
We don't foresee there
being more than 100 comments
per potion, and the data
doesn't change that often.
Now let's check out
comments and users.
We've chosen to reference
users and comments,
because a comment
only really needs
to know the username
for each user.
It doesn't need to
know the other details
and it doesn't make sense
for us to embed all of that
and duplicate our data.
In the event we ever want to get
more information on the user,
we can simply query
for it, but we'd never
expect that to really happen.
Before we head over
to the challenges,
here's some brief
guidelines and take-aways.
First, generally
it's OK to consider
embedding as the first option.
Second, you'll want to
reference data that needs
to be accessed independently.
Third, consider referencing
when you have large data sizes.
Most importantly,
always consider
how your data is going
to be used and allow
that to guide you.
If you find that your data
calls for complex relationships
and your data really
seems relational,
you should consider using a
relational database instead
of a document oriented database.
Now it's time for
you to practice
making some good modeling
decisions in the challenges.
Have fun.
Whenever we-- we.
Not good.
-No, I thought that was good.