Welcome back.
In this section, we'll learn
how we can customize our queries
even more.
We're putting together a
blog post of all the best
potions we've ever used.
Let's put together
a query to find
all potions that have a grade
greater than or equal to 80.
But we're only going to
need the name and the vendor
for these potions.
First, we're going to
find potions with a grade
greater than or equal to 80.
Now this is going to
return all the fields,
but we only want the
name and the vendor.
To do this, we can add a second
parameter called projections.
By specifying the fields we want
returned and setting the true,
we can build custom results.
For instance, by setting
vendor and name to true,
we're only going to be
returned the ID, the name,
and the vendor for each
potion that matches the query.
By default, document
IDs are always returned.
It's best practice to only
retrieve the data that we need.
With projections, we either
select the fields we want,
or we exclude the
fields we don't want.
In this case, if we
wanted to pull everything
but the vendor and the price,
we'd set their fields to false.
This is great when we want
to remove sensitive data
from our results.
So far we've seen the ID
field returned every time,
but sometimes we
may not want that ID
field, especially when
we're sending results
to non-developers.
In order to remove the ID, we
can specify the underscore ID
and set it to false.
This is the only time you can
have a true and false value
in a projection.
Let's see what would happen if
we try to select and exclude
in the same projection.
What happens is we raise an
error that says projection
cannot have a mix of
inclusion and exclusion.
And that's because we
only want to select
all the fields we want
or exclude the fields
we don't need.
Time to amp up our
marketing campaign.
We want to establish our sales
as the go-to place for potion
reviews by listing the
number of potion reviews
we have on the top of our site.
To do this, we
need a way to count
the number of potion reviews
we have in our database.
It turns out that whenever
we run the find method,
we're actually returning
a cursor that's pointing
to the documents that match.
By default, the cursor
will print out the first 20
documents right in our shell.
Let's take a look at
what happens if we
have more than 20 documents.
We've populated our
database with 80 documents.
When we run the find
method, we'll match all 80.
But we'll only get the first
20 documents sent back.
But this time, we'll have
a response that says type
it for more.
Here we'll literally
type it, which
will move the cursor to the next
20 documents, send them to us,
and then prompt us again
until the cycle is complete
and we've iterated
through all of the cursor.
So now that we know that
find returns a cursor object,
this means that we can call
methods on that cursor object,
like count, which will count
the number of documents
in a cursor, which
in this case is 80.
Now remember, cursor
methods will always
come after find since find is
returning the cursor object.
So what other cursor
methods can we use?
Well, we want to allow users
to sort potions by their price.
To do this, we can use
the sort cursor method.
First, we'll find
all the documents.
Then we'll add the
sort cursor method
with the field we want to
sort by, which in this case
is price.
Next, we can either
add the value of one
for ascending or minus
one for descending.
We'll add the value 1 to sort
our potions by price ascending.
Now we can see our
potions arranged in order
with the prices ascending
from $3.99 to $59.99.
We've decided to add
pagination to our site
so that instead of having
an endless scrolling page,
we can have three
potions per page.
To do this, we can use the
skip and limit cursor methods.
Here are the potions
that we want to paginate.
All we need to do here
for the first page
is limit our results to three
by using the limit cursor
method with the value of 3.
For the second page,
we need to add a skip
to skip over the potions we've
returned on the first page.
To do this, we'll add the
skip with the value of 3.
And then we'll add a
limit, again, by 3.
The last page will skip by
6 but still limit by 3.
This approach technically works
but can become quite costly
for large collections.
So keep that in mind.
But for now, it's time for you
to head over to the challenges
and try out some the projections
and cursors on your own.
[BEEPING]
Fields we don't want, want.
Ha,ha,ha.
[BEEPING]
Either select the
fields we want.
[LAUGHTER]
[BEEPING]
Want it.
I really want it.
[BEEPING]
The fields we want.
[LAUGHTER]
[BEEPING]