[SINGING] Store
documents in collections,
conjure them with projections.
Update, Remove,
Insert, and Find.
It's schemaless,
keep this in mind.
NoSQL looks like wizardry in
the Magical Marvels of MongoDB.
You're watching the
Magical Marvels of MongoDB.
I'm Joel Taylor,
and this is Level 2.
We'll talk about
removing and modifying
documents in our database.
While getting our
potion site set up,
we accidentally sneezed
a spell, and as a result,
messed up our database.
Now our application isn't
displaying our potions
correctly.
We need a way to remove
all the affected potions.
Here's all the potions
that got ruined.
Our love potion review has gone
rogue and we need to remove it.
To do this, we can use the
Remove Collection method,
along with a query of
equality to specify
the document we want to remove.
In this case, we'll query for
a potion with the field name
and a value of Love.
When we run that command,
we get a WriteResults saying
it nRemoved with a value 1.
nRemoved is the
number of documents
removed, letting us know one
document was successfully
removed.
Now let's remove the
other two potions.
It turns out the remaining
two potions have one thing
in common, their vendor.
So instead of removing
the potions one by one,
we can write a query to match
the vendor of Kettlecooked.
By default, the
Remove method will
remove all matching documents.
When we run this command, we
get a WriteResult back saying
that two documents were removed.
Instead of completely
removing a potion,
we can also update specific
fields with new values.
For instance, this
love potion has a price
of $40.99, which is completely
wrong, because love potions are
always cheap.
To fix this, we can use the
Update Collection method.
The first thing you want to do
is pass in a query parameter
to select the document
we want to update.
So here we'll pass in the field
name with the value Love.
The Update method also
takes an update parameter.
In this example, we'll be
using the set update operator
to set the field to a new value.
Update operators
are tools we can
use to perform various
operations on our documents,
and always begin
with a dollar sign.
To update our potion,
we'll use $set with a field
price and a value of $3.99.
So you can see, our
potion successfully
updates with the new price.
It's important to note
that the update only
applies to the first matching
document, which in this case,
is ok, because we only want
to update a single potion.
Whenever we perform
an update, we
get returned a WriteResult
that has three fields.
The first is
nMatched, which lets
us know how many
documents were matched.
The second is nUpserted,
which is the number
of documents that were
created because of the update.
The third is nModify, which
is the number of documents
that were modified.
As we expected, we matched
and modified one document.
What would happen if
we didn't use an update
operator with the Update
method, and instead
just passed a document
with the price of $3.99?
This results in a
complete replacement
of our matched document.
You can see
everything but the ID
gets replaced with the values
of the update parameter.
This might seem a
bit counterintuitive,
but it's great for importing
or overwriting data.
After the whole
sneeze fiasco, we
were adding our potions
back in and accidentally set
some potions to the vendor of
KC instead of Kettlecooked.
Well, we got this
angry letter and we
need to fix this immediately,
else Kettlecooked
is going to send us
more angry letters.
First, we'll pass
in a query parameter
to find potions
with a vendor of KC.
Then we'll pass in an update
parameter using the set operator
to set the field
vendor to Kettlecooked.
We know that as is,
this will only update
the first matching potion.
In order to perform
multiple updates,
we need to add a
third parameter, which
is the options parameter.
And we can specify the
option multi to true.
And by doing so, we're
telling the update
to perform the operation
on all matching documents.
If we run this code,
we'll see that we matched
and modified four documents.
Our application is trying
to grow in popularity,
and we want to see which potions
users care about the most.
To do this, we'll start
logging user behavior.
Whenever a user
clicks More info,
we want to create a log
document with a potion
name and a count which will get
stored in the Logs Collection.
Whenever that potion's More
info button gets clicked again,
we'll update the existing log
document with a count increment
by 1.
First, let's see
how we would update
an existing document that's
already in the Logs Collection.
We'll use the Update method and
a query for the name Shrinking.
We can then use the
$inc update operator
which will update
the specified field
by any positive or
negative value we supply.
So here we'll increment
the field count by 1.
As you can see, the document
now has a count of 2.
What happens if we try to update
a log that doesn't exist yet?
For instance, there is no log
document with the name Love.
When we run this update, we
get a WriteResult back saying
that no documents were matched,
which means none were modified.
What can we do to fix this?
Another option we can specify
when performing an update
is upsert, which when true will
create a new document with all
the details of the query
and update parameters
when no document gets matched.
Running the same update as
before with upsert set to true,
we get back a WriteResult that
says no documents matched,
but one was upserted, letting us
know one document was created.
And sure enough, we've create a
log document with the name Love
and a count of 1.
Now, what happens when we
run this same query again?
Running this code
again, we'll see
that we matched and
modified a document
and increase its count by 1.
This time, no documents were
upserted because we matched
a document with our query.
Now it's time for you to perform
some mystical modifications
in the challenges.