[SINGING] The SDK for iOS
has really got my back.
There's places, modes,
and sweet controls
to make the perfect app.
From polylines and
polygons and geocoded lats,
I delegate the methods to
create the perfect map.
Directions and street views,
these are the very best.
I must confess
it's time to start
exploring Google Maps for iOS.
Welcome to Exploring
Google Maps with iOS.
I'm Jon Friskics.
And in this course,
we're going to learn
how to embed a Google map inside
of your own iPhone application.
To do this, we're going
to use the Google Maps
SDK for iOS, which is a
framework that you can add
to your app that contains code
for working with Google Maps.
In addition to standard
things like displaying a map,
adding markers and info
windows, and even drawing
lines and shapes
on the map, we'll
be able to do a few other
things that other mapping
frameworks are not able to do.
Using Google Maps also gives
you access to Street View
and Indoor views,
really easy integration
with other Google services
like geocoding and direction
finding.
And it gives you access to
some really powerful gesture
based controls in your map that
are unique to the Google Maps
platform.
In this course, after
we display a map
and add some
markers to it, we'll
learn how to make a
network request for data
and add new markers based
on the data we get back.
We'll geocode an address and get
directions between two places
and show that on the map.
We'll draw some lines
and shapes on the map.
And finally, view
our marker locations
in Google Street View.
We're almost ready to
start looking at some code.
But first, I want to remind
you that this course is
for developers that already
have a little bit of experience
with iOS.
If you need a refresher, you
should check out Code School's
Try Objective-C and Try
iOS courses to get up
to speed enough to
be able to understand
what's happening in this course.
The first step to using
the Google Maps SDK for iOS
is setting up an API key.
Every app that displays a Google
map needs to have an API key.
An API key would look
something like this.
Just a collection of
letters and numbers.
That API key is associated
with an app's Bundle Identifier
which might look
something like this.
You can visit the Google
Developers Console to set up
an API key for your
app's Bundle Identifier.
And we've even
provided a walk-through
to do this in the course.
Once you've set up your API
key, you need to set up the SDK.
Now if you're completing
challenges in this Code School
course, you're not
going to actually need
to set up the SDK because
we've set it up for you
in all the challenge projects
you'll be downloading.
But if you're putting
together your own app
using the techniques we're
teaching you in this course,
you can watch the
"Setting Up the SDK"
screencast that will walk
you through all the libraries
and settings that you need in
Xcode to make the Google Maps
SDK for iOS work.
So let's get started
building our app.
First in the AppDelegate, we'll
want to import the Google Maps
framework so that
we can access all
of that code inside
of our project.
Next, in the application
didFinishLaunchingWithOptions
method, we'll want to send
a provideAPIKey message
to a GMS services class
and enter in our API key
that we got from
the Google Console.
Adding in this code
lets Google know
that we're ready to put
a map inside of our app.
While we're still in the
AppDelegate, let's go ahead
and import the main
class that we're
going to use to display our map,
which here is called LakeMapVC.
So we'll import LakeMapVC
to the AppDelegate,
we'll create a
LakeMapVC instance,
and then we'll assign it to
the rootViewController.
So that it's the
default window that
displays when our app opens.
In LakeMapVC, notice
that we do have
to re-import the
Google Maps framework.
When we imported it
before in the AppDelegate,
that was so we could provide
the API key to Google
to turn on our maps access.
But we're also going to
need to access the SDK
inside of LakeMapVC, so that's
why we need to re-import it.
We're also going to want
to GMSMapView property.
GMSMapView is the
main class that we'll
use to display a
map in our view.
There are few ways to
create the MapView object.
But the simplest one is to
call the mapWithFrame camera
initializer.
And that will return
a mapView that you
can add as a subview
of self.view.
Here we're setting
the frame to be
the entire bounds of the
screen so the map takes up
the entire view.
We're also passing in
this camera object,
so we'll need to look at
what it takes to create that.
That's actually a
GMSCameraPosition.
That camera object is created
from the GMSCameraPosition
class.
And like the mapView, there's
a few different initializers
that you can use to make it.
The one we're using
here is called cameraWithLatitude,
longitude,
zoom, bearing, viewing angle.
So let's look at what
each of those things mean.
As you know, latitude
and longitude
are the way that you
find any point on a map.
Latitude are lines
that run east and west.
And longitude are lines
that run north and south.
And the combination of any one
latitude and longitude number
will give you a unique
point anywhere on the map.
For example, the
Envy Labs office
is located at latitude
28.53, longitude -81.36.
And that's the point
we're going to use
at the center of our map.
Zoom is just a
number that lets you
display more or less of the map.
Higher zoom means that you're
going to be showing less map
area and a lower zoom
means that you're
going to be zoomed way out
and showing a lot of the map
all at once.
Bearing determines what
direction the map is rotated.
The default rotation is zero and
means that the top of the map
is pointing north.
But you can pick any
number between zero and 360
to rotate the map.
And finally, by having a
viewing angle greater than zero,
you can give the
impression of looking
at the map in sort of
a 3D downward view.
Like you see here.
It's completely up
to you what numbers
you put in this camera
position object.
But with these
numbers, this is what
our map will look
like when we apply
that camera object
to our mapView.
And there's a few other options
that you can set in your map.
One of them is the mapType.
Where you have the
option kGMSTypeNormal,
Satellite, which will
give you satellite view,
Hybrid which is sort of
a combination of Normal
and Satellite view,
and Terrain, which
will show you things
like hills and mountains
if that data is available.
It's really easy to show your
current location on the map
just by setting the myLocationEnabled
property to YES.
When you do that, you'll
get a little blue dot
with an arrow pointing
out the top that
indicates which direction
the device is pointing.
Kind of like a mini compass.
If you think your users might
be rotating the map at all,
then it might be a
good idea to turn
on the compass button
which will draw
a little compass at the
top right of the screen
so they always know
which direction is north.
And you can add a button that
your users can tap to find
and center the map on
their own location.
There's some other options you
can set too, like whether you
want to enable or disable
scrolling, tilting, zooming,
and even rotation.
And if there's
indoor views present,
you can also add
a button to select
which floor you want to view.
Speaking of zooming,
might not always
be desirable to
let your users zoom
all the way in or
all the way out.
Zooming a map all
the way out is going
to show most of
the entire world.
So it's not always practical
to give them that much control.
So you can constrain
the amount they
can zoom using the
setMinZoom, maxZoom
method by passing in the lower
bound and the upper bound.
And you can see the
result of that here.
You might have noticed
in the previous examples
that the status bar was
sitting on top of the map.
And especially when you have
all those words for street names
and road names, can be
kind of hard to read
the time in the status bar and
have those names on screen.
So course iOS 7
gives us the ability
to turn that status bar
off by adding the line
prefersStatusBarHidden
and returning YES.
Now you know how
to display a map
and change some of
the default settings.
But there's another situation
that you're probably
going to find
yourself in once you
try adding a map
into your own app.
In the previous
examples, our map
was taking up the entire view.
But in this example, we've
added a tab bar controller
that contains a
navigation controller.
And you can see that the myLocation
button and compass are
now hidden by the nav
bar and the tab bar.
Since iOS 7 uses
full screen views,
those controls are now
hidden underneath those bars
and that's a problem.
The way we can fix
this is by adjusting
the mapView's padding.
This padding property
uses UI edge insets
to define the amount that it
should push those controls away
from the top, right, bottom
and left of the view.
When we're displaying the
compass button and the myLocation
button, we'll
want to have top padding
to push that compass
down and we'll
want to have bottom padding to
push that location button up.
And the best place to do this
is in the viewWillLayoutSubviews
method, as you see here.
Now it's time for
you to practice
setting up a map
in the challenges.
If you're not watching
this video on Code School,
you can visit this
URL to get access
to all the free challenges
for this course.
Or you can learn more about
the Google Maps SDK for iOS
by visiting Google's
Developer documentation.