[SINGING] The SDK for iOS
has really got my back.
There's places, modes,
and sweet controls
to make the perfect app.
From polylines and polygons
and geocoded lats.
I delegate the methods to
create the perfect map.
Directions and street views,
these are the very best.
I must confess,
it's time to start
exploring Google Maps for iOS.
Welcome back.
In this level,
we're going to look
at how we can add markers
for points on the map,
because just a plain map
with no information on it
isn't very exciting.
We're also going to add some
data to each marker that's
going to display in the Info
window that pops up whenever
one of those markers is tapped.
The class we use to create
markers is called GMSMarker.
And the simplest GMSMarker you
can create looks like this.
We just initialize
the object, give it
a position, which is
a latitude-longitude,
and then set the map property
of that marker to our mapView.
Now, this map property really
acts as an on-off switch.
It's only ever going to
be one of two values.
If our map property
is nil, it means
that our marker is off and
not showing on the map.
But if it's our mapView,
that means it's on,
and it is showing on the map.
It will only ever be
one of those two values.
In addition to
just the position,
we can set the "title" and "snippet"
properties of the marker.
And those will show up as text
whenever the marker is tapped.
There's an appearAnimation
option
that can be set to either
kGMSMarkerAnimationPop
or kGMSMarkerAnimationNone.
And you can see here the effect
of adding that Pop animation
when the marker is created.
The default marker
icon is a red pin.
But you can change that icon
either with the GMSMarker class
to create a different
color, or just
setting that icon property
to a UIImage to any image
that you have in your app.
When you want to display more
than one marker on the map
at a time, you could just create
multiple GMSMarker objects
by hand and just have a
lot of code duplication.
But that's not ideal.
So let's look at a strategy for
dealing with multiple markers.
First, whenever we
have multiple markers,
we want to actually
set the Map property
to nil when we've created them.
This means that they
won't immediately
be added to the map.
But that will give
us the flexibility
to turn them on or off later on.
If you have more than
just a few markers,
you're going to want to put
them all inside of a collection
so you can easily manage them.
And the collection we'll
use for this is an NSSet.
Now, you might be
thinking, I'd rather
use an NSArray to store
all these markers.
But we're using an
NSSet here for a reason.
And that reason will
become clear very soon.
We're calling our set "markers".
So to initialize
our set, we can just
call the setWithObjects
initializer on the NSSet class.
And if you're used to
working with NSArrays
and NSDictionaries, you probably
love using that literal syntax
for creating them.
And unfortunately,
NSSet does not
have a literal syntax
shortcut in Objective-C.
So we have to create it
the old way by passing
the setWithObjects
method to the class.
Also, notice that the last
object in our set is nil.
And that's important, because
that's how sets are created.
When we set up our markers, the
map property for each of them
was nil.
So we've created another
method called drawMarkers.
Inside of drawMarkers,
all we're doing
is iterating through each
of those markers in our set
and setting the map
property to self.mapview.
So now, whenever we
call drawMarkers,
our markers will be displayed
on the map, as you see here.
You're probably going to add to
the markers that are displayed
multiple times while a
user's working with an app.
But right now, every
time we call drawMarkers,
it's going to redraw every
marker in our set every time.
So instead, we can add
a little bit of logic
in here that says, only set the
map property if it is currently
nil, meaning that if the marker
is currently off, turn it on.
But if it's on,
don't disturb it.
We talked about how if a
marker's title property is set,
an Info window will be displayed
when you tap on that marker.
But you can actually
create a custom Info window
to show anything that you want.
The custom Info
window is created
using a delegate method.
So that means we need to
adopt the GMSMapViewDelegate
in our LakeMap class.
And then, of course, we need
to set the mapView.delegate
to self so that we can access
all of those delegate methods
inside of our class.
The method we'll
use here is called
mapView markerInfoWindow.
And it returns a UIView.
That means that
inside of this method,
you could create
your own UIView,
and customize it to look
any way that you want,
and have any content
inside of it.
And that will display
whenever the marker's tapped.
Starting small, we've
created a simple UIView
with a gray background
color, as you can see here.
Then, we're adding a UILabel.
And since we have access
to the marker that
was tapped inside
this method, we
can access that
marker's title property
to show text inside
of that label.
We also have access to
this marker's snippet text.
So we can create another
UILabel the displays
that in a custom way, too.
You might even be
thinking that you
can add a UIButton to this Info
window so that when you tap it,
it takes you to another
part of your app,
or shows a new piece
of information.
But that's actually not going to
work inside of an info window.
It turns out that even though
this method returns a UIView,
that UIView is actually
just snapshotted and applied
as an image on the map.
That means you can't
have anything that's
interactive inside
of that Info window.
Fortunately, though, there
is another delegate method
called mapView
didTapInfoWindowOfMarker.
And as you might have
guessed from the name,
it's going to run every time
you tap the Info window.
So inside of this
method, you can
have code that causes
something to happen based
on the data inside
of that marker.
Normally, that might be passing
you onto a different view
controller with some
more detailed information
about that place.
And here, we're just
showing a UIAlertView,
just to show you
that that works.
We can easily display a custom
background image in the custom
Info window by
creating a UIImageView
and adding it as the first
subview of the info window,
like this.
Now it's your turn
to draw some markers
on the map in the challenges.
If you're not watching this
video on CodeSchool.com,
you can visit this
URL to access all
of the free challenges
for this course.
Or you can learn more about
the Google Maps SDK for iOS
by visiting Google's
Developer Documentation.