[SINGING] The SDK for iOS
has really got my back.
There's places, modes,
and sweet controls
to make the perfect app.
From polylines and
polygons and geocoded lats,
I delegate the methods to
create the perfect map.
Directions and street views,
these are the very best.
I must confess
it's time to start
exploring Google Maps for iOS.
Welcome back.
In this level, we're going to be
learning how to create markers
from data that comes back
from a network request, which
is a pretty common scenario
when you're working with maps.
Not all of your data
will be sitting inside
of your app at all times.
It will usually come in
from of network requests.
So because we're
making those requests,
we need an NSURLSession object
that all those requests move
through.
We're not going to go into
detail about how NSURLSession
works in this course,
but this code right here
should be all you need to
complete all the network
requests in this level.
If you're interested
in learning more,
you can check out Code
School's Core iOS 7 course,
where Level 8 is
dedicated entirely
to understanding NSURLSession.
So we've added the UI
button to our app that
calls the downloadMarkerData
method when it's tapped.
Inside of that
method, we'll first
want to create an NSURL that
points to a JSON file that
contains some data that
we'll use to make markers.
Then we'll create our
NSURLSessionDataTask
and we'll use the
URL to our JSON file.
Finally, we'll call
Resume on that task, which
starts the request.
We'll take that JSON
response and we'll
serialize it into an NSArray.
And that's a few steps that
we just did pretty quickly.
So let's stop and log
out that JSON array,
so we can see
what's inside of it.
When you're using
NSLog, anytime you
see stuff inside of
parentheses, it usually
means that that's
contained in an array.
So we've got multiple pieces of
data inside of an array here.
If you see curly
brackets, that usually
indicates that you're
working with a dictionary.
So here we have an
array of dictionaries.
And finally, when we see
some kind of word or term
equal to some
other type of data,
that usually means that
those are the keys and values
inside of that dictionary.
So again, we have
a JSON array that
has multiple dictionaries
inside of it.
And each one of
those dictionaries
has keys for things like
Appear Animation, Lat, Long,
and Title, and the values
for each of those keys.
And this is the data
that we're going
to use to map to
GMSMarkerObjects
that we can display
as markers on our map.
In those dictionary
values, obviously
if it has quotes around
it, it's a string
and if it doesn't have
any quotes around it,
it's a number.
Now that we know the structure
of our JSON response,
let's create another
method called
createMarkerObjectsWithJson
and pass our JSON array inside.
There's a few things we're
going to have to do inside
of this
createMarkerObjectsWithJson
method.
So let's form a plan of attack.
First we're going to want
to get a mutable copy of all
of the markers in
our self.markers set.
This is so we can add more
as we loop through the data.
Next we need to loop
through each one
of those dictionaries
one at a time,
and create a marker
object for each one,
and then add that new
marker object to our set.
Once we're done with
that loop, we'll
want to save the
current state of our set
back in self.markers
as an immutable copy.
And finally, since we
have new marker data,
we'll want to call drawMarkers
so we can update the display.
Getting a mutable copy of
the set is pretty easy.
We just create an
NSMutableSet object
and use the
initWithSet initializer
and pass in self.markers.
To loop through each of the
dictionaries in the JSON array,
we can just use a simple
for in enumerator.
Before we look at what
goes on inside that loop,
we can finish out
the method because we
know we're going
to need to create
an immutable copy
of our mutable set
and store it back
in self.markers.
And we're going to need to draw
the markers once that's all
done.
So back inside that
for loop, we're
looking at each
dictionary one a time
in an object called markerData.
So we'll create a GMSMarker
called newMarker and really
just map each one of those
newMarker's properties
to the corresponding data inside
of the marker data dictionary.
You can see here that we're
mapping the appearAnimation,
position, title, snippet,
and of course, we're
setting the map property to nil.
Note that sometimes we also have
to convert the data in the JSON
array into the appropriate
format for GMSMarker.
The appearAnimation property
is expecting an integer,
so we need to make sure
that we're giving it that.
And the position
property is looking
for two double values for
latitude and longitude.
So we need to make
sure that we're
returning the double
value version of our lat
and long data in the array.
Since title and snippet
are expecting strings,
we don't need to do
anything special there.
And finally, now we've got a
great new marker full of data,
so let's add it to our set.
So it seems like we've
done everything right,
but if we try to run this code
and tap our load button to load
new markers, you can see
that our app crashes.
That's not good.
The specific error
that we're getting
is Terminating app
due to uncaught
caught exception
GMSThreadException.
Fortunately for
us, a nice reason
is also included
with this exception.
Says that all calls to the
Google Maps SDK for iOS
must be made from the UI thread,
which is the main thread.
What's happening is that since
we're creating GMSMarker
objects inside of
a network callback,
it's not guaranteed that we're
going to be on the main thread.
We can fix this
problem pretty easily
by making sure we call the
createMarkerObjectsWithJson
method from inside
of the main thread.
And one way to do that is to
create an NSOperationQueue
on the main queue, like this.
So now we tap that load
button and our markers appear.
But we might actually
want to tap that load
button multiple times.
Say we're in a new
area of the map
or some positions of the
markers that are on the map
have changed.
Well you can see when we
do that, we're actually
generating tons of
duplicate markers.
Every time we hit that
button, we're just
getting a duplicate of
all of those markers
over and over and over
again and our set just
keeps growing and
growing and growing,
even though there's
no new markers being
displayed on the map.
So we need to fix this problem.
In the last level,
we decided to use
an NSSet instead of an NSArray.
One of the main reasons
you would choose to do that
is that an NSSet contains
only distinct objects, which
means unique objects.
By their very nature, sets
are resisting duplicate data,
but they need to be
to told what makes
an object a
duplicate of another.
They don't understand
that on their own.
So every time we try to
add an object to a set,
a calculation like
this is happening.
It's saying is GMSMarker
A equal to GMSMarker B?
But if we don't define
what makes them equal,
it's going to just make
a hash of those objects
and try to compare them.
So an example of what that
might actually be comparing
would be two giant
numbers like this.
Since these two numbers
are definitely not equal,
you might look at them
and say, "OK, both of these
can go in the set because these
objects must not be equal."
We need some way to tell
these markers whether or not
they truly are equal.
We need to find what's
unique about them.
Well, in our JSON
response, we do
have an ID that's unique for
every marker that comes back.
So why don't we just add
an objectID property
to each marker and then override
the isEqual and hash methods
to use that object ID.
And that way we'll know if those
two objects are truly equal.
So we have another problem.
We can't just edit
GMSMarker, since that's
a class that's part
of the framework.
But we can create a
subclass of GMSMarker
and add an objectID
property to that.
So it looks something like this.
Here we've created a CSMarker
for Code School marker.
It inherits from the GMSMarker.
That means that all of the
properties in GMSMarker
are still available, like
appearAnimation, map, position,
title, and subtitle.
But inside of our CSMarker, we
can add an objectID property.
And we'll use that
objectID to check
whether these objects are equal.
We can make that
objectID and NSString.
And then we have to override
these two methods inside
of the implementation of
CSMarker: isEqual and hash.
So inside of
isEqual, we just need
to check if the current
MarkersObjectID that we're
trying to add into the
set is equal to one
of the objectIDs that's
already in the set.
If it is equal, we'll return
YES and if not, we'll return NO.
Now we also have to
override this hash method,
but it's really just an
implementation detail.
And you can see that by reading
the isEqual documentation.
Since we're using our objectID,
all we need to do in here
is return self.objectID's
hash and everything will just
work fine.
So back now in
LakeMapVC, inside of
our createMarkerObjectsWithJson
method,
we're going to change our GMSMarker object
marker object into a CSMarker,
because we've now just imported
that into our view controller.
And we'll also add that objectID
that comes back from the JSON
response to our new marker.
Doing those few things
is enough to make
our mutable set smart
enough that it won't
try to add a new
marker if it already
finds that that
objectID is in the set,
and our duplicates will be gone.
Before we see it
all working, we need
to make one other
tiny little tweak.
This time to the
drawMarkers method.
Because now we're
storing CSMarkers instead
of GMSMarkers, we'll want
to change our drawMarkers
class to use CSMarker as well.
And here you can
see that now when
we tap the Load
button repeatedly,
the size of our self.markers
array doesn't get any bigger
and there's no duplicates
added into the set.
Which is exactly what we wanted.
It's your turn to
practice creating markers
with data from a network
request in the challenges.
If you're not watching this
video on CodeSchool.com,
can visit this URL to get access
to all the free challenges
for this course.
Or you can learn more about
the Google Maps SDK for iOS
by visiting Google's
developer documentation.