We've got a great
handle now on how
to make a network
request for marker data,
and then create a bunch of
markers and put them in a set
without having any duplicates.
But there's one case
that's kind of an exception
to the rule for a marker that
we don't want in our main marker
set, and that's a
user-created marker.
In most mapping
applications, a user-created
marker is usually
generated through some gesture.
And in this example, we're
going to use the long press
gesture to create a
marker wherever the user long
presses on the map view.
Let's look at some of the
differences between our set
markers and our
user-created marker
so we can better understand why
we should keep those separate.
So first, markers in a set
come from a network request
and probably contain lots
and lots and lots of data,
versus the user-created
marker which
is created from a gesture
like a tab for a long press.
Markers in the set are
probably displayed permanently
once they're loaded
into the map,
but our user-created
markers are only going
to be displayed temporarily.
And finally when we
have markers in the set
we probably want to
display all or nothing.
But the user-created
marker, we only
ever want to show one at a time.
We don't want five user-created
markers on our map.
We want to just delete
the current one as soon
as a new one is created.
So for these reasons, we'll want
to create a separate CSMarker
property called
userCreatedMarker that's
going to allow us to
track that marker that's
created from a gesture.
Our mapView delegate gives
us another great method
called mapView
didLongPressAtCoordinate, which
will be called every time a long
press is detected on the map.
And inside of this method,
we can create a CSMarker
and instead of
receiving a marker,
this method actually
receives the coordinate
where the long press happened.
This is great because now we
can create a CSMarker object
and for the position
of that marker,
we can use that coordinate
where the long press happened.
We can set all the
same properties
that we did for
our other markers
like appearAnimation,
title, snippet.
And just like before,
we'll set our map property
to nil when our
marker is created.
We'll start this
marker out turned off.
And just like before, we'll
call the drawMarkers method
to turn it on.
In our current
drawMarkers method,
we're only looping through
each of the markers that
are in our marker set.
So after that code,
that we'll leave intact,
we'll add another
conditional that
says if the
userCreatedMarker is not nil,
and if the userCreatedMarker's
map property is nil, that
means our marker exists, but
it's currently turned off.
So if those two things are
true, we'll turn the marker on,
and we'll even set the
mapViews selectedMarker
property to our new
user-created marker.
Setting the selectedMarker
property on a map view
is a programmatic way
to tap the marker, which
means that as soon as this
marker's created and displayed,
the Info window is
going to pop up.
So if we take a look at
where we're at right now,
we're definitely creating
markers and showing the Info
window whenever a long
press gesture happens.
But we've got some
problems still.
For one, our old
user-created marker
should be removed as soon
as we create a new one,
and they're not right now.
And second, the map
doesn't actually
re-center on each one of
those newly created markers.
When we have a normal
marker and we tap on it,
the map gets re-centered on it.
So we need to recreate
that centering animation
inside of our
drawMarkers method.
Since we already created a
GMSCameraPosition object
initially when we
created the map,
we can use another class called
GMSCameraUpdate to change
the properties of
that existing camera.
There's quite a few options
that this GMSCameraUpdate
will take.
But here since we want
to recenter the map
on the userCreatedMarker, we
can use the setTarget method
and pass it our
userCreatedMarker's position.
Then we can send the
animateWithCameraUpdate message
to our mapView and pass in
our cameraUpdate object.
And now, when that
new marker is drawn,
the map will re-center
on it like this.
So that solves one
of our problems,
but we still have
the issue where
we're showing more than
one user-created marker
on the screen at the same time.
We really only want to show one.
To fix this, we can go inside of
our long press delegate method
where we create the marker,
and before we try to create it,
we first check if it's not
nil, meaning that it's there,
it exists.
And if it does exist, we'll set
the map property of it to nil,
and then we'll just
completely nil out the object
and remove it.
Now it is important but
you do these in that order.
If you first nil out
the object and then try
to nil out the map property,
the object will cease to exist,
but the map view will
not update and you'll
see this like ghost
marker just floating
on top of your map view.
And that's not what you want.
So make sure to always nil
out the map property and then
the object.