[SINGING] The SDK for iOS
has really got my back.
There's places, modes
and, sweet controls
to make the perfect app.
From polylines and
polygons and geocoded lats,
I delegate the methods to
create the perfect map.
Directions and street views,
these are the very best.
I must confess
it's time to start
exploring Google Maps for iOS.
Displaying strings
in an info window
is one of the simple things
you can do with markers.
So in this level,
we'll be looking
at how we can enrich
some of that data
by using Google's geocoder
and directions API services.
First, let's look at how
we can use a geocoder
to fill in the address and
city of the user-created marker
when it's tapped.
So there's two
kinds of geocoders
that we can work with.
The first one, called
the forward geocoder,
takes an address and turns it
into a latitude and longitude.
But for each of these
markers, we already
have a latitude and
longitude, so that's not
going to be really
helpful for us.
The second geocoder is
called a reverse geocoder.
And there, we'll be able to
take an existing latitude
and longitude point and
turn it into an address.
So that's the one we're
going to build into our app.
We're going to add this geocoder
into our long press delegate
method, since that's where
we're creating our marker.
So we'll start by creating
a GMSGeocoder object,
using this initializer.
And then we'll send it the
reverseGeocodeCoordinate
completionHandler
message, passing
in the coordinate where
the long press happened.
Inside of this
completionHandler method,
we're going to have
access to some of the data
that the geocoder returns.
So that's where we're
going to now want
to create our marker, inside
of this completionHandler.
Here you can see we've moved
the marker creation code
inside of the completionHandler.
We're using data from
the geocoder response
for the title and
snippet of the marker.
Now this specific
configuration will give us
a street address and city name.
Let's look at what the
different options are.
First there's
administrativeArea.
And that's basically
a state or region.
Country is the country.
Locality is the city.
subLocality is a subdivision,
district, or park,
if that level of detail exists
in the geocode response.
And the thoroughfare is
actually just the street number
and name.
If we were to reverse geocode
the Envy Labs office location,
the response's thoroughfare
would be 618 East South Street.
And the response's locality
would be the city, Orlando.
This is the data that we're
going to use for our marker.
So now if we run this
again and tap on our marker
so we can see the
Info window, you
see that the address of
the places that we're
creating with our user created
marker are automatically
being filled in our info window.
This means the
geocoder's working.
Another powerful
service that you
have access to when you're
using the Google Maps SDK
is the Google Directions API.
We're going to be able
to use that Directions
API to get a step by step
list of route directions
from our current location
to any tapped marker.
And each new marker
that we tap will
update the directions
that are shown
and a new table view controller.
So let's look at
how to set that up.
Since we want to
calculate directions
between our current location
and a tapped marker,
we can detect when a marker
is tapped using the delegate
method mapView didTapMarker.
Another thing we
want to do in here
is to have this check
at the start that
says if mapView
myLocation is not nil,
then we can calculate
the directions.
We don't want to try
to get directions
between our location
and a marker
if our location
is not available.
Next, we'll want to create
an NSURL in the format
that the directions API
wants, using our current user
location and the tapped
marker's location.
Then we'll use that URL
to make a network request
and again we'll get
a JSON response back.
Now this is a different
JSON response than before,
but it's still JSON.
And finally, we
want to do something
with that JSON response.
So we'll talk about
that when we get there.
Since the directions
API is URL based,
it's going to help to look
at some of the options we're
going to need to
pass in that URL.
This is the base
URL for all requests
made for the Directions API.
And there's a few
required parameters
that have to be at the end.
The origin is a latitude and
longitude separated by a comma -
that's the start
location where you're
looking for directions from.
For the origin,
we're going to use
the user's current location.
The destination parameter also
takes a latitude and longitude
number separated by comma
and this is the location
that you're driving to.
The third parameter
called "sensor."
And since we're intending
for our app to ultimately
be installed on an iOS device
that has a GPS tracker in it,
we want to set that
property to true.
It's a requirement
of the Directions API
to have the sensor property set
to true if the device making
the directions request
has a GPS in it.
Finally, we'll need to
have a key property.
And its value should be
our "browser app" API key.
Note that this is
a different API
key than the one we originally
included in our AppDelegate.
That iOS app key and
bundle identifier
allowed us to register our
app with the Google Maps SDK
for iOS to display a
Google map in our app.
But since the directions
API is a web service and not
specific to just iOS apps, it
uses a different browser app
API key.
So we can look at the code used
to build that URL string now
that we know the
different parts of it.
We can use NSString
format placeholders
to make this a
little more readable.
We'll start by
applying the base URL,
then the start location's
latitude and longitude, then
our end location, which is
the currently tapped marker's
position.
And finally, our
browser app API key.
We'll use that URL string
to make an NSURL object.
And then we'll use that
URL to make a request
and get a JSON response.
Now the JSON this time is
a little bit different.
We're going to look at
the structure in a second,
but I'll start by telling
you that this is actually
an NSDictionary that's
returned, not an NSArray.
So we'll store our JSON
in an NSDictionary.
This response has
a deep structure
with multiple arrays and
dictionaries nested inside
of each other.
But the part we want right
now, the array of steps,
can be accessed with this code.
So we've got those
steps and we want
to be able to access
them from different parts
of our application.
So we've created an NSArray
property called "steps."
And we're assigning it
to that JSON response.
So now that we've isolated
just the array of steps,
let's look at what's
inside of there.
There's actually quite a bit
of data in there as well,
but fortunately we're
going to only look
at one part in the
examples in this level.
And that part is the
HTML instructions field.
HTML instructions
contains a string of HTML
that has the directions for each
step inside the steps array.
So this makes it really easy
to create a UI tableview
and then in each
UITableViewCell,
we can display UI webview that
uses the HTML instructions
string to show the text.
Now that's not a Google
Maps specific thing,
so we're not going to show you
that code here in the slides.
But we'll give you
all that code when
you're working on
the challenges.
We look at how to link to that
table view from our mapView,
though.
We've gone ahead and
created a UI button that's
going to call the
directions tapped method
whenever the button is tapped.
And inside of that
directionsTapped method,
we'll include our
DirectionsListVC,
which is our table view.
And since the DirectionsListVC
accepts an array of steps,
we'll send it that array of
steps, which we can access
from our self.steps
object, and then we'll
just present the ViewController.
Notice also that
in the completion
block of
presentViewController, we're
going to set our
self.steps array to nil
and we're going
to set our mapView
selected marker to nil as well.
This is because as soon as
the directions window closes,
we don't want to have
any directions lingering.
We've already
closed that window.
We need to nil out
that object so we
don't keep a reference around.
And we'll deselect the
marker because again, we've
closed those directions.
We're done interacting
with that marker.
We want it to have
the effect of closing
as soon as the table view closes.
So here's what our app looks
like as our code stands
right now.
You can see that
we can tap a marker
and we have a directions
button on screen.
And we can tap that
directions button
and get a list of directions.
We can hit Back, but the
directions button never
goes away.
And that doesn't
seem quite right.
Seems like we probably only
want the directions button
to appear whenever
the marker is tapped.
And as soon as the
marker's not selected,
we want the directions
button to go away.
The way we're going to
show and hide that button
is to set it as a property
in our ViewController
and then adjust the alpha
property of it between zero
and one.
One meaning the
button is showing,
zero meaning the
button is hidden.
We'll create the
button in viewDidLoad,
but we'll immediately
set its alpha to zero.
And that means that when
the map view first loads,
the button is
nowhere to be found.
Then, inside of our mapView
didTapMarker delegate method,
inside of our Directions API
request completionHandler,
we're already
capturing the steps
we need in the self.steps array.
And as soon we have some
steps for each of one
of our direction routes,
we can be pretty sure
that we want to show
that directions button.
Because as soon as
we have those steps,
our users might
want to access them.
So we'll set our directionsButton
alpha to one.
And notice how we're doing
this inside of the main queue,
just like we did before to
avoid any kind of thread issues.
In our directionsTapped
method, we'll
set the directionsButton
alpha to zero inside
of the completion block.
Because we're setting
self.steps to nil,
meaning there's no more
directions that we need,
we also want to hide the button
that accesses those directions.
When we run the
app again, you can
see that we don't get a
directions button on screen
until a marker is tapped and
as soon as we hit our Back
button from the table
view controller,
the directions button goes away.
But now if we just tap
somewhere on the map
or drag and move the map,
the directions button
is still there.
And that's not ideal either.
We don't want it to be on screen
unless a marker was tapped.
To fix this here, we're using
the mapView didTapAtCoordinate
method.
We're basically saying if
the button is currently
showing when the map is
tapped, then hide it.
Likewise, in the mapView
willMove method,
we're saying if the map
the scrolled at all, then
hide the directions button
if it's currently showing
and go ahead and
deselect the marker, too.
We don't want a
marker's info window
to stay up while we're
dragging the map.
With these simple settings
of showing and hiding
buttons and marker Info
windows at the right time,
we're going to provide
a much better user
experience in our app.
And here we can see everything's
working as expected.
Now it's time for you to
practice geocoding and getting
directions in the challenges.
If you're not watching this
video on CodeSchool.com,
you can visit this
URL to get access
to all the free challenges
for this course.
Or you can learn more about
the Google Maps SDK for iOS
by visiting Google's
developer documentation.