[SINGING] The SDK for iOS
has really got my back.
There's places, modes,
and sweet controls
to make the perfect app.
From polylines and
polygons and geocoded lats,
I delegate the methods to
create the perfect map.
Directions and street views,
these are the very best,
I must confess.
It's time to start exploring
Google Maps for iOS.
In this level,
we're going to look
at how we can draw lines
and shapes on the map.
Let's start by drawing
a really simple line,
so we can see how this works.
We'll create a
GMSMutablePath object,
and then we'll use the addLatitude,
longitude method
to add one point at a time.
The simplest line we can
draw is just two points,
so we'll start there.
Then, once we have that path,
we can use the GMSPolyline
in order to create a line that
will be displayed on the map.
And here we're using the
polylineWithPath initializer,
since we already have a path.
And just like with
markers, the way
that we turn the polyline on
or off is by setting the map
property to either
self.mapView to turn it on
or nil to turn it off.
And here you can see the
simple line drawn on the map.
We can change the
style of that line
by adjusting the strokeWidth
or the strokeColor,
which takes a UIColor object.
So here we've made the width a
little bit thicker than normal,
and we've made the
line a bright green.
Now drawing a shape
is a lot like drawing
a line, except it consists
of more than two points.
The shape gets
closed automatically
by a line connecting the
first and last points.
Then, instead of
the GMSPolyline,
we can create a GMSPolygon
using the polygonWithPath
initializer.
And just like before, we can set
the strokeWidth and the strokeColor,
and in addition, we
have a fillColor property
that lets us change
the color of the area
in between all the lines.
And then again, we
can set our polygon
to on or off by setting
it to self.mapView or nil.
And here's our polygon.
So as you can see,
it's really easy
to draw lines and shapes on the
map, but the catch to all this
is you already have to have all
of that point data somewhere.
There's some services that
provide this point data via
APIs, but a lot of them don't.
And you'll need to generate
that set of points yourself.
Once you have all
that point data,
though, you can make
very complex shapes,
like this one showing the city
limits of the city of Orlando.
One practical use of using
a polyline on the map
is showing each step
of the directions
by drawing that step along the
roads, like you can see here.
As we tap each
marker, we're drawing
all of the steps from the user
location to that destination.
So you're probably
thinking, that's going
to be a lot of different
lines to worry about,
and how am I going to find all
those exact coordinates where
they're all going to go?
Well, turns out
there's this neat thing
called the "Encoded
Polyline Algorithm Format."
And you can read
more about it here,
but we're going to
look at what you
need to draw that
line pretty easily.
What this encoded
algorithm does is
it lets you take lots and lots
of different lines on the map
and shrink them down into
one crazy looking string,
like this string right here.
And with just a
few method calls,
we'll be able to take
that crazy looking string
and turn it into
that line that you
see at the bottom
of the map there.
Back in LakeMapVC in
the viewDidLoad method,
we're creating a
GMSPath object that's
literally just that
crazy encoded string.
Then we can pass the
polylineWithPath method
to the GMSPolyline class
and provide it that string,
and that's it.
Our polyline magically
gets constructed for us,
and then we can set the
width and color of it
and add it to the map, just like
we did with our simple polyline
before.
So the real challenge here
is not creating the line,
but it's figuring out how we
can get that encoded string.
Where does that come from?
Well, if we look back to the
structure of our Directions API
JSON response and we scan all
the different fields inside
of that dictionary, there's one
that kind of jumps out at us
called overview_polyline.
That overview_polyine is
actually the encoded string.
So if we can access
that polyline,
we have the string that we need.
We're back now inside of
our Directions API request,
inside of that main
queue operation
where we set the directions
button, alpha to 1,
showing the button.
And right after that,
we'll create our GMSPath
using the overview polyline
inside of our response.
And then we'll set some
properties for that polyline's
display, and add it to the map.
Notice also that we're using
a GMSPolyline property here
to show this overview.
You can tell that because
we're using self.polyine.
As you might have
guessed, this is
because we're going to want
to turn the polyline on
and off at all at the
same times that we're
turning the directions
button on and off,
and having it as a property
makes it easy to access
those display properties
in any method.
So here's the result of
running this app right now.
You can see, as we tap a
marker, the polyline is drawn,
but we've got a problem.
With each new
marker that we tap,
the old polyline is not removed.
So let's go in and
remove it on each tap.
And that's as simple as going
to the start of this mapView
didTapMarker method and setting
the polyline's map property
to nil and then nilling out
the polyline object itself.
Remember that we want to
set the map to nil first
and then delete the object.
And now we don't have the
problem of two lines being
drawn at once, but we still
do have the problem where
after a marker is no longer
selected and we move the map,
the polyline remains.
We want to remove it then too.
So in each of our
delegate methods, we'll
turn off the
polyline when there's
a new user created marker
in the LongPress method.
We'll turn it off
whenever the map is tapped
in a location that
doesn't have a marker,
and we'll do that with the
mapView didTapAtCoordinate
method, and we'll turn it off
whenever the map is dragged
using the mapView
willMove method.
Here you can see
the final result.
It's time for you to draw
some lines and shapes
on the map in the challenges.
If you're not watching this
video on CodeSchool.com,
you can visit this
URL to get access
to all of the free
challenges for this course,
or you can learn more about
the Google Maps SDK for iOS
by visiting Google's
developer documentation.