[SINGING] The SDK for iOS
has really got my back.
There's places, modes,
and sweet controls
to make the perfect app.
From polylines and
polygons and geocoded lats,
I delegate the methods to
create the perfect map.
Directions and street views,
these are the very best.
I must confess
it's time to start
exploring Google Maps for iOS.
In this level,
we're going to learn
to work with something that's
completely unique to the Google
Maps SDK, and that's Street View.
Google has amassed a
ton of Street View data
for places all over the world.
We're going to be able
to access and interact
with that Street View
data by pinching to zoom,
panning with our finger,
and even double-tapping
to move in and out.
The app we have so far lets
us tap on a load button
to download a set of markers.
Once we have those markers
displayed, we can tap on one
and get the directions
from our current location
to that marker.
We're going to want
to set up something
similar to that
for the Street View.
To display the
street view, we'll
need a StreetView
view controller.
And let's start by comparing
that to a view controller
we already have - the
Directions view controller.
So with the Directions
view, we needed
to create and add a button
to load the Directions view
controller.
And with StreetView, we
need to also create and add
a button to load StreetView.
In both cases, we need
to only show the button
when a marker is active.
And we need to hide
that button when
the marker is no longer active.
In the case of
directions, we need
to pass the steps
for those directions
into the DirectionsVC.
And in the case of our
StreetView view controller,
we need to pass the coordinate
of where the Street View is.
So really, these are
the exact same steps
we used to set up the
Directions view controller,
except this time we're passing
a different kind of data
into the view controller.
We'll start by setting up
all the pieces we'll need.
We'll create a UIButton
property called streetViewButton
that will manage-- just like we
did the Directions view button.
We'll also create a
CLLocationCoordinate2D property
called activeMarkerCoordinate.
And we'll use that
property to store
the currently tapped marker's
location so that we can pass it
into the StreetView
view controller.
You can see here
that a great place
to do that is right at the start
of the mapView didTapMarker
method.
Because as soon as
that marker's tapped,
we can set it as
the active marker.
Then we'll have a method
that gets called whenever
the StreetView button is tapped.
I'm calling this
one showStreetView.
We'll create our
StreetView view controller.
We'll set a StreetView
view controller's
coordinate property equal to
our active marker coordinate.
And then, we'll present
the view controller.
Just like before when we showed
directions in our completion
block, we'll set the StreetView
button's alpha to zero,
so then it goes away
whenever the view
controller's presented.
And then, we'll deselect the
currently selected marker.
The app we have so far lets
us tap on a load button
to download a set of markers.
Once we have those markers
displayed, we can tap on one
and get the directions
from our current location
to that marker.
We're going to want
to set up something
similar to that
for the StreetView.
In StreetViewVC's
header, we'll need
to import the Google
Maps SDK again.
Because StreetViewVC is going
to access some of the StreetView
methods that are
part of the SDK.
We'll also need a
CLLocation2D property -
we called it "coordinate"
in the last slide
so we can pass our active
marker coordinate into this view
controller.
We usually use strong
for the memory type,
but here we have to use assign.
Because CLLocationCoordinate2D
is not an object,
it's actually a struct.
So if we give it
the assign keyword,
then everything will
work the way we want.
Our goal in this Street View
is to get and display
a panorama object.
Panorama is the name of street
views in the Google Maps SDK.
So in the viewDidAppear
method, we'll
start by creating a
GMSPanorama service.
And then we'll use
that service to request
a panorama near a coordinate.
And we'll pass in
our active marker's
coordinate into this method.
The callback will return
a GMSPanorama object
that we can use to
display the Street View.
But there's a few pieces
that we need to understand.
Here's where we are right now.
We've got a GMSPanorama
service that
is returning a GMSPanorama
for a specific coordinate.
We also need to create a
GMSPanorama camera object.
And that camera is
going to determine
which direction the
Street View is facing.
There's a few options you can
pass when creating this object,
and here's a pretty
standard start.
I'm passing 180 for the
heading, zero for the pitch,
one for the zoom,
and 90 for the FOV.
This is the StreetView
we would get
for the coordinate of
the Eiffel Tower in Paris
with these settings.
If we change the
heading from 180 to 130,
you can see the
Eiffel Tower is better
framed in the Street View.
The heading determines
which direction the camera
is pointing, from
zero to 360 degrees.
If we then changed the
pitch from zero to 30,
instead of looking straight
across the horizon,
the camera is tilted up.
And we can see more of
the top of the tower.
A pitch from one to 90
will tilt the camera up.
And a pitch of negative
1 to negative 90
will tilt the camera down.
If we were to then take the
FOV, or field of view, property
from 90 to 150, you can see that
the depth of field has changed.
And FOV between one and 90
produces a zoomed-in effect.
And a FOV between 90
and 160 looks more
like you're viewing the Street
View through the fish-eye lens.
Once we're happy with
our GMSPanoramaCamera,
we'll need to create a
GMSPanoramaView object.
This is the object
that will actually
end up displaying
the Street View.
We take the GMSPanorama
object we already
have and the PanoramaCamera.
And we apply those
to the panoramaView.
Then we'll take
that panoramicView
and replace self.view so
the Street View takes up
the entire screen.
We'll probably want a way to
close the Street View when
we're done looking at it.
So we can add a close
Street View button
to the view that
calls a method that
closes off this view controller.
We'll also want to make sure
that the Street View button
inside of our mapView
controller
goes away at the
right times so we
can control the alpha in
the LongPressAtCoordinate,
DidTapItCoordinate, and
willMove delegate methods.
So here's an example of
StreetView as it is right now.
We can find an address, turn
Street View on, look around,
close the Street View.
But look at what
happens if I try
to access the Street View
in the middle of a lake.
I just get a white screen.
What's happening here is that
there's no GMSPanorama object
that Google can find for
the middle of this lake.
Makes sense, right?
It's called Street View,
not lake view.
So we'll need to
add some extra logic
into our application for
situations like this.
Inside of our panorama
request callback,
we can first check if the
panorama object is non-nil.
If it's non-nil, that means
we have some panorama data
and we should try to show it.
If it is nil, we
can do something
like display an
alert view that says
there's no data
available for that point.
And then we can call the
close Street View method again
to make sure that
that window closes.
Now if we jump back
into our app and access
a point that has
Street View data,
we can see it just
like we could before.
But if we close
Street View and try
to access a point that might
not have Street View data,
we get an alert
view that tells us
that no data exists
for that point.
It's time for you to practice
displaying Street Views
in your own app
in the challenges.
If you're not watching this
video on CodeSchool.com,
you can visit this
URL to get access
to all the free challenges
for this course.
Or to learn more about the
Google Maps SDK for iOS,
you can visit this link to
the developer documentation.