[SINGING] Deep in
your app. there's
a space filled up
by a great database.
Its tables are where
information goes, made up of
cells inside columns and rows.
To speak to it, we can
connect using INSERT,
UPDATE, and SELECT.
With a language
that has no equal,
we need more people to Try SQL.
SQL.
Welcome to Try SQL.
My name is Chari Clark,
and I look forward
to giving you some
key points on how
to use the database programming
language known as SQL.
This course is
designed to teach you
the basics on how
to read, write,
and program in the database
language known as SQL.
Let's begin with level
one, section one —
Understanding Databases.
So the story begins
with a question.
We want to see a movie
at the Gatsby Theaters,
but we're only interested
in seeing comedies.
How can we get the titles of
all the movies that are comedies
and what can we
use to get those?
Of course, we could use
the local newspapers.
But there are so
many reasons that
make this not the
most convenient tool
to use in today's society.
Instead, we could
look at a website
for reviewing current movie
listings and run times.
With today's technology,
the biggest difference
in these two forms of media
is that only one of these
can be continuously updated,
while the newspaper will
remain static.
This makes the use of the
web much better in keeping up
to date information about almost
anything we wish to find out.
But what is it exactly that
makes a website stay updated?
Well, this is because it's
being updated by a database.
A database collects and
organizes information
so that it can be
easily retrieved.
For example, the
movie listings website
goes to a database to request
the most current showtimes
for its theater.
Believe it or not, databases are
used in most of the technology
that we use every day.
And many different services —
such as email, GPS, Facebook,
our cell phones,
Twitter, and websites —
also use databases in
some form or another.
We will be using a database to
solve some of these problems
that we will encounter
in this course.
The database that we'll use
is called the Gatsby Theaters
database, which has all
types of information.
But how is all this
information, such as movie info
and showtimes info, organized?
Our information or
data is organized
into what we call tables.
A table holds the data that
can be used in a database
and allows for it to
be easily retrieved.
The database holds four tables:
Movies, Concessions,
Showtimes, and Promotions.
So here's a question.
In order to look up
information on movies,
we would need to go
inside which database
and look inside which table?
As you can probably
see, we would
need to go inside the
Gatsby Theaters database
and look inside
the Movies table.
This is where we can
find our information.
Now, let's go a little
deeper and find out
what's inside the table.
We see the data from the website
but not quite in the same form.
What we actually see is the
same data stored and organized
into what's known
as cells or fields,
where each cell holds
a separate value that
can be accessed by a website.
These cells for each table
are organized into rows.
Basically, a row represents
an entire data record
within each table.
For example, we can look
at the first row of data
as having an ID of 1 with
a title of Metropolis,
and a genre of sci-fi, along
with having a duration of 153.
Each row is separate
from the next.
A table is also
made up of columns,
which hold similar data
for each separate value.
Each column is given
a descriptive name,
which describes the type of
data that can be found in it.
The four columns we have are
ID, title, genre, and duration.
Often, a table will have
some unique identifier, which
is used to order the rows.
Another name for this is the
primary key of the table.
Let's look at how to find
some data in our database.
Say, for example, we want
to find the value "Nosferatu."
How would we find this
value in our table?
To move through a
table in a database,
we should first
look at the columns.
We'll start with the ID column.
Since there are no
matching records here,
we move to the right
one column to find
that the matching record
is in the title column.
Next is to search by row.
Let's move through each
row in the column of title
and find Nosferatu.
We find that Nosferatu
is in the title column
and on the second row.
Generally, tables will contain
fewer columns than rows.
So, while the table may
have over a million rows,
it may have only a couple
of hundred columns.
The search path first moves
through the columns from left
to right.
And then we search the
rows from top to bottom.
That's all we have
for section one.
Now let's look at
some challenges
to help reinforce
these concepts.