Welcome back to Try SQL.
I hope you enjoyed
those challenges.
In this section, we'll get our
first taste of using the SQL
programming language.
We now know about
databases, tables,
and how they're used every day.
But how do we actually talk
to this database thingy?
Well, the answer is simple.
Three letters.
SQL, or better known as SQL.
SQL is a programming
language that allows
us to interact with a database.
More or less, we provide the
database with the SQL code,
and it produces a result.
But is it really
that cut and dry?
Let's take a closer look.
When working with a database,
SQL language or code
is written in statements that
ask the database to perform
many different commands.
First, some code is written.
The database receives the
code and processes it.
And finally, the data
reaches its destination
and the results are given.
Simple, right?
Let's take a look at our
example from section one.
The browser sends out a request,
which would be the SQL code,
and this goes to the database.
The database returns the result
and the updated movie showtimes
are available back
on the website.
Here we see that
the browser uses
the exact same process
we discussed earlier
to obtain these results.
So now we're ready to do
a few things with SQL.
We have the original
issue of finding
all of the movie titles being
shown at the Gatsby Theaters.
But let's add a few more
tasks to really show
how useful SQL can be.
First, we want to get a list
of all the movies and all
the information about them.
Next, we want to find
just the title of a movie
with an ID of 2.
Lastly, we want to retrieve
all the movies that
have the title The Kid.
Let's take a look
at a SQL recipe
that will return the precise
results that we're looking for.
To do this, we're going
to use a SELECT statement.
In the SELECT recipe, we
have SELECT blank FROM blank.
The first blank
is where we would
enter the name of
the column from which
we want to get some data.
And the second
blank is the table
where the data is located.
Additionally, all SQL
statements must have a semicolon
at the end to complete
the statement.
Let's tackle the
original question
of retrieving all the movie
titles from the Gatsby
Theaters.
Here we have the Movies table
and all of its contents.
We want to write a SQL SELECT
statement that will return
a list of all movie titles.
To do this, we will
use the SELECT recipe
and write SELECT title, which
is the column we're interested
in, and then FROM movies,
which is the table the title
column is located in.
Only a single
column was selected
from which to get some data.
So the result will contain
only this column's data
for any matching rows.
So now if we run this
awesome SQL code,
we'll see that the Gatsby
Theater database returns
all the requested titles.
Since we didn't give the database
any more specific requests,
it will return
all of the titles.
Looking at our
next task, we want
to list all of the movies
and the information
that goes along with them.
Check out this
first box of code.
You can see here
that we can actually
select more than one column.
This statement would
return all movie titles
as before, but along with the
genre for those movies as well.
With that in mind, it's possible
to add all of our columns
to the SELECT statement,
as shown in the second box.
This would return all
data in all columns.
What if you had 100,000 columns?
You wouldn't want to list
all of those out, right?
It turns out we have
an alternate way
of signaling all columns.
If we were to run the SELECT
statement with the asterisk,
we would have all of the
movies and their data returned,
as if we had listed
out all the columns.
Pretty cool, right?
Alright.
So now we know we can
go to the database
and get all of our data,
which is, of course, useful.
But what if we only
wanted to retrieve
a small portion of that data?
We can filter or
pinpoint the data
we want to find by using
a WHERE clause at the end
of our SELECT statement.
If we look here at
our WHERE recipe box,
we can see the WHERE
clause at the end.
Let's show the
effectiveness of adding this
by now requesting the movie
title with an ID of 2.
In order to retrieve the title
of a movie with an ID of 2,
we would include a
WHERE ID equals 2
at the end of the
SELECT statement.
This will allow us to return a
more well-defined set of data,
specifically all titles
to all movies that
happen to have an ID of 2.
This bit of SQL will first
select all columns named title
from the table called Movies.
Next, the database
finds the ID column
and seeks where the
ID of the movie is 2.
Look at that first box.
Is that ID correct?
No, clearly not.
So now let's look
further down the column.
With one more step —
aha, we found a match
where the ID is, in fact, 2.
If we find a row that
meets all the conditions
of our WHERE clause, the
database will pull that row
and get it ready for returning.
But it's not done searching yet.
So we found one correct
row, but the database
doesn't know if there are
any other rows with that ID.
So the last two rows
are also searched
for matching conditions.
Turns out, though,
that there aren't any.
So now, with the
search complete, we
find that the cell
that contains Nosferatu
is the data that
we're looking for.
And since we are only
selecting one column,
right, which is title, then
only the data from that column
is returned.
What if instead we wanted to
search for a string of data,
such as a word or a phrase?
SQL will allow us
do this as well.
We can use actual
words in what can
be seen as a string of
letters or characters
to search for matching
words within that table.
Here, we are
searching all columns
by using the star within
the table Movies, where
inside the column title,
there is a record that
matches The Kid exactly.
Because we are selecting
all data from movies,
we know that all
records are first
considered for the search.
The WHERE clause allows us
to focus on the column title
as the first filter.
And within that column,
we find a matching record
for The Kid, which is the
record we're looking for.
Something to be aware of
when performing searches
of this type — check out how
we have the single quotes
around the string value.
We use these when
we are selecting
exact sequences of characters
that we want to match.
In other words, you will need
to use single quotes when
doing searches of this type.
And that is all for section two.
Now it's time for
some more challenges.
We'll see you in
the next section.