Welcome back to Try SQL.
I hope you're having
as much fun as I am.
Let's continue.
In section three, we'll
be guiding data criteria.
In the previous
section, we found out
how to select and filter
data that we wanted to find.
But what if we wanted to sort
this data in a special way?
For example, what if we wanted
to find all movie titles
and sort these by their duration
or their length of movie time?
To achieve this goal,
we'll use a new SQL recipe.
We'll call it the
ORDER BY recipe.
Let's take a look.
We use the SELECT and FROM
clauses as we normally have,
but we add an ORDER BY
clause after the FROM clause.
This allows us to sort
the data by columns based
on how we choose to view it.
So back to the question at hand.
We want to retrieve
all movie titles
but sort them by duration.
To start, we have to select
these from the title column.
When using the
ORDER BY clause, we
can also choose
which way to view
the data, in either ascending
or descending order.
So keeping in mind
that we are looking
for results from
the title column,
we must also remember that
we are sorting the title
column based on which
duration is the lowest.
This is one of the advantages
of using the ORDER BY clause.
Now, if we run the
SELECT statement,
we can see that the film titles
are returned to us in ascending
order, or lowest to highest.
This means that the titles
are sorted by lowest duration
first, but that the title
with the highest duration
is to be last because
the duration is growing
as more results are returned.
Notice that we aren't getting
any duration results back,
just the titles
organized by duration.
But this can be
done the other way
around by returning the
film titles in what's
known as descending order.
This means that the titles
are returned with the highest
duration time first and
descends all the way
until the title with the
lowest duration is returned.
Notice that DESC is used to
denote what the ORDER BY clause
will return in this fashion.
SQL automatically assumes
that if this is not given,
the sort order will be
returned in ascending order,
as we saw previously.
So now we've found
a few different ways
to improve SQL searches by
including some search criteria.
But what if we wanted to
return specific ranges of data
based on comparison by
including some boundary value?
As an example, let's
retrieve all films
that have a duration of
over 100 minutes using SQL.
We're not looking
for films that have
exactly 100 minutes, but
rather all films that have more
than that.
We will use the SELECT
FROM WHERE recipe
and include a comparison
operator between two objects.
Here, you can see the
special comparison operator.
The greater than sign,
commonly used in mathematics,
to signify that all
items in this column
are greater than what is to the
right of the greater than sign.
But guess what?
We've already introduced
a comparison operator.
That's right.
The equal sign is a
type of comparison.
The query here
retrieves no records
which provide a true
result when compared,
because no film has a duration
that is exactly 100 minutes.
But if we use the greater
than sign in the WHERE clause,
we retrieve the above record.
Since the duration
for Metropolis
is compared to all movie
durations in the table,
it is the only film
in the table that
has a duration that is
greater than or longer
than 100 minutes.
There are other
comparison operators
used in SQL that we want
to illustrate for you.
First, by adding the
less than operator,
the query will
return all records
with a duration of
less than 100 minutes.
If we exchange it for the
greater than or equal to sign,
the query will
retrieve all records
where the duration is greater
than or equal to 94 minutes.
And finally, if
it were exchanged
for the less than
or equal to sign,
the query will
retrieve all records
where the duration is less
than or equal to 95 minutes.
We have one last
comparison operator,
which kind of looks like a
strange less than/greater
than thing.
What the heck is that?
Well, this operator
finds all records
that do not match the search
criteria we're looking for.
This is the not equal to sign.
Say, for example, you want
to see all movies that
are not horror films.
You could use the not equal
to sign to compare all
records that do not have a
genre of horror, as shown.
Metropolis, The Kid,
and The Gold Rush
do not have a genre of horror.
Next up, what would
we do if we wanted
to find data with multiple
specific conditions to match?
How would we accomplish this?
Let's say, for
example, that we are
asked to find all records
which have both an ID of 1
and a genre of comedy.
How can we do this with SQL?
We are presented with a new
operator — the AND operator —
and with that, a new SQL recipe.
We can use a normal
SELECT FROM WHERE clause.
At the end of the
statement, the AND operator
is added to help
add matching yet
specific criteria for a search.
Looking back at
the Movies table,
in SQL, when using the AND
operator, part of the criteria
is that all the conditions
of the SELECT statement
must be met.
As we see here, when we try
to use it on the Movies table,
we perform the SELECT
statement and find
that there are no records that
match all of the criteria we
are searching for.
But if we change the genre
of the film Metropolis
to comedy from sci-fi, now
we'll get some useful results.
So, taking into consideration
that both the WHERE and the AND
conditions must be met, we see
that all the data with an ID
of 1 is first located.
And then those items
are searched for genres
matching comedy.
Based on our new genre
switch, only the first title,
Metropolis, meets all of the
conditions for that search.
Now, let's look at another
way to return data
based on matching criteria.
What if, instead of finding
all film titles which
have both an ID of 1
and a genre of comedy,
we search for all film
titles with either an ID of 1
or a genre of comedy.
SQL offers us another
new piece of syntax
to handle this scenario:
the OR keyword, along
with a new SQL recipe.
First, we use the SELECT FROM
WHERE clause, as we've done.
And at the end of
the statement, we
add the OR operator to look for
matching criteria in the query.
Looking at the OR
operator, when referencing
two or more separate conditions,
either one of the criteria
can be met for a
SELECT statement
to return matching results.
In the SELECT
statement shown here,
we are simply looking for either
the record to have an ID of 1
or have a genre of comedy.
Turns out the table has two
records in the title column
that match the search criteria.
As we see, Metropolis
has an ID of 1
and also happens to
have a genre of comedy,
while The Kid just
has a genre of comedy.
And since each of
these titles has
one of the allowable
criteria, they
both get returned in our result.
This is all for section
three and also for level one.
Now it's time for some more
fun challenges with SQL.
We'll see you back
in the next level.
It's time to suck less at SQL.
We can reinforce these issues.
Say.
Something to be aware —
A werewolf?
A werewolf, yeah.