[SINGING] Deep in
your app, there's
a space filled up
by a great database.
Its tables are where
information goes, made up of
cells inside columns and rows.
To speak to it, we can
connect using INSERT,
UPDATE, and SELECT.
With a language
that has no equal,
we need more people to Try SQL.
SQL.
Welcome back to
level two of Try SQL.
In the previous
levels, we looked
at ways of getting
data out of the tables.
In this next level,
we'll look at ways
of adding data to the tables.
Okay, great.
We now know how to access
data in our Movies table,
but what would we want to
do if we wanted to add more
data to what we currently have?
Let's say we have a new film
called The Circus that we wish
to add to the table of Movies.
It's a comedy with a
duration of 71 minutes.
Let's add it to the table.
To start, in order to add
a new record to an existing
table in SQL, we'll use what's
known as an INSERT statement.
Here we have the
INSERT recipe, which
has some new concepts
for us to look at.
The SQL statement begins
with the INSERT INTO,
which indicates to SQL that
we wish to add new data.
Next, is the table to which
we wish to add the data.
And we follow it up with
a set of parentheses
that indicate the column
or columns to which we
want to add the data.
The VALUES keyword comes next.
And after that, we place
the actual data values
that are going to be
added to the table.
Looking at the Movies table,
we know we have four records.
But now, we wish to
add a new fifth record
by inserting a film
with the title
The Circus along with
its genre of comedy
and its duration of 71 minutes.
So first, we add the
INSERT INTO clause,
the table we'll be inserting
data into — in this case,
movies —
and the columns where
the data will go.
We specify the
column names to let
the database know into
which column each value
will be added.
The order of these
columns doesn't matter,
but it must match the
order of your inserted data,
if you want the data to
get to the right place.
Finally, the actual
values are entered.
Check out those
quotes surrounding
the strings of characters.
Remember those?
Very important.
So we execute the
INSERT INTO statement
and see that the Movies table
goes from having four rows
or records to having five rows.
As with many things
in SQL, there
are different ways to
add data to a table,
some better than others.
Here, we see that we could
have done the same thing
but omitting the columns
from the SQL statement.
This works since we
are inserting data
into all of the columns.
Both statements
do the same thing,
but the bottom statement
shows a quicker way
to write the code, which
saves the developer time.
Here, the order of the
values definitely needs
to match the order
of the columns.
Now, do we actually have to
add data to every column
to add data to the table?
Not at all.
In fact, here are
a couple examples
to show you how to
accomplish this with SQL.
We could add a row which
only has an ID and a title.
You can see this fills
in only an ID and a title
for that new record.
Or, we could simply
add a row that
includes the title and
the duration alone.
Something important
to check out here:
Did you catch how the ID was set
even though we didn't set it?
Why did this happen?
Let's take a look.
So this ID column over
here is serving as what's
known as our primary key.
Basically a primary
key is a unique column,
meaning that every
record in that column
has a distinct value from
all other present values.
This field will never
be blank or empty.
Our Movies table happens to
use a numerical primary key.
But how did the ID column
get that value of 6
for the new row?
SQL can automatically increment
the primary key for a table
by allowing a
higher number to be
generated when a new record
is inserted into a table.
Since our primary
key is the ID, it
will be automatically
incremented
by the database each time a
row is added to the table.
This is now the new
row with an ID of 6.
Also, you may be wondering what
value the genre column holds
within our new row.
Well, believe it or not,
SQL uses a unique value
to hold place for the
data in this spot.
The data in this field is seen
as null data or a NULL value.
A NULL value is
used to represent
a field with missing data.
The field with the NULL
value may appear to be blank,
but this is only because
having data for this column
is optional.
Therefore, a NULL
value can be seen also
as a placeholder for
unknown or unavailable data.
This is all for level
two, section one.
Now it's time for
some more challenges.
We'll see you back
in the next section.