Welcome back to Try SQL.
Let's continue with
section two of level two.
Here, we'll look at changing
current data in our tables.
Alright.
We've learned how to do
some pretty good things,
like selecting existing
data and adding
new data to our database.
But how will we update existing
data currently in our database?
We want to use SQL to change
the genre for the film
The Circus from
comedy to romance.
To change movie
information that currently
exists in the database,
we'll use what's
called an UPDATE statement.
In an UPDATE recipe, we
have the UPDATE keyword,
which lets the database
know that we want to change
some data in the database.
The following blank
will contain the table
where we want the
update to take place.
Next, we see the SET keyword,
which tells the database both
the column that
we wish to update
and the new data value we want
to place within that column
after the equal sign.
The parentheses in this recipe
indicate that a WHERE clause
is optional here.
If we were to use
a WHERE clause,
we can pinpoint parts
of a column to update.
If we use no WHERE
clause, the entire column
will update for all rows.
Back in the Movies
table, we realize
that the new film isn't actually
a comedy, but it's a romance.
So now we have to change the
genre of the film The Circus.
But how do we do that?
Let's use the UPDATE recipe
to change the existing row.
First, we use the
UPDATE keyword followed
by the table we wish to update,
which is, of course, movies.
Next, we set the
genre to romance.
Lastly and importantly,
we use a WHERE clause
to signal that we only
want a column update
where the ID of the
film is equal to 5.
Once we run the
UPDATE statement,
we see that the genre
of the film The Circus
has been successfully changed
from comedy to romance.
Another great thing
about SQL is that we
are able to change multiple
columns within a row.
This is done by simply
adding each column name along
with an updated value
and separating each
of those changes with a comma.
We can change the genre of
The Circus back to comedy
and change the duration time to
70 — all in the same statement.
Cool, right?
This update thing
gets even better.
Check it out.
SQL will let us make changes to
different rows at the same time
by adding an OR to
the WHERE clause.
This will allow us to pinpoint
even more rows to update than
by using just one criteria.
If you have multiple
criteria, you
can string together
several OR statements
to get everything you need.
UPDATE statements can be very
powerful and useful in SQL.
And that's it for section two.
Now for some more challenges.
And we'll see you back
in the next section.