Welcome back to Try SQL.
In section three, we'll find
out how to remove some data.
We now know how to select,
add, and update data
with an existing
table on a database.
But what if we want to actually
remove data from a table?
Let's look at removing the
film The Circus from our Movies
table.
In order to remove data
from an existing table,
we will need to use
the DELETE statement.
The DELETE keyword is used
to tell the database that we
wish to remove some data.
It's followed by
the FROM keyword
and the table which contains
the data we wish to remove.
As we know, we can
use a WHERE condition
to help pinpoint where the
change will take place.
Let's say we wish to take the
film The Circus off the marquee
at the Gatsby Theater.
How do we remove it?
Of course, we'll delete it.
The DELETE statement
can be used to remove
only the rows from
the table that
match specific conditions
indicated by the WHERE clause.
The FROM keyword is followed
by the table, which is Movies.
And the row is specified
with the WHERE clause.
Let's take a look at
why the WHERE clause
is so important in this case.
If we execute the
DELETE statement,
we see that the row has
been successfully removed
from the Movies table.
But now, what would have
happened if we had not
used that WHERE clause?
Turns out, disaster
would have happened.
We would have completely removed
all the data from the table.
It is typically not advisable
to perform this type of delete
because once the data
has been deleted,
it is almost impossible
to recover that data once
performed.
Lucky for us, we
didn't do that, right?
We can, however, remove
multiple rows from a table
because sometimes
we need to do that.
One of the ways we
could accomplish this
is to possibly include one
of our friendly comparison
operators in a WHERE statement.
In this example,
the SQL code shows
how we would remove all
rows with a duration
of less than 100 minutes.
As you can see, the DELETE
statement is very powerful.
And it's one to
be used with much
caution to avoid laying
waste to your data.
That's all for level two.
We're going to give you
some more challenges
and we'll see you back
in the next level.
Romance.
SQL offers —
SQL offers us
another piece of —