[SINGING] Deep in
your app, there's
a space filled up
by a great database.
Its tables are where
information goes, made up of
cells inside columns and rows.
To speak to it, we can
connect using INSERT,
UPDATE, and SELECT.
With a language
that has no equal,
we need more people to Try SQL.
SQL.
Welcome to the third level
of the Try SQL course.
Let's continue with some more
exciting topics in the database
language called SQL.
Here's in section one, we'll
be creating and removing
databases and tables.
So far, we have
learned quite a bit
about how to retrieve and
manipulate data using SQL.
Now, let's take a look at how
to create databases and tables
as well as alter
the actual table
structure within a database.
So how can we use SQL to create
a completely new database?
We will add a new theater
to the list of databases.
Our next task will be
adding a new theater
to the list of databases.
But how can we do
that using SQL?
Let's take a look.
First, let's review
the structure
of the first database:
Gatsby Theaters.
The original Gatsby Theaters
contained four tables.
We wish to create a
database similar to this.
We will call the new database
the Chaplin Theaters.
It will be empty at
first, containing no data.
Taking a cue from
the Gatsby Theaters,
we know that we'll
need four tables.
Let's see how to
get to that point.
To establish a totally new
database on our server,
we will use a brand new SQL
recipe call the CREATE DATABASE
recipe.
Basically, it starts with the
CREATE DATABASE key phrase,
which is the SQL statement
to create a database,
followed by the name
the database will have.
We execute the CREATE
DATABASE statement and — voila —
we have a brand new database
called the Chaplin Theaters.
Since it is a new database,
it is also an empty database.
But we'll see how to
change that very soon.
Before we look at adding
tables, structure, and data,
and all those things
to this new database,
let's also see what it would
take to completely remove
a database.
Scary, right?
For example, say
we realized that we
don't need a new Chaplin
Theaters database at all.
How would we get rid of that?
When we remove a database,
be it old or new,
it is known as
dropping a database.
So for that, we'll use what
is called the DROP DATABASE
recipe.
It starts with the
DROP DATABASE statement
to remove the database.
And it's followed by the
database we wish to remove.
But be careful.
When removing or
dropping a database,
it's important to remember
that once the DROP DATABASE
statement is executed,
the database and all
of its contents will
no longer be available.
So, if we actually ran
this SQL statement,
the new Chaplin
Theaters database
would have been
completely removed.
But we're glad we didn't
do that since we still
have plans for it.
Okay.
Let's assume we did
not drop our database
and that we still have
our database set up
for Chaplin Theaters.
Let's see how to create a
table inside of that database.
We want to create a Movies table
inside of the Chaplin Theaters
database that will hold
data for other films
that we wish to list.
We will use the CREATE
TABLE recipe to do this.
The CREATE TABLE portion
signals that a new table will
be created on the database.
Followed by the name we
want our table to have.
A set of parentheses
surrounds the table structure,
while inside the
parentheses we state
the name we wish the columns to
have, followed by a data type.
Now, don't be scared
of these data types.
They just tell us what
kind of value the column
must contain.
When creating a table, every
column must have a data type.
And we use a comma to separate
each column in our list.
Looking at how we wish to
create the new database,
based on Gatsby
Theaters, we know
that we have the data for
movie info, concessions
info, showtime info,
and promotions info.
You may notice none of this
data has any table structure.
The first table we will
add to the new database
will be the Movies table, which
will hold the movie info data.
Before we actually
create the table,
let's take a look at how we
want the columns inside to look.
So if we're looking
at the raw data,
this is how it will look in
all of its shining glory.
Not so impressive, right?
In many instances,
table data is taken
from spreadsheets
or other sources
in some format or another.
It is from these sources
where we'll decide
how to build the table columns.
From the spreadsheet,
we see that we
have four columns of data.
Each one of these columns
has a different kind of value,
which will help us
determine how we will create
new columns in the table.
Over here, the first
column has the title of ID.
It appears to be made up of
only numbers which continuously
grow incrementally.
So when we look at
the new Movies table,
we will name the
first column ID.
And since this column
will hold only numbers,
we will give it a data type of
INT, which is used primarily
for numbers or integers.
Since we also wish
for the numbers
to grow incrementally in this
column as we add more data,
we will use this column
as the primary key.
Now, a primary key can be set
in a number of different ways,
and we'll look at those
ways in the next course.
But for now, just know that
ID is serving as a primary key
and will automatically be
incremented as data is added.
Next, we have the title
column from the grid of data.
It looks like this column is
where the film names are given,
but could be letters
and/or numbers
depending on the actual
name of the movie title.
Knowing this, we will give the
second column a name of title
with a data type of VARCHAR.
This data type
allows the data here
to have a variable length
of letters and numbers
within this field.
Let's give this data type a
length of 50 digits, which means
that no matter what
the data is here,
it cannot be longer than
50 character spaces.
The third column
on the spreadsheet
has a name of
genre, which appears
to hold a description of the
type of film for each movie.
This value, like the
previous title column,
is made up of a string
of letters as well.
Like the title column, we
will make the genre column
a data type of VARCHAR.
Usually a film's title
can be longer or shorter
than its description.
Therefore, we'll give the
genre a lower maximum
variable character length of 15.
The last column
from our data grid,
duration, looks like
it only holds numbers.
So based on that
fact, we can finally
name the last column duration,
and give it a data type of INT.
The data type may appear to
be the same as that of ID,
but we know that movie
times can be the same.
Therefore, this column will
not be the primary key
or hold unique values.
Once we run the SQL
CREATE TABLE statement,
we can see that we
have successfully
created the Movies table inside
the Chaplin Theaters database.
There are many
different data types,
which can have a lot of
different properties.
More information on
these can be found
on the web in a
number of places,
but we'll leave this up to
you to research as you wish.
Looking at the new
table, do we actually
have any data inside of it?
Not yet.
So it looks like it's
time to add or INSERT
some data into the table, which
we already know how to do.
But let's say for some
reason that the new table
wasn't created correctly.
How would we remove it from
the Chaplin Theaters database?
Like removing a database,
we would drop a table
from a database to remove it.
Let's take a look.
Here, we have the
DROP TABLE recipe
where we signify that a table
is to be removed with the DROP
TABLE statement, followed
by the name of the table
we want to remove.
Looking at the Chaplin
Theaters database,
here's what would take place if
we chose to remove the Movies
table from the database.
We would run our DROP TABLE
statement, removing the table
from the database entirely.
It would no longer be available
to use by the Chaplin Theaters
database.
And that's all there is for this
first section of level three.
Now it's time for
some more challenges,
and we'll see you back
in the next section.