Welcome back to Try SQL
level three, section two.
In this section, we'll show
you how to manipulate tables
within a database.
So, how would we add, change,
or even remove an entire column
from an existing table?
Let's first start by
adding the ratings column
to our Movies table.
We do want to see how well
a movie is doing, right?
We have a new SQL recipe, which
we'll call the ALTER TABLE ADD
recipe.
We first give the ALTER
TABLE command, followed
by the table we want to change.
Next, we issue an
ADD COLUMN clause
stating that we want to add a
column to the indicated table.
This is followed by the name
of the new column and the data
type we want it to have.
So now if we take our
ALTER TABLE ADD recipe
and supply the
table name of movies
along with the new column named
ratings and a data type of INT,
here's what the SQL
code will look like.
We give the data type as
INT because we wish to rate
these films from 1 to 10.
We run this SQL statement
and see that the new column
ratings is now created.
But all the fields are empty.
Let's update these fields
with some actual data.
Since we currently have data
in the columns of the Chaplin
Theaters database, issuing
these separate UPDATE
commands will change only the
field in the ratings column.
We use the WHERE
clause to pinpoint
which title needs to get the
rating indicated by the set
keyword.
Then we'll execute
all of the statements
and find that our new
ratings column has
some data of its own.
Cool.
But what if we no
longer needed a column?
We can remove it by issuing
the ALTER TABLE DROP statement.
Let's drop or remove the
ratings column altogether.
The DROP COLUMN clause deletes
a column in an existing table.
As we see, no more ratings
column to be found.
Death to critics.
There are tons of other
great and useful things
we can use SQL for, but we'll
get to those in later courses.
For now, thanks for
joining us for Try SQL.
Let's finish strong and
complete these final challenges.
Thanks for using Code School.
We'll see you soon.
Column from —
We'll see you in the next course.
Thank you for
joining Code School.
Welcome back to Try SQL.
Let's get back to
trying some SQL.
This guy.
I just — I just.