[SINGING] So you learned
your database ABCs —
more than foreign
and primary keys.
Aggregate functions
you'll wax within —
they're count, sum,
average, max, and min.
Make it sleek,
add a few constraints
to stop unique
and null complaints.
Use check, joins, and
a few subqueries.
The Sequel to SQL
is the bee's knees.
You're watching
The Sequel to SQL.
I'm Gregg Pollack.
And if you're a
beginner to SQL, make
sure you've taken
our Try SQL course.
Otherwise, if you
already know the basics,
you're in the right place.
In this first level,
we're going to take a look
at common aggregate functions.
So here's our Movies database.
How would we find
the total number
of rows in this Movies table?
Well, we could select
all the information out
of the Movies table and
then programmatically,
in whatever we're
using, count the number
of rows that were returned.
But there's a better
way to do this.
And that is using the
count aggregate function.
You see that syntax down there?
We say select count,
put a star in between
two parentheses,
and that's going to give
us the total number of rows
in this Movies table —
in this case, four.
It's worth noting that count
star will count all the rows,
regardless of any null values.
In this level, we're going
to take a look at five
different aggregate functions.
And here are their recipes.
First, there's count.
We saw that a minute ago.
We can also add up
a column using sum.
We can find the average
of a column using average.
We can find the largest
value in a column using max.
Or we can find the smallest
value in a column using min.
These last four are only going
to work if your column contains
numbers.
So before, we used count
star to signify that we
wanted to count all the rows.
But we can also put a column
name inside of our count
aggregate function.
In this case, if
we do count title,
it's going to count
all of the rows that
have a title which are not
null — in this case, three.
Next, how do we find the total
cost of producing all our movies?
Well, we need to add up
all of the cost column.
We can do that using the
sum aggregate function.
We'll say select sum
cost from Movies.
It'll add up all the
values in the cost column
and give us back this result.
What if we wanted to find
the average number of tickets
sold for all movies,
given this database table?
We could run select
average tickets from Movies
and it would return 1,017.
What if we wanted to find
the number of tickets
sold for the most popular movie
and the least popular movie?
In this case, we could do
select max tickets from Movies
and we would get back 1,500.
And we could also select
min tickets from Movies
to get the least
number of tickets sold.
Max returns the highest
value in that column,
and min returns
the lowest value.
When it comes to
aggregate functions,
we can combine them to get back
different pieces of information
all at the same time.
For example, here's max and
min in the same statement.
Now it's time for
you to have some fun
with aggregate functions
in the challenges.
And, hey, while
you're out, maybe
check out The Case of
the Insignificant White
Space at a Code School
theater near you.
It's not really a movie, but
it's kind of funny, isn't it?