Welcome back.
In this section, we're
going to look deeper
at aggregate functions
and figure out
how to filter data to provide
more accurate results.
Here we are back in
our Movies table.
Notice we've added a genre
column with romance and horror.
What if we wanted to find
the cost of all these movies
but grouped by genre?
So, the cost of all romance
movies, and the cost
of all horror movies?
If we use the sum
aggregate function
like we did before and
just summed up the cost,
it would be the cost
of all the movies.
But we don't want that.
How would we get just the cost
of romance and horror grouped
together?
We do this using
the group by clause.
So down in our select
statement, first, we
specify the genre, because we
want that to be listed next
to the cost.
And then we say group by genre.
As you can see,
what this returns
is a list of all the genres and
a sum total of the cost of each
of them.
The recipe for using
genre looks something
like this, where we
have to specify a column
name, an aggregate function,
and then at the bottom,
specify what to group it by.
We've gone ahead and built out
a larger Movies table with more
movies and more genres.
Notice we now have a
comedy genre in there.
If we run our same
select statement,
you can see we get
back the genres
and the total cost of all
the movies in those genres.
But what if we
only wanted genres
that appear more than once
to be a part of our result?
In this case, we only
have one comedy film.
So, how could we filter
that out of the results,
to only have groups that
have two genres in them?
We can do this using
the having clause.
In this case, right under
our group by statement,
we can say having count
star greater than one,
which means only
list groups that
have more than one row
associated with them.
In this case, comedy
only has one row,
so it doesn't get
listed in our result.
Adding to our
recipe, you can see
we've added the having clause
after our group by clause,
and it needs an aggregate
function, column name,
operator, and value.
You might also
notice we have where
in here, which can
be useful when you're
doing these types of queries.
For example, what
if we only wanted
to count movies who have grossed
at least a million dollars?
We would use a SQL
statement, which
looks something like this.
So, let's walk through
the execution of this.
First, when it hits
that where clause,
it filters out all
the movies that are
less than a million dollars.
In this case, it's Gone with
the Wind and Some Scary Movie
at the bottom.
And then using
the having clause,
it'll filter out any
of the groups that
only have one movie in them.
In this case, it's our
Not So Funny Movie.
And here's the result
that gets returned.
That's all I got for level one.
It's time for you to have some
fun with group by and having
in the challenges.
Regardless or not, if there
are null values — regardless if
there are null values.
I can do it.
Without further ado.
Group by claws.
Claws.