[SINGING] So you learned
your database ABCs —
more than foreign
and primary keys.
Aggregate functions
you'll wax within —
they're count, sum,
average, max, and min.
Make it sleek,
add a few constraints
to stop unique
and null complaints.
Use check, joins,
and a few subqueries.
The Sequel to SQL
is the bee's knees.
You're watching
The Sequel to SQL.
And this is level
two, where we're
going to be taking a
look at constraints.
You know when you have the tools
to insert millions of rows
of data into your table.
But how do you prevent
bad or unwanted data
from getting in there?
This is where
constraints come in.
Here's the SQL we would use
to create the Promotions table.
And with the creation of
this table, if we then
go to insert a row,
you might notice
that we can insert a row which
has a null name value, which
is bad.
We need to make sure that our
promotions always have a name.
And how might we do that?
We can do this using
the not null constraint.
So we modify our
create table syntax
and specify not null
on the name column.
Then when we go to insert
into the Promotions table,
without the name,
our database is
going to throw back an
error letting us know
we're not allowed to do that.
Thumbs up, this is a good error.
We wanted this to happen
to prevent bad data
from getting in our table.
As you can see, the default
behavior of our database
is very permissive.
This is why sometimes
we use constraints.
Constraints can help us prevent
null values, like we just saw.
It can ensure column
values are unique.
And lastly, they can provide
additional validations,
which we'll get into.
So here we are back in
our Promotions table.
And you can see we already have
a promotion called matinee.
Now, if we insert
another promotion,
we can actually create
another promotion
that also has that same name
of matinee, which isn't good.
We want to prevent
those duplicate values.
And the database behavior, by
default, doesn't prevent that.
By using the unique
column constraint,
we can prevent duplicate values.
So now, when we insert
into Promotions,
it will properly
send back an error.
Now, all the values in the
name column must be unique.
As you might have noticed, we
can use multiple constraints
per column.
In this case, name has
both not null and unique.
If we take a closer look
at this error message,
it says, "duplicate
key value violates
unique constraint
'promotions_name_key.'"
This is the constraint
name automatically assigned
by the database.
But sometimes, we
might want to define
the name of our constraint.
It'll make it easier
to alter it later.
We can do this by assigning
a unique table constraint.
The syntax to create
one looks like this.
We specify constraint; our
custom name, which in this case
is unique name; the constraint
we want to apply, in this case,
unique; and then the target
column, in this case, name.
Now if we try to insert a
duplicate promotion name,
we get back the
same error message.
But this time it uses the name
we specified — unique name.
Let's take a look at
the two different ways
we can create a unique
constraint on our name column.
On the bottom, you can
see our table constraint.
And on the top, like before,
is our column constraint.
These create the same behavior.
Except for not null,
every column constraint
can also be written
as a table constraint.
So we couldn't use the
table constraint syntax
and say not null before unique.
It just wouldn't work.
What if it was okay to have a
promotion with the same name?
But we would never
want a promotion
with both the same name
and the same category.
Could we make that unique?
Well, you can specify any
number of columns inside your
unique constraint.
In this case, we can
specify name comma category.
And now, if we try to
insert into the Promotions
table a row with
both the same name
and category — in this case,
half off and discount —
it's not going to
let us because it
matches both the name and
category with an existing
record.
In a relational database,
it's recommended
that every table have
something called a primary key.
Usually, this is the id column.
And primary keys are important
to be both unique and not null.
So this, here, this
wouldn't be good.
By adding the primary key
constraint to our id column,
it means that IDs cannot be
null and they must be unique.
So now, if we try to
insert a promotion
with the same id of one
that already exists,
it's going to give us an
error message that tells us
we violated the
unique constraint
on our primary key column.
Similarly, if we try to insert
a promotion without an ID,
it's going to tell us that
the null value in column ID
violates our not
null constraint.
You might be wondering, what
is the difference between using
a primary key constraint and a
not null and unique constraint,
because they kind of
have the same behavior.
And that is, that a
primary key can only
be defined once per table,
while multiple
columns on a table
can have a not null and unique
constraint, like you see here.
Time for you to have fun with
constraints in the challenges.
And don't forget to see the new
movie coming from Code School,
You Only Truncate Once.