Welcome back.
In this section, we're
going to be talking
about value constraints.
So here, you see we have a
Promotions table and a Movies
table.
And we need to associate
specific promotions
with our movies.
How might we do that?
Well, we could put a title
column inside our Promotions
table and reference
the movie that way,
but that would be duplicating
data — feels dirty.
But a better way
to do this would
be to reference the movie's
primary key — that id column —
from the Promotions table.
So, here you can see we've
created a movie_id column.
And that references the ID
column in the Movies table.
When creating these
types of references,
there's a common
naming convention.
We singularize the table we're
referencing — in this case,
"movie" — and then we use
an underscore followed
by the column name —
in this case, "id."
There's a name for this type of
column, and it's a foreign key.
A foreign key is a
column in one table
that references the primary
key column in another table.
So in this case, the movie_id
column is a foreign key
referencing the primary key
column — in this case, "id" —
of the Movies table.
Using these new
tables, how do you
think I would find promotions
for the movie Gone
With the Wind?
Well, I would have
to do two queries.
First, if I didn't
know it already,
I would have to find the id for
the movie Gone With the Wind
like so.
That would return the value 2.
I can then use that value in a
second query on the Promotions
table to get the name
and the category.
And I would need to specify the
foreign key movie_id equals 2.
What would happen if we
inserted a new promotion
and specified an invalid
movie_id — in this case, 999?
It would work.
It would actually
insert this row.
But, of course, if we
looked in our Movies table,
we wouldn't see any
movie with the id of 999.
The solution to this problem
is a foreign key constraint.
But before we get
into that, we need
to take a look at our
create table statements.
Here, you see we have
create table movies.
We have id as the primary key.
We haven't seen that
before until now,
but id is the primary key.
Then down in our create
table Promotions statement,
you can see we now have a
foreign key called movie_id.
And let's add the
new constraint.
All we have to do is say,
movie_id, int, references,
movies, ID.
That creates our
foreign key constraint.
It's important to note
here that if you create
a foreign key
constraint like this,
it needs to be referencing
a table that has already
been created.
So in this case,
the Movies table
had to have been created first.
Now, if we go back
to our tables and we
try to insert a promotion
referencing a movie that
does not exist — one
with an id of 999 —
we properly get back an error
saying that our insert violates
our foreign key constraint.
There's a slightly shorter
way to define a foreign key.
And that is, we don't have
to specify the column.
So here, by default,
it's going to use the ID
column as the foreign key.
We can also create a
foreign key constraint
by using the table constraint
syntax, like you see here.
Another problem
that you often run
into with relational
database tables
is you have orphan records.
Let me show you what that means.
Here we have our Movies
table, and Promotions table,
and a movie with an ID
of 6, and a promotion
associated with that movie.
What happens when that movie
of id of 6 gets deleted?
Well, that promotion
still sticks around.
Yet, it has no movie
it's associated with.
It's called an orphan
record, and it's bad data.
The solution to
orphan records is
using a foreign key
constraint, which we've already
added to our Promotions table.
So if we go to
delete a movie that
has a promotion
associated with it,
our database isn't
going to let us.
It's going to give us back an
error, which looks like this.
Notice this error message
at the bottom even tells us,
"Key id equals 6 is
still referenced
from the table 'promotions'."
So if we want to
delete this movie,
we first need to
delete the promotion
with the movie id equals 6.
And then we can delete the movie,
and the database will let us.
Another way we might end
up with orphan records
in our database is if we
drop a table and other tables
are referencing
items in that table.
So if we try to drop
the table Movies,
it would error out,
telling us the constraint
in our Promotions table
depends on the table Movies.
So we first have to drop
the Promotions table,
and then we can drop
the Movies table.
I want to teach you
one last constraint.
Here we are in our
Movies table, and we
have that duration column back.
And we can put any number into
that duration column, even
negative numbers.
But that doesn't make any sense.
The Wolfman Lives is not
negative 10 minutes long.
The check constraint allows
us to validate the value that
can be placed in the column.
So in this case,
we can say, check —
that's the check constraint —
duration greater than zero.
And then if we go to
insert a movie that
has a duration that's
negative, we'll
get back this error saying
that we violated the check
constraint.
Time for you to jump
into the challenges,
because you only truncate once.
And I'll see you
in the next level.
Enjoying your constraints —
Where are you going with this?
I don't know.