[SINGING] So you learned
your database ABCs —
more than foreign
and primary keys.
Aggregate functions
you'll wax within —
they're count, sum,
average, max, and min.
Make it sleek,
add a few constraints
to stop unique
and null complaints.
Use check, joins, and
a few subqueries.
The Sequel to SQL
is the bee's knees.
You're watching
The Sequel to SQL.
I'm Gregg Pollack,
and this is level three,
where we're going to be
talking about relationships
and normalization.
The movies application
we're building
has a form that looks like
this that allows someone
to create a new movie.
You can see we put in the title,
the genre, and the movie's
duration.
So for Peter Pan, you can see
we can click multiple genres.
But how would we represent
the different genres
in our current database table?
Well, one way we can
do that is simply
list each genre in the same
column separated by a comma.
But what if we wanted
to pull all adventure
movies from the database?
We might do a SQL statement
that looks something like this.
But it's only going
to return Robin Hood,
it's not going to
return Peter Pan.
So there's a problem
with doing it this way.
Also it's going to be harder to
update these values separately.
What if we want to take
out adventure and put
in romance into that genre
column for Peter Pan?
We're stuck.
We can avoid these problems
by using some database
normalization.
Normalization is the process
of reducing duplication
in database tables.
And there's a couple
normal form rules
that will help us do this.
We're going to be talking
about the first two.
The first one says
that tables must not
contain repeating groups
of data in one column.
We're obviously
violating that rule.
The second normal form
rule says tables must not
contain redundancy.
Redundancy meaning unnecessary
repeating information.
Right now in our
Movies table, we
do have repeating groups
of data in the one column.
This is bad.
So if we apply the
first normal form rule,
we would end up with a table
that looks something like this.
Notice we have Peter
Pan listed twice,
one for each of its genres.
Now, this is fine.
This satisfies the
first normal form.
But we still have problems here.
When we update a
movie's duration,
now we have to update
every duplicate movie row.
And it would make sense
for our Movies table
to have a unique
constraint on the titles
column, in which case, we
couldn't have duplicate titles
like we do right now.
So let's apply the second normal
form rule, meaning that tables
must not contain
redundancy, meaning
unnecessary repeating
information, which
we do have right now.
The first step to
eliminating this redundancy
is to create a new
Movies table, which
doesn't have a reference to
genre and each movie is unique.
The second step is to create
a Genres table, where each
of the genres is also unique.
So even though Peter
Pan and Robin Hood
both have the adventure genre,
here in the new Genres table
that's only
represented by one row.
Awesome.
So we've got two new
tables, and both new tables
contain no repeating entries.
This is great.
But we still don't know which
movie belongs to which genre.
We're going to need
another table for that.
We need a way to link
the data between one
table and the other.
This is called a join table.
And creating a join table has
a naming convention, where
we take the name of
the Movies table,
underscore the name
of the Genres table.
So that's going to be the
name of this new table.
Inside the table, we're
going to have two fields.
First, movie_id, which
references the primary key
of the Movies table.
And then second, genre_id,
which references the primary key
of the Genres table.
Both of these columns
are foreign keys
because they reference
primary keys on other tables.
Now we can start mapping
rows from the Movies table
to rows from the Genres table.
So we know that the movie
with id of 1, Don Juan
has a genre of romance.
So we put in that row 1 and 1.
And we know that Peter Pan has
both adventure and fantasy.
So we do 2, 2 and 2,
3 and so on until we
have the proper mapping
between the two tables.
To recap, now we've met the
two normalization form rules.
Rule number one, where we don't
have repeating groups of data.
And rule number
two, where tables
don't contain any redundancy.
Working with these
tables are pretty easy.
If we need to update
movie duration,
we update that in one place
here in the Movies table.
And if we need to add
a genre to a movie.
For example, adding the
genre fantasy to Robin Hood,
we would insert a new value
into the Movie_Genres table
with the values of 4 and 3.
The only disadvantage of
splitting things up into tables
now is gathering that
data back out has
become a little more complex.
For example, how would we find
the genres of the movie Peter
Pan?
Well, we'd first need
to look up the id.
So we could do select
id from Movies,
where title equals Peter Pan.
That will fetch the id.
Then using that id, we
can get the genre_ids
from the Movie_Genres table,
where the movie id equals 2.
And lastly, we can fetch
the names of the genres
that it's mapped to, where
id equals 2 or id equals 3.
Sweet.
There's another
way we could write
this, which is where id IN 2
comma 3, like you see there.
It's just a simpler syntax if
you have multiple or conditions
on the same column.
If you're not an
absolute beginner
when it comes to
writing SQL queries,
you might know what's coming.
Eventually, we'll figure
out how to write one query
to get all the data out of
these three tables at once.
But hold your horses, that'll
be coming up in the next level.
For now, jump into
the challenges.
And I'll see you in
the next section.