Welcome back.
In this section, we're going
to be looking at relationships.
And we've got three different
types of relationships
to tackle.
First, one-to-one,
then one-to-many,
and then finally many-to-many.
We'll look at each of them
and a bunch of examples.
Back in level two, we had our
Promotions table, each of which
was associated with
a specific movie
through the foreign
key column, movie_id.
What is the name for
this relationship, where
a promotion can have one
movie and a movie can
have many promotions?
We call this a
one-to-many relationship.
And if you wanted to
create a database diagram,
here's how you
would represent it.
You would say one movie
can have many promotions
with that little
1 on that one side
and the star on that promotion
side, meaning one-to-many.
The recipe for this
looks something
like you see here with
Table A and Table B,
where one row on
the left can refer
to multiple rows on the right.
Remember these tables, where
a movie can have many genres
and a genre can
have many movies?
Well, this is called a
many-to-many relationship.
And in the diagram it
would look something
like this, where you have
the star on the movie
side and a star on the genre
side, which means many-to-many.
Notice in this diagram,
we don't have a square
for that join table,
for the Movie_Genres
join table, we
don't write it out
in our database diagram.
The recipe for this
relationship looks
like this, where
multiple rows on the left
can refer to multiple
rows on the right.
Sometimes you'll
have a table that
has a bunch of
different columns,
some may be very text-heavy.
And you might want to
split a single table
item into two separate tables.
An example for this might
be address information.
We could take customer
information, split that out
into the Customers table.
And then we could have
address information
on a separate table.
And create that
address_id foreign key
on that Customers table to
refer to the address item
that it belongs to.
In this case, a customer
has one address.
And an address has one customer.
So this relationship is called
a one-to-one relationship,
where a customer can
have only one address.
And we put the number 1 next to
customer and the number 1 next
to address to represent this
one-to-one relationship.
And the recipe for
this relationship
looks like this, where
one row on the left
can refer to one
row on the right.
So those are the three
different table relationships:
one-to-one, one-to-many,
and many-to-many.
Now, let's look at
two different examples
and see if we can figure out
what kind of relationship
they need.
Here you can see we
have our Movies table
and we also have
our Reviews table.
What kind of
relationship do you think
these two tables will have?
If you said one-to-many
relationship,
you're the bee's knees.
So one movie can have
many reviews — one-to-many.
So what would that look like?
Well, each of our reviews
needs to be associated
with a specific movie.
To map this properly, we'll
create a movie_id column,
which will be our
foreign key, which
maps to the primary key
on the Movies table, which
in this case is id.
Here you can see that Don Juan
has three different reviews
associated with it.
Here are two more tables — a
Movies table and a Promotions
table.
What kind of relationship do
you think they should have, even
from a business perspective?
Before, they had a
one-to-many relationship
when we were mapping
things back and forth.
But really, should a promotion
belong to a single movie?
I don't think so.
I think movies can have
many different promotions.
And promotions can have
many different movies.
So this is a many-to-many
relationship,
like you see here.
This means we need another
one of those join tables.
We'll call it the
Movies_Promotions
table, like you see here.
And then we can map which
movies are associated
with which promotions.
Because we might have a
half-off promotion, and that
might apply to several
different movies.
Makes sense.
It's time for you to
practice your relationships
in the challenges.
And when you're done, take
your favorite relationship
to the Code School
picture, Tables on a Train.
I'm sure they'll love it.
[BEEP]
Relationships, they never work.
[LAUGH]
[BEEP]
Foreign.
All fancy and [BLEEP]
database diagram.
[BEEP]