[SINGING] So you learned
your database ABCs —
more than foreign
and primary keys.
Aggregate functions
you'll wax within —
they're count, sum,
average, max, and min.
Make it sleek,
add a few constraints
to stop unique
and null complaints.
Use check, joins, and
a few subqueries.
The Sequel to SQL
is the bee's knees.
You're watching Sequel to
SQL. I'm Gregg Pollack,
and this is level
four, where we're going
to be talking all about
joining tables together,
starting with inner joins.
Here you can see we
have our Movies table
and our Reviews table.
Now, how would we
get a list of reviews
and then get all of the
associated movie titles?
We'd have to write two queries.
First, we would select the
review text and the movie_id
from the Reviews table.
We would take the
movie_ids that were returned,
and use that to get the
titles from the Movies
table with select title from
Movies where id in 1, 3, 4.
This will get us what we want.
But there's a way to get
this data using one query.
But how would we visualize
the data that we want here?
We're looking for
all the records
that have a match
in both tables.
So if you look at
this diagram here,
we have some movies
that aren't associated
with reviews and some reviews
that don't have movies.
And we want the
ones in the middle,
in the inner part of
those two circles.
To get this information,
we have to write
some SQL code that joins
these two tables together.
The movie_id column
in our Reviews table
is the foreign key.
And of course that relates
back to the id column
in the Movies table.
Using the inner join clause,
we'll write select
star from Movies,
inner join Reviews on Movies_id
equals Reviews.movie_id.
So inner join tells it
what table to join with.
And then the second line
right after that tells it
how to join those two tables
using that foreign key.
Here's what the result
might look like.
You can see in the
middle it matched up
the primary key of
the Movies table
with the foreign key in the
Reviews table, the movie_id,
those are all matched
as we expected.
Also notice that
the Don Juan movie
is listed three times because
it has three different reviews.
And notice that movie
number 2, Peter Pan,
is not here, since it does
not have a matching review.
It's worth noting
that with inner joins,
we can write this query
in two different ways.
We can do from Movies,
inner join Reviews.
And we can also do from
Reviews, inner join Movies.
And it's going to
return the same thing.
Because both ways, we're
talking about the reviews
that have movies or the
movies that have reviews.
So the overlapping
part of the circles.
In reality, we
probably don't want
to get all the data
from both tables.
In this case, we want
the movie's title
and we want the review column
from the Reviews table.
And since we're working
with two tables now,
we have to specify which table
each column is coming from.
So, in this case, we
do select Movies.title,
Reviews.review.
And that will return just those
columns, like you see here.
Remember the slide
from the previous level,
where we were trying to figure out
all the genres of the Peter Pan
movie, and we had to do
three different queries?
Well, there's a way to do an
inner join across all three
tables to get back the
data we want in one query.
This can get a little complex.
So don't freak out, you might
need to look at it twice.
But here we go with one query.
We want the movie title and
the genre name from Movies.
Here's our first inner
join — Movies_Genres.
Then we need to say how
to join these tables.
In this case, Movies.id,
Movies_Genres.movie_id.
Now we need to inner
join on another table.
Inner join Genres on
Movies_Genres.genre_id,
that's the foreign
key, equal genre_id, that's
the primary key on
the Genres table, where
Movies.title equals Peter Pan.
And that's going to get
us back a table which
looks like this, showing us the
title of a movie and the genres
it's associated with.
Mind blown.
I know, it's a
little much to grock.
But you can do it.
And you can play with it in the
challenges coming up right now.