Before we get all
crazy with more joins,
we're going to talk a
little bit about aliases.
Because it'll make writing
joins a little easier.
Here's our current
movie review inner
join that we were
just working with.
And here's the output
that we received.
Now, notice these
column headers, here.
We have title and review.
What if we wanted to
change those titles?
How would we do that?
By using a column alias, we can
define these column headers.
We can say,
Movies.title AS films —
and Reviews.review AS
reviews — and it'll
print out more
understandable headers,
as you can see here,
with films and reviews.
We can simplify this further
by simply dropping the "as"
and just specifying films and
reviews — works just the same.
Sometimes, we might want to
use multiple words as an alias,
in this case, weekly
movies or weekly reviews.
In which case, we just
need to enclose them
in some quotation marks.
And here's what our
result will look like.
After a while, it
gets kind of verbose
having to type an entire
table name every time
you want to specify a column
on that table or order
by on that table.
That's where table
aliases come in.
Table aliases allow
you to do just that.
We can set an alias of
"m" for the Movies table
by just saying,
from Movies m. Then
every other place in the
query where we would need
to reference the
Movies table name,
we can just write m.
M.title, m.id,
and then m.title
down at the bottom.
Table aliases can be used on
tables even outside of the
from clause.
So back with our inner join,
we can specify the alias of "r"
for our Reviews table and then
use that r alias elsewhere
in our query.
As you can see, the query has
become a lot less verbose.
Remember this crazy inner
join from the last section?
Let's apply table
aliases to this query
and see how it changes it.
You can see it's
a lot shorter now.
We have three different
aliases: m for the Movies table,
mg for the Movies_Genres table,
and g for the Genres table.
It's time for you to play
around with some aliases
in the challenges.
Meanwhile, I'm going to go catch
Humphrey Bigint in Datablanca.