Welcome back.
So we took a look
at inner joins.
It's time to figure
out outer joins.
So let's jump back
into our tables.
We have our Movies table
and our Reviews table.
This time around,
we want to show
all the records
in the left table
and display matching records
from the table on the right.
This is where we need
a left outer join.
What this means is
we're going to take
all of the movies
in the Movies table
and definitely
display all of them.
And if it so happens
that there are reviews
that are associated
with these movies,
let's display those too.
To write this left
outer join, we
do select star from Movies,
left outer join Reviews.
And just like the
inner join, we need
to specify how these
tables get joined together
by using on Movies_id
equals Reviews.movie_id.
Here's the result
that gets returned.
And I want you to
notice two things.
First of all, Don Juan is
listed three different times
because there are three
different reviews.
Secondly, notice that
all of the movies
are listed, even though
Peter Pan has no review,
it's just listed
there as a movie.
And there's just an
empty review space
over there on the
right-hand side.
Now that we know we're joining
tables the way we want to,
let's fine-tune this query.
First, we're going
to use table aliases.
We're also just going to return
the title and the review body.
And then lastly, we'll
order it by the review_id.
So here's the results.
And since Peter Pan
doesn't have a review
and we're ordering
by review_id, it
gets listed at the bottom
with no associated review.
So that's left
outer join, where we
display all the movies and
matching reviews, if they exist.
We can also do a
right outer join.
That's going to
display all the reviews
and matching movies,
if they exist.
Let's dive into that.
So let's use a right
outer join to get
all of our reviews and movies
that are associated with them.
Notice here in the
Reviews table, though,
to make this a better
example, I've nulled out two
of the movie_ids.
Let's jump into our query.
And we'll do select star from
Movies, right outer join
Reviews, and then specify
that these two tables join
together on the movie_id.
Here's what the query returns.
Notice here we're listing
every single review,
but we have some missing movies.
That's because, remember,
two of our reviews
don't have an associated movie.
And that's totally fine.
That's our right outer join.
Now that we know we're getting
the appropriate result,
let's polish this query.
We'll use aliases, we'll only
fetch the title and the review
body, and we'll
specify an order.
And here's what the
result looks like.
Alright.
Joins are probably the
most difficult part
about this entire course.
So it's okay if you need
to go back and watch
this whole thing again.
Don't be ashamed, you can do it.
And also you can use
hints, really, it's okay.
Use hints if you need
them — I won't be mad.
So why don't you get
into the challenges,
and I'll see you
in the final level.
Meanwhile, I'm going to go
watch Where danger.lives = true
by Alfred Tablelock.
It's a good movie, really.
[BEEP]
Relationships and orphan
records, it's so sad.
Can't take it.
[BEEP]
It's time for the door to open.
[GIBBERISH] That wasn't good.
[BEEP]