[SINGING] So you learned
your database ABCs —
more than foreign
and primary keys.
Aggregate functions
you'll wax within —
they're count, sum,
average, max, and min.
Make it sleek,
add a few constraints
to stop unique
and null complaints.
Use check, joins, and
a few subqueries.
The Sequel to SQL
is the bee's knees.
You're watching
The Sequel to SQL.
And this is level
five, where we're gonna
be talking about subqueries.
Here you can see we're
back in our Movies
table with a sales column.
And our Promotions
table, notice it
has a foreign key of
movie_id, so each
promotion belongs
to one movie.
We want to try to find
the sum of all sales
for movies that are showing
as a non-cash promotion.
So how might we
write this query?
Let's break this
down step by step.
First, we need to query
for the promotions that
have category equal to non-cash
and return the movie_id,
like you see here.
We're going to call
this our inner query.
We can take the results
of our inner query
and feed them into
an outer query
to find the sum of all sales.
So notice here, we write,
select sum sales from Movies,
where id in, and then
put in our inner query.
Notice it's surrounded
by parentheses.
This is called a subquery
because it's inside
of another query.
When we execute this query,
it does what you probably
think it does.
It runs the inner query
first, gets a result —
in this case, 1 and
4 — and then it runs
the outer query, returning
a result of 95,000.
You might be wondering,
this is cool and all
that you can do
this subquery thing,
but couldn't we do
this with a join?
We just learned joins.
And you would be correct.
In this particular instance,
we could rewrite this subquery
as a join, like
so, where we have
select sum sales from
Movies, inner join Promotions,
on the ids, where category
is equal to non-cash.
And we would get
the same result.
The difference here
is simply preference.
The subquery is easier to
read, whereas the join query,
in the long run, it's going
to be more performant.
There's lots of different
syntax for doing subqueries.
And we're just going
to focus on two.
The first is where we use in —
just like we saw a minute ago —
to filter rows that
have a matching
id from the inner query.
Or we could do not in,
which will filter rows
that don't have a matching id.
Let's take a look at
a subquery that we
couldn't reproduce as a join.
Here we have our
Movies table and we've
got the duration column.
What if we wanted to
find only films that
have a duration greater than the
average duration of all films?
You might think you could write
a query like this — select star
from Movies, where
duration is greater
than the average duration.
Running this query, the
database with return an error:
"Aggregate functions are
not allowed in where."
So, the right
solution here will be
to use a correlated subquery.
First, we'll write our inner
query — select average
duration from Movies.
Then, we need to feed that
into our outer query —
in this case, select star from
Movies, where duration greater
than the return value
from our inner query.
Both queries depend
on each other's values
to return a correct result. That
makes it a correlated subquery.
And it returns Robin
Hood, the only movie
that has a higher
than average duration.
Subqueries can be
a little tricky.
So you're going to go
straight into the challenges
and play around with them.
And I'll see you
in the outro video.
Meanwhile, I'm going
to go watch Once
Upon a Timestamp, with
Cary Privilege Grant.
Right now — here I go.
Go to the challenges —
really. I'm going already.
I think so.
I think it's right.
I said it.
Therefore, I am right.
Not really.