[SINGING] In 1980 Tim
wrote ENQUIRE at CERN
and invented the idea
of hyperlinks in turn.
In 1990 Robert joined,
a document they charted.
And that's pretty much how the
whole world wide web started.
They defined some
markup code called
HTML, which paved the way for
stylesheets to decorate, as
well.
Navigate through URLs
to internet locations.
You can learn it all at
Front-End Foundations.
You're watching
I'm Jon Friskics.
And in this course,
we're going to learn
how to build a basic web page.
To do this, we're going
to learn HTML and CSS.
We're going to write HTML text
tags and use CSS selectors.
We're going to
learn how to lay out
a web page that has multiple
sections and multiple pages.
We're going to work with
images on that web page.
And finally, we're
going to learn
how to customize fonts
and build HTML forms.
Now, once you've completed all
the challenges in this course,
you'll learn the course badge.
If you're already pretty
familiar with HTML and CSS,
you might consider skipping
ahead to the challenges,
so you can earn that badge.
Before we dive into
some code, let's look
at a short history of the
web and its creator Tim
Berners-Lee.
In the early '80s,
Tim worked for a group
called CERN, where he proposed
a better way for researchers
to share and read documents.
You know, CERN, you
probably know that better
now as the people who run
the Large Hadron Collider.
In 1984, he built
a system that he
called ENQUIRE, which took a
series of cards, or documents,
and linked them together with
things called hyperlinks.
Now, it was a really
cool system for the time.
But it was only being used
by researchers internally.
So he had an idea that
he could take this system
and make it available
to the entire world.
So with Robert Cailliau,
he wrote a proposal in 1990
for the creation of what
became the world wide web.
This is actually world
wide web's first logo.
It's come a long way since then.
Like ENQUIRE, the
web links together
documents called web
pages with hyperlinks.
And the language of building
a web page is called HTML.
HTML allows you to take a
plain text document written
in any simple text editor
and organize it into lists,
link to other web pages,
include images, and more.
You might be wondering what
the letters in HTML stand for.
They stand for HyperText
Markup Language.
Now, hypertext is
really just a fancy way
of saying text that has
some enhanced capabilities,
like the ability
to be interactive.
And markup language,
which literally
means you can mark up different
sections of your page as lists,
links, and even do things like
specify attributes and change
the font sizes, for example.
When we write HTML, we
put it inside of a file.
And we always make sure that
the extension for that file
is dot html.
And that lets our web
browser know to display
that markup properly.
So a web browser is really
just an HTML reader.
The browser takes in
some HTML and knows
how to display that
markup language properly
on the screen for you.
And hopefully, that markup is
displayed the same no matter
which browser you use.
At least that's the idea.
In this course,
we'll be showing you
HTML code, CSS code, and the way
that the browser displays them.
So keep an eye out
for these symbols
so you always know the type of
content that you're looking at.
The site that we will be
building in these videos
is called Recipe World.
It's a multi-page site that has
a home page, a list of recipes,
an individual recipe page with
directions and ingredients,
and even a
suggest-a-recipe page.
We're going to start by
building out the recipe page.
Now, before you
build any web page,
you always have to
figure out what content
you're going to display on it.
And a good way to start
that is to figure out
what the main sections of
content are going to be.
So here we know
we're going to have
a page title, Recipe World.
We know we're going to have the
name of our recipe, Magic Cake.
And we're going to have
a section for ingredients
and directions.
The way you write HTML is
with something called a tag.
And most tags have opening
and closing versions.
And content goes in between
those opening and closing tags.
Here we've put
some content, which
is the title of the page, Recipe
World, inside of an h1 tag.
You can see that we
first open the tag.
We put our content next.
And then we close the tag
by writing the tag name
but putting a slash before
the name that appears.
And this is how that will
display in the browser.
h1 is just one of
many HTML tags.
And we'll be looking at a
bunch of them in this course.
Don't worry about
memorizing every single tag
right now because you'll
always be able to refer
to a list of them later on.
h1 is part of a group of
tags called heading tags.
And heading tags
are used whenever
you want to declare the
title of a section of content
on your page.
Generally speaking,
the lower the h number,
the more important the
content is for that page.
So you'll usually see things
like a page title or company
name inside of a h1 tag,
the main subject or idea
of the page in an h2 tag.
Here it's Magic Cake,
the name of the recipe
the rest of the
page will be about.
And then h3 through h6 are
used to further organize
some of the lesser important
content on the page.
Here on our recipe
page, it's going
to be the ingredients and
the directions for combining
those ingredients.
When we display
this in the browser,
you'll notice that the h1
tag is naturally displayed
bigger than the h2 and h3.
And the h3 is smaller
than the h1 and h2.
Next, we'll add a
description of our recipe.
Now, any time that you have
text content on the page that's
not part of one of the
headers, it usually
goes inside of a paragraph
tag, which is written with p.
The name's a little misleading.
You don't have to only
put paragraphs in there.
Even if you only
have a few words
to add that aren't part
of a section title,
you should put them
in a paragraph tag.
If you need to display
a list of things,
you can use an
unordered list tag.
Now, with an unordered
list, each item in the list
also has to be inside of
an li tag or list item tag.
Now, you'll notice that
this is the first time we've
had a tag that
contains another tag.
Before, we've just had an
opening tag, some text,
and then a closing tag.
But here in between the
open and close ul tags,
we've got a couple other tags
that are opening and closing
inside of there.
This is called nesting tags.
And when you have a tag like
li that's inside of a ul tag,
the ul is called the parent tag.
And the li is called the
child because the li is inside
of the ul.
Indenting your
code is a great way
to see which tags are
nested inside of others.
Anytime you have a
tag that's nested,
you put either two
spaces or a tab,
so you can really
easily scan the page
and see which tags
are inside of others.
Here's an example of how
not to write nested tags.
This is technically valid HTML.
But it's pretty hard to
just look at really quick
and determine that these
lis are inside of a ul tag.
So stick with
indenting your tags.
Our list of ingredients
was an unordered list
because it didn't need to
appear in any specific order.
But if you do you need items
to appear in a specific order,
like in the case of directions
for making this cake,
you can use an ordered list tag.
Ordered lists work just
like unordered lists,
but the tag name is
ol instead of ul.
Here's what that list
looks like in the browser.
Ordered lists will naturally
number each one of the list
items because they need to be
followed in a certain order.
We're making great
progress on our page.
And we've got all of
our content marked up.
But there's a few
additional tags
that we'll need to
wrap everything in
to make a truly
standards-compliant HTML page.
So the first is body.
All of the visible
content on your page
should be wrapped
inside of a body tag
so that the body is the
parent of all of that content.
Body doesn't actually
display anything or change
the way things are displayed.
But it just helps keep the page
content organized and helps
the browser understand that
that's the stuff that it really
should be showing.
Any code that has to be run
before the page displays
goes inside of the head tag.
We don't actually have anything
to put inside of this tag yet.
But we'll eventually use it
to load other useful scripts,
like CSS and even JavaScript.
So we'll add it to
our page right now,
so it's ready for later.
Then we'll want to go one step
further and take everything
in our head and body
tags and make them
children of a single HTML tag.
There's always only
one HTML tag on a page.
And like head and
body, it doesn't really
change the way anything looks.
But it just helps keep all
of your content organized,
so the browser can display
it in the best way possible.
Notice, too, that
as we build out
this final structure
of our HTML page,
we're keeping those
indentations accurate.
So we can easily see
that head and body
are children of the HTML tag.
And our h1's and
paragraphs and lists
are also still children of body.
So the final cherry on
the top of our HTML cake
is the doctype.
The doctype sets
the version of HTML
that the browser
should use to display
the HTML that you wrote.
By writing doctype HTML and not
specifying a version number,
we're actually just
telling the browser
to use the latest version.
If we go back to
the browser and look
at the page we've
created so far,
we can see that we're
off to a good start.
So now it's your
turn to practice
writing HTML in the challenges.
end