Welcome back.
We've got our web page
started, but now we
want to also have
the ability to go
to different pages
inside our website,
and even maybe link to a page
that's not on our website
at all.
So in this level, we're going
to look at how we can add links
to our page with HTML.
We'll add a site
navigation that allows
us to switch between the
different pages in our website,
and we'll even add a link
inside of a paragraph tag
to a legal description
in our site.
Let's first think
about what happens
when you type a URL in
the browser address bar.
You type that URL in, which
is made up of a protocol,
which is the HTTP
part, a server,
which we'll use example.com
here, and a path to a file,
like magic-cake.html.
We'll enter that URL in the
address bar, and hit Enter.
A request is then sent to the
example.com server for the file
magic cake.
Example.com sends
magic-cake.html back over
to the browser, and the
browser displays it.
So a link in HTML is actually
working the exact same way,
it's just that the URL is
stored inside of the HTML,
so you don't have to type it
in the browser address bar
every time.
Here we've got a link that's
inside of magic-cake.html that
links to legal.html.
If we click that link we're
requesting legal.html from
the example.com server, and
then legal.html is, again,
returned to the browser, and it
replaces magic-cake.html with
the new legal page.
The browser even
updates the address bar
so that we can see that
our new page is loaded.
To create a link in
HTML, you use the a tag,
which is short for anchor.
You use an opening and
closing a tag, and any text
that you put inside
of those tags
is going to be the
clickable part of the link.
Now there's no URL
inside of this a tag yet,
so we need a way to put
that URL inside of there.
And we do this with something
called a HTML attribute.
Attributes are written
inside of an opening tag,
by writing the attribute name,
then an equal sign, and then
the value of that attribute.
Here we're using
the href attribute,
which sets what the page should
open when the link is clicked.
And we've assigned
that to a URL.
And that URL is in quotes, it's
important to have those quotes
there.
HTML attributes let you
add additional features,
or additional information
beyond what you can just
put in between the
opening and closing tags.
Now, like HTML tags, don't
worry about memorizing
every single HTML
attribute out there.
You'll be able to
refer to a reference
when you're writing
this yourself.
Another example of an attribute
that works with an anchor tag
is the target attribute.
The target attribute
sets where the page
that you set in the
href should open up
whenever that link is clicked.
So if we set the
target equal to _blank,
that means that when this
link is clicked we should open
the page in a new
tab, or window.
If we set it to _self, it
means just replace the page
we're currently looking
at with the new one that
we're requesting.
And the default behavior
is actually self,
so if you want it
to work that way
you don't have to write
that target attribute.
Back in our browser,
you can see now
that when we click on
the legal page link text
it's going to open up a new tab
with the legal.html content.
Now the URL that we included as
the value of our href attribute
is called an absolute path.
Absolute paths ask
for a specific file
from a specific server.
Here we're writing
that we want this
file to come from example.com
always and forever.
But that's not always
the best approach,
and instead we can
use a relative path.
Relative paths ask
for a file, but they
don't specify any server.
So it would look like
this href="legal.html".
Since there's no protocol
or server name specified
in the path, the browser
performs some magic,
and it assumes that you
mean the same server
that the link your
clicking is currently on.
So if this link appears
in a page that's currently
on the example.com
server, the browser
is going to automatically
insert that http://example.com
in front of the legal.html
Just to be sure how this works,
let's look at it another way.
We have magic-cake.html that's
on the example.com server
currently loaded in the browser.
That contains a link for a
relative path to legal.html.
When we click on that
link, the browser
assumes that we're
trying to find legal.html
on example.com because we
didn't specify that server name.
And then it returns legal.html
back to the browser,
just like we expected.
Since our site has
multiple web pages,
where you're going to
have multiple HTML files.
So if we look at the
folder on our server
that is going to
contain all these files,
it might look
something like this.
The three main pages
on our site are
going to be the home,
recipes, and suggest pages.
So those are the
three that should
go on our main site navigation.
We'll be able to
get to magic cake
and legal from the recipes
page, so that doesn't need
to be in our main navigation.
Now relative links
should almost always
be used whenever you're
linking to pages that are all
stored on the same site.
So here we've created
an unordered list
underneath our h1 tag.
And that list has
three list items.
And each of those list
items has an anchor tag
with a relative link
inside of it, one for home,
one for recipes,
and one for suggest.
If we take this unordered
list block of HTML,
and put it on all
of our HTML pages,
we'll be able to navigate
between each page.
And we've created starter
pages for home, recipes,
and suggest, that just have an
h2 with the title of the page.
And as we click through those
three main navigation items
you can see we're able
to load, and freely
move between each one
of those three pages.
Back on our magic
cake recipe page,
let's say there's a certain
kind of sugar that really should
be used when making this cake.
We might go to a
site like Amazon.com
and find the specific
sugar that should be used.
Then we can copy the
URL from Amazon.com,
and we can paste it
into our magic cake page
as an absolute link.
Absolute links need
to be used whenever
you're linking to a page
that's not on your website.
Notice in the link that
the protocol and server,
Amazon.com, are still there.
Absolute paths need
to be used whenever
you're linking to a file
that's not on your own website.
Since this file is on Amazon,
we need the protocol and server
in there for an absolute path.
And now when we click
on that link for sugar,
we're redirected
to Amazon where we
can buy the sugar that we need.
Now it's time for you to set
up multiple pages of site
navigation, and some other
links in the challenges.