[SINGING] In 1980 0 Tim
wrote Enquire at CERN,
invented the idea of
hyperlinks in turn.
In 1990 Robert joined,
a document they charted,
that's pretty much how the
world wide web started.
They defined some
markup code called
HTML, which paved the
way for stylesheets
to decorate as well.
Navigate through URLs
to internet locations,
you can learn it all with
Front-End Foundations,
Front-End Foundations.
Eh.
Welcome back.
In this section,
we're going to learn
how we can use CSS to change
the style of our HTML tags.
So back in the early
days of the web
there was no CSS,
and that meant there
was no separation between the
HTML that defines your content,
and the way that HTML looks.
So you would have really
nasty HTML like this,
where you would determine
the color as an attribute
inside of your tag, and
you would write things,
like center, as tags
that really just modified
the way things looked, rather
than the way that they worked.
So thankfully the
people making the web
realize that that was not
the greatest way to go.
So they created a
separate language
where you can make rules
for how tags should display,
and that language is called CSS.
With CSS you describe
how a tag should
look, saying things like,
make the h3 tag green,
make it have a
bigger font, and make
it have a border at the bottom.
The combination of
all of these CSS rules
is going to make your page
look the way that it does.
In fact, if go to any web
page and turn off the CSS,
they all kind of start
looking the same there's
no differences between them.
It's all of those CSS rules
that make all of the pages
that you visit look
different from each other.
Here's what our page currently
looks like without CSS
in the browser.
Here's what it might look like
after we apply some CSS styles.
The way CSS works
is you write code
called selectors that
select HTML tags.
And then you can
alter the properties
of the display of
those HTML tags
to change the way
that things look.
So here we've got a simple
paragraph tag in HTML.
If we want to select that
paragraph tag in CSS,
we start by writing the
letter P. The simplest way
to select a tag is just to
write the name of the tag
without those angle brackets.
So CSS does not include
the angle brackets.
In this example we're altering
the text decoration property,
which is one of many
properties that you can change
of the display of each tag.
Unlike before,
don't worry so much
about memorizing the properties.
You'll be able to
look them up later.
We're setting the value of
the text decoration property
to underline, and the result
when we look in our browser,
is that our paragraph
tag is now underlined.
So the general format
for writing any selector
is to first write the selector
name, followed by a space
and then a curly bracket.
Inside of that curly bracket
you can write a property name,
and then a colon, and then
the value for that property,
and then a semicolon.
This is actually very
important, if you
forget the curly bracket,
colon, or semicolon,
or don't have them
in the right spot,
then your CSS is not
going to work properly.
Finally you close off your list
of properties for that selector
by writing a closed
curly bracket.
That curly bracket
is nice, because it
lets you write more than one
property for each selector.
So back at our
paragraph tag we've
set the text
decoration to underline
in the previous slide.
But now we've also added a new
rule to set the color to red.
And if we look in
the browser now we
have a red underlined paragraph.
When we select the tag in CSS
by writing the tag name, that
rule we define is applied
to every single instance
of that tag in the HTML page.
So here, even though we've only
set one rule, where the font
size should be 24
pixels for li it
gets applied to every
single li tag on the page.
You can see here that they
all just got a little bigger.
If you want to only apply a
CSS rule to a certain, smaller
subset of tags, one way we
can do that is with something
called a descendant selector.
The way a descendant
selector is written
is you first write the parent
tag in your selector name,
and then the child tag.
This CSS rule of making
the font size bigger
is now only going
to apply to li tags
that are children of ul tags.
And we view that
in the browser, we
can see that our honorerd
list text got bigger,
while our ordered
list text stayed
the same size, because the
rule doesn't apply to it.
Another type of selector
is the pseudo-selector.
You can see here that we've
set our anchor tags to all
have text-decoration:
none; which
means that every
link on our page
is no longer going to have
an underline under it.
If we also declare another
rule for the anchor tag,
with the colon hover
pseudo-selector,
and we set the text
decoration to underline
and the color to
dark red, that rule
is only going to be
applied when the mouse is
over the link, when
it's hovering over it.
So pseudo-selectors
are used to modify
the appearance of an HTML tag
based on some type of action
or behavior.
When you're no longer
hovered over the link,
then the underline and
the color red go away.
Another pseudo-selector
you could add
is called first child.
If a tag has children,
adding first-child to the end
of the selector name will
select the first child
that's nested inside of it.
Here you can see
we're only changing
the color of the first
ordered list item
by using the selector ol
colon first dash child.
I hope you're getting excited
about the crazy possibilities
of using CSS to change
the way your HTML looks.
So to write CSS inside
of our HTML pages
there's a couple
different ways to do it.
One of the simplest
ways to add CSS
is to include a style tag
as a child of the head tag.
Remember that we set
up our head tag before,
but we didn't have
anything in it.
And this is the first thing
that we're putting inside of it.
If we create that
style tag, and give it
an attribute name of type, with
the value of text slash CSS,
then the browser
is going to know
to look at that block of
CSS and apply it to our HTML
whenever the page is displayed.
So we can set up our CSS
rules, with our selectors,
and our properties,
and those values,
inside of that style
tag and they'll all
be applied to the HTML page.
Now you're ready
to start changing
the presentation of the tags
on your page in the challenges.