The colors you've
been using so far
have descriptive names like
red, green, blue, yellow.
But if you've ever looked
at any CSS colors before,
you probably have seen something
like this, this pound symbol
with a bunch of letters
and numbers after it.
These are actually
hexadecimal numbers.
And they're a very popular
way to set the color in CSS.
Here's three
descriptive colors and
their hexadecimal equivalents.
Red is FF0000.
Black is just six zeroes.
And yellow is four F's
followed by two zeros.
But what's really going on here?
Why are these weird
letters equaling colors?
To start answering
that question,
let's look at the different
parts of a hexadecimal color.
The first two numbers
actually determine
the amount of red in the color.
The next two determine
the amount of green.
And the last two determine
the amount of blue.
So you're really looking
at three separate numbers,
all kind of just
chunked together
in one six-character statement.
If we were to attach a numeric
value to the possible colors
in HTML, they run from 0
to 255 decimal or 00 to FF
hexadecimal.
So when we look at a
number like FFFF00,
we're really saying
that this color
is the maximum amount of red,
the maximum amount of green,
and absolutely no blue at all.
And that's roughly equivalent
to the color yellow.
So to quickly understand
why this works
and why we can use letters
in the place of numbers,
let's first look at how
to make a decimal number.
Now, decimal numbers can
contain the value zero
through 9 and nothing
else, no letters.
If we have the
decimal number 76,
it's really like saying 7
times 10 plus 6 times 1.
We multiply the first number
by 10, the second number by 1.
We add those together,
and we get 76.
Now, if this were a hexadecimal
76 instead of a decimal,
instead of multiplying
by 10, we multiply by 16.
That hexa part of
hexadecimal means six.
So 6 and 10 is 16, right?
So if we multiply the 7 by 16
and then add it to 6 times 1,
we get 118.
So believe it or not, 76
in hexadecimal numbers
is actually equivalent to 118
in our normal decimal number
system.
So stay with me.
Now we've got hexadecimal FF.
So we can calculate the
decimal version of this
by taking F times
16 plus F times 1.
But how do we
multiply by a letter?
That doesn't really
make any sense, right?
Well, these letters
actually stand for numbers.
A stands for 10.
B stands for 11, and so on.
And F stands for 15.
So when we have the
hexadecimal number FF,
we're actually calculating
it by having 15 times
16 plus 15 times 1.
That equals 255 decimal.
So with that in mind, let's
look at a more complicated
hexadecimal color, 7403AB.
We know that the first
two represent red.
The next two represent green.
And the last two represent blue.
So if we first look
at the red color,
we can see that it's 7 times 16
plus 4 times 1, which gives you
116.
And you can see how to calculate
green and blue, as well.
So this really, then,
means that this color
is some amount of red, almost no
green at all, and way more blue
than red.
And that ends up looking
like the color purple.
Here's another
hexadecimal color, FF00B3.
If we do the math and get the
decimal equivalents of these,
we see that this color
has a ton of red.
It actually has the maximum
amount of red possible.
It has no green
at all, no green.
And it has a little
less blue than red.
And that color actually
displays as hot pink.
So by using hexadecimal
colors, we actually
get 256 times 256 times
256 possible color values.
That's 16 million colors.
That's a lot of colors.
So it's time for you play
with some of those 16 million
in the challenges.