Welcome back.
So you had a chance to play
around with some basic CSS
selectors, changing some
simple properties like color.
But got a question about the
current state of our page here.
How does our page know how much
vertical and horizontal space
to put between the tags?
We've got spacing
in between the h1,
and the ULs, and the paragraphs,
and even the ordered lists.
But how does the browser know
to put that much spacing there?
And even more
importantly, how can we
change that spacing if we
want to make it more or less?
And the answer lies in
something called the box model.
So first, let's talk
about what the box is.
Every tag that's
shown on the page
is contained in this
invisible rectangle
that we're going
to call the box.
So here I've got two paragraph
tags on MagicCake.HTML.
And if we look at how those
get rendered in the browser,
we can imagine that
there's these two
invisible boxes around them.
We'll show the boxes here so it
makes it easier to talk about.
If we look at the rest of
the content on our page,
we can imagine that these boxes
that contain all this content
look something like this.
We got a box that represents
the content of every single tag
on our page.
So it turns out that
almost all of these tags we
have on our page
right now are what's
known as a block-level tag.
When you have block level
tags, their content box
takes up the entire width of
the container that they're in.
The container for
these tags is the body.
So every one of these tags takes
up as much horizontal space
as it can.
Sense block-level tags
take up the entire width
of their container,
every new box
gets automatically pushed
down to the line below.
Here's a list of just some of
the tags that are block level.
And you can see that
they are tags that we're
using in our page right now.
If a tag is not block-level,
it's called inline-level.
Inline-level tags do not try
to take up the entire width
of their container.
And they actually
just flow along
with the text and other
content around them.
Anchor tag as an example
of an inline-level tag.
So that's why when
we nest an anchor tag
inside of a paragraph
tag, it doesn't try
to push itself onto a new line.
It just flows naturally with
the rest of the paragraph text.
Some other examples
of inline-level tags
are img, inputs, and labels,
which we'll touch on later
in this course.
Sometimes you'll even want
to turn a block-level tag
into an inline-level
tag, or vice versa.
You can do that by setting
the display property in CSS
for that tag to inline.
So here we've taken
all list items that
are children of
an unordered list
and we set them
to display inline.
This is really handy because it
allows us to take these three
li block-level boxes,
and display them
as inline boxes from left to
right, as you can see here.
All right, so we know that
each tags content is contained
in this invisible box.
And we know that
every block-level tags
box is going to try to take up
an entire line of the container
that it's in.
So back to that
original problem,
how does the browser know
how much space goes in
between those boxes?
To be able to fully understand
how to answer that question,
we need to learn
about the box model.
Now, the box model is just a
way to describe the borders
and spacing in between
the boxes for each tag.
And there's actually four
components to the box model.
The first one is called
the content area.
And the content area
is the part that
contains your actual content.
So if we write an h1 tag or h2
tag and it has some text in it,
that text is inside of the
content area of the box.
The second part is padding.
And padding describes a
layer just to around all
of the edges of
the content area.
Padding can be added to
the top, right, bottom,
or left of the content
area independently.
Now, most tags are not
going to need a border.
But if they do, you can add
one with the border property.
Like the padding, borders
can be added individually
to the top, right, bottom,
or left of the box.
Or they can be applied
to all sides at once.
The fourth and final part of
the box model are margins.
Margins are space that can
be added to the top, right,
bottom, or left of the border.
So not every tag is going
to have padding, border,
and margins added all
at once to all sides.
But the size of the box is
equal to the size of the content
area, plus the padding, plus
the border, plus any margins.
The way that we can
control these in CSS
is through a series
of properties.
So we can either set the padding
top, right, bottom, and left
individually each with
one separate rule in CSS,
or we can combine all of them
into the shorthand, where
we write the top, right,
bottom, and left padding
all in one line.
You can see here that we've
added a padding of six pixels
to the top of this box,
three pixels to the right,
and no padding on the
bottom or the left.
To add a border around
all sides of a box,
you can either set these three
properties individually--
the width of the border,
the style of the border,
and the color of the border.
Or like padding, you can use
the special shorthand syntax
that declares the
width, style, and color
all on one line with one rule.
Now, this applies a
border to all sides
of the box at the same time.
So if you do you want to
apply a border to just one
side of a box, you can use
either border top, right,
bottom, or left.
And then set the width
style and color there.
Adding margins works the same
way that you add padding.
You just either set the
margin top, right, bottom,
and left properties
individually.
Or use that shorthand
that combines them
all into one line.
Here we've got a bottom
margin of six pixels
and a top margin of six
pixels, but no right and left
margins at all.
And we can see the final version
with the final dimensions
of our box.
The place to use borders
is pretty obvious.
You add a border if
you want a border.
But using padding and margins
needs a little bit more
explanation.
So in general,
you'll use padding
to control the size of
a box without adjusting
the size of the content inside.
So here on the left, we
can see that the padding
is 0 for all four
sides of this box that
contains the text magic cake.
And if we set a top and
bottom padding of 10 pixels,
we can see that the size of the
magic cake part hasn't changed.
But we have increased the
size of the content box
by 10 pixels on
the top and bottom.
So our content box got bigger,
while the content inside
did not.
Margins should be used to
add space between two boxes.
In this example
on the left, we're
setting a top and bottom
margin of 20 pixels.
And you can see what that
looks like in the browser here.
And notice how
that red box that's
showing us our
box for the h2 tag
is not any bigger
because of the margins.
The margins are that invisible
space outside of that red line.
If we were to change
that number from 20 to 4,
we can see that the vertical
space between the three boxes
gets smaller, because
we've decreased
the margins between them.
OK, so a quick summary
of all the things
we know now about boxes
and the box model.
We know each tags content
fits in this invisible box.
We know that each
block level tags
box takes up an entire line.
We know that we
should use padding
to adjust the space
inside a container.
And margine to adjust the
spacing between containers.
But why is there spacing here?
We didn't write any
CSS to change any
of these margins or padding.
So why is the browser
doing that for us?
Well, the answer is that
the browser actually
has a default style sheet.
And if you don't override those
styles to make them your own,
it's just going to
use the defaults.
So here on the left we can
see the defaults left on.
If we were to turn those default
padding margins and borders
off, this is what
our page would look
like when we viewed it again.
Definitely looks
a lot different,
and we're certainly missing
a lot of those nice spacing.
Here's some CSS that we
could write to achieve
this reset layout of the page.
We just include one
selector for each one
of the tags in our page.
And we set the padding, border,
and margin equal to zero.
And that's going to reset all
of those box model properties
back to this even
baseline that we
can use to build up our own
version of the box model
for each of these tags.
This is important to
start from this baseline.
Because if you let
the browser determine
what your defaults
are, you're never
going to be sure if
the CSS you're writing
is affecting the layout, or if
it's that default browser CSS
that's affecting everything.
Now that all these
properties are reset,
we're going to need
to do some work
to build up the
layout of our page
again, so that it's
something that is little bit
easier to look at.
There's probably
many different places
you could start doing this.
So we're just going to suggest
one approach in this video.
First, start with the body
tag and add some padding
around all of the sides.
This is going to have
the effect of pushing
all of the children of the body
tag, which is all of our HTML,
pushing that inside away
from the edges of the screen.
And you can see the
effect of that here.
After we've set our
body style, we'll
move on to the next most
important tag, which
in this document is the h1.
For that h1, we'll add a
top and bottom margin, which
is going to have the effect
of adding some spacing
a little bit before and a little
bit below that recipe world
title.
Next, we'll move
on to the h2 tags.
And again, we'll add
some margin in there,
leaving us some space
between our menu
items and our paragraph tag.
Then we'll move
on to the h3 tag.
Again, making some
adjustments so that it's
a little bit easier
to read the section
header and it's not too close to
the paragraphs above or below.
Then after your
margins are in place,
think about where borders
might be necessary.
Not a lot of places were going
to use borders in the site.
But one place that might make
things a little more readable
is to add a bottom
border to our h3 tags.
When we do this, we've got
this nice section divider
for our ingredients and
directions sections.
If you feel that the border
at the bottom of that h3
is a little bit too close
to the ingredients text,
you could always add
some bottom padding
to push the border a little
bit away from the content area.
Remember that the box model
goes content, padding,
and then border.
So by adding some
padding in there,
we're pushing the content away
from the border a little bit.
Another use for padding
is to indent list items.
Since we turn all of our padding
off when we reset our styles,
our list items are
pushing all the way
to the left of the screen.
And you can even see
in our ordered list
that those numbers are kind
of getting cut off on the edge
because we don't have the
padding that's needed there.
We'd much rather have
some of that side padding,
like you see here on the right.
We want to add this
padding to the list itself,
and not just the items inside.
So we can add a left
padding of 50 pixels
to both the unordered list
and unordered list tags.
And now we've got some
padding to push those lists
a little bit over to the right.
Here's the result of reapplying
all of those box model
properties to the
tags on our page.
There's still a
few layout issues
that we'll handle at the
beginning of the next level.
But for now, it's your turn
to try working with the box
model in the challenges.
Have fun.