[SINGING] In 1980 Tim
wrote ENQUIRE at CERN,
invented the idea of
hyperlinks in turn.
In 1990 Robert joined,
a document they charted.
That's pretty much how the
world wide web started.
They defined some
markup code called
HTML, which paved the way for
stylesheets to decorate, as
well.
Navigate through URLs
to internet locations.
You can learn it all with
Front-End Foundations.
That's right.
Welcome back to
Front-End Foundations.
We've got our page in
a pretty good place.
But there's still a
few layout issues.
One of those problems
that I can see right away
is that we've got a padding
applied to our navigation
and to our ingredients
unordered lists.
But we really only want
that padding to be applied
to the ingredients list.
The problem is
that we can't just
set padding on ul because that's
going to apply to all uls.
We need a way to add padding
to one ul and not the other.
So we need a way to
differentiate those two tags.
Solving this problem
is a two-part fix.
First, in the HTML,
we'll want to go
into the unordered list that
contains our site navigation
and give that tag an
attribute of class.
And set that class
attribute equal to nav.
Then in our CSS, we
can write dot nav.
And that tag will be selected.
So we have a class
of nav in HTML.
And we can access the tag
that has that class by writing
dot class name.
Now inside of that
nav rule, we can
set our padding left to zero.
And our padding for our
site navigation is gone.
But the padding for our
ingredients ul remains.
Now that we have the
special nav class,
what if you want to do
something like change
the style of only anchor
tags that are inside
of a tag with that class?
Well, we can do that with
descendant selectors,
just like we learned before.
So we can write dot nav space a.
And that means find all
"a" tags that are inside
of the dot nav tag and apply
these styles to those anchors.
With this knowledge,
we should be
able to fix another main
problem with our unordered list
layouts-- the fact that our
site navigation is displaying
inline.
But our ingredients list
is also displaying inline.
We would rather have
that still display block,
so we get those
nice bullet points.
Right now in our CSS
we've got this rule.
We're selecting all list
items that are children of ul
and setting them
to display inline.
That's making sure that the site
navigation and the ingredients
are displaying inline.
But now that we have a more
specific navigation class,
we can move that
display inline rule
into the dot nav li selector.
And it's only going to apply
to the site navigation.
That means our
regular unordered list
inside of our
ingredients section
gets its bullet points back.
I want to point out
something important
when you start
working with class
selectors and regular
type selectors together.
The order that you write those
selectors in your CSS file
matters.
Here, I've got a dot
nav selector that
sets the padding left to zero.
That padding left for
the ul is actually
going to override the
padding for the dot nav.
That's because the HTML
tag that has a class of nav
is also a ul.
Since the HTML tag
with a class of nav
is an unordered list,
by writing my generic ul
selector after that, I'm
actually overriding the padding
that I set in dot nav.
And that's not what
I want to happen.
So a good rule of thumb when
you're organizing your CSS
is to always declare
your broad, generic rules
for individual tags at
the top of your CSS file.
And then after that, you can
declare any specific rules
that will get applied to the
class versions of those tags.
Now we're setting a padding
left of 50 for all ul tags,
except for just this one ul
tag with a class of dot nav.
That's going to have a
padding left of zero.
You might even say that the
broader rules cascade down
into the more specific rules.
And that's actually
part of the reason
why CSS is called
Cascading Style Sheets.
So far, we've only been
working in magic-cake.html.
But there's other
pages for our site.
One of those pages
is the recipes page.
So let's switch gears and
start building that page up.
The HTML structure of that page
will look something like this.
We've got the same h1
and site navigation.
But we've got
different header two,
indicating this is
the list of recipes.
And we'll set up an
unordered list of list items.
And instead of just a single
tag in those list items,
it will contain a link to a
recipe and a short description
of that recipe with
a paragraph tag.
If we try to view this page
right now in our browser,
though, it looks like
we're back to square one.
None of our styles that we
just created have carried over.
That's because in
magic-cake.html we included
the style tag in the
head of that page.
But that style tag is not in
the head of this recipes page.
So we need a way to take our
CSS, put it all in one file,
and link to that file from every
single one of our HTML pages
so that we don't have
to constantly rewrite
the same CSS over and over.
Luckily for us, CSS can actually
be written in a plain text
file, also.
All we have to do
is make sure that we
save that file with
the extension dot css.
So here we'll take all
the CSS that was currently
in that style tag in our
HTML, and we'll copy it over
to a file called main.css
so that all of our CSS
can live in one place.
Next, we need to import
main.css into our HTML file
so that those styles can
be applied to our page.
And the way we can do this
is with a tag called link.
Now, link looks a little bit
different than any tag we've
seen so far in that it doesn't
have a corresponding closing
version.
You just write the opening link
tag, and you don't close it.
So since there's
no closing part,
you might have
guessed that we can
tell this tag what to do by
giving it certain attributes.
The first attribute we
can add is called type.
And we can set it
equal to text/css.
And that's going to let the
browser know that we're getting
ready to load a CSS file.
Another attribute
called rel, which
is short for relationship,
can be set to stylesheet.
And that lets the HTML know
that it should relate to the CSS
and apply it to the page.
And finally, we can
use an href attribute,
just like we did when
we had an anchor tag,
to set the path of the CSS
file that should be loaded.
Adding the single link tag
to the head of your document
with these options is going to
make sure that CSS file gets
loaded at the top of your page.
Now if we reload our
recipes.html page
after we've linked
that CSS file,
things are looking much better.
We're now inheriting all
those same styles that we made
originally for magic-cake.html
But those broad rules are being
applied to all of the tags
inside of recipes.html, too.
The very top of
recipes.html looks OK as is.
But the list of recipes could
use a little bit of attention.
Because we're applying
those same broad styles
that we had in
magic-cake, you can
see that we've got these
bullet points next to each one
of the list items.
We've got an underline
underneath the name
of the recipe.
And the spacing, in general,
is just kind of off.
Instead, we can work
towards a layout
that's something like this.
We don't want any kind
of list style for the ul.
So we don't have any bullets.
We want to have a
border around the li,
so we can differentiate
the sections.
We want to have some left
padding between the list item
border and the content
area of the list item.
We want to remove that
border underneath the h3.
And we want to use our
green heading color
for that anchor tag
for the recipe name,
instead of just that
default blue link color.
So this is really
a similar problem
to the one we faced with
our site navigation.
We need a way to differentiate
the second unordered list
from any other
unordered list that
might appear on any other page.
So like before, we can assign
this unordered list a class.
And we'll call this one
recipes, since this style will
apply to only the recipes page.
Our existing broad ul style
has a left padding of 50.
We can take our recipes
class style, which is a ul,
and we can set the
list-style-type to none
to make those bullet
points disappear.
And we can set the
padding to zero
to turn that left padding off.
To add some border
and padding to the li,
we can just select the dot
recipes li and apply it there.
And this is what we'll get.
To create a more specific
version of our h3
that's inside of
the recipes ul, we
don't have to do a whole
lot because we actually
want to still inherit
all of these styles
from the generic h3.
We just want to turn
the bottom border off.
So we can do that by
writing border-bottom zero.
And finally, we'll
make a specific rule
that changes the color
of the anchor tags that
are only inside of the recipes
ul with the recipes class.
And we'll remove that
underline from them.
So now it's your turn to tweak
styles on multiple pages using
class selectors and
move all of your CSS
into a separate file
in the challenges.