Welcome back.
We're on a roll organizing
the different parts
and styles for our page.
So let's go another
step further.
In our current layout, we've
got this pretty clear separation
on all of our pages between
the header of the page that
contains our site title
and the site navigation
and all the content
that's below it.
So we should go an
extra step and somehow
organize these into
separate units on the page.
We can do that with
a tag called div,
which is short for division.
And it's really just
this block-level tag
that's a very generic
way to group related
content on your page.
Grouping your HTML
inside of divs
is really just as
simple as deciding
where the open and close
div tags go on the page.
Here, since we want our
h1 and our site navigation
inside of our header
div, we'll create
one open and close div block
that contains just those two
pieces of HTML.
For the rest of the
HTML on the page,
we'll create another
open and close div block.
We'll throw all of
that inside of there.
And we'll indent
all the HTML again
to show that these two divs
are children of the body tag.
Now that we have
two divs, we need
a way to differentiate
them in our CSS.
So, again, we'll add
a class of header
to the first div and a class of
main-content to the second div,
so we can tell them apart.
As we're adjusting the
styles for these divs,
we'll want to reset the padding
of 20 pixels that's currently
around our body
and just turn that
off and make it zero again.
And then we can reapply
that padding individually
to both the header div
and the main-content div,
along with some other properties
like borders and margins.
Another thing we can do now
that our header is separate
is we can give it a completely
distinct visual style
from the rest of the page.
So here we've set the
background color of the header
to this reddish color.
And then we change
the anchors that
are in the header and the h1
tag, which is in the header
also, to white, so we can see
them against this new color.
Since div is a block-level
tag, its natural tendency
is going to be to take
up 100% of the width
that it has available
inside of a container.
In this case, it's the
body tag as a container.
But we can change this by
setting the width property
on the div to some number.
Here we've set it to 500 pixels.
So now that div is only ever
going to be 500 pixels wide.
And all of the
content inside of it
is also going to have to reflow
to fit in that 500-pixel space.
Since the width
of this div is now
less than the entire
width of the screen,
it'd be really cool if we
could center it on the page.
There's two ways to center
content when you're using CSS.
And it depends on the type of
content that you're centering.
If you want to center an entire
block-level tag and that tag
is fixed width, then you can
set the left and right margins
for that tag to Auto.
As you can see in the
browser, that main content div
is now centered.
Auto is the special value that
really means take as much space
as you can.
And since both the
left and right margins
are trying to take up as
much space as they can,
they push the main content div
into the center of the screen.
So margin auto is for centering
an entire block-level tag.
But if you want to center
content that's inside
of a block-level tag, then you
set the text-align property
of that content to center.
So here I'm taking the h1
that's inside of our header div,
setting the
text-align to center.
And that's going to put that
h1 in the center of the screen.
We can use the same technique
to center the navigation menu
in the header and even
the h2 that's inside
of our main content section.
So before you try
some more challenges,
I wanted to say one
thing about fixed widths.
If you've been reading about
or making websites before,
you're probably
wondering why we're
teaching fixed widths here
instead of relative widths,
like percentages and ems.
Fixed widths are great for
learning how page layout works.
And after this course,
you can actually
continue into our Journey
Into Mobile course
where you'll learn
how to convert
all your fixed widths into
their relative equivalents.
So have fun in the challenges.