[SINGING] In 1980 Tim
wrote ENQUIRE at CERN,
invented the idea of
hyperlinks in turn.
In 1990 Robert joined,
a document they charted.
And that's pretty much how the
whole world wide web started.
They defined some
markup code called
HTML, which paved the way for
stylesheets to decorate, as
well.
Navigate through URLs
to internet locations.
And you can learn it all,
Front-End Foundations.
You can learn it all,
Welcome back to
Front-End Foundations.
In this section, we're
going to be adding images
to our web page.
Now, when you're working
with content on the web,
there's really three
different types of images
that you encounter-- content
images, layout images, and user
interface images.
Content images are
images that are just
as necessary to the page as all
the text that appears on it.
An example of that are the
product images on amazon.com.
These images are actual
content on the site.
And they help you decide what
content you want to look at.
Layout images, on
the other hand,
are images that appear in the
background of the web page.
And they're not
necessary to understand
the content of the page.
Take this Adobe
page, for example.
If this little star at
the bottom right corner
was not part of
the background, you
would still be able to
consume and understand all
of this content on the page.
So it's a layout image.
Another type are user
interface images.
And these are images
that will help
you understand
how to move around
or navigate through the
different sections on the site.
These are helpful images.
But they're not
in the background.
And they're not actual content.
So they're sort of
their own category.
Let's start by learning how
to create content images.
Images are created
with the img tag.
And like link, img
is an empty tag,
which means you don't have an
opening and a closing version.
The place where you tell the
img tag which image to display
is with the src attribute.
You set that src attribute
equal to a path to an image.
So if we look at the
contents of our server,
we might have our
magic-cake.html file.
And in the same folder
we might have cake.png,
which is an image file.
It might make more
sense, though,
to put all of our images
in their own folder,
so they're not cluttering up
our main folder that contains
all of our HTML and CSS.
Setting that up is really easy.
We just create a folder and
put the images inside of it.
But that means that we also
need to update our relative path
that's linking to the image.
So instead of just
linking to cake.png,
we now have to link
to images/cake.png.
And that's going
to tell the browser
to look for an images
folder with that image file
inside of it and
display it on the page.
Let's look at how
images are loaded
in a little bit of
a different way.
So first, the browser
requests an HTML file,
like magic-cake.html.
Then magic-cake.html is
returned to the browser,
and the HTML is loaded.
In that HTML, there's an img
tag with an src attribute.
The file in that src is then
requested from the server,
in this case in images/cake.png.
And then that image file is
returned back to the browser
and displayed.
So there's two requests
happening here.
The first time, we're
requesting the HTML.
And then that HTML is making
another request for an image.
Another attribute that
all img tags should
have is the Alt attribute.
And inside of that
Alt attribute,
you should put a description
of the content of the image.
You might be asking,
well, why do I
need a description of my image?
And in short, it's for
accessibility reasons.
Not all visitors to
your site are going
to be able to view the images.
And visually-impaired users
rely on screen readers
to describe the text
and the images to them.
And adding an Alt
attribute is an easy way
to let screen readers do that.
Img is an inline-level tag.
So like anchor tags, which
are also inline level,
they're usually
going to go inside
of another block-level tag.
So here on magic-cake.html,
we've added another section
called Your Photos.
And that contains an unordered
list with a class of Photos
and some list items that
contain image files.
So when we view
that in the browser,
things don't look exactly
the way we want them to.
Each one of these
photos is displaying
on top of each other, as
opposed to side by side.
So we'll need to jump into
CSS to fix that problem.
We can first take
off the bullet points
and remove the padding from
our unordered list of photos.
And then we can
adjust that photos
list items to display
inline and have
a little bit of a
padding on the left,
so all three photos
aren't just pushed right
against each other.
And this is what we see.
Another place where
content images are commonly
used it to display
the logo for a site
or some other kind of site mark.
So here we're going to replace
our site's h1 with an img
tag that contains an
image version of our logo,
as you can see here.
Just like the h1 text
that we replaced,
we want our image to be
centered inside of the header.
But img is an inline-level tag.
And therefore it
can't be centered
with the text-align property.
Instead, we can just
change the image
to display as a block-level tag
and use Margin Auto to center
it.
When we write the
CSS, we'll want
to make sure to only select
images that are children
of the tag that has
a class of Header
so that all images
aren't affected.
And now it's time for
you to work with content
images in the challenges.