Welcome back.
In this section,
we're going to look
at how to add background
images to tags on the page.
And this is the
layout that we're
going to be going for by
the end of this section.
Background images are
not added in HTML.
They're added in CSS.
And there's several
different properties
that relate to adding
background images.
The first is the
background-color property.
Now, even if you're going
to be displaying an image,
you should always set a
background color in case,
for some reason, that
background image fails to load.
You want to use that
color as a fallback.
So since our background image is
going to be a very dark image,
we'll set our background
color to dark gray.
Next, we can use the
background-image property
to actually define
an image file.
And the syntax here is
a little bit different
than it was in HTML.
You set this property
equal to the word url,
with lowercase letters,
open and close parentheses,
and then inside the parentheses
the relative path to your image
file.
Also notice that quotes don't
need to be around the path
when you're adding a
background image with CSS.
Here, that's going to
load the gobbler.png file
from our Images folder as
a background of the body,
since that's the
tag we're selecting.
Which looks like this.
Next, we can control
the background position
of where in the container
the image appears.
And we do that by
declaring two key words.
The first keyword can either
be top, center, or bottom.
And the second
keyword can either
be left, center, or right.
So here by saying
top left, we're
taking the small
background image,
and we're making it appear
in the top, left corner
of the body.
If we were instead to set the
background position to center
right, you can see here
that the small background
image will appear
vertically centered
in the body on the right side.
So since we just have the
small background image,
we would like it to repeat
across the entire page.
And we can do that with the
background-repeat property
by setting it to repeat.
And you can see when we do
that the small background
image actually gets
tiled all across
and repeated all
across the body.
And it appears to be
one solid background.
Now there are some other
options for background repeat
like repeat just in
the x-direction or just
in the y-direction.
Or we can explicitly say don't
repeat this image at all.
But here it makes the
most sense to use repeat,
since we want this
to be repeated
in the x- and the y-directions
across the entire body tag.
Like some other CSS
properties, background
can be shortened
into just one line
by first defining the
color, then the image, then
the position, and then whether
it needs to repeat or not.
Since we have different
sections on our page,
we can also get creative with
our tile background images.
And we can set one
background for the body,
another background
for the main content
which sits on top of the
body, and another background
for the recipes list items which
are on top of the main content.
And now when we view
that in the browser,
we can see that the main
content sits on top of the body.
And the recipes' lis sit
on top of the main content.
And it gives a little bit of a
sense of depth and separation
to the different
sections of our page.
Another common use
of background images
is to set up containers
that display backgrounds
and then add text
tags on top of them.
Here's a list from the Game Spot
website that does just that.
Each one of those games
has a background image
that has actual HTML
text tags on top of it.
It would not be practical to try
to do this with content images.
So layout images
in the background
are a good choice here.
So one way to do this is to
create a div specifically
for displaying a
background image.
So here on our
home.html we're going
to show a featured
recipe of the month.
To do that, we'll
create a new div
with a class of featured-image
inside of our main content.
And then we'll adjust the
CSS for that featured image
to have a width
and height that's
equal to the size of our
background image to make sure
that we're showing all of it.
And then we'll set the
background to load our image.
You can see here that our image
is displaying in this container
as we expect.
But since this is
a background image,
we can add a text tag
inside of that div
as a child of that div.
Here we're using an h3.
And we're saying
featured magic cake.
When we style that h3
tag, we can do things
like set the background
color to something different,
change the color of the text
inside, adjust the padding,
even do something crazy
like make the text all
uppercase so it really stands
out against that image.
When we look at
the browser again,
now we have text appearing
on top of an image
because that image
is in the background.
So now it's your turn
to play with background
images in the challenges.