There's another
pretty common case,
when you're working
with images and that's
when you need to
have an image sitting
to the left of some text.
Now an image is an
inline-level tag
but text is a block-level tag.
So how can we make this work?
How can we make two
block-level tags sit aside
from an inline-level tag?
So we might try
something like this.
We might create to divs that
contain all of this content
and set their display to inline.
Seems like it would work, right?
Two inline tags sitting
next to each other.
That's how our previous images
and previous navigation menus
worked.
This approach will
actually not work.
And it's going to
look pretty nasty when
you view it in the browser.
It's still going to put those
things on top of each other,
even though the display
is set to inline.
So instead, we need
to use a special CSS
property called float.
Float is going to grant
these temporary powers
to an inline-level tag
to allow them to take up
some of that space that a
block-level tag is normally
going to try to fight for.
So here I've got an image,
an h3, and a paragraph tag
inside of this li.
If I target all of the
images that are inside
of this recipe's list
and float them left,
it's going to take each
one of those images that
is floated left and allow it
to occupy the left space where
a block level tag would
normally try to push it down
to the next line.
As you can see
here, the image has
floated to the left
of the two text tags.
And we've even added a
little bit of padding
to the right of the
image so it doesn't touch
right up against the text.
Now there's a lot more that
goes into working with floats
that I'm showing you here.
But code school
has a course called
CSS cross country, which goes
into a lot of different float
use cases in much
greater detail.
But now, something
simple like putting
an image to the left of two
block level text tags so
that they appear the way
we want them in our layout,
is going to be as easy as
using the float property.
And now it's your
turn to try floating
some images against some
text in the challenges.