[SINGING] In 1980 Tim
wrote ENQUIRE at CERN,
invented the idea of
hyperlinks in turn.
In 1990 Robert joined,
a document they charted.
And that's pretty much how the
whole world wide web started.
They defined some
markup code called
HTML, which paved the way for
stylesheets to decorate, as
well.
Navigate through URLs
to internet locations.
You can learn it all with
Front-end Foundations.
Front-End Foundations.
Welcome back to
In this final level
of the course,
we're going to be polishing
up our site's fonts
and even look at how we can
implement some basic form
designs for our Suggest page.
So fonts and font styles
can be controlled with CSS.
On a page like Code
School, you can
see that we've got a
couple different font
styles in action.
We've got a bold, large font
for the tagline, Learn By Doing.
We've got a regular,
medium-weight font
for the secondary
tagline, No setup.
No hassle.
Just learning.
We've got regular, normal
font for this sentence
or two of description
of Code School.
We've got a smaller
font for this tiny link
that says "Learn where to start"
that takes you to a new page.
We've got an
uppercase font applied
to the call-to-action
button "view our courses."
And then we've got an
uppercase font, again,
with bold applied to this
"learn, get, backbone,
sass, rails, and jQuery" list.
So we've got multiple font
styles on a single page.
Back on our Magic
Cake page, we can
see that there's definitely
been some fonts and font
styles applied.
And we haven't applied
them ourselves,
so there's probably some
default font trickery
that's happening in here.
But first let's
look at how we can
change the font of our page.
In the body
selector, which means
it's going to apply to every
tag that's inside the body,
I can use the
font-family property
to specify a list of
fonts that should be used.
Now, the first font in that
list is the ideal font,
meaning that the
browser is going
to try first to load that font.
If the browser can't
find that first font,
you can specify a
list of other fonts
that it should try to
load in the order it
should try to load them.
So here I'm also
trying to load Arial
if Helvetica is not available,
Times New Roman if Arial is not
available, and then
finally just a very
generic sans-serif default
font if none of those fonts
are available.
Remember, not all browsers
and operating systems
have all fonts
installed by default.
So sometimes the font you
want is not just always going
to be available in the browser.
So here's our Magic Cake
page after changing the font
to Helvetica.
And you can see that all of
the fonts for every type of tag
have been updated because
we applied this to the body.
If we look a little closer,
though, some of our tags
definitely have different sizes
and weights to those fonts.
We didn't set those
in our CSS yet.
So this is a clue that lets us
know that the browser is again
applying some of its default
behaviors to our CSS.
We didn't set this.
The browser set it.
So just like we did with
padding, borders, and margins,
we can reset our fonts to
a baseline default level.
One of the easiest
ways to do this
is to set the font-size property
to 100% for all the tags
that appear in your page and set
the font property to inherit.
And you can see, when you
do that, now every tag's
font on the page is the same
size and the same weight,
which is now a great template
for us to improve upon.
So we can start with our h2.
And we can use the
font-size property
to change the size
to 26 pixels, which
is going to make it a lot bigger
than the paragraph text that's
on the page.
Now pixels aren't
the only option
when you're choosing size.
You can also use relative
sizes like percentages and ems.
But like I mentioned in an
earlier level, in this course
we're focusing just
on fixed widths
so that you don't have too many
options while you're learning.
We can change the
thickness of this header
by adjusting the
font-weight property
and setting it to bold.
Normal is the default weight.
And bold makes the
font look bold.
You can also use
some other keywords
like lighter and bolder.
Or you can just use
numbers, like 100, 200, 300,
all the way through 900, to
set the weight of the font.
There's many other
font properties
that you can look up in
a CSS reference guide
when you're writing
your own font styles.
And we've just
listed a few of them
here so you can see the
effect they have on some text.
Aside from the font
properties, there's
another important text-based
property called line-height.
Line-height is like margin
for each line inside a box.
You remember that we can adjust
the space between content boxes
by using the margin property.
But that's not going
to adjust the spacing
of the lines in a single box.
And that's what
line-height is for.
By setting the line-height
to some number,
we can make the spacing
smaller or bigger
in between lines
of the same tag,
in this case, the
same paragraph tag.
So now it's your turn to
adjust your site's font styles
and line heights
in the challenges.