Welcome back.
In this last section, we're
going to look at how we can add
and style web forms.
Forms are a way for a
web page to get input
from a user beyond simple
input like just clicking links.
HTML forms, like this
Code School sign-in form,
usually contain
things like labels,
inputs of different types,
text areas, and even
a Submit button, so
all of the information
entered into the form fields
can be sent to a server.
Now, that last part I mentioned
of sending data to a server
is not going to be
covered in this course.
But it is covered in
many other code school
courses that talk about
server-side topics,
like Rails for
Zombies for example.
But we can still
design how we want
this form to look
in the browser,
even if we don't hook it up
to a server to save that data.
So on our suggest.html
page, we're
going to have a form that
has several labels, a text
area, several input
fields, a check box input,
and, finally, a Submit button.
Here's some HTML for
a very simple form.
It starts with a form tag.
And that's a parent tag that
contains a couple others.
This one contains a label
and an input with type text.
The label describes
what the user should
enter for that text input.
In this case, the
label is recipe name,
so this text input
should have a recipe
name when the user's done.
We're also including a special
input type called submit,
which will take all
of the user input
and send it up to the server,
assuming you connect that part.
There's several
different types of inputs
that you could
have in your page,
like text, check
boxes, radio buttons,
file uploads, a
password which will just
change all the letters that
you're typing in the field
to hide the password that's
being typed, and, of course,
the Submit button.
There are several others, but
these are a few common ones.
There's also some
attributes that you
should add to your
labels and inputs
in order to connect them
together at the HTML level.
So the label tag takes an
attribute called for that
can be set to any value.
Here, I've said
it to recipe-name.
And in order to associate
that label with the text input
below it, you want to set an
ID on that text input that's
equivalent to the same value of
the for attribute in the label.
So again, our label's for
attribute is recipe-name.
And therefore our input's ID
should also be recipe-name.
And now that label is
associated with that input.
Input tags are great if
you only need your users
to enter a little bit of text.
But if you want them
to enter a lot of text
or multiple lines of text,
you should use a textarea tag.
Now, textarea tags look
a lot like inputs that
are just a little bit taller.
But the way you write the
HTML is actually different.
Textareas use opening
and closing tags
where inputs do not.
You'll also notice
that textareas
don't need to define a
type, as the only thing that
can go inside of there is text.
And here we've also set an ID
of ingredients on this textarea
because the associated label has
a for attribute of ingredients.
When it comes to
styling forms, one
of the first things
you're usually
going to want to do when you
have labels and text inputs
is switch their display to
block instead of inline.
The reason for this
is that you don't
want your labels and inputs
reading from left to right.
You want them reading
from top to bottom.
So here when we set our label
and our input fields to block,
you can see the
result in the browser.
We have multiple labels
and inputs in our form.
And they're pretty scrunched
together right now.
So we want to apply
a bottom margin
to our labels which will put
some space between the labels
and inputs.
And we'll also want
to add a bottom margin
to our inputs which
will put even more space
between the inputs and labels.
We can also set a
width on our inputs
so that they're all the
same horizontal size.
We have one problem,
though, when we did this.
By setting that width
on all input tags,
our Submit button was
affected because it is also
an input tag.
And we don't want
our Submit button
to be the same width
as our text boxes.
So we can use a cool CSS
selector called an attribute
selector.
And the way that you
write that is you
write the name of the tag.
And then you write
square brackets.
And you put the name
of the attribute
equals the value
that you want to select.
And notice also that
we don't need quotes
around the attribute value.
So this selector is looking
for all input tags that
have an attribute of type
where that attribute is
equal to submit.
And we're applying the rule
of making the width smaller
and adjusting the font size.
We can do something similar
with our text inputs
by selecting only inputs
that have a type of text
with another attribute selector
and then setting their border
to some different color.
We've already adjusted the
width of our input fields
by using the width property,
but we can't actually
use the height property to
adjust the height of text input
fields.
Instead, we have to use
a combination of changing
the font size or padding.
So here you can see we changed
the font size to 24 px.
And the input field
has gotten bigger
to fit that new text size.
But if we also want
to make the input
bigger beyond just the text,
we can add some padding
to this text box.
Because, remember, that
padding increases the space
between content and borders.
Textareas, on the
other hand, can
be sized with the width
and height properties.
So it's perfectly OK
here to set the width
and height of this textarea
and have it grow accordingly.
Our text and textarea inputs
are at a pretty good spot.
So now we want to
add a check box input
that the user will
be able to check
if they want to receive a
newsletter when they submit
a recipe to our site.
So we'll start by adding the
HTML with a label and an input
for that check box.
But unlike text inputs,
you don't usually
want to have your label and
check box on different lines.
You want them to display from
left to right because it's just
a lot easier to read that way.
The problem is we've already
set all of our labels and inputs
to block, which is
forcing that check box
input onto a new line.
So, again with
attribute selectors,
we can select all inputs
with a type of check box
and all labels with a for
attribute equal to newsletter.
And you can set their
display back to inline.
And now we've got our
label and our check
box appearing next to each
other on the same line.
Here we can see the final
state of our suggest form.
And it's looking pretty good.
So now it's time for you
to go into the challenges
and create and style your
own form for the site
that you're building.
Good luck.