[SINGING] An Ember app
contains it all, your templates
big and sometimes
small, their routers
roots components to let
Ember Models work for you.
Controllers to help decorate the
views which you can integrate.
Mix them together, in December
warming up with Ember.
You're watching warming
up with ember.js.
And this is level
three, where we're
going to take a route
through the woods
and learn about resource routes.
In the last level, we
learned about controllers.
Remember, the name
of the controller
matches the name of the
route and the template name.
And then if we take a look
inside the template, remember,
templates use properties
from controllers.
Well in this level, we're
going to build a products list.
So when we click on that
products link up above,
it's going to show all of our
products on our products page.
Obviously, the first step
when we have a new page
we want to add in
our application,
is to add a new route for it.
So here we are
back in our router.
But before we do that,
we need to make sure
we understand the difference
between regular routes
and these new routes
called resource routes.
Regular routes are typically
adjectives, verbs, or adverbs.
So an adjective
might be something
like on sale, expiring,
new, or internal.
A verb route might be something
like sign up, ignite, help,
or rate.
Resource routes
on the other hand,
are typically nouns,
things like tree,
review, books, or contacts.
Notice they can be
singular or plural.
In our case, we have
a list of products
so we're going to call our
resource route products.
And put that up there
inside of our router.
A resource route behaves
a lot like a normal route,
except it has some additional
functionality, which
we'll get to later
in this level.
Just like a route,
if we want to we
can pass in an optional
path, as you see here.
We can also define a template
with the same name that
will get rendered when
we go to that route.
Lastly, to add a
link to this route,
we simply do as
we've done before
and say link to
products, tag name
LI because our links
are list items.
Here you can see if we go
to this URL listed here,
we'll see that the link
has a class of active,
because we're in
the product's route.
And it renders the products
template as we'd expect.
To build out this page,
we want to list out
a series of products.
But we want to
pull that list out
of some sort of data resource.
So let's figure out
how to do that now.
To properly do this,
we're going to need
another component
called a route.
A route fetches data and passes
it to the Ember controller.
It also decides what model
to use in the current route,
and also decides what template
to render to the screen.
Just to review, every
Ember application
has one ember router, which
translates paths into routes.
Every application can
have multiple Ember routes
that provides data
for the controllers.
These are two
separate components.
Don't get them confused.
Here comes a diagram again.
And as I mentioned a
minute ago, the route
sits between the router
and the controller.
Let's solidify
this all together.
So first of all,
we have the router,
which defines a routes
or application needs.
In our case, we have a
resource route called products.
Then we have the route, which
is responsible for getting data
from external resources.
And just like the
controller, it's
created by Ember if
it's not defined.
This is what the code looks
like that it defines for you.
Then you have the controller,
which decorates the model
and provides property values.
And this is what the default
code looks like for that.
Let's take a look at
a very basic model.
So here you can see we
have an array of products
that we want to render
out into our web page.
We're putting it inside
of our application.
Notice the name space app dot.
At the end of the
next level, we'll
show you how you could pull
this data out of an API.
But for now, we're simply going
to store it in our application.
Then we're going to
define our products route,
specifying the model
property, which
is a function that
returns this array.
The model property
here can either
be an object or an array.
In our case, we have an array.
To put it all
together, the route
is responsible for
fetching the model.
Ember will set this
model on the controller.
And that's what will be used
in your handlebar template.
So what would happen if we set
a handlebars template called
products, which simply printed
out the model property.
In this case, it would print out
object, object, object, object.
Which is really
just two objects.
And those objects, as you
might assume, are our products.
This is obviously an array.
So we'll need to loop
through it to print out
the different values.
To loop using
handlebars, we could
say each product in model.
And then inside there,
specify product dot title.
In this case, it would loop
through each item in the model
array, and print out
the product title.
It would look
something like this--
There's a simpler
way to write this.
Because our template
knows that our data
is inside of our model property.
We can simply write each.
And inside each, specify the
properties from the product
that we want to print out.
And our template knows
what we're talking about.
We want to print out
all the information
from all of our products.
So we're going to create
a few more HTML elements,
printing out our properties
with some styling.
And if we go to
our browser, we now
see a list of all
of our products.
Time for you to build some
resource routes and also
some routes.
Don't get confused.
But that's what
you're going to do.
It will make more sense
in the challenges.
Go.
What are you waiting for?