In the last section, we created
our first resource route,
as well as our first
Ember route which
mapped a model to a
controller and a template.
So we have our products list.
But how might we make it so
that we have a unique URL which
goes to a specific
product page, and so
that we could click on a
specific product in our listing
and view more details
about a product?
As with any new page
in our application,
we start in the router.
So here, because
product is a noun,
we're going to write
this.resource('product').
However, this isn't quite
enough because there's
nothing unique
here to that path.
We need a path with a
parameter, maybe something that
goes to product slash and
the product title name,
so we know what product we're
trying to view on that page.
To do that, we're going to add
a path with a dynamic segment.
Here you can see we
have products/:title.
This will allow us to go to
this URL, products/Flint,
and in this case, it will
allow our application
to read the string
Flint out of that path.
Similarly, if we were
to go to products/4,
it would allow us to
read 4 from that path.
How can we get
access to this data?
Well, it's inside
our route object.
So you can see, we defined
a ProductRoute, not products
route, but singular
product route,
because that's the
name of our route.
And inside of it, we
define our model property.
And look, we have a
function with parameters.
Now we're simply going to
log out those parameters.
If we went into our browser,
we would see that when we go
to products/Flint that our
parameter looks exactly like
this, title:'Flint'.
So now I can get access
to those parameters.
But logging out to the console
isn't what we want to do.
We need to figure
out a way to look up
a product out of our products
array, which, remember,
looks something like this.
It turns out that
Ember adds some helper
methods to base JavaScript
objects, including array,
and we're about to use
one of those methods.
Here, we're going to
grab the PRODUCTS array
and then call the
findBy method, sending
in two parameters, the
title, because that's
what we want to
find the product by,
and the title that was passed
in through the parameters.
So now when we go
to products/Flint,
the model that should
get found and returned
should be the Flint product.
Now we'll create a new
template for the product route.
We'll simply print out the
title, description, and price.
When this template sees
those Handlebars expressions,
first, it's going to look in
the controller for properties
that have these names.
If it doesn't find
them, it's then
going to look in the model
for properties, where
it will find them and
print them to the page.
So if we jump back
into our browser
and go to products/Flint, we'll
see that our product template
is rendered, and our product
is printed to the page.
Two more things we want
to add to the store.
First, let's add an image
to our Product page,
using that bind attributes
helper method, like so.
No surprises here.
The second thing we
want to do is jump back
into the products
template, where
we list out all the products.
Here, we want to link to
each individual Product page.
So all we have to do here is
specify link-to 'product'.
And then we need to send in
the product we want to link to.
We're going to be using the
keyword this, which specifies
the current product that
we're on in the array.
Here's where things
get interesting.
See, the link-to
helper knows that when
it goes to create the URL
that we should be creating
a URL with the
title value in it.
It knows this because
when we defined our route,
we had :title as
our dynamic segment.
Thus, when we go to
link-to 'product' this,
it's going to create
the URL products/Flint.
And now, if we jump
back into our browser,
we can see that here on
the Products List page,
we can click a link,
and it brings us
to the product route, which
renders the product template.
And if we click on Products,
we can go back to the list
and see that the other
product works as well.
Let's have you try out
some dynamic segments,
and I'll see you
in the next video.