So we just created our first
dynamic segments inside
of resource routes, as
well as creating a singular
product for our product route.
Now we're going to revise
some of our templates.
We're going to create
a nested template.
See, right now, in
our products list,
we're rendering that
out in the outlet
in our application template.
And same thing with our product.
We're rendering
our product inside
of the outlet in the
application template.
To visualize it, we've got
the application template.
And it's got that one outlet.
And both the products
template and the product
template render inside
that single outlet.
But what if we wanted to
do something different?
What if we wanted
to do something
like this, where we have a list
of products on the left hand
side.
And when we click on that, it
shows us that specific product
on the right hand side.
This instance, our
products template
that lists the products is
going to be in one template.
And then inside of
that, there's going
to be another inner template
showing the product.
So basically, we want to
put our product template
displaying one product inside
of our products template, which
is going to list out
all the products.
But how is that possible?
Well, the first
step to doing this
is, of course, to jump
back into the router.
If we're going to
have nested templates,
we're also going to
have a nested route.
In this case, our
product resource route
is going to be nested inside
our products resource route.
We're still specifying the
dynamic segment of title
but notice it doesn't contain
slash products anymore.
This is because it's nested
inside of the products resource
route.
It's simply assumed.
The Ember path that this
creates is products slash title.
That's a dynamic segment.
The route that is going
to call is product.
That product route
keyword is what
it's going to use
to look up if it
has a route, or a controller,
or a template of that name.
And the URL that we're going
to use to access this route
is simply products slash Flint.
This is the first step
for nesting a template
within a template.
Next we need to add a new outlet
inside of our products list
to show it where to render
the specific information
about a product.
So here you can see we're
going to specify a new outlet
inside of that
products template.
And that's where the product
template will be rendered.
Here we are in our code.
And as you might notice,
we've changed up our products
template to be a
list of products.
And there at the bottom,
we're going to add an outlet.
Now we go back to the web page.
On the left hand side, you can
see we have our products list.
And when we click
on one of those,
our product template
gets rendered inside
of our products template.
Effectively nesting it.
As your application contains
more templates and more routes,
you may need help debugging.
This is where the ember
inspector for Chrome comes in.
It's just for Chrome for now.
And it's just a plug-in you
can install to the browser.
And I'm going to show
you what it does.
So here we are
inside of our app.
I'm going to call up dev tools.
You'll see we have
a new ember tab.
Inside that tab, we've
got our View Tree.
So as we scroll through
different templates,
it actually shows
us on our web page
where each of our templates are.
Then if we click on
routes in this tab,
we're going to see a list
of all the routings we have
in our application-- the
name of the routes, the name
of the controller, what
template its rendering,
as well as the URL that
would trigger this route.
In this case, we're
at the product route.
But look at that.
There's another route that
we haven't mapped before.
It's products dot index,
which maps to a template
called products slash index.
Bet you wonder what that is.
It turns out this product slash
index template gets rendered
when you go to the
products route,
where we just list
out the products.
And if you have this template,
products slash index,
it's going to load that into
that outlet on the products
template.
That's a little confusing.
Don't worry.
It'll be clear in a second.
We're going to create a
template with the name products
slash index.
And it prompts people
to choose a product
from the list on the left.
Now when we go back
to our products list,
you can see that template
show up right there.
Choose a product from
those on the left.
When we click on a product, it
will come to the product page.
Then when we click
on the products
link in the upper
right hand corner,
it goes back and shows us that
product slash index template.
One interesting
thing to note here
is that you see how both
the products navigation
list item and the
product link are active.
That's because it's
effectively giving both links
the class of active.
Kind of neat.
Why don't you go try
some nesting on your own,
and I'll see you in level four.
A route-- no router.
--must be our products.
I think I hit the microphone.
Are typically adjects.
Adjects?
Rejects.