[SINGING] An Ember
app contains it,
all your templates big
and sometimes small.
They're in routers,
roots, components, too.
Let Ember models work for you.
Controllers to help decorate the
views which you can integrate.
Mix them together in December,
warming up with Ember.
Welcome back to Warming
Up With ember.js.
In this level, level
five, we're going
to be first looking
at array controllers.
Back in level four, inside
of our products route,
we wrote some code to
set the model, which
is all of the
products in this case.
We say, find all products.
But how might we do sorting,
or ordering, on these products?
For example, back
on this page, you
see how none of those products
are sorted alphabetically?
Well, first let's figure
out how to do that.
We're going to look
at two different ways
to sort your models.
The first is right
here, where we're
going to call Find--
not Find All-- Product.
And then the second
parameter is going
to be an object with the key
of Order and a value of Title.
Sorting in this way is actually
leaving it up to our server
to do the sorting before it
sends the data into our Ember
application.
So it's going to go to our
store, our store's client side.
The store tells the adapter if
we're using the REST adapter.
It's then going to call
out to our web service.
And this might
generate a URL, which
looks like this to send
back to our server, which
tells our server that the order
we're looking for equals Title.
And that's going to just
be a parameter on the URL.
And we're leaving
it up to our server
to sort things properly
and give us back a JSON
array, which is in
the proper order.
So this is how we're going to
have our server do the sorting.
However, the other
way we can do sorting
is to have our client, or
our browser, do the sorting.
And in order to do
that, we put that code
inside the controller.
Remember, your
controller is where
you decorate your applications
data for the template.
In order to sort arrays
inside of our controller,
we actually need to use a
special type of controller that
knows how to deal
with array objects.
See, a controller has
two different variants
which we'll often use.
The first is an
Ember.ObjectController,
which helps you decorate
a single object.
And the one we need to use
is Ember.ArrayController,
which specifically
decorates an array
and gives us lots
of helper methods.
Basically, if our
model is an array,
we should be using
an array controller.
So here you can
see, we've properly
declared it in our code.
This gives our controllers
some special abilities,
including this option
called sortProperties,
where we can specify how
we want to sort the model.
By default, this
will automatically
sort in ascending order,
that's from A to Z.
If you wanted to
do it descending,
then you just need to specify
another option, sortAscending,
false.
Now if we jump back
into our browser,
we can see that our products
are properly sorted by name.
And in this case, we're using
this sorting in the controller.
Now that's partially because
we're using fixtures now.
Remember in the last
level, we switched over
to the rest adapter to
do calls to the server.
Well, for the remainder
of this course,
we're just going to be using
fixtures to keep things simple,
which in that
case, we have to do
our sorting inside
the controller.
Back in level two, we
created a property inside
of our IndexController
called productsCount,
with the number of products.
But now since we have
a products model,
we should probably go back
here and have it actually count
the length of the
products array,
to have the right number of
products there on our index.
First step here is to
go into the Index wrap
and set the proper model.
So in our case, we just do
this.sstore.findAll product.
The next step, since
our model is an array,
is to change our controller
to an array controller.
We need to get the
length of our model
in the productsCount property.
So to do that, we're first
going to wrap it in a function.
Next, we need to call the
this.get length method.
This is first going
to look inside
of our current controller
for a property called Length.
It's not going to find it.
So it's going to
delegate to the model
and look for a property
called Length, where it's
going to find it and return the
length of our product array.
This is equivalent to
calling model.length.
Now what if in some other
part of your application,
somebody creates a new
product, or deletes a product.
We're going to need
to update this value.
So we need some way
of telling the code,
keep an eye out on the
length of the product array.
And if it changes, well,
get the length again
and update the page.
To do this, we're going to
send in an argument of length.
This is going to keep a
watch on the Length property
of the controller.
And if it changes, it's going
to update the productCount here,
and on the page,
and in any templates
that use that property.
You're going to be writing a
lot of these type of properties
in Ember.
So there's a shorthand
way of doing it
that looks something like this,
with Ember.computed.alias.
It's functionally
the same thing.
So now if we jump
into our browser,
we're going to see that we
have six items displayed.
But let's go ahead and on the
console, delete one product.
Do you see how it got
updated on the page?
Now there's five.
If we lead another
product, now there's four.
So no matter which page deletes
a product or creates a product,
this template will
always get updated,
even if it's not
on the home page,
and the proper number
of products shown.
Why don't you try creating some
of your own array controllers?
And I'll see you in
the next section.