In the previous section, we
created our first component
to eliminate duplicate
template code.
But what if inside our
component template,
we wanted to add some
additional functionality,
like for instance, checking to
see if a product has reviews,
and if it does, print
out the reviews count.
So let's figure
out how we can add
these properties, hasReviews
and our views count,
to our component.
When we call product
details, our Ember component
from inside a template, the
first thing that happens
is it looks for a
component object.
In this case, it would be
App.ProductDetailsComponent.
This is where we
can set properties.
You know, the ones we saw
in the previous slide.
Once this component
object is loaded,
it's then going to render
our component template,
like we have been doing.
Let's go ahead and create
that component object.
Here, you can see we have
App.ProductDetailsComponent.
our first property is
going to be reviewsCount,
which simply uses our
passed in product.
Then we have our
hasReviews property.
This is going to get the reviews
count, the property we just
declared, and check to see
if it's greater than zero.
Obviously, if it is, it's
going to return True.
Lastly, we want to keep an
eye on that reviewsCount.
We want to watch it, because
if the length of the reviews
changes, well, we want
to run this function
and update the template.
Now that we've declared
our component object,
we can see now here in our
component template that's
going to properly check to
see if a product has reviews.
And if so, print out
the number of reviews.
Now if we go back
to our browser,
we can see that
under each product,
it says Read All Reviews, and
has the number of reviews.
Before we jump into
the challenges,
you can try creating one
of these component objects.
I want to show you
an alternate method
for setting the tag
names and class names.
Remember, when we were
setting them in a template,
called the Ember component.
However, we can also set these
inside our component object.
So let's go ahead and remove
them from our example.
And then inside of our
ProductDetailComponent,
we can simply write tagName,
Li, and ClassNames row,
and it's going to
do the same thing.
We would only want to do this if
we wanted to have the same tag
name and class names every time
that Ember component was used.
However, in our case, we've got
different tag names and class
names, depending on where it is.
Remember, sometimes
we had a div,
and then another time,
we had a list item.
So our example
wouldn't use this.
Go ahead and do a
component object,
and I'll see you in a minute.