Here we are back on
our product page.
You can see we have
product details, including
some reviews.
But there's no indicator here
that this product is on sale.
How might we add
a class for that?
So here's a product template.
And what we want to do is
add the class "is on sale"
to this top div, if
the product is on sale.
To do this, we're going
to be using an Ember
view, represented by this
little pine cone you see here.
A view is responsible for
encapsulating HTML content,
like what we're doing
here, registering
and responding to
user initiated events.
And finally, Ember component
extends from Ember view.
You've kind of seen
a view already.
Back in our Ember diagram,
views sit it about there.
So it's after the
controller, before we
get the handlebars template.
When we first declared a
product route in our router,
it created for us a
product route like this.
And of course, we don't
have to write that code
unless we want to
really customize it.
In the same way, it created
a product controller for us.
It also created a
product view you
for us, which we can of
course declare and add
custom behavior, which
we will in a second.
After the view, the
request then look
for a product template,
called product.
Here we are back in
our product template.
Notice here we have
div, class, row.
Well if we looked at the source
of our browser creates for us,
remember it's going
to be two divs--
the ember view div and
then the class row div.
Well we only want one div.
And it turns out we
can define a view
to set the proper classes
on the templates div.
This is obviously the row class.
And if the product
is on sale, we
want it to add the
is on sale class.
So obviously the
first step here is
to get rid of that second div.
So we're going to
take that row class
and move it down into
our product view.
Here we're declaring
And it has a class name of row.
We can alter a
bunch of properties
here, including tag,
class, even which
template it should render.
To figure out if a
product is on sale,
we need to call the
is on sale property.
We're going to do it like this.
This is going to look
for the is on sale
property inside the controller.
It's not going to find it.
So it's going to look
inside the model.
This way, views can
get access to the model
from their controller.
Now we're going
to use a property
that you haven't seen before.
It's called class name bindings.
What this does is it first
checks the is on sale property.
The one we just declared.
And if it returns
true, then it's
going to add a new class
to our template div, called
is-on-sale.
So as you can see here, it
took our camel case class name
and converted it into dash case.
So now in our browser, we can
see that this div properly
added the row class and
the is on sale class.
Why don't you try
creating a view.
And I'll see you in
the next section.