Here we are back in
our Products template.
You notice we have Reviews.
But what if we also show
things like comments,
related products, products
other customers bought?
This template will
start to get really big.
We might want to start
splitting things out,
maybe into their own templates.
Well, let's do
that with Reviews.
So here we're going to
shrink it down a little bit.
And we'll move reviews
into its own template.
But does it need to
be its own component?
It might be overkill.
What we need to do is create
what's called a partial.
Our partial is going
to be called Reviews.
So back in our Product
template, we'll
say Partial Reviews to
render out that partial.
We don't need to pass
anything into a partial,
because it's going
to have access
to everything that this
template already has access to.
We then name our
partial "_reviews."
All partials begin
with an underscore.
If you're familiar with Ruby
on Rails, the idea of a partial
should be really familiar.
If we jump back into
our Products page,
we can see that it's rendering
out just like it was before,
but now the template is
a little more organized.
As I mentioned, partials have
access to all the same things
that the template which called
the partial has access to do.
So in this case, it's
Product Controller,
they have the same
Product Controller.
They have access to the same
models and the same properties.
Let's take a look at
the different handlebars
helpers that we've
learned so far compared
to the regular amber route.
So component helper has
both a component object,
and then it renders
out a template.
Or a partial just has
a single template.
Why don't you try
playing with partials?
And then I'll see you
in the next section.