[SINGING] An Ember
app contains it all,
your templates big
and sometimes small.
Their routers,
routes, components,
too-- let Ember
models work for you.
Controllers to help decorate the
views which you can integrate.
Mix them together in December,
warming up with Ember.
You're watching
Warming Up with Ember,
and this is the final level,
Level 7, where first, we're
going to be talking
about controller actions.
So in the previous
level, we wrapped up
with talking about
render and about how
that calls a new controller
and then a view and then
a template for our reviews.
But one thing we
did not talked about
was how to create new reviews.
So let's go ahead and add
a new form on this page
and have it update
that list of reviews.
We're going to add this form
inside the product template.
So here we have a
div class new review,
and it's going to have
a text area in there.
We're going to be using a value
binding, like you see here.
This binds the value
of the text area
to the text property
inside the controller.
We want to show the user
what the review looks
like before it
actually gets posted.
We simply do this by printing
out the property to the screen,
just like we would
with any property.
If we jump back into the browser
and we start typing a review,
you can see every time we hit
a key inside that text box
the text property
gets updated and then
the template gets updated.
So we see the preview
on the screen.
There are three
more things we need
to do to make this
form fully functional.
The first is we only want to
print out that review preview
paragraph if the
text has a value.
Then, we need to do something
with the Submit button
to make sure it
submits to something,
and then we need to
write the code that
receives the review when it
gets submitted and updates
our model properly.
First up, back at
our template, we're
simply going to add
a conditional here.
If text-- if there is
something in this property--
then show the review preview.
Then, in our Submit
button, we're
going to use the Action
Helper and specify
the action create review.
That's going to call
the create review
function on our controller.
Let's go ahead and jump
back into our controller.
The first thing we're
going to want to do
is declare the text property
here and set it to blank.
If we let this off, the property
would be set in the model.
That wouldn't be good.
Next, we're going to declare
a section in our product
controller for actions, like
when we submit the button.
Inside actions, we
need to create the one
that our button calls-- in
this case, create review.
And for now, we're simply
going to log out to the console
every time this
action is called.
Back in our browser, we can
try clicking the Review button.
And as you can see,
every time it's clicked,
it logs out-- create
review called.
So our action is working,
but we're not yet
saving the review
in a model that's
associated with the
product, so there's
three more steps
inside this code.
We need to build out a new
review object, save the review,
and then clear out
the text variable,
because the review
was submitted.
Step one, we're going to
call the create record
method on our Ember store.
We're creating a
review, and then
the second argument is
simply an object, which
contains the text of the
review, and we're simply
going to get the text property.
And we'll set the association
by getting the model, which
is our current
product, and then we'll
go ahead and set an extra field.
We'll set reviewed At
to our current date.
Create record doesn't
actually save the record,
so that's what we need to
do next, called review.save.
If we were using
the rest adapter,
this would be the point at
which it would call back
to our server and give it
the data for the new record
that we just created.
Next, we need to
specify what happens
if the record gets
saved successfully.
In order to do
this, we first need
to create an extra
variable, called
controller, which
is simply going
to store this, which in this
case is the product controller.
When we call save, it
returns a type of object
called a promise.
If you're not familiar
with promises,
checkout jQuery Return Flight,
the code school course.
We go over promises.
This promise has a
method on it called then,
which allows us to
specify a function
to call once the save
call is finished.
Inside this function, we need
to reference the controller
and set the text to blank.
That's blanking out the text
property in our template.
And then secondly, we need
to assess the reviews model
from that controller and
add our new review to it.
Adding this new review will then
trigger an update to our page,
adding our template
to the existing list.
So here we are in the browser.
Let's give it a try.
We create a new
review, submit it,
and boom-- our review
gets added to the list.
Forms are a pretty key component
of any web application.
It's time for you
to give it a try.