In the previous section,
we split out the reviews
into its own template.
But what if we wanted to
sort by most recent reviews
and do this on the client side?
Well, sorting typically happens
in the controller, right?
So how would we do this?
What we need to do in this case
is, from that product template,
go from there to a
ReviewsController.
That's where our
sorting's going to happen.
It'll then render out
the ReviewsView and then
our reviews Template, which
will no longer be a partial.
We do this using
the render helper.
We're going to say
render 'reviews' reviews.
Basically, that second
reviews is the object
which is going to be
passed into the controller
and automatically
set as the model.
Then our partials
name is simply going
to get rid of that underscore
and just be reviews.
So from our product
template, it's
this line-- render
'reviews' reviews-- that
tells Ember to go look
for a ReviewsController
and set reviews as the model.
Let's go ahead and
create our controller.
It's going to be
an array controller
because we have a
list of reviews.
And we're going to set the
sort properties to reviewedAt
and sort it descending.
This is going to use
the reviewed passed in
as the model, as we mentioned.
And it's going to render out
the reviews Template, which
we saw before.
And now, if we go back
to the product page,
we can see that we're showing
the newest reviews first.
So really, we have a
bunch of different ways
of rendering templates.
We would use a route when
we have an endpoint URL.
And the route uses a controller
and a view and a template.
We can use the render
handlebars helper
if we need a controller where
we can decorate a model, perhaps
do sorting.
And that's going to have
a view and a template.
Then we can use
a component if we
need to create a highly
reusable part of our webpage
that doesn't need a controller
and only gets the information
that we pass into it.
And then lastly,
we have a partial,
which is another
reusable template, which
is going to use the parent
controller-- whatever
it got included from.
You get it?
I know it's a lot of
different helpers,
a lot of different information.
Why don't you jump into some
challenges, let it sink in,
and then I'll see you
in the next level.