So, we created our review form.
We also went into the
product controller
and reformatted that
to use a review object,
and our "create
review" action uses
that object to create a review.
But what if our products page
looks something like this,
and our reviews are
getting a little bit long?
Wouldn't it be nice if
there was a Read More link?
Maybe it showed you the
first 100 or 200 characters
and then you could hit Read
More and it would expand.
Maybe you could even say Read
Less and it would get smaller.
And what about
allowing our users
to use the markdown
template language?
Well in this level, we'll figure
out how to do these two things.
To add these additional
user interface properties
to our list of
reviews, we're going
to be creating a custom view.
The first thing we can
do with a custom view,
is have it encapsulate some of
our tags, for example our li.
We're going to declare
[? "view tag, li." ?] And
that's simply going to
wrap things in an li.
This is functionally the
same as we had before.
Next, we need to specify a
custom name for our review.
We're going to call
ours "App.ReviewView."
And now we're going
to create that class.
You can do it like this.
So we declare, "App.ReviewView."
But what goes
inside of the View?
Well, there's two
things we need to do.
First, we need to add a
class, "isExpanded," that gets
added to our li when
the text is expanded.
Secondly, we need a click
event, and every time somebody
clicks on it, it's going to
toggle the "isExpanded" class.
First, we're going to create
the "isExpanded" property
and set it to false.
Because starting out, we're
not going to be expanded.
Next, we're going to add a class
name binding of "isExpanded."
What this does, is
it's going to watch
the "isExpanded" property.
And if that ever
get set to true,
it's going to add the
is-expanded class to our li.
Next, let's add our click event.
So we're going to simply specify
"click" and then a "function."
Inside the function,
we're simply
going to toggle the property
"isExpanded," which will set it
to true if it's false,
and false if it's true.
Ember has a bunch of
different other view
events that we can listen
for, whether it's submit,
keyDown, mouseDown,
change, or keyUp.
And you can read all about
these events in the API Docs.
Let's jump back
into the browser.
But before we do,
I need to mention
that we set some code
in our style sheet
so that reviews, by default,
have a maximum height, so
that it's only going to show the
first two lines of the review.
Then, once the "isExpanded"
class is added,
well, it's going to expand to
the full height of that list
item.
So here, you can see, when we
click on a particular view,
it adds the "isExpanded" class.
And it looks like we can click
on reviews, even though they're
not longer than two lines.
We might want to change our
code to account for that.
Also, we need a "read
more" button, right?
So our problem here is that
we need to add a class, "read
more," if our list item is
more than 140 characters.
We're going to solve
this in four steps.
First, we're going to send
our "text.length" value
into the View, so
that we can access it.
Then we'll create a
function called "readMore"
which will check to
see if that string is
more than 140 characters.
Then, we'll add the
"readMore" class name
to those particular list items.
And lastly, we'll
modify our template so
that, if we can read more, we'll
show that "Read More" link,
and if not, we'll
show "Read Less."
Our first step is to pass in
the length to our custom view.
We're going to do that by just
doing "length=text.length."
Next, we'll create the
"readMore" property,
which is going to
be a function that
checks to see if the length
that we just passed in
is greater than 140 characters.
And we'll want to keep an
eye on the length property,
in case it changes.
Now, as a third step, we need
to add a new ClassName binding
of "readMore" so than when
it's true, it adds "read-more"
to our list item as a class.
And lastly, back
in our template,
we're going to add
a new span which
will say "Read Less" if
we already are expanded,
or "Read More" if we
haven't been expanded.
And this span is
only going to show up
if our list item has
the class "Read More."
You might notice that
in our conditional,
we have "view.isExpanded."
We need that view dot so that
it's accessing our custom view.
Otherwise, it would be
looking for "isExpanded"
as a property in our controller.
Before we check this
out in the browser,
there's one way we
can simplify it.
Instead of calling
the code you see here,
we can simply call--
readMore, Ember.computed.gt,
as in greater than, with the
arguments of length and 140.
And Ember has a bunch of
these computer properties
that you can read more
about in the documentation.
Now, if we jump back into our
browser and click "Read More,"
it works.
Hey look, and it
changed to "Read Less."
And even "Read Less" works.
It properly toggles
our "isExpanded" class.
We're almost done.
Just one last thing before we
get to the final challenges,
and that is, we're
going to learn
how to define our own
handlebars helper.
It looks something like this.
We call
"Ember.Handlebars.registerBoundHelper."
The name of our
helper is "markdown."
No need to specify the function
that this helper invokes.
In this case, we're simply going
to take the text that comes in
and pass it back out.
Then, in our
template, we're going
to use this helper by just
specifying the name of it--
markdown-- and then the text
we want to pass into it.
So obviously,
right now, the text
would just get
passed right through,
but we want to make
it convert markdown.
So to do that, we're
going to include
our own external
markdown library.
And that markdown library we can
call by doing markdown.toHTML
and send in our text, which
is in markdown format,
so it's converting it into HTML.
But there's one more thing we
have to do before this works.
See, handlebars is going
to automatically escape
all the HTML and the
strings that we pass to it.
And in this case,
our markdown is
converting to HTML that
we don't want escaped.
So, to get around that,
we need to tell handlebars
that this HTML is safe
to print to the screen.
Now, when we go back
into our browser,
we can see that we did some
markdown-- doing some bold,
doing some bullet
points, worked out well.
It's worth mentioning, before
you get into the challenges,
that Ember likes to
stay unopinionated
when it comes to text
in HTML formatting.
They believe you
should go out and get
your own external
libraries, because there
are a lot of really great
libraries for JavaScript
that do this already.
So, something to know.
Now it's time for to
do the last challenges,
and I'll see you
in the outro video.
This (SPEAKING SLOWLY) level--
[OFFSCREEN LAUGHING]
[BEEPING]
You can see that the review
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)--
[OFFSCREEN LAUGHING]
[BEEPING]
Our review-- view--
[OFFSCREEN LAUGHING]