(SINGING) An Ember wrap contains
it all-- your templates,
big and sometimes small.
There are routers,
roots, components too--
let Ember models work for you.
Controllers to help decorate the
views, which you can integrate.
Mix them together.
In December-- warming
up with Ember.
You're watching Warming
Up With Ember.js.
And this is level
one, where we're
going to be talking about
how to get set up with Ember.
Ember.js is a
JavaScript framework
used to create ambitious
web applications.
And there's a lot
of companies that
have used it, in some
form, to create their own.
In order to learn
Ember.js, you're
going to need to be familiar
with HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
and jQuery.
If you're not, Code School
has some great courses
on that topic.
Head over to the
JavaScript path.
You do not need to know any
of the back-end frameworks,
like Ruby on Rails or
Django, to learn Ember,
because Ember.js is a
JavaScript framework.
So it resides on the front-end.
Here's an example of an
application that uses Ember.
This is Discourse.
It's, effectively,
a discussion board.
And as I click
around on Discourse,
you'll notice the pages
load pretty quick.
It's very responsive,
you might say.
This is one of
Ember's strong points.
Discourse, itself, is also
a very dynamic website.
A lot of the content
in there is getting
loaded from some sort of
database on the back-end.
In a typical web
application, we probably
fetch information from
the database and use
that to render out
HTML, which we then
send back to the browser.
Some web applications
also have APIs,
which might be
used to communicate
to native applications,
like maybe on your iPhone,
through iOS, or on
your Android phone.
But here's what's
interesting about Ember.
See, Ember sits on
the client side,
and it communicates
with your application
through that same API,
pulling data and then
rendering different
templates to the screen.
Not only does Ember make
navigation from page
to page quick, but if you
want to provide your user
with instant
feedback, like, say,
a preview of the
reviews they're typing,
Ember makes this super simple.
You wouldn't want
to use Ember.js
when your application doesn't
have a lot of interactivity,
like, say, with a blog, or a
newspaper, or a static website.
It might be overkill to go
through and build a full stack
Ember application.
To start building an
Ember application,
you'll want to go to the
official Ember website
and download the starter
kit they have there.
It contains all the libraries
you need to get going.
Also, if you want to communicate
with a back-end server
and pull data through an API
into your Ember application,
then you might also
want to grab Ember Data.
Next up, in our
application, we're
going to be using
Twitter Bootstrap, just
to make our website
organized and look pretty.
And so you might want
to grab that as well,
if you're going to follow
along with our course.
You could play around
with the starter kit,
but we're going to build an
Ember application from scratch,
so you can see what it looks
like from the ground up.
So let's start by building
our index.html page.
We'll start by including the
jQuery framework, as well
as the Handlebars framework,
which we'll go into later.
Then we'll include the
base Ember.js framework
file, as well as the
Ember Data library.
Lastly, we'll include
a file that we're
going to create-- app.js.
Now, we're going to be working
in this app.js file for most
of this course.
This is where all of
our custom JavaScript
is going to be placed.
And lastly, we have our
Twitter Bootstrap style sheet.
As you might have noticed
with the theme of this course,
it all centers around
these fire sprites.
So we're going to create
an online store for them,
because even fire sprites
need online shopping.
And they can buy things like
Flint, Matches, and Tinder
in our online store,
called The Flint & Flame.
In this first
level, we're simply
going to be building out the
main Index page and the About
page.
And the first step to
build an Ember application
is to create our
application object.
This application contains
everything about our Ember app,
and we basically namespace
it by calling it App.
But you could have called
it anything you wanted to.
You see that little icon there?
Well, that means we're talking
about the Ember application,
and we're going to
use that icon whenever
we're talking about
our application.
It's the roots of our app.
And we basically only need
to create one of them,
and all the other
components grow from there.
The first thing we can
do with this application
is send in a series of options
as a JavaScript object.
For example, if we wanted to
log out a message to the browser
every time a page
is accessed, we
could set
LOG_TRANSITIONS to true.
Now let's build out a little
more of our index.html.
We'll have a navbar.
We'll have a container,
and we'll have our footer.
To open this application,
we can actually just
double-click on the index.html.
You don't need any server
to run an Ember application.
So if we did that, and we looked
at the source of our HTML,
we would see
something interesting.
We would see that
Ember added a body
class and a data-ember-extension
to our code.
This is so Ember knows what part
of our web page it can control.
In our store, we're going
to be dynamically updating
parts of the page, based
on what people click on.
And in order to do
that, we need some way
of telling our browser
what parts of our page
are dynamic and can be changed.
To do this, we're going
to wrap our three elements
in a template.
By default, Ember.js
uses Handlebars template.
Remember the library
we included earlier,
the Handlebars library?
So to wrap these in
a template, we're
simply going to use the
script tag, like you see here.
This is a Handlebars template.
So now, if we open up our
index.html in our browser
and inspect the
page, we'll notice
that a new div has been added,
representing that Handlebars
template.
And it even generated a
unique id for that div.
Whenever we're talking
about Ember templates,
you're going to
see this leaf icon.
Templates contain plain
old HTML, and, of course,
Ember uses Handlebars.js, as
I mentioned, for templates.
And really, it represents
the part of the application
that people see.
That's why it's a leaf.
Before we get much
further, let's make sure
that you understand
what we're doing
and get you starting to build
your first Ember application.