So in the previous
section, you saw
how we could take
an index template
and get it loaded into
our application template.
But that begs the
question, how do
we load the about template
into our application template?
And how would we also
map that to a URL,
so when somebody goes to
our application, /about,
it would load up the
correct template?
To do this, we're going
to need the Ember router.
And we're going to use the
symbol of the tree trunk
whenever we see the
router, because it
translates a path into a route.
And like a tree trunk,
all requests start here.
The Ember framework is
made up of many components.
We've already introduced
the Handlebars template,
which sits down here.
And now we've talked about
the Ember router, which
sits pretty close to
the browser request,
because it figures out the route
name for each request coming
in.
Here we are back
in our app.js This
is where all of our
custom JavaScript
goes to build our
Ember application.
And as you can see,
up there at the top,
we have our Ember application.
Now let's build a router.
To start defining routes
in our application,
we simply write
App.Router.map and pass
in an anonymous function.
Every page in our website
will be defined by the router.
So what do we need
to add to the router
when our browser goes
to visit the About page,
and we want to render
out the about template?
To do this, we write
this.route and send
in the about string
as an argument.
What this tells our application
is that when our browser visits
the about path, we want our
Ember application to render
the about route, and
thus, when an outlet is
found inside of our
application template,
to go ahead and load the
about template inside of it.
Now if we jump into our browser,
and we visit the About page,
we'll notice that we get
About The Fire Sprites.
The proper template
has been loaded.
You may also notice that down
below in Developer Tools,
it printed out Transitioned
into 'about', because of our
LOG_TRANSITIONS true option that
we sent into our application.
You might be wondering, what's
going on with that weird hash
sign that happens
after the domain name?
Could we go to our
domain name /about?
Would that work?
Well, no.
If we went there, it would
say web page not found.
That's because there's no
about/index.html or about.html
path that our
application knows about.
That's because in Ember.js,
our entire application and all
the HTML it needs to render
is getting loaded through one
file, the index.html file.
And that's what gets loaded
when we go to example.com.
It doesn't matter what
page we load-- whether it's
the Home page, About page, or
Product List page-- we will
have first loaded the index.html
page, because that contains
all of the templates.
Just to reiterate, when our
browser accesses our Ember
application, the
first thing it does
is it sends over all the
templates, into the client,
into the browser.
Then at that point, it goes and
loads up individual templates
to display something
on the screen.
In this case, it's loading the
application template and then
the about template.
In case you haven't
caught on yet,
that hash tells our browser that
everything after this is not
part of the file path.
That information will
get passed into Ember,
so we can figure out
what templates to render.
But as far as our
browser is concerned,
it's going to load the
root path and load up
that index.html file.
If we didn't have
that hash-- well,
our application would
error out, because there
is no file path in or out.
If we followed a more complex
path, like you see here,
it's going to load up the
store file path on our server--
maybe look for a store.html.
And then if that's
an Ember application,
it might look at the
remainder of the URL
to load the shopping cart route.
Let's get back to
our about route.
Remember, it looks
something like this.
Now when our browser goes
to this URL, the file path
it loads up is
none, because it's
going to load up our
index.html if this
is the first time we've
visited this page.
The path it's going
to load is /about.
And that's going to map
to the route of about.
But what if we want to
override this default behavior
and maybe go to the
aboutus Ember path
and load the about route?
How might we do that?
Ember makes this really easy.
And we can do this by sending
in a new object to the route,
which specifies path:'/aboutus'.
Now when we go to
this URL and look up
the Ember path, aboutus, which
will load the about route
and properly load
up our About page.
Now you might be wondering, do
we need to add an index route,
so when someone goes
to the base URL,
it loads up the blank
Ember path and then maps
that to the index route?
The code might look something
like this, you might think.
It turns out we don't
need this code at all.
The default behavior in
Ember is to load the index
template, which is why, earlier,
when we had our Home page,
and we were loading
up the index template,
we didn't need a router at all.
So now if we jump
back into the browser,
you'll notice when we
click on the About link,
the URL changes to #/about.
And then we can
click on Home, which,
again, loads up the index route.
Now it's time for you
to add a new route,
and I'll see you
in the next level.
[BEEP] Web app-- blah,
blah, blah, blah.
[BEEP] Which is on our web
application-- web application--
[SPEAKING GIBBERISH] [BEEP]
[SPEAKING GIBBERISH] [BEEP] I
don't know [BEEP].