In the previous section, we
created our first Ember model
that used Ember data.
And we also revised
our product's route
so that it pulled the proper
records out of the Ember store.
But what if our model,
products, was associated
with another model,
like reviews?
That's not uncommon.
A store has products and
the product has reviews.
How might we create
those different models
and express that relationship?
Let's create another model
that represents a review.
Here you can see it has a
text field, which is a string,
and review at, which is a date.
Our next step is to express the
relationship between these two
models.
We simply have to write
reviews, DS.hasMany, review,
and then we'll specify an
option called async:true.
This will allow
for lazy loading.
This means when we're iterating
to the products later,
and we want to print out
a review for a product,
it will be smart enough
to then go and fetch
the records out of the
store for those reviews
so we can print
them to the page.
We also might want to
express the opposite side
of the relationship.
This wouldn't be
required in our example,
but it might be good to do.
So we'll say
product:DS.belongsto product.
Next, we'll create
our review fixtures.
They're going to require
an ID, and we're just
going to specify text and
give our review some text.
Finally, we'll map those
reviews back to a product.
The first one will be mapped to
product one and the second one
also product one.
Now we'll want to go back
to our product fixtures
and add those associations.
So here we can say
reviews, and we'll
specify the IDs of each of
the reviews for this product.
If you're maybe a Ruby developer
and familiar with ActiveRecord,
you're probably
wondering about now
why we need to represent
the relationship
in both directions, and tell the
reviews what product it belongs
to, and the product
what reviews it has.
Well this is just because
we're using fixtures.
Obviously, if you were
using a back end server,
you could map things
however you want.
But because we're using
fixtures, what's important here
is that we map products to
reviews, because we're always
going to be looking up the
product first, and listing
the reviews underneath it.
So it's most important
that our product
knows what reviews it contains.
Not the other way around.
Our reviews,
technically, don't need
to know what products
they belong to.
Now, back inside of
our product template,
we're going to show the reviews.
We'll loop over them saying
each review in reviews.
And then we'll print
out the review text.
Fairly simple.
Once again, we can
simplify this each loop
and just specify each reviews
and then the text element
we want to print out.
We also might want to
print something out
when a product has
no reviews at all.
In this case, our each
loop has an else condition
that will be run when
there are no reviews.
So, here we can say, no reviews
yet, be the first to write one.
Now when we go back
to our page, we
can see that our Flint has two
reviews there at the bottom.
And now if we click
on Kindling, we
can see that it has no reviews
yet, be the first to write one.
Before we set you loose
on the challenges,
I did promise you I
was going to show you
how to make restful server calls
to fetch this product in review
data.
And it's really
simple to get started.
All we have to do is set our
Ember application adapter
to the Ember data rest adapter.
Once we do this, and we
go back into our browser,
we can see that it attempted
to do a server request
to localhost:3000/products.
And I didn't find any JSON data.
So from here, we could either
create a file, called products
with some JSON data
in it, or we can even
create a server that might
have a database with a products
table and a reviews table.
And our Ember
application would want
us to create JSON that
looks something like this.
You can see this returns
both an array of products,
and an array of reviews.
And each product specifies
which reviews it has many of.
Now, if we go back
to our server,
the first time we
load up the server,
you can see it did one request,
called up all the JSON,
and now we can navigate
through our website listing
out the products, getting
the product information.
It's not connecting back
to the server at all.
It's keeping everything
on the client side
and simply accessing the
storage and pulling records
onto the page.
So now you know all
of the components
you need to build a
basic Ember application.
There's a lot more to it,
so get to those challenges.
We wong.
So this evening,
I won't be talking
about Acorn Models and
Pinecone Data, to the ladies.