[SINGING] An Ember
wrap contains it all,
your templates big
and sometimes small.
They're in routers,
routes, components
to let ember models
work for you.
Controllers to help decorate the
views which you can integrate.
Mix some together in December,
warming up with ember.
Welcome back to Warming
Up with Ember.js.
In this level,
Level 6, we're going
through the template forest.
Going through the forest.
Looking out for the trees and
the lions and tigers and bears.
In this first
section, we're going
to be looking over components.
Let's get into it.
In the previous level, we worked
with a bunch of product models.
We find all the products
in the Products Route,
and then in the
Products On Sale Route,
we were getting the model
from the Parent Route
and filtering that down to just
the ones that were on sale.
Then, on both the Index template
and the Product/ On Sale
template, we were printing
out a list of products.
But you might have
noticed we were
using the same HTML
in both places.
So in this level, we're
going to figure out
how to remove some
of that duplication.
To do this, we're
going to be using
an Ember Component,
this icon here.
Ember Components are
similar to web components,
if you're familiar with those.
If you're not, that's OK too.
We can split out any
part of our web page
into reusable components
using an Ember Component,
and we can also wrap
user interactivity.
You'll see what we
mean in a minute.
Back in our Ember
diagram, we can
see that components fit
down there at the bottom.
They're something we use
after the Controller that
helps us with our templates.
Back inside of our
Index template,
you can see here
the HTML code that
is going to be moved
into a component.
First let's shrink
it down, and then
we're going to take
the contents there,
and we're going to move it
into a new template, like so.
Later on, on the
top template, we'll
write some code
that will tell it
to render what we just
put on the bottom.
But our first step is we
need to name this template.
We're going to name it
component/product-details.
The template name for all
components must start with
components/, and also, all
components need to have a dash
in the component name.
Back inside our Index template,
to render our new component,
we simply write product-details.
But there's one more step here.
We need to send some sort
of data to our component
so it will render that
out to the screen,
so it knows what we're talking
about when we say Title.
To pass our current
product into our component,
we simply write product = this.
Then, inside of our
Product Details component,
we can simply write
product.title.
You remember how, every
time we create a template,
it wraps things in a div?
So really, by creating
this component right now,
we added another div
inside of our each loop.
So we want to get rid of that.
How would we get rid
of one of the divs?
Well, you see that col 4?
We're going to add
that class to the div
that our component template
would be creating for us.
We're going to move it up
into the Product Details col
and simply specify class names
= and then send in our class.
And this will give
our class name
to the div created by our
Product Details template.
Now if we jump into
our browser, we
can see that it's properly
rendering our Ember component,
and it gave it the proper class.
Remember there were
two different places
we were using that same code?
And the second one was
on the On Sale page.
Here we have a Product Details.
We need to use that
same component here too.
Just like we saw before, here
we write Product Detail, product
= this, and it's going
to include our new Ember
component.
You'll notice here, though,
we have LI class = row.
Well, remember, our component's
going to create a div.
But in this case, can we
make it create a list item
with a class of row?
We can, by writing
this: tag name = LI,
and class names = row.
We used Tag Name once before,
when we worked with Link To,
if you remember.
Now if we jump into
our browser, we
can see our component
rendering to the page,
and we have a list item with
a class of Ember View and row.
Be careful wandering
through the forest.
You might run into some Ember
components in the challenges.