(SINGING) An Ember
[? wrap ?] contains it all.
Your template's big
and sometimes small.
Their routers reach
components, too.
Let Ember Models work for you.
Controllers to help decorate the
views which you can integrate.
Mix them together in December,
warming up with Ember.
You are warming
up with ember.js.
And this is Level
4, where we're going
to be talking about Acorn
Models and Pinecone Data.
In the previous level, we
learned about Ember routes
and loaded in some data
from a JavaScript array.
But what if we wanted to fetch
these products from a server?
Well, that's where we're
going to be getting to
at the end of this level.
But there's a couple things
you need to learn about
before we get there, starting
with the Ember Model.
So the Ember Model
is a class that
defines the properties
and behavior of the data
that you present to the user,
and well, every route can
have a Model.
Previously, we set this
Model to a JavaScript array.
On our chart, you can see
that the Model appears
under the route, because
it's the route that
tells the controller
what Model to use,
and that also gets rendered
out in the template.
In programming language terms,
you might think of a Model
as a class.
In our case, we're
working with products,
so we're going to
have a product Model.
And that class is
going to allow us
to create many
instances of products
that might have
different values.
Models are typically nouns,
just like the typical class,
and we create one just
like you see here.
We also need to
tell our Model what
attributes it contains, just
like you would set attributes
on a class.
So remember our product data?
We need to take a look
at that and figure out
what data types our
Model should expect.
Are there strings,
numbers, Booleans, dates?
What are each of
those attributes?
Let's go ahead and define
the different properties
in our Model definition.
You can see that we have a
title, which is a string;
price, which is a number;
description, which
is a string: "is on
sale," which is a Boolean;
and then, finally, an image,
which is also a string.
It's a good practice to
define the different data
types that your Model
properties have.
However, it's not required.
If the property types
aren't supplied like this,
they'll be implied by Ember.
Typically, Ember Models
will use another library
called Ember Data.
They don't have to,
but most of them
will, because
Ember Data makes it
easy to use Models to retrieve
records from a server,
cache them for performance,
save updates back to the server,
and create new
records on a client.
The Ember Data
component, of course,
sits under the
Model in our chart.
Ember Data has
different adapters
you can use to load in data.
The first allows you to
communicate with an HTTP
server using JSON, and
that is the RESTAdapter.
This is the default
adapter for Ember Data.
The second allows you to
load records from memory.
This is the FixtureAdapter.
And this is what we're going
to use in our application,
so we can just load data right
there from the page itself
into Models.
Fixtures are also great if
you're creating an application
from scratch, and you
don't have a back end
to connect it with yet.
We need to slightly modify
our JavaScript array
with our data in it so
it can become a Fixture.
To do this, it needs
to use the Fixtures
constant within the Model.
So we call App.product.FIXTURES.
We also need to give
each product a unique ID.
All Models in Ember need
to have a unique ID.
Ember Data has this
notion of a store.
It's a central repository for
all records in your application
available in routes
and controllers.
You can think of it as a cache
store for all your records.
So inside of that store is
the Fixtures we just created.
And we'll use the store to
set and retrieve records.
To use Ember Data
in our application,
we need to make some
small tweaks to our app.
First of all, inside
of our router,
instead of using the
dynamic segment title,
we need to switch
to using the product
ID as the dynamic segment.
This is because
Ember Data, again,
needs a unique identifier.
Now, potentially, we could
have multiple products
with the same title.
Next, we need to
update our routes
to get our Fixture
data out of the store.
So here, instead of
returning app PRODUCTS,
we're going to return
this.store.findALL "products"
which will return all
the product models.
Next, since we're no longer
using a JavaScript array,
to fetch a particular
product, we're
going to call
this.store.find "product"
and then pass in the
parameter product_id, which
we'll get from
the URL passed in.
Ember is full of
intelligent defaults,
and here's another one of them.
If this is the behavior we
want inside our product route
to find a specific
product with the product
ID we pass in,
then, well, we don't
need to specify it at all.
We don't need any of this code.
And it's going to find
the proper product
based on the product ID.
So now, if we jump back
over to our server,
we can click around, call up
a Flint, call up the Kindling.
You'll notice it's
now using the ID.
We can refresh,
and it all works.
Let's try building some
Models with Fixtures
in the challenges.
And I'll see you in
the next section.