So now that we have a
Handlebars template,
how about we put dynamic
content inside of that template?
Well, as we learn
more about Handlebars,
we'll learn about these things
called Handlebars expressions.
Expressions allow us to insert
a variable into our HTML page.
In this case, we've got Welcome
to {?_[? siteName ?].
Notice that siteName has
curly braces, two of them
on either side.
The siteName's value will need
to be provided by our Ember app
to render it out
on the web page.
But we're not going to cover
how to do that quite yet.
That will be in further levels.
We don't have enough
knowledge yet.
In the meantime, we need
to add a few more templates
to our application.
Remember, our template, right
now, contains three elements.
We have our navigation
bar, our container--
where most of the content
for the page will go--
and our footer.
But our application is going to
contain at least three pages.
Where does the content for
the Home page, About page,
or Product List go?
Well, when we render the About
page, the content for that page
is going to need to get
rendered inside the div
with the class of container.
And also, when we
render the Home page,
we're also going to
have content which
should get rendered inside that
container, which also happens
to be the default we want
to occur when we load up
index.html for the first time.
There's a few steps
we need to take
so that we can have one
index.html and dynamically load
in the contents for the
About or Index page,
depending on which one we want.
And the first step is
to name our templates.
We're going to name our
main template we already
created, the application
template, and then
we're going to create templates
for about and for index.
So here we are back
in the code, and we're
going to add a
data-template-name
for our application, like so.
This contains the main
layout of our application,
and is going to be
rendered on every page.
Now we're going to create
another template for our Home
page.
We're going to give it the
data-template-name of index.
And inside of a
script tag, we'll
put the HTML for the Home page.
Next, we'll create the about
template, call it about,
and put the proper HTML
content inside the script tag.
Now let's load back
up our index.html.
But uh-oh, it's not working.
Our application template's
not even showing.
There's no welcome message.
It should be there.
What's going on?
Well, we forgot one step.
So if we look back
inside of our app,
we'll see that we need a way
to tell our templates where
to render.
So there's our index
template, but it
doesn't know where to render
inside of our main application
template.
To do this, we need to add
an outlet to our application
template.
This tells our code where
to insert templates.
On top of this, when we hit the
Home page, if our application
layout hits an
outlet, it's going
to look for an index
template by default.
And now, sure enough, when
we open up our index.html,
we see that our index
template is rendered inside
of our application template,
as we needed it to.
And now it's time for you to
try this out in the challenges.