So we know how to map path names
to route names in our router.
And we know how to link to other
pages using route names, not
the paths, like you see here.
How would we print out dynamic
data inside of our template?
For example, if we
wanted to print out
the number of products,
doing something like this,
how do we set the
productsCount property
so it gets rendered
out to the page?
This is where Ember
controllers come in.
A controller is
where a template is
going to look to find
the value of a property.
It's also how you're going
to decorate your applications
for the template, and it
also contains information
that is not stored
on the server.
We're going to represent
it as a branch,
because a branch has leaves.
Get it?
Back in our chart, the
controller goes about here.
And remember, it provides the
properties for the templates.
Well, it does a
lot more than that,
but that's how we're going to
be using it in this section.
So here we are back
in our index template,
and inside of that we have
a productsCount property.
When this template
gets rendered,
the first thing that happens is
that it looks for a controller,
called IndexController,
and then checks
to see if that index controller
has a property inside of it
called productsCount.
So the first step
is to create this.
We need to create
this controller.
So here you can see we
create an index controller,
namespacing it with
our Ember application,
and we define it like so.
Then inside of it, we declare
a productsCount property
which has a value of 6.
This code properly
renders out, "There
are 6 products," to the screen.
Now there's no
coincidence here that we
have an index template
and an index controller.
These both are referenced
by the index route.
Because we are doing
the index route,
it's rendering that template.
And because we are
doing the index route,
it's going to go looking
for the index controller.
It turns out that in
Ember, every route
has a default controller.
Remember our About route?
Well, we didn't have to
define a controller there.
That's because
Ember automatically
created one for us,
behind the scenes.
It looks a little bit like this.
But we don't need
to write that code.
We only need to write that out
if we need to define properties
inside of the controller,
which we don't, so we
don't need to have it.
If we open this up in our
browser and inspect the code,
we're going to see
something like this.
Our value, you can see here,
is wrapped in a script tag
with an id of metamorph.
What is that metamorph?
It sounds like
something out of X-Men.
Is it going to morph
into something?
I don't know.
Well, it turns out
that Ember uses
this script tag,
metamorph, to keep tabs
on properties in your
templates, in case
it needs to update them later.
There's another term for this.
It's called binding.
It's binding the properties.
Let's add another property
to our controller,
this time specifying a
logo to render to our page.
Now, you would think you might
be able to just print it out
to the screen like we did our
other property, just wrapping
it in curly braces.
Well, it turns out
that's not going to work.
And if we look
inside the source,
we can see there's the image.
And right after src=", it
actually inserted that script
tag and screwed up
our entire page.
Let's look at that.
This rendered to that,
which obviously is not
the right thing.
If we have properties
that are attributes,
we need to bind
them differently.
In this case, we're going to
use the bind attributes helper,
specifying src="logo".
Logo, here, is the
name of our property.
This then properly
renders out our image tag
with an extra data attribute,
so Ember can keep track of it.
Now if we go back
into our Inspector,
we can see that the image,
indeed, renders out properly.
Now what if we
wanted to print out
the current time in a template?
Well, to get the current
time on somebody's browser,
we would need to call
this JavaScript function.
But this is more
than just a value.
We actually need
to call a function
and return that
into this property.
To do this, we set time equal
to an anonymous function,
put the function that needs
to be called inside of there,
and return the value.
There's one more thing we
need to do here though.
We need to tell
Ember that this is
a property it needs to call
to get the return value.
To do this, it's simple.
We simply add the property
function to the end.
Now if we go back
in our code, we
can see that the time
properly gets printed out.
Why don't you go try
building some controllers?
And I'll see you in a minute.
[BEEP] [INAUDIBLE].
[BEEP] Trust me.
Just trust me.
[BEEP] [INAUDIBLE].
[BEEP]