In the previous section,
we hooked up our form.
So here you can see
our new review form.
And then in the
product controller,
we created a new action
called create review,
where we created a new
record and then saved it.
But if we go into
our browser now,
and we type in a new review,
and then we switch products,
you'll notice that the same
text appears in the text box.
It doesn't get changed
between different products.
Why is this?
It turns out that
controllers get reused.
When we switch from product
page to product page,
the only thing that gets
switched out is the model.
If we have properties
that have values in them,
they stay the same.
So how might we fix this?
There are a few
ways to fix this.
But how we're going to do it
is by creating a new review
object that will bind
into the template.
Then back inside
of our controller,
obviously instead of
creating a text property,
we're going to create a review,
which you'll see in a minute.
And then secondly, we'll
need to watch the product
to see if it changes.
And if it does, we will need
to create a new review object.
So replacing our
text property, we're
going to create a
property called review.
This is going to
create a new record.
Set the product on this
review to the current model.
And lastly, we'll tell
it to watch the model
on this controller,
and if it changes,
then create a new review.
Keep in mind, when we
call create record,
it's not saving a new review.
It's creating a new
instance of a review model.
But it hasn't been
saved anywhere.
Now let's jump back
into our template
and use our new review model.
So all we have to do here is
set review.doc, review.text,
and review.text.
So it's accessing that property
on our new unsaved review.
Now let's jump back into
are controller action,
create review.
This needs to be revised.
You can see here that
we're creating a record.
We don't need to
create another record.
We just did that.
So that code is
going to go away.
All we really need to do here
is set the controller to this,
get the review to set
the reviewed at date,
and then get the review
again to call save.
Everything else is
pretty much the same.
Now if we jump back into
the browser, let's go ahead
and submit a new review.
It worked.
But our review
form is still there
and the content is still there,
which we probably don't want.
We're only going
to want to submit
one review for a product.
So how do we basically hide that
form when we submit a review?
We're going to do
this by creating
a new property called
is not reviewed.
We're going to be checking that,
and if it has been reviewed,
then we don't want
to show the form.
Now back in our
product controller,
we're going to create our is
not reviewed property, which
is going to be a computer
alias of review.isnew.
Is new is a property on
the Ember data model.
As you can see, here's a
couple of different states
that you can check on a model.
There's a lot more
of these that you
can check out in the API Docs.
Now if we jump back
into our browser,
and we type in a review,
the review gets added,
and our form disappears
as we wanted it to.
And now it's time for you to
go disappear yourself and do
some challenges.