[SINGING] An Ember
wrap contains it all.
Your template's big
and sometimes small.
There are routers,
routes, components
to let Ember models
work for you.
Controllers to help decorate the
views which you can integrate.
Mix them together in December,
Warming Up With Ember.
You're watching Warming
Up With Ember.js
and this is level
two, where we're
going to be talking a
little more about handlebars
and some basics of
Ember controllers.
Back in level one,
we learned all
about the router,
which is in charge
of mapping a path
to an Ember route.
But how do we create
links to these routes?
Can't we just hard code
links like you see here?
Well, it turns out
this is a bad practice.
You never want to
hard code your links.
Instead we use the routes to
dynamically retrieve the URLs
when we create links in
our Ember application.
Let me show you what
that looks like.
To do this, we use a
handlebars link-to helper
and send in the route
name we want to link to.
Do this we use the Ember link-to
helper inside of our template.
It allows us to use the route
name to look up the path.
So here you can see
we call a link-to,
send in the route name.
Could be index, could be about.
We then have some text which
is the actual link text.
Then we have to
close our link-to.
Each of these will
determine the path
based on the route
name we send in.
And here's what the resulting
HTML will look like.
But what if we want to add
a custom class to our link?
Well, that's pretty simple.
All we have to do
in our link helper
is specify class
equals navbar brand
and the rendered HTML will
simply add that class.
Back in our browser, we
can click the About link,
which will bring us to be about
route and the Home link, which
will bring us to
the index route.
If you take a look inside
our devtools inspector,
you'll notice that our
logo has an active class
and our Home link also
has an active class.
About doesn't.
But look what happens
when we click on About.
Now About has the
active class, so it's
moved from the Home
link to the About link.
Ember has this nice,
intelligent default
where if you have a
link-to helper, which
is the same route as the one
you're currently visiting,
it will give you an
active class on that link.
And as you might imagine, you
can style that appropriately
in your CSS.
Next it turns out, since
we're using Twitter Bootstrap,
we need our links to have an li
element and not an a element.
So how might we
switch those tags?
Well, the link-to helper
has a tag name option.
So if we specify tag name
equals li for both of our links,
sure enough, it's going
to render out two li's
Now you might notice the
href has disappeared.
But it's still going
to work in the browser.
That's because
Ember's smart enough
to hook onto those li
elements and make it
so that the proper
pages are called up
when we click those list items.
So now if we jump
back into the browser,
you can see that both of our
links are now list items.
And if we click on About, it
properly goes to that page
and also sets the active class.
Now, if you're following
along using Twitter Bootstrap,
you obviously don't have
our styles or images.
If you want to,
follow the link below,
somewhere around
this video, that
will lead you to the
GitHub repository
where you can download
that style and images.
Time for you to
create some links.
And I'll see you in
the next section.