So in the previous
section, we learned
how to sort the array of
products inside the controller,
like you see here,
and we also learned
how to create a property tied
to a method on the model,
in this case, length.
The next thing we want
to add to our home page
is a list of three
products which are on sale.
To do this, we're going
to create a new property
inside of our controller.
Remember, it's our controller
that decorates our model.
So we have an
onSale property here
that needs to return for
us three products that
are on sale.
We're going to use a
filter here to filter
through our current products
and find three that are on sale.
Inside this property
function, we're
going to use the
filter method, which
is a method inside
array controller.
It will allow us to loop
over all the products
and return only those
that return true
from the inner function.
So inside there, we're
going to write return
product.get("isOnSale").
That isOnSale property
is either true or false.
So if it returns
true, then it's going
to keep that particular
product in the array.
If it's false, it's
going to filter it out.
There's a simpler
way to write this
by using the filterBy method.
Here, we specify
isOnSale because that's
how we want to
filter things, and we
want to return only products
which isOnSale is true.
So we set that in as
the second parameter.
It turns out the second
argument, by default,
is going to be true.
So we can simplify this and
just say filterBy("isOnSale"),
which is going to return for us
an array of products which are
on sale.
However, this is going to
return all the products that
are on sale, and
we only want three
to display on the home page.
So to return the first
three on sale products,
we simply use a JavaScript
function called slice.
This will give us the first
three items in the array.
Now back in our index template,
to loop through each of our
on sale products,
we call each onSale,
and it's going to loop
through each of the products.
Finally, we'll write some HTML,
printing out the proper product
properties to the page.
If we jump back
into our browser,
we now see we have three on sale
properties on our home page.
Now if we jump
into Ember console,
we click over on
the Data tab, we
can see our different products.
Let's try selecting one and
changing isOnSale to false.
It should-- hm,
nothing happened.
You might have expected it to
get removed from the home page,
but it didn't when we
set isOnSale to false.
Hm, what code would we have
to write to make this happen?
To fix this, we need to
jump back inside our index
controller, and we
need to tell our code
that any time the
isOnSale property
changes inside any product to go
ahead and refresh the template.
To do this, we
write each.isOnSale.
This is going to watch the
isOnSale property on all
of our products, and
if any of them change,
it's going to
update our template.
So now if we jump
back into our browser
and change isOnSale to false
for one of our products,
we can see that the template
is properly updated.
We've got a few more challenges
working with array controllers.
And I'll see you in
the next section.