[SINGING] Building websites
is a breeze with a framework
as you please.
Easy as slicing cheese,
with the tools such as these.
Structure pages quick.
No CSS to make you sick.
Use the layout that you pick.
Navigation helps you click.
Icons and buttons you can tap.
Your containers close the gap.
Responsive gridding is a snap.
You'll be launching off the map,
blasting off with Bootstrap.
Blasting Off with Bootstrap.
Hey, hey, everybody.
Welcome to Blasting
Off with Bootstrap.
I'm Adam Fortuna, and
in this first level,
we're going to be
looking at some
of the capabilities
of Bootstrap,
how to add Bootstrap to our
site, and a few basic classes.
Let's get started.
So let's say you want
to build a website.
Knowing how to combine
structure, style, and behavior
is necessary to get an
attractive and useful site up
and running.
If you have a basic
understanding of websites,
you know that HTML is what
provides our page structure.
Next, CSS will provide
our page with some styling
for our elements.
Then JavaScript comes
in, and provides our page
with some much-needed behavior.
Standard website development
follows some typical patterns.
We'll start by
adding our HTML file,
and that's where we'll be adding
the structure of our page.
That page styling
we talked about?
That'll go in this CSS file.
And lastly, our
page behavior, that
will be added to
a JavaScript file.
So once we have this structure
set in our HTML file,
we can jump over and
style it in our CSS file.
As we add more structure
to our HTML file,
we might realize we need
to add some behavior
and jump over to
our JavaScript file.
You might then jump
back to our HTML file,
and continue building our page.
All of this movement
between files
shows just how much work a
good website can require.
One of the things that can
help us with this process
is a framework.
What exactly is a framework?
Well, it's a set of tools
that can help assist us
in building our website.
So what is the most
popular framework
for styling and
organizing our website?
Well, Bootstrap.
So what can Bootstrap do for us?
Well, it can help us by
letting us skip writing our CSS
and JavaScript, and
let us focus primarily
on our HTML and the
structure of our site.
Instead of having our own
CSS and JavaScript files,
we're going to use
Bootstrap's files instead.
These will provide some
page styling and behavior
for our app without us
having to do anything.
That's pretty cool, right?
You might be wondering
who's using Bootstrap.
Well, like we said, Bootstrap
is the most popular HTML and CSS
framework, so there's a
lot of sites using it.
One that you might
have heard of is
Lyft, a company disrupting
the taxi industry.
Although they modify
it heavily, they
use Bootstrap on
their page to provide
the structure you see here.
Another site using Bootstrap is
Meteor, a JavaScript framework.
Much of the site is using
Bootstrap, including
this navigation bar at the
top and the grid system used
to control how the
page is structured.
Bootstrap isn't just
for start-ups, though.
Apple's Maps Connect page,
which is used by businesses
to manage their
Google Maps presence,
is also using the
framework, showing just
how useful it can be.
Let's take a look at what we'll
be building in this course.
The Intergalactic
Transit Authority
is responsible for taking
its passengers into space,
and has a few options
available for travelers.
We're going to be creating a
web page using Bootstrap just
for them.
At the end of the
course, you'll know
how every element on this page
works, and a couple more too.
This includes things
like this navigation bar
here at the top, with a
dropdown for additional links,
which will be handy
on any site you build.
Bootstrap is also great for
designing responsive websites.
Those are ones that will respond
great in many different page
resolutions.
This lets us write
one code base that
works well on a desktop,
a tablet, or a phone
with minimal added
work required.
So how do we start building
this beautiful page?
Well, to start
off, we need to get
a hold of the
Bootstrap framework.
To do that, we can head over
to the Bootstrap website
and download the
Bootstrap library.
In this case, we're
going to be checking out
this version of Bootstrap,
which contains the JavaScript
and CSS files we'll need.
If you already
know Less or Sass,
you can give one of these
other versions a shot, too.
So once you download
the Bootstrap framework
and unzip it, you'll
see this dist folder.
So let's take a look at
what's inside that.
This folder contains the
entire Bootstrap framework.
To start off, let's check out
what's inside the CSS folder.
There's a bunch of files
in the CSS folder,
but the two that we'll be using
are the bootstrap.css file
and the bootstrap.min.css file.
These two are
functionally the same,
and they will both save us
from needing to write a bunch
of CSS, but the .min version is
recommended for production use,
because it is a little smaller.
Alright.
So what's in the fonts folder?
Well, there's a couple of these
glyphicon-halfling-regular
files, and Bootstrap
provides a font
that can be used as icons that
we'll go over a little bit more
in level three.
The last folder in
here is the js folder,
and that contains some of the
Bootstrap JavaScript files
that will add
behavior to our site.
To start out, we're going
to create an index.html file
inside of that dist folder.
In this file, we'll
start off by adding
some of the usual things
you'll see in any HTML file.
We'll add our doctype, and
an HTML tag with our head
and title tag, same as any page.
To follow that up,
we're going to start
by adding some sample
content on our page.
We'll begin by adding
a lot of our headers.
So we'll start by adding some
sample H1 tags, H2, and H3 tags.
Next, we'll add in
some paragraph tags
to describe each
of our headings.
To finish things off, our
page needs some kind of call
to action, so we're going
to add a couple of buttons
for our users to engage with
under our H2 in its paragraph.
If we open up our page
right now in a browser,
it's going to look
a little like this.
Not exactly the best.
All of these styles are
being applied by the browser
itself, because we
haven't provided
any kind of styling
definition for this page.
Let's see how we can
add Bootstrap to it
to improve the look
and feel of it.
So let's bring our
page back in here.
In order to add
Bootstrap to it, we're
going to need to add a couple
of additional tags to it.
The first tag that we need
to add is the link tag.
That'll be up here in the
head, and it'll reference this
css/bootstrap.css file.
Remember how this index.html
file is in our dist folder?
Well, that css/boostrap.css
file is a relative path
to our index.html file.
By just adding this
link tag, we're
set on the styling of
our web page for now.
But to add some
behavior, we'll need
to add some JavaScript
to our page.
Turns out the
Bootstrap framework
depends on the jQuery
framework, and is
needed to do a bunch
of cool things.
We'll add a script tag to the
jQuery library at the bottom
here.
Now that we have
jQuery in there,
we can add another script
tag to load in the Bootstrap
JavaScript library.
We'll explore this one
a little more later.
Here's our initial website,
without using Bootstrap.
Let's see what it
can look like once
we add Bootstrap to the page.
So far, not too
hugely different.
The fonts changed a little bit
and the buttons are styled,
but there's still a lot more
we can do to improve the look
and feel of it.
One of the ways we can
visually improve our site
is by centering our
content elements
and creating a pair
of side margins.
This will prevent our
content from wrapping
to the very edges of our page.
To do that, we're going to use
Bootstrap's container class.
The container class
will responsively
add some margins and kind
of center our content,
but what do we add the
container class to?
In this case,
we're going to wrap
all of that content
in a div, and we
want that div to responsively add
margins and center our content.
In order to do that, we can
add a class of container,
which will create that
fixed-width element that we
really need that will
respond to the current size
of the browser.
So now that we've added
this container class,
let's check out what it
looks like in the browser.
You'll notice that, just by
wrapping our page in a div
and adding a container
class, our page now
doesn't take up the entire
width of the browser window.
Instead, it's confined within
these two invisible margins.
Also, you can see that the text
within our div wasn't centered.
The only thing that was
centered in this case
was our entire container
element, this div,
which has these invisible
margins on both sides of it.
Checking out what
we've got so far, we
can see that if we drag the
edge of our browser window,
we see that the margins
will periodically
reset when the
width of the window
crosses some small, medium,
or large boundary lines.
But we'll discuss
that a bit more later.
Eventually, we see that the
margins become very small
at the smallest window
size, and then content
begins to fully wrap.
Then, we drag it back again.
The margins snap
back into place when
we cross the size boundaries.
The margins will continue to
grow within each window size
to keep the content centered
within the padding for us.
So what if you have some
content on your page
that you want to stretch
completely across it?
You don't want it to be
confined to a container.
You might think you can just
leave it out of the container
and it'll work,
but it might run up
against the very, very
edges of your page.
To get around that, we
can wrap our content
in a container-fluid class.
That will add a little bit of
padding within that element,
but still allow
the div to stretch
the entire width of the page.
So let's take a look
at our page again.
What if we wanted all
of these H3 elements
to stretch across
the entire page?
We would no longer be
able to include them
within our container element.
Instead, we need
to create a new div
and give it a class
of container-fluid,
and move all of our H3s into it.
Now, this div will take
up the entire page,
while our container will
be centered in the middle.
If we take a look at our
responsive site here,
we'll drag the
edge of the window
and watch the top H1
and H2 portions start
to get some margins and
move towards the center,
because they are in
a standard container,
while the H3 portions
that we'd wrapped
a container-fluid — well,
those guys will grow
with the page, which causes
the text in those elements
to experience a
constant wrapping
and unwrapping as the width
of the window changes.
That's it for level one.
Time for you to see
what you've learned
about Bootstrap
in the challenges.
We'll see you back in level two.
I like that.
Don't say couple,
though, say a few.
A few?
A couple's two, right?
I don't want to mess them up.
I define a couple
as more than two.
I mean—
A couple?
A pair is two.
So is a couple.
A couple is — a few.
No.
[LAUGHTER]