[SINGING] Building websites
is a breeze with a framework
as you please.
Easy as slicing cheese,
with the tools such as these.
Structure pages quick.
No CSS to make you sick.
Use the layout that you pick.
Navigation helps you click.
Icons and buttons you can tap.
Your containers close the gap.
Responsive gridding is a snap.
You'll be launching off the map,
blasting off with Bootstrap.
Blasting Off with Bootstrap.
Welcome back to level two of
This is section one —
Thinking in Grids.
So here's our site so far.
We've learned how, by
adding a class of container
to our wrapper
element, we've added
some structure to our content.
But our site is still
looking very vertical.
Every element shows up
as a new row on our page.
How can we work with
Bootstrap to position things,
so that they show up, and we use
more of our horizontal space?
If we take a little bit
closer look at our page,
we can visualize
our content elements
as being grouped
into horizontal rows.
First, we could take
a look at the H1 tag,
the part with Blasting
Off With Bootstrap,
as its own row of data.
Next, the H2 tag combined with
its paragraph and buttons,
those can make up
another row of data.
Lastly, our H3 tags, each
with the H3 and a paragraph,
they could each
be a row of data.
So you could think of
this page as having
five distinct rows
of data on it.
If rows are a horizontal
grouping of data,
columns are a vertical grouping.
If we take a look at
our site right now,
we can see there's
really only one column.
Everything flows
down the page, right
after the previous element.
If our page is
only one column, we
won't be able to use much
of the horizontal space.
The way that Bootstrap
helps us solve this problem
is by dividing our
page into 12 columns
that we can use as needed.
Currently, each of
our rows of data
is using all of these
columns, since we're not
specifying otherwise.
What would it look like if some
of our elements on the page
only used some of these columns?
Let's take a look at the
visual goal for our page
at the end of this section.
Next, let's split our page
up into the 12 columns
that Bootstrap provides for us.
Let's take a look at all
the elements on the page
and see how many columns
each of them take up.
To start with, let's
look at the H1.
Here, our title
spans 12 columns.
Below that, we have our H2 and
our paragraph and button area.
And then we have this
image that we added.
Each of these two elements
spans six columns.
Towards the bottom
of our page, you
can see our H3 tags and their
corresponding paragraphs.
Well, each of them
take up four columns.
So what do all of
these have in common?
Well, if you add up the number
of columns in every row,
it always equals 12.
If we were to wire
frame our grid design,
it might look a
little like this.
We have our 12-column
header, our two
six-column main
sections, and then
our three four-column features.
Remember, each row
of data adds up
to use all 12 columns
in each of these cases.
In order to do this, we'll need
to limit the number of columns
that each of our
elements can use.
We can use Bootstrap's
.col-md-* classes,
and we can denote the number
of columns each of our elements
takes up.
The md in this class
name? That represents
a medium-sized screen,
like on a laptop.
We'll explore some other
screen sizes later on.
But md is a good starting
point for creating your grid.
To start, we know our H1 tag is
going to span all 12 columns,
so what we'll need
to do is wrap our H1
in an element that has
a class of col-md-12.
If we wanted to wrap an element
that took up half of the page,
we could use a similar class of
col-md-6, to span six columns.
Similarly, if we only
wanted to use four columns,
we could just use col-md-4.
Let's take a look
at our code so far.
Here we have our H1 tag.
That's the one that we want
to span all 12 columns.
We'll need to wrap our H1
tag in another div that
has a class of col-md-12.
If we look at this
in the browser now,
we can see our H1 tag is now
taking up all 12 columns.
What about our H2 and
this blasting off image
that we added?
Well, we want the H2, the
paragraph, and the buttons,
to be in six columns.
And then we want the image
to be in another six columns.
As you might expect, we'll need
to wrap our H2, our paragraph,
and our buttons in a div.
And we'll need to wrap
our image in a div.
Since we want both of these
to take up six columns,
we're going to add a class
of col-md-6 to each of them.
So you can probably see a
pattern developing here.
When we want to create
a column of data,
we usually wrap it in an element
and add some class to it.
Let's try that on these
last couple of elements.
So for our featured items,
we want each of them
to span four columns.
Similar to before, we'll need
to wrap each of our features
in another div.
Then we can add a
class of col-md-4
to it, to make each of
them use four columns.
Alright, so let's take a look
at this in the browser now.
If we open it up,
we can see we're
using a lot more of
a horizontal space.
Our H1 takes up the entire page.
Our features are each
taking up four columns.
And our image and our lead both
show up using half of the page,
with only adding a couple of classes.
If we take a look
back at our HTML,
we can see it's a
little bit hard to read.
If we're just looking at
this, it's really hard
to tell which elements are
appearing on which rows,
without doing a
little bit of math.
What can we do to clean
this up and make it obvious?
Turns out, Bootstrap
has a class that
will help us fix up our code in
just this way, called the row
class.
Within each row, you'll see
that the number of columns
added here, it always equals 12.
By adding this row class, we've
added a bit of smart styling
to our row.
And we've also
let Bootstrap know
to expect a grid
within that element.
You'll want to make sure
that the number of columns
within a row never exceeds 12.
If we take a look at
our page in the browser,
you'd see it looks almost
the same as it did before.
But we're actually using a
little bit more of the screen,
thanks to these rows.
Our HTML is also a
lot easier to read.
So far, the number of columns
in each row has added up to 12.
But what about if it didn't?
Let's see what
would happen if we
changed one of these elements
to instead take up five columns.
If you add these
up together, you'll
see it now equals 13 columns.
How would this look
in the browser?
If we check this
out in the browser,
it probably doesn't
look like you'd expect.
Our RocketBus
element didn't have
enough space on the first row.
So instead, it jumped
down to the second one.
This is very similar to
how our page was structured
before we started using rows.
When designing with
grids, we're not
limited to elements that span
equal number of columns,
like six, six, and
four, four, four.
One very popular
proportion for sites
is nine columns
and three columns.
So here's what that
would look like.
You'll see this
ratio quite often
for blogs that have a sidebar.
So far, the elements in each row
were very close to each other.
There wasn't much
padding between them.
What if we wanted
to do something
like this, where we had an
entire column of padding
between our blog, let's
say, and our sidebar?
Using what we know so
far, one way to do this
might be to create
an empty column.
We could do that by
creating another div
and giving it a
class of col-md-1.
Now, between our main
content and that col-md-8,
and our sidebar
and the col-md-3,
there's going to be an empty column.
Although this would work,
there is a better way.
Bootstrap provides
a class that we
can use to offset our elements
by a given number of columns.
So in this case, we can get
rid of that col-md-1 element
and instead add a class of
col-md-offset-1 to our sidebar.
What this would do is
add a column of padding
to the left of our
three-column sidebar.
This star here? That could
be anything from zero to 12.
And it will add that
many columns of padding
to the left side of the element.
Let's take a look at
an example website
from the Bootstrap web
page using this technique.
This Bootstrap Blog
illustrates the concept
we were just talking about.
So if you take a
look at it, there
are eight columns of content,
one column of offset,
and then another three
columns for the sidebar.
That's it for section one.
It's time for you
to try thinking
in grids in the challenges.
And I'll see you
back in section two.