Welcome back to Blasting
Off with Bootstrap.
This is level two, section
two — Responsive Gridding.
If we take a look at
our website so far,
it looks great on desktops.
But what happens if
we view it on a phone?
Well, our columns are all gone.
It turns out that's
because none of the columns
that we've been using
work below 992 pixels.
Let's take a look at what
we can do to fix this.
Here's what we want our page
to look like on a phone.
We really don't need that big
image on smaller resolutions.
And also, we still
want our featured items
to take up some
horizontal space.
But we really want "Book
Today!" to be on its own row,
since that's the
most important thing.
You'll notice this
little icon up here?
That means that we're seeing the
same thing that a phone would
see for this screenshot.
So far, we have concentrated
on getting our site
looking great on medium-sized
screens — things like laptops.
To do that, we use that col-md-*
class and the col-md-offset-*
one.
But these only work for screen
sizes of 992 pixels and larger.
For smaller resolutions, like
tablets and even compact laptop
screens, there's another great
size we could be designing for.
And that's called
the small size.
The small size uses
similar classes
to the ones we've
worked with so far,
except we replace the md
part with the sm part.
The small grid size will work
for screen sizes of 768 pixels
and above.
Let's see how we can use
our grids for small devices.
If we take a look at
our features so far,
we'll see we're using
the col-md-4 class.
Now this class is only working
for resolutions of 992 pixels
and up.
So nothing is happening
for our small screen sizes.
What can we do differently
to make this work on tablets?
By changing this
class to col-sm-4,
now these featured
items are all going
to take up four columns in
small- and medium-sized devices.
So if we take a look at how
this looks in a medium device,
you'll see that it looks
exactly the same as before.
Our features are still
spanning four columns.
You'll see from the
little laptop icon,
this is us viewing the
page in medium mode.
But what if we check it out
in small mode, represented
by this tablet?
Notice how even though
our page is a lot smaller,
our featured items are still
taking up four columns.
Each of these columns
is a little bit smaller
because our page
itself is smaller.
But if we shrink the
page a little more,
well, our columns are
going to disappear again.
That's because our
grids were only
being applied for screen
sizes of 768 pixels and above.
What about below 768 pixels?
Let's take a look
at extra-small mode,
which is what you'd see if you
viewed your site on a phone.
When designing for extra-small
devices like phones,
you can use this
col-xs prefix for all
of your grids and offsets.
This will be applied for
screens zero pixels and above.
This is great for
applying a minimum width
for your elements, things that
will be applied across all grid
sizes.
The extra-small classes
are great for specifying
a minimum width on
elements, assuming
you don't override them
with another grid class
from a larger size.
If we wanted our
featured items to take up
a little more horizontal
space on extra-small screens,
one way we could
do that might be
to add a col-xs-4 class
to our featured items.
But if we view that on
an extra-small device,
it looks a little cramped.
This is going to be very hard to
read on an extra-small device.
I think we could
do a lot better.
Let's rewind things
a bit and see
what we want our featured
items to look like.
We really want our "Book Today!"
feature to take up 10 columns
and have one column
of offset before it.
Next, we want the
other two features
to each take up six columns.
Let's start off by making
the "Book Today!" part take up
an entire 12 columns
in extra-small mode.
Next, we want "Go
Anywhere" and "RocketBus"
to be below "Book
Today!", but each of them
will take up six columns.
To do that, we can add a
col-xs-6 to each of them.
If we take a look at this
on an extra-small device,
we'll see that our "Book Today!"
element is spanning 12 columns,
and also that our "Go Anywhere"
and "RocketBus" are both
spanning six.
So why is it that
we were able to use
24 columns in this
row, rather than 12?
You'll notice that "Book Today!"
is using all 12 columns,
like we told it to.
But it's also pushed down
"Go Anywhere" and "RocketBus"
to the next available
vertical space below it.
We could still improve
this a little bit more.
What we really want
to do is for people
to read the "Book Today!" part.
So let's make that stand
out a little bit more
on extra-small devices.
How can we do that?
Well, we don't want
"Book Today!" to take up
all 12 columns in
extra-small mode.
Instead, we really
want it to take up
just the middle 10 columns.
In order for it to take
up the middle 10 columns,
we need to give it a column
of padding on the left.
To do that, we can
use an offset of one
that only is applied
for extra-small devices.
Remember, the order that we
add these classes to our HTML
doesn't matter.
Let's check this out on
an extra-small device.
We'll see that
"Book Today!" shows up
centered with an empty
column on the left
and another empty
column on the right.
"Go Anywhere" and "RocketBus" each
take up six columns, adding up
to 12 to take up the entire row.
What's important to
note here is that we've
used only 11 total
columns to accomplish
this centering effect.
The remaining one
column to the right
of "Book Today!" wasn't used
because nothing was there
except empty space.
If we had made "Book
Today!" take 11 columns,
we wouldn't have the
centering effect.
When "Go Anywhere"
and "RocketBus" try
to find a place
on the page, they
can't roll up right
next to "Book Today!"
because there's only one
column of space left.
So Bootstrap puts them
where space is available.
In this case, the next
horizontal space down.
If we preview our site
again in small mode,
we'll see that
our featured items
don't look like
we'd expect them to.
Our offset that we added
for extra-small mode, well,
it's actually being applied for
small and medium resolutions
as well, because we
haven't overridden it
for those larger sizes.
Since we're using nine columns
in the first horizontal space,
"RocketBus" is moved
to the next row.
Let's check out how to override
this offset for small screens
and above.
To do that, we can add
another class, which
will remove the offset for
small devices and above.
In this case, we can add
a col-sm-offset-0 class.
This is essentially removing
that offset for small devices
and above.
So now if we open this up
on a medium-sized device
or a small device, we'll
see that our featured items
no longer have that
offset added to them.
The grid sizes we've
worked with so far
will work for almost every
situation you'll encounter.
But if you want to design
for a very, very large screen,
like a great big
monitor, you might
want to use the large
grid size, which
will work for screen sizes
of 1,200 pixels and above.
There's only a few
other changes we
want to make in this section.
The first of which
is that we only
want this image to show for
medium and large resolutions.
So what can we do to
make that happen?
If we want to hide an element
in one or more screen sizes,
Bootstrap has a couple of
classes that can help us out.
Let's take a look at those.
In this case, we want
to hide this image only
in small and extra-small mode.
To do that, we're going to
add a class of hidden-sm
and hidden-xs to this element.
This will hide it in small
and extra-small modes.
If we wanted to hide this
element in other screen sizes,
Bootstrap has some other classes
to help out with that as well.
If we check out our
page in a small device,
we will see the image is hidden.
The same goes for an
extra-small device.
On the other hand, what if
instead of hiding something,
we wanted to only show something
for certain screen sizes?
Well, to do that we could use
these visible-md and visible-lg
classes.
This will only show our image
for medium and large screen
sizes.
You'll notice each
of these classes ends
with a screen size indicator,
like sm, xs, md, and lg.
If we open this up
in a browser, we'll
see that our image shows up
in medium and large devices.
But in small and
extra-small, it's
hidden just like
we'd expect it to be.
That's the end of
Responsive Gridding.
It's time for you to try
using it in the challenges,
and I'll see you in level three.
Then, we'll need to give—
We got too many columns!