[SINGING] Building websites
is a breeze with a framework
as you please.
Easy as slicing cheese, with
the tools such as these.
Structure pages quick.
No CSS to make you sick.
Use the layout that you pick.
Navigation helps you click.
Icons and buttons you can tap.
Your containers close the gap.
Responsive gridding is a snap.
You'll be launching off the map,
blasting off with Bootstrap.
Blasting Off with Bootstrap.
Welcome back to Blasting
Off with Bootstrap.
This is level three — Typography.
So what exactly is typography?
Well, Wikipedia defines it
as, "The art and technique
of arranging text on the page
to make it most appealing."
In the web world, when
we talk about typography,
we're generally concerned
with fonts, including
what font, the size,
the position, color,
and how to make
them work together.
If we take a look
at our page so far,
we'll see that it's not using
the default browser font.
That's because this
bootstrap.css file
that we included, well,
it overrides all the fonts
used on our page.
If you're familiar with
CSS, this style definition
will shed a little light on
what Bootstrap is doing for us.
There's a lot going on here,
including changing the font
to use this Helvetica
Neue typeface.
And it's also changing
the default size, and even
the color to this kind
of neutral gray, which
is a lot easier on the eyes.
Now all of those
styles, they're being
applied to our entire
page, but any of them
can also be overridden.
For instance, our H1 tag,
well, it isn't 14 pixels.
We overrode that font
size by using a tag, H1,
that is setting the
font size larger.
Using tags is one way to
override Bootstrap styles.
But there's another way using
some typography CSS classes
that Bootstrap provides.
Let's see how it can
make our lead text
stand out a little bit more
by using one of these classes.
Here's the relevant
part of our page,
the paragraph just
below our H2 tag
where we describe our company.
This sentence isn't
a header, but we
do want to make it stand out
more than the other sentences
on the page.
To do that, we'll add the class
of lead to this paragraph tag.
This will actually increase
the font size and the weight,
but it will also add
a little more space
around the element,
kind of giving it
a little breathing room.
If we compare our paragraph
tag without using lead,
and with it, they do
seem kind of similar.
The font size for
our lead paragraph
is 50% larger, though,
making it stand out
compared to all of the other
paragraphs on our page.
Another characteristic
of good typography
involves font alignment.
Now Bootstrap has
a couple of classes
that can help us
with that as well.
Let's take a look at
our featured items
to see how it could
help us there.
Hm.
They're okay.
And it's nice that our "Book
Today!" element is centered.
But what if the text within
them was also centered?
Let's give it a try and see
what that would look like.
Here's our div row for
our three featured items.
We'll try centering all
text within this row.
In order to do that, we'll
use a text alignment class
for a row, which will affect
all of the text within that row.
In this case, we want
to center the text.
So we'll add a class of
text center to the div.
Well, what if we had only
wanted to center the H3 tag?
Well, we could have added a text
center class to that element
instead.
In this case, though, by
adding the class here,
it will center all
the headers and all
of the paragraphs
within this row.
Additionally, Bootstrap has
a few other alignment classes
that can help us out for
aligning left or right,
or even justifying text,
which spaces your text out
so it's flush against both
the right and the left sides
of the screen.
Let's open our new design up in
a browser and see how it looks.
Nice.
All the elements in
the row are being
centered by adding
just that one class.
Each is being centered
within its element,
using the full number of
columns available to it.
But since we got rid of
that image in small and
extra-small mode, this
page is looking a bit bare.
What if we added some icons that
show up next to our features
to really draw the eye?
Usually that would mean going
out to search for some images,
right, making sure that
they're legal to use,
adding in image tags, and
generally a lot more work.
Let's see what that process
is if we're using Bootstrap.
Remember this font folder
that came with Bootstrap?
Well, this is actually an
entire library of icons.
If you think about it,
a font is a mapping
from a character code
to some font image.
Code 41 might be a capital A in
fonts like Helvetica and Times
New Roman, but in this
cool glyphicon font,
code 41 might map to a tag
image or a profile image.
We don't need to
know which codes map
to which icons to
use them, luckily.
Bootstrap provides CSS classes
that we can add to our HTML
when we need to use these icons.
This glyphicon library —
which you would usually
have to pay for separately —
is actually free with Bootstrap,
and contains 200
icons you can use.
Oh, and if you're
wondering why there's so
many fonts in this folder,
well, blame web browsers.
The .woff file — or
web open font format —
is now used by all
modern web browsers.
But there's a few
fallbacks in there
for older versions
of Internet Explorer
and a few other special cases.
So how do we go about
using these icons?
In our case, we want this
icon to show up right
above our "Book Today!" header.
To add an icon,
we'll need an element
to which to attach a class.
We'll use an i element for this.
This element was originally
used for italic text,
but it's become a
standard practice
to use it for icons as well.
We need this element to use the
glyphicons font, rather than
that Helvetica Neue font,
like the rest of our page.
To do that, we'll add in
a class of glyphicon
to this element.
If we open this up
and view it now,
we're not really
seeing anything.
In order for an icon
to show up, we'll
still need to specify
which icon we want to use.
Our paragraph here
is all about travel.
So we'll go ahead and add
a briefcase icon here,
since it kind of
resembles luggage.
To do that, we'll add the
glyphicon briefcase class
to our i element.
This is a pattern you'll
see very often in Bootstrap —
applying two classes to
accomplish a single task.
This helps keep the Bootstrap
CSS file much smaller.
In this case, the
glyphicon class
is what's setting the
font family we'll use,
while the glyphicon briefcase
class, that is actually
specifying which
icon we can use.
Let's go ahead and add icons
to our other featured items.
We'll follow the same
pattern as before,
creating an i element
for "Go Anywhere",
and give it a
class of glyphicon.
If we head over to the
Bootstrap web page,
we can pick out
another icon and find
the associated class for it.
In this case, I'm going to add
the glyphicon random class,
which creates this
crossed paths icon.
For our "RocketBus", we'll
follow the same pattern again
and pick out an icon.
There is no rocket
icon, unfortunately.
But this paper plane icon
conveys a similar meaning.
Now, if we really
needed a rocket icon,
we could go find
another library that
provides additional
icons, like Font Awesome.
I'm okay with our plane
icon for now, though,
so let's stick with it.
Let's see what our
page looks like
with these shiny new icons.
So we're all excited to see
our new icons in action.
So we open up a new
page in a browser
and, oh no, they turned
out much smaller
than we might have expected.
How do we increase the
font size of these icons?
Well, if these were
images, we could just
set the height and width
on them, and we'd be fine.
But that won't
work in this case.
Remember earlier on we mentioned
how Bootstrap sets the default
font size of our
page to 14 pixels.
Well, it turns out that's also
setting the size of our icons,
since they're also a font.
But the good news
is we can override
the font size of
our icons by adding
a very small amount of CSS
and increasing the font size.
Let's give it a shot.
First, we don't want to be
editing the bootstrap.css file.
If we ever wanted
to update Bootstrap,
we don't want any of our
custom changes to be in there.
Instead, we'll add another link
to a new main.css file, which
we'll create all of
our customizations.
Next, we'll add one additional
class to our row of features.
And we'll call it
Features, of course.
This could be whatever you want.
It's not a class provided
by Bootstrap, right?
We just need some
way of identifying
this section of the page.
Then we can create
this css/main.css file,
and define a single CSS
selector of .features.glyphicon.
This just means that we'll
only be styling glyphicons that
are inside of an element
with a class of features.
In this case, we'll increase
the font size to 32 pixels,
making them stand
out quite a bit
from their surrounding text.
It's important to note here that
if we left out the .features
part, we would be styling
all glyphicons on the page.
At the moment, that
would be okay, but it's
a best practice to only
style what you need.
Alright.
So now we can open
this up in a browser
and see that our icons
are looking great.
They're big enough to add
some distinction to our page,
but also space it out, adding
a little more breathing room.
Now because these
icons are a font,
there's some nifty
customizations
we can do with them.
Let's check a few of those out.
If our page had a
different color scheme
or had a dark background,
then having these dark icons
wouldn't really work, right?
We can set the color of
these icons in the same way
that we'd set any font color,
and affect all of the icons
on the page at once.
For our icons though,
we're OK with them matching
the default font
color of the page.
So we won't be changing
them to red right now.
One part of the page that we
haven't looked into just yet
is the footer.
This is where we'll have a few
links to the rest of our site,
a brief description
of our company,
and some ways of
getting in touch.
But what about those
bullets next to Links?
They really stand out.
That's the default
browser behavior
when you use an unordered list.
But it's not really
what we want.
Let's check out how to get
rid of those bullet icons.
Here's what the code for
this section of our footer
looks like.
We have an H4 for
our links, and a ul,
which contains a
few of these links.
By default, ul elements will
add a list style CSS property,
which adds in
these little bullet
icons and a little
bit of spacing.
We can remove both
of these additions
by changing the style
of our ul element.
To do that, we'll
go ahead and add
a class of list-unstyled
to our ul element.
This is a Bootstrap
class that will not only
remove those bullet
icons that we don't need,
it will also get
rid of those margins
that were messing up our look.
Bootstrap has another
list class that's helpful
called list-inline, which
will do the same thing as
list-unstyled, but also causes
the li elements to show up
horizontally rather
than vertically.
To check out our
finished footer,
we'll open this
page up in a browser
and see that our page is
starting to really take shape.
Our bullet icons are all
gone from the footer,
making it much easier to read.
Besides that, the
icons that we added,
and that lead text,
all help to make
different parts of
our page stand out.
And that is the end of level three.
It's time for you
to see what you
know about typography
in the challenges.
And I'll see you
back for level four.
This element was originally —
a little drunk there.