[SINGING] Building websites
is a breeze with the framework
as you please.
Easy as slicing cheese,
with the tools such as these.
Structure pages quick.
No CSS to make you sick.
Use the layout that you pick.
Navigation helps you click.
Icon and buttons you can tap.
Your containers close the gap.
Responsive gridding is a snap.
You'll be launching off the map,
blasting off with Bootstrap.
Blasting Off with Bootstrap.
Welcome back to Blasting
Off with Bootstrap.
This is level four, section one —
Enough CSS to be Dangerous.
Our page is coming together.
But let's see what we can
do to make it even better.
In this section, we'll
add a dash of style
using more Bootstrap
awesomeness.
To start out, we'll
focus on what's
above the fold: our
lead and these buttons,
which are kind of our main call
to action on the entire page.
Let's see what we
can do to encourage
people to click on them.
Here's the section of our page
that we'll be looking at.
This row contains a header,
our lead text, the buttons,
and that image that only shows
up for those larger screens.
This entire row could stand
out quite a bit more, though.
One way to make
this stand out more
is to use Bootstrap's
well class, which
will give it a nice inset effect
to the entire element row.
If we check this out in the browser,
we'll see that there's a background on this element now,
but also a border with rounded corners around it.
It's not a bad change
for just adding one little class.
To make it stand
out even more, we
could specify a bit more
padding within the element
by adding a well-lg class to it.
The only thing this will do
is add a touch more padding
within our element to
make it slightly larger.
Since this is our main
focus of the page,
using this well-lg class
makes a lot of sense here.
Similarly, if part of our
page needed a little bit
less padding, we could
use the well-sm class
to decrease the amount of padding around the well.
We can open this up
in a browser and see
that our section
definitely stands out
much more than it did before.
The background color
and rounded border
are a clean addition
to our page.
Those buttons are
starting to seem
like they don't
belong on our page.
Kind of ugly, right?
Let's work on improving
those guys next.
Here's the HTML for
our buttons so far.
These are functional, but they
will look slightly different
in all browsers.
In order to let Bootstrap
style these buttons so
that they look the
same for all browsers,
we'll need to add a class
of btn to our buttons.
If you looked at them now,
they look completely different.
They have some
padding around them,
and there's this
nice gray background.
However, nothing happens
when you mouse over them,
making it really tough to tell
if these buttons are working.
They're also a little
bit small for being
such an important
part of our page.
What can we do to fix that?
To increase their size, we can
add another Bootstrap class
of btn-lg to both of
these button elements.
This will cause these buttons
to show up with a larger font
and add a little bit
more padding to them.
There are a few other button
sizes that we can use as well,
including btn-xs,
btn-sm, and btn-lg.
These sizes should be
a little bit familiar
because they're the
same sizes that we
used for all of our grids.
The same way we
started by designing
for medium-sized screens,
that's the default for buttons
as well.
If you don't specify
a button size,
you can assume it will
just use the medium size.
One important thing
here is that we're again
adding multiple
classes to our button.
This is similar to how we
added multiple classes when
we were working with
glyphicons earlier.
Each additional class adds
unique style to our buttons,
combining them to create
our intended appearance.
Gray buttons that
don't change colors
don't do much for
the imagination.
Let's go ahead and add some
additional button classes
to specify a color for
both of our buttons.
For our Take the
Tour button, we're
going to use the btn-default
class, indicating
that this is a normal
button on our page
without any additional
meaning to it.
Our Book Tickets Now
button, though, well, that's
actually the primary
action on our page
that we want everyone to click
when they come to our site.
For that one, we'll add a
class of btn-primary to it.
Now if we check these
out in the browser,
we'll see the Tour button
has this white background,
while the Book Tickets
Now button adds
the first real touch of
color to our page, which
will immediately
draw attention to it.
We're not limited to white
and blue button backgrounds,
though.
Bootstrap provides a
handful of other colors
that we can work with.
These button styles aren't
characterized by their colors,
but rather based
on their intention.
For instance, if you had
a button on your page
to launch RocketBus,
we probably want
it to use the btn-danger
class because that
is a potentially
dangerous action.
Likewise, if you wanted
people to feel comfortable
placing an order, we might
add a btn-success class
to our Form Submit.
Alright, we've done
a few cool things.
Let's check out
what our page looks
like in a few
different resolutions.
Well, you can see
that in small mode,
our well is attractive
and stands out
and our buttons look plenty
big to draw attention.
Additionally, if we
shrink the browser down
to extra-small mode, the
well stretches all the way
across the page without
that same white background
showing on each side of it.
And so you've reached
the end of this section.
It's time for you
to see if you know
enough CSS to be dangerous
in the challenges.
And I'll see you
back in section two.