Welcome back to Blasting
Off with Bootstrap.
This is level four, section
two — Navigating Navigation.
So far, the only way to
navigate between pages
is that list of links way
down there in the footer
that very few people
will ever see.
In this section,
we'll be working
on adding a navigation
bar at the top of our page
that we can use instead.
So here's what we'll be
building in this section.
We want the title of our
page to really stand out,
and we want our
most important links
to be easily accessible
at the top of our page.
Just as a refresher, here's
our current page header
that we'll be working with.
We'll be replacing this
entire row with a navigation
bar using Bootstrap.
One major difference
for our navigation
is that we will no longer
be using a grid system.
Because of that, we
can remove our row
and our col-md-12
elements altogether.
So why aren't we
using a grid here?
Well, we'll want the
width of the elements
in our navigation to be
determined by their content
rather than by a grid system.
We'll see how that
will allow us to build
a more flexible navigation
throughout this section.
To get our links ready
for our navigation bar,
we can copy them from our footer
and put them up here as well.
These are all links to
other pages in our site.
If you remember how our
footer looked when we first
looked at it, you might
have a guess as to what
our page looks like so far.
You can see that if
we preview our updated
page, our navigation
has those default bullet
icons next to them, kind of like
all unstyled, unordered lists do.
We will definitely work
on cleaning those up,
but first, let's get
that H1 converted to be
a link back to our home page.
Since we want this to be a link,
we can get rid of that H1 tag
that we added in
earlier and convert it
to a standard link
using an a tag.
Now that we've converted
this into a link that points
to our home page, we'll need
to add a class of navbar-brand
to it.
This class specifies
that the text or image
represents your brand and
will be positioned way over
to the left side of the page.
If we open this up
in a browser, we'll
see that we're making a
little bit of progress.
Our link element and our
navigation list element
are at least on the same line.
The navbar-brand class is
a great place for you to put
your site logo as well.
It's a common pattern that
the very top left corner
of your website links
back to your home page,
and it's where people will first
look when they visit your site.
Let's see what we
can do to clean up
our list of links next.
One very easy change we can
do is use Bootstrap's nav
component by adding a class
of nav to our ul element.
This nav class specifies
that the list items
within this entire
element are links,
and then styles
them accordingly.
In our case, they will still
appear next to our brand.
You might ask why the
beginning of our list
is still appearing on the
same line as our title.
Well, our list is still starting
at the same spot it was before.
But because of this nav
class, now all of our links
are being carried down
to following lines.
The nav class is similar
to btn or glyphicon.
It's a starting
point that we can
use to say, "We're going
to use a nav here."
We'll still need to
add another class
to let Bootstrap know what type
of navigation we want to use.
There are a few possible nav
modifiers available that we can
use throughout our page,
not just in our header.
The nav-pills is
a very common one
and will cause the links
to appear horizontally
with a nice padding around each
link with this cool border.
The nav-tabs class handles
creating a tab navigation
bar where the content
below it could
be relevant to the active tab.
In this case, though, we want to
use the navbar-nav class, which
will cause our
unordered list of links
to appear inline horizontally,
kind of like nav-pills
but without the same
rounded borders.
Lastly, we want our
nav to be all the way
on the right side of
our page, separate
from our brand position.
To do that, we
can add in a class
of navbar-right, which will
position our nav way over here.
We can open this up in a
browser and see that we now
have a working navigation.
It's positioned correctly due
to that navbar-right class,
and the navbar-nav class even
adds some different background
colors when we hover
over each of those links.
Things are getting
there, but our navigation
is looking a little too close
to the rest of our page.
Our goal navigation looked quite a bit different.
Here's one more look at
where we're headed on this.
This navigation has
a nice background
that stretches all the
way across the page,
as well as some more muted
colors for these links.
Let's see what we need to
do to get our page looking
a little bit more like this.
One simple but massive
change to our page
is changing this div
that we've been working
with into a navigation bar
using Bootstrap's navigation
component.
To do that, we can
add a class of navbar
to our div that contains our
brand and our list of links.
By itself, this
won't do too much.
It's similar to the btn
class that we used earlier.
In order to specify a color
scheme for our navigation bar,
we can add a class of
navbar-default to this element.
If we checked out our
navigation bar now,
we'd see that it has this nice
gray background with some muted
colors for our text as well.
Bootstrap has one other
navigation bar theme
called navbar-inverse, which is
great for darker color schemes.
Opening this up in
a browser, we can
see that our navigation
bar is styled correctly,
but it doesn't stretch all
the way across the page.
It's being centered,
like our content,
and looks very similar to
our well we added earlier.
What can we do to
make this stretch
all the way across the page?
The reason our
navigation bar shows up
like this is because its
width and its margins
are being set by the container
class, which keeps it centered
in the middle of the page.
What we really need
is for our navigation
to be separated
from our container.
Here's what the HTML
for our navigation
looks like right now.
We have one div that is
being centered, thanks
to our container class,
and has all the styles
for our navigation bar, thanks to our
other two navigation classes.
What we want, though,
is for our container
to be inside of
our navigation bar.
To do that, we'll need to go
ahead and create a new div that
will surround our container and
move our other two navigation
bar classes on to that new div.
Now, our gray styling
for our navigation bar
will stretch all the
way across the page,
but then the content
within that navigation bar,
it'll still be centered.
This will now look like
our goal navigation.
Bootstrap's navigation
component isn't required
to be at the top of the page.
Navigation bars
could be positioned
in the middle of a page
or even at the bottom.
The default navigation bar
will have four rounded corners
on it, kind of like our
well element earlier,
but we don't really
want that in our case.
To let Bootstrap know, we'll add
one more class to our navbar,
and that class is called
navbar-static-top.
This will let Bootstrap know
that this navigation bar should
be at the very top of our page.
As you might guess,
there's also a class
for positioning a navigation bar
at the very bottom of a page.
There's a few other classes
available for setting a fixed
position as well.
Fixed positions will always
be visible on the page,
so as you scroll,
the navigation bar
will always show up on top
of whatever other content is
on your page.
It's a bit tough to describe
these without an example,
so let's take a
look at what I mean.
Here's a navigation bar
using navbar-static-top.
As we scroll down the page,
the navigation bar goes away.
Static just means
that it's stationary,
and will scroll just like
the rest of our page content.
Now, if we change this up to be
using a navbar-fixed-top class
and then scroll down, we'd see
that the navigation bar still
shows up on top of the
rest of our content.
This would be useful if we
had a very long page that
had lots and lots of
content and always wanted
our navigation bar visible.
When using
navbar-fixed-top, you'll
also notice that our
navigation bar shows up on top
of the content that follows it.
To fix that, you'd want to
add a little bit of padding
to your body to help
counteract the overlap.
So we've talked quite a
lot about navbar and nav,
but what exactly is the
difference between them?
Well, think of the nav class
as being a very basic building
block of your entire site.
You might have multiple navs on
a page, or you might have a sub
nav that shows up
in your sidebar.
Each could use one of the
different nav styles that
Bootstrap provides.
For navbar, though, you
probably won't want to have
more than one of these
on your entire website.
You could if you wanted, but
that would most likely confuse
people.
That's about it for this
section and level four.
It's time for you to
navigate some navigation
in the challenges, and we'll
see you back in level five.
You to try navigating
navigation in the challenges.
That's the name of the level.
Time for you to try
navigating navigations —
Time for you to try navigating some
navigation in the challenges,
and we'll see you back —
I can't do it.
For you to navigate
some navigation —