[SINGING] Building websites
is a breeze with a framework
as you please.
Easy as slicing cheese,
with the tools such as these.
Structure pages quick.
No CSS to make you sick.
Use the layout that you pick.
Navigation helps you click.
Icons and buttons you can tap.
Your containers close the gap.
Responsive gridding is a snap.
You'll be launching off the map,
blasting off with Bootstrap.
Blasting Off with Bootstrap.
Welcome back to Blasting
Off with Bootstrap.
This is level five, section one —
JavaScript Components.
We did a lot of work to make our
navigation look really awesome.
But if we shrink our
screen down a little bit
into extra-small
mode, well, things
don't look exactly
like we expect.
In this small size, we won't
be able to have our brand link
and our nav list on the
same horizontal row.
Instead, we'll
need to find a way
to make better use of
our vertical space.
But we really don't want
the first thing people
see when they visit our site
is a really big list of links
where they have to scroll
down just to book tickets.
Maybe we could do something
to make our navigation
collapsible.
Here's what we'll be
going for in this section.
When a visitor visits our
page, they'll see our title,
and they'll see this little
icon to expand our navigation.
When they click on that,
it will expand our nav,
and then they can click on
one of these other links
to head over to that
part of our site.
To do this, we'll need to add
some behavior to our website.
Now, we mentioned before that
CSS is for styling our web page.
This includes
things like changing
the background of the page,
increasing the font size,
or even adding padding
around an element.
In order to add
behavior to our page,
though, we're going to need to
add a little bit of JavaScript.
So what do I mean
when I say behavior?
Well, that could be things
like responding in some way
when an element is clicked, or
when a specific key is pressed.
These are things that cannot be
controlled through CSS or HTML
alone.
Here's a recap of our
navigation so far.
This ul element
contains our links.
We want to be able to
switch between seeing
a list of those links, or
seeing an icon of some kind.
To start things off, we
can add a class of collapse
to our ul element.
This will completely
hide our navigation
for all screen sizes.
In order to make it show
up for specific sizes,
you might think of using
the visible classes
we talked about before.
Well, that isn't ideal
for this situation
though, because we're not using
grids for our navigation bar.
Instead, though, we can search
through the Bootstrap docs
on navigation and see
what they suggest.
Turns out there's
a specific class
just for this case
called navbar-collapse.
This class will
cause the element
to show up in small
screens and above,
but to be hidden only
for extra-small screens.
Next, let's add a button
that we can click on
to show that nav that's only
visible in extra-small mode.
We'll need to create this
button here in the nav bar,
making sure to put it
before our nav list.
We'll give it some
informative text.
Let's say, toggle navigation.
Now if we view just
this piece on a phone,
well, it's getting there.
We do have our work cut
out for us on this one.
Let's see how to
style and position
it a little more attractively.
Even though we've
labeled our button,
we don't actually want
that toggle navigation text
to show up, because
it's a little bit long.
So how can we hide that
without hiding the button?
To do that, we can wrap
that text in a span
with the class of sr-only.
sr-only stands for
"screen readers only."
And that means that the
contents of that element
will only be
available to software
that reads screen content
to the visually impaired.
This is a good
practice to get into.
It's kind of like adding
alt tags for images.
If we didn't do
this, then visitors
to our site using
screen readers wouldn't
know what this button does.
If we view this button now, it
doesn't have anything in it,
though, and it shows up
right next to our brand.
Let's move it over to
the right a little bit,
kind of like what we saw
in our finished product.
To position our button all
the way over to the right,
we can use the
navbar-toggle class,
which will float our
button all the way
to the right of wherever
it currently is.
Bootstrap has some other helper
classes for floating elements
left and right that you
can use elsewhere
on your page, including
pull-left and pull-right.
It looks like our button
is in the right place,
but it still needs an icon.
And how do we make it
actually do something
when we click on it?
Let's start by adding an icon.
One way to add an
icon here would
be to use a glyphicon,
like we did earlier.
The problem with that is that
it won't scale correctly,
which would cause
it to stand out
from the rest of our header.
The solution for this —
and you can probably
guess what I'm
gonna say by now —
is to create a new element with
a class provided by Bootstrap.
In this case, we're
going to create
a span with the
class of icon-bar.
This class will add a single
small, horizontal bar.
In total, though, we're
adding three horizontal bars
to provide that
hamburger icon look
that our users
are familiar with.
Alright.
So let's see what our button
looks like in a browser.
If we open this up and resize
our browser to a small size,
we can see that our full
navigation list of links
is visible.
If we shrink our browser
a little bit more, though,
our navigation disappears
and is completely
replaced by our little button.
Okay. Sweet.
Now on extra-small devices,
the first thing people will see
is that Book Tickets Now
button, just like we want.
Cool.
We've got our button.
But what does it do?
In this case, nothing yet.
Let's work on making
that button functional.
To do that, we're
going to need to add
some behavior using JavaScript.
Before adding that
code, let's plan out
exactly what we want to happen.
Here's the button
that we just created
as part of our list
of links that's
being hidden in
extra-small mode.
What we really want is
for the collapse class
to be removed from
our list of links
whenever this button is clicked.
Then, if our user clicks
the button again,
we should add the collapse class
back to that unordered list
to hide the links once again.
To do that, we're going to need
to use the Bootstrap JavaScript
collapse plugin.
But how do we get started using
JavaScript with Bootstrap?
Back in level one, we already
added our Bootstrap JavaScript
library to the page, but
we haven't used it yet.
Each Bootstrap
JavaScript library
is a little bit different.
But kind of like
our CSS classes,
they follow some of
the same patterns.
The two main ways to use most
Bootstrap JavaScript plugins is
by adding additional
data attributes
to specific elements
on your page.
This is similar to how we've
been adding all those classes
to our page, but now instead
of adding a class attribute,
we'll be adding data attributes.
This is the method we'll
be using in this course.
Now there's also another way
of using all of the Bootstrap
plugins by writing raw
JavaScript as well.
This requires a little more
knowledge of the plugins.
And knowing the basics of
jQuery will definitely help out.
We won't be looking into
that method in this course,
but we encourage
you to check it out.
It's probably a lot
easier than you'd think,
and can help out in a pinch.
So here's our button once again.
Remember what we
wanted to do here?
We want to toggle the
existence of the collapse class
on the ul element.
To do that, we need
to specify which
class to toggle using the
data-toggle attribute,
and specifying collapse.
The idea is that this
will add and remove
the collapse class from
some element on the page.
But what element?
We need to add a second
attribute of data-target, which
is a CSS selector for
any element on the page.
In this case, we'll use
.navbar-collapse,
because there's only
one element on our page
that matches that CSS
selector: our list of links.
The first time we
click on this button,
it's going to
remove the collapse
class from our unordered list.
If we click on the
button again, it's
going to add the collapse class
back in to our unordered list,
causing it to be hidden.
Let's check it out.
Sweet.
We have liftoff.
Our toggle works and
expands when clicked,
but, aw — the position of our
links is a little bit off.
What we really need
is for the Blasting
Off with Bootstrap part to be
on its own row with the button.
Then when the button
is clicked, we'd
want each link
within our list to be
on its own row
underneath the brand.
Let's see what we need to
change to make that happen.
Here's our navigation
bar so far.
When we think about how to
organize our elements, what
we really need is for our
brand and our toggle button
to be on one row,
while our list of links
rests below the brand
with one link on each row.
Like our grid system,
this means we'll
need to group these
elements by wrapping them
in some new elements.
Our brand and button
can be wrapped
in a div with a class
of navbar-header.
This navbar-header class
will cause the header
to take up the entire
width of the navbar
on extra-small screens.
Think of it as being similar
to col-xs-12, what
we used to make
an element take up
the entire width of the
page on extra-small screens.
Luckily, we don't
need to do anything
with our list of links.
We're already grouping
all these links
within a list, which will
now show up below our header.
Let's see what this
looks like in a browser.
If we open this up in a browser
and shrink our page down
to extra-small mode, we'll see
that the button works correctly
and expands our links.
When we click that
button again, it
will collapse our links, just
like when we loaded the page.
Each link is on its
own row as well,
helping them be much easier
to click when using a phone.
In larger resolutions,
like on our laptop,
the navigation looks exactly
the same as when we started.
Hey, at least we
didn't break anything.
And that's the end of
level five, section one.
It's time for you
to try your hand
at JavaScript components
in the challenges.
And I'll see you
back for section two.