[MUSIC PLAYING]
Welcome back to Blasting
Off with Bootstrap.
This is level five, section two —
Dropping Down From Orbit.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
We have this amazing navigation
that we created and even got
working on mobile sites.
But once we let other people
on our team start using it,
something goes completely wrong.
There's too many links
in our navigation bar.
No one wants to
read all of that,
but it's nice to have some
of these links somewhere
more pronounced than our footer.
What can we do to clean
up our navigation bar?
One thing we could
do is group together
a number of these links
and have them show up
when our About link is clicked.
This might sound a little
similar to our collapse
functionality we
showed before.
The difference here is that
our expanded navigation will
be shown on top of other
content rather than pushing
the rest of the page down.
This creates this
dropdown effect
that we want where it can
be opened only when needed.
How would this work in our
extra-small view, though?
We probably don't
want our dropdown
showing up on top of
our other elements
in our already very limited
screen real estate.
Well, what if it looked
something like this
where, if they expand
our About link,
it still shows like the
rest of our navigation?
I think this is something
we can work with.
Let's start by adding
that little dropdown
icon to our existing About link.
Here's our nav list so far with
some of the links in there.
What happens right
now if someone
clicks on this About link?
Well, right now,
they'll be taken
to an entirely different page.
We'll need to change that so
they stay on the same page
when About is clicked.
We can do that really fast
by linking to this hash sign
instead.
This means that we're
linking to an anchor
on the current page.
In this case, it's at
the very top of the page.
This will work for
now and stop the link
from going to a new page.
Next, we'll want to add
that little dropdown
arrow after the About text.
Remember, from our collapse
graphic and our header,
we didn't want to use
a glyphicon up here
in the navigation bar?
Well, that also holds
true for this one as well.
Instead, we'll use a span
with a class of caret.
This will add that
little down-arrow icon.
I'd say we're off
to a good start.
Let's see how to make
the rest of our links
show up only when this
About link is clicked.
Our About link is looking
good, but what about those
links that we want to add to
it, like the ones for Contact Us
and Blog?
Well, we can group these
within our list item
for About by creating an
entirely new list inside of it
and moving all of
our links there.
Now, our navigation
is logically grouped
by the three links we want to
show at the top of the page.
But if we open this
up in a browser,
these links will always show up.
They'll also have these nested
link bullet icons next to them.
Let's start by hiding
this list on page load.
We can use a class provided
by the Bootstrap dropdown
library, which will produce
the style of a dropdown menu.
This single class
does quite a lot.
The only thing
we'd see right now,
though, is that our ul will
actually be completely hidden
when the page loads with
no way for us to expand it.
In order to expand
it, we're going
to need to add some
behavior — and not
just style — to our About link.
Let's review how to use
Bootstrap JavaScript plugins.
Actually, we can use the
dropdown plugin the same two
ways as our Bootstrap
collapse plugin —
either by adding data attributes
that we add to our HTML
or by writing JavaScript.
Again, we'll be
adding data attributes
to our HTML, which
is by far the easiest
way to use the Bootstrap
dropdown plugin.
Let's see what data
attributes we need to add.
Similar to the
collapse plugin, we'll
need to toggle the existence
of a CSS class on and off.
We'll actually use the
same data attribute
we used for the collapse
plugin — data-toggle —
but in this case,
we'll specify dropdown.
When the page loads and the
Bootstrap JavaScript runs,
it'll see this value and
add the dropdown behavior
to our About link.
So what should happen
when this link is clicked?
Well, we aren't
removing a class that's
already added, like with
the collapse plugin.
Instead, clicking on About
will add a class of open
to the parent of
the clicked link.
In this case, what that means
is that the li element, which
is the parent element
of our About link,
well, it'll get a class of open.
Bootstrap has some
styles so that,
if a dropdown menu is
inside of an element
with a class of
open, we'll actually
see the dropdown menu,
which, in this case,
is exactly what we want.
Not too bad for just
adding one data attribute.
If we really wanted
to, we could actually
start the dropdown
menu as open by adding
a class of open to
that parent li element.
Now, when we click on
About for the first time,
the Bootstrap
JavaScript plugin will
remove the open class,
hiding our dropdown.
If we view the
page as a whole, we
can see that it's much
clearer now with only three
navigation items rather
than those eight links that
were up there before, but
there's one thing missing.
There were some dividers between
our links within our dropdown.
One way to add those
might be adding some CSS
and maybe adding
a border-bottom to
some of our links.
Well, there's a much
easier way to do that
by editing our HTML markup.
Let's see what that looks like.
We can add some empty li
elements at the places
where we want dividers to go.
In this case, we'll split up
these links into three groups.
Let's think of them as
internal links, social media
links, and then our blog,
which can stand on its own.
These empty li elements will
be spacers between our links
that we'll add a
class of divider to.
If we check our
dropdown menu out now,
we'll see a very clear
separation between our link
groups.
This is a small change in our
HTML but huge for usability.
How would our dropdown
menu work for users
that don't have
JavaScript enabled?
Well, right now, if
they click on About,
they're not going
to see anything.
Nothing's going to
happen, and no dropdown
is going to be shown.
The page will scroll to the
very top due to that hash sign,
but our dropdown menu
will never be seen.
What we want is for our
page to gracefully degrade
for older browsers — still
giving those visitors
with older software a good
experience of our content.
To do that, we'll actually
need to change our href back
to pointing to about.html
instead of the hash sign.
If the user doesn't have
JavaScript enabled, now
they'll be taken
to the About page.
And on there, we
could drive people
to the other links that
were previously nested.
If they do have
JavaScript enabled,
they will see the dropdown, but
then they'll immediately still
be taken to the About page.
Not exactly something
we want to happen.
In order to prevent that,
we can add one last data
attribute: data-target.
This is the href
that will be used
when JavaScript is enabled.
In this case, we're going
to set it to that hash sign
just like we were doing before.
Now, for users whose browsers
work with JavaScript,
things will appear
just as expected.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
That's the end of this section
and the end of this course.
It's time for you to
drop down into the code
and complete a few challenges.
Thanks for taking Blasting
Off with Bootstrap
and for using Code School.
I am Adam Fortuna, and
we'll see you real soon.
[MUSIC PLAYING]