Welcome back to section two
of Flying Through Python.
Looking at our program again,
it might be a little confusing
that the first piece
of code that gets run
is at the bottom of our script.
That's because the function
definition is at the top
and doesn't get run
until it's called.
If it helps, we can think
of the code at the bottom
as the main part of our
program and the code at the top
just as functions that
get used in the main part.
This allows us to
be sloppy though.
We could scatter these lines of
code all throughout our script.
To be more organized, we can
take our main program code
and put it in a
function called main.
Then the only piece
of code that's
not in a function in our
file will be one single call
to main to kick
off our program.
This is not required, but is
the best practice in Python
and what we'll do
throughout the course.
Let's look at our
order of execution
now that we've created main.
Since functions don't
run until they're called,
all of the execution kicks off
with the first call to main
then runs the lines of code in
main until average gets called.
Then average runs and returns
a value to main and main
continues.
When you're working
with functions,
you need to be aware of scope.
Scope determines what
parts of your program
can access certain variables.
So if you declare a
variable inside a function,
it only exists within that
function or it has local scope.
For example, the
variable total is created
within the average function.
If we try to access total
in our main function,
we get "Name error:
'total' is not defined."
We would get the same error
if we tried to access numbers.
This is because total
and numbers don't
exist inside the main function.
They only exist inside
the average function,
or you could say their scope is
local to the average function.
Variables that are declared
outside of a function
have global scope.
Global scope means that they
can be accessed anywhere inside
of the script.
For example, order
goal has global scope.
So if we try to access it in our
main, we don't get any errors
and are able to print its value.
Our functions also
have global scope.
But variables still can't be
used until they're declared.
So if we instead declared order
goal after we called main,
main will be run before
order goal is created.
Then we main tries
to print order goal,
we'll get the same name error.
Now it's time for you create
your own main function
and see what
trouble you get into
with local and global scope.
Have fun.