Welcome back to
Flying through Python.
In this section, we'll
be covering dictionaries.
What if we wanted
another list to keep
track of the
American definitions
of our British slang list?
Then we would have
two lists to maintain.
If we do anything to one of
our lists, like delete an item
or add an item,
we'd have to also
delete or add the matching
item from the other list.
So that the slang
words still match up
with their definitions.
Maintaining two lists can
be tiring and error-prone.
We can see how we can improve upon this
by using dictionaries.
Dictionaries are
similar to lists.
But instead of looking
up an item by its index,
you look up an
item with its key.
So we'll make our keys
the British slang words,
and the values will be
their American definitions.
So we can look up the
definition of our slang word
by using the word like
an actual dictionary.
When we create
our dictionary, we
use curly brackets, instead
of square brackets.
And we specify the
key and the value
it's assigned to with a colon.
For example, we
have the key cheerio
assigned to the value, goodbye.
Each item in the dictionary
is called a key-value pair.
And we separate all of our
key value pairs with commas.
We can then look up
an entry by putting
a key in square brackets.
Here we look up
the key cheerio
and get the value goodbye.
Like lists, we
can store anything
in a Python dictionary.
We can use strings as
both the key and value,
as we're doing with
our slang dictionary.
We can use a string as the
key and a number as the value.
For instance, here we have a
menu item's name as the key,
and its price as the value.
We can actually use any
combination of types,
such as a number
mapped to a string,
and a number mapped to a number.
We can create an
empty dictionary
with empty curly braces, and
then add items as we need to.
We add items by using
square brackets key, which
is the same way we
would look up the value,
and then using an equal sign
to assign the desired value.
This will also work
for updating a value
for a key that already exists.
If we print out
our dictionary, we
see that we have
three key value pairs.
Let's say we want to update
the value of smashing to be
awesome instead of terrific.
We just look up the smashing
key with the square brackets,
and assign it the value
awesome with an equal sign.
Then if we look up in print
smashing, we get awesome.
So updating our
dictionary worked.
Like with lists, you can
use del -- short for delete --
to delete an item by
looking up its key.
Here we have three
items in our dictionary,
and we want to delete the
cheerio key value pair.
We type del and then
look up the key cheerio.
Then, if we print out
the resulting dictionary,
the key cheerio and
its value was deleted.
If you try to access a key
in the dictionary that's
not there, you'll
get a key error,
and your program will quit.
To avoid this, you can
use the GET method.
If the key exists, the
value will be returned.
If the key doesn't exist,
"none" will be returned.
"None" is a special type
of value in Python
that actually means
that absence of a value.
Since "none" represents the
absence of a value in Python,
"none" evaluates to
false in a conditional.
And if a value exists,
it evaluates to true.
So we can try to get the
value of the key, bloody,
and then check if it was found
by checking if the result was
a value, like the word darn.
Otherwise, if result was none,
we'll print key doesn't exist.
In this case, we would
print key doesn't exist,
because bloody is not
in our dictionary.
Let's use our slang dictionary
to translate a sentence.
We've concatenated each of
the British slang words,
mate and cheeky, separately, to
make it easier to look them up.
We can then replace each slang
word with its translation
by getting it from
the dictionary.
We can then print out the
slang version of the sentence,
and the translated
version of the sentence.
Now it's time for you
to practice dictionaries
and the challenges.
The key is to add value.
Get it?
Key, value, dictionaries?