[SINGING] Cheerio pip pip,
let's code some Python files.
We'll use quick lists, and
loops with fors and whiles.
Use modules we can, with
functions write them on.
Come join the Spam Van
and fly through Python.
Welcome to Flying
Through Python.
I'm Sarah Buchanan.
And in this course, we'll be
building upon the basics taught
in Try Python.
And learning more about the
language's core constructs.
Lists, dictionaries, loops,
functions, and modules.
At the end of this
course, we want
to build a basic
point of sale system
for our circus food
truck, the Spam Van.
And to do that,
we'll want to start
with a list of British
slang to inspire our menu.
Let's get started with
lists and dictionaries.
Lists in Python are containers
that can store any type of data
that you want.
We can create an empty
list with square brackets
and add things later, or
we can initialize our lists
with some values
separated by commas.
Such as a list of numbers,
a list of strings, or you
can even have a
mixed list of items.
If you remember the string
level from Try Python,
we've actually already
seen lists before.
Just like a string is a list of
characters starting from zero,
list are ordered lists starting
with position or index zero.
And you can get
each item in a list
with its index using
square brackets.
Here we have a list of strings.
So if we look up the string
at index zero, we get cheers.
And the string
index three is hiya.
We can also slice
a list to get a sub
list in the same way we slice
a string to get a substring.
So the slice from one to three
gives us cheerio and watcha.
Now that we know how
to create a list,
let's create a list
of British sayings
to inspire our Spam Van menu.
We can create the list
with elements in it
already or create an empty list.
And we can add more
items as we need them.
We add an item to
the end of our list
by typing the name of the list,
slang.append and then the item
we want to append
in parentheses.
Here, the string cheeky.
And we'll also add yonks.
And we end up with the
following list of five strings:
Cheerio, pip pip, smashing,
cheeky, and yonks.
We can remove items from
our list in two ways.
If we know the item
we want to remove,
we use the remove
method in the same way
we use the append method.
With the list name,
slang.remove, and the item
cheeky in parentheses.
If we don't know the exact
item but we know the position,
we can use del --
short for delete --
followed by the list's name,
square brackets, and the index.
If we had used either
one of these statements,
we end up with the
resulting list:
Cheerio, pip pip,
smashing, yonks.
We can also delete a slice,
or a section of our list,
by using del followed
by the slice.
Here we deleted the
first two items,
and end up with the
list: smashing, yonks.
Now it's time for
you to practice
with lists in the challenges.
Good luck.