Welcome back.
Now that we have for
loops in our tool belt,
let's create a fun British-themed
menu for our Spam Van.
Since our menu
features a lot of spam,
let's take our
British slang list,
and then append spam to
each word inside of it.
To do this we'll start
with an empty menu list.
Then we'll loop over every
slang word and concatenate spam
to each word.
And then append the
result to our menu list.
And we end up with the
resulting menu items.
Knackered spam, Pip
pip spam, Squidgy spam,
and Smashing spam.
For each of our menu items
let's also assign a price.
We'll start with $0.50 and
each item will be $1 more than
the next.
To do this we'll use a
dictionary called menu prices.
The keys will be the
item name and the values
will be the price.
We'll start by creating
an empty dictionary.
And we'll also create a variable
price that starts at $0.50.
Then we'll loop over each
item in our menu list.
Next, we'll assign the
dictionary with the key item
to the price.
And lastly, we'll increase
the price by $1 each loop.
If we print out our final
dictionary menu prices
we have all of our items assigned a price.
Now, we want to print these
items out on separate lines
to display our menu.
But if we just use the
same four loop format
as we did with a list, this
defaults to just printing
the keys in the dictionary.
But we also want the prices.
In the for loop we can
use menu prices.items
to get a list of our
dictionaries key value pairs.
And then we can access
both in our loop.
We use the temporary
variable names, name and price,
for each key and value
in menu_prices.items.
If we look at our
result, the menu
has all the
information it needs.
But we'd like to
format it better.
The print function defaults
to separating each argument
with a space.
Which makes things
look a little weird.
We can get rid of
those extra spaces.
In print, we can set sep
equal to an empty string which
removes that space separator.
Now, the spacing
is looking better.
But we need to round
to two decimal places.
Instead of printing out 0.5
we want to print out $0.50.
We can format our price by using
the built-in format function.
And we write format ( price, .2f -
which means f for float and two
decimal places.
Now, our menu is printed
out with numbers that
look more like actual prices.
And it's time for
you to practice more
with for loops
in the challenges.
Good luck.