[SINGING] Cheerio pip pip,
let's code some Python files.
We'll use quick lists, and
loops with fors and whiles.
Use modules we can, with
functions write them on.
Come join the Spam Van
and fly through Python.
Welcome back to
Flying through Python.
I'm Sarah Buchanan, and this
is level two, Loopty Loops.
Remember our goal.
At the end of this
course, we want
to create a basic sales
system for our circus food
truck, the Spam Van.
But in order to do
that, we'll want a way
to easily repeat behavior.
And loops will allow
us to do just that.
We're going to use a
for loop to calculate
the average price of
our menu so that we
can prove we deserve
a single dollar sign
rating on sites like Yelp.
To do this, we'll use a loop to look at each price in our price
list.
We want to sum all of the
prices in a price list
to figure out the average.
But first, let's just print out
each price in our price list.
The format of our for loop
is, for price in prices.
And then the code
we want to repeat.
Which is, printing
price is price.
This for statement
is like saying,
do this for each individual
price in our list.
And price, here, is
a temporary variable
we create that holds one
of the prices in the list
for each run of the loop.
Let's see this loop in action.
The first time through
the loop, price
is the first number
in prices, 2.5.
So we print price is 2.5.
Then price is the second
number in prices, 3.5,
and we print price is 3.5.
And finally, prices 4.5,
and we print price is 4.5.
Now let's add in our code
for summing our prices
into the variable total, and
also print out total each time
through the loop.
If we look at what's
happening behind the scenes,
the first time
through the loop price
is the first element
in the list, 2.5.
Then total is set
equal to 0 plus 2.5,
and we print total is 2.5.
The second time through
the loop, price is 3.5,
and total is now assigned
its old value, 2.5, plus 3.5,
which is 6.
So we print total is 6.
And we continue this pattern
for each number in the list.
And the final total is 10.5.
Finally, outside of the loop,
we calculate that average
by dividing the total
by the number of prices.
The length function of
prices will give us that.
And then we print out the
final result: average is 3.5.
We also want to do something
fun for our customers,
so with each purchase a
customer gets a raffle ticket.
And at the end of the day, we
draw 10 random raffle tickets
and hand out prizes.
To do this, we'll
need to first generate
a random ticket number, and second repeat that 10 times.
We can use a loop to repeat.
First, let's take a
slight detour from loops
and figure out how to
generate a random number.
First, we type import random to
import the random module, which
allows us to pick random
numbers in a few different ways.
Random.random gives us a
random number from 0 to 1,
random.choice lets us select
a random number from a list,
and random.randint gives us
a random number in a range.
We'll assume our raffle tickets
have numbers one through 1000.
And we'll use randint.
Now we just need to repeat that 10 times with a loop.
Now we know what we
want inside our loop,
to pick a random number
and print it out.
But we don't have a list
for our loop, so how will
we loop 10 times?
We can use the built-in
function range.
Range of 10 will create
a list of 10 numbers, zero
through nine for us
behind the scenes.
So now we will look at
our for loop using range.
We have, for i -- where i is
our temporary variable name --
in range of 10.
And this will repeat the
indented code 10 times.
Here we see our 10 random raffle
ticket numbers printed out.
And we have our lucky winners.
Notice that we didn't use the
variable i in the for loop
because we didn't need to.
But there are some situations
where we will need to.
For example, now we
want to print now
all of the years we've held
our circus in Orlando, Florida.
From 2005, every
other year until now.
The list in our for loop is
generated by range again,
but here we'll use an
alternative format of range
where we can set the start,
stop, and step values.
We would use range by putting
in the start year as 2005,
the current year, 2016,
as the stop value,
and the step value
as every two years.
This would print 2005,
add the step of two,
print 2007, and so
on, and stop at 2015
before the stop value of 2016.
Now it's time for
you to practice
with for loops, random numbers,
and range in the challenges.
Good luck.