Welcome back.
In this section, we'll
be reading from files.
Every day, our boss sends us
a file of dollar menu items.
We'd like to read
this file into a list.
To read from a file, the
steps are similar to writing.
First, we'll open the file.
We use the open function with
the file name and the mode.
Here it's R for read.
Second, we read from the file.
The dollar spam.read will read
the entire file's contents.
Finally, we close the file
with dollar spam.close.
There's a few other ways
to read from a file instead
of reading the entire
file's contents at once.
Read line will allow you
to read one line at a time
by looking for a
new line character,
and it will keep track
of what line we're on.
You can also read
all of the lines
individually in a loop, which
will be convenient for reading
all of the lines into our list.
But before we do
this, let's write code
to print out each
line of our file.
We'll do this by
using a for loop
and write for line
in dollar spam
and then print out the line.
Great.
Printing works.
Now let's try reading
each of these lines
into a list called dollar menu.
So we create our variable
dollar menu as an empty list.
And then inside our for loop,
we append each line of our file
to our dollar menu list.
And then after the loop,
we print our dollar menu
and finally close
our dollar spam file.
This was perfect for reading
each line into a list.
The only problem is we also
read in the new line characters.
We'll want to fix this by
getting rid of the new lines.
If we use the
string method strip,
this will return
a string with all
of the leading and trailing
white space removed,
and white space includes
new line characters.
And there you have it.
We've successfully read in our
dollar menu file into a list.
Now it's time for you
to practice reading
from files and the challenges.
Good luck.