(SINGING) Cheerio, pip pip,
let's code some Python files.
We'll use quick lists, and
loop with fors and whiles.
Use modules we can, with
functions write them on.
Come join the Spam Van,
fly through Python.
Welcome back to
Flying through Python.
This is level four, covering
reading and writing to files.
The Spam Van has become
wildly successful,
and is trying to improve its
business with daily sales
reports.
But to do this, we'll need
more permanent storage.
You see, if we add each
individual sale to a list,
the lifetime of that
list is only while we
are running the program.
If we quit the program and run
it again, our list isn't saved.
So at the end of
the day, we want
to be able to store these
sales more permanently.
We can do that in several ways--
with more complex applications
you can use a database,
but here we'll
look at writing data to a
file, and reading from a file.
To write to a file,
first we open the file.
We use the open function with
the file name and the mode.
Here it's W for write.
After we open the file, we
went to save the open file
to a variable.
Here it's sales log.
Second we'll write to the file.
Using saleslog.write,
we'll write
the string in parentheses.
Finally, we'll close the
file with saleslog.close.
Here we would have
our resulting file
with our strings written to it.
If the file doesn't exist
for a right or an append,
Python will create it for us.
And also notice that
unlike print, we'll
need to add our own
new line characters.
If we add the new line
character at the end
of our first write
statement, then our strings
are written to separate lines.
After we get a
customer's order, it
would be great if we could
write it to a sales.txt file,
like the one shown here.
Let's assume each
customer's order
is stored as a dictionary of
menu items and their prices.
So we're going to
write each item
and price on a separate line,
and then the order's total.
We'll write our own
function, write sales
log, that takes in
the orders dictionary.
In this function we'll open
the file in mode W for write,
then we'll write the order and
the order's total to the file,
and after we're done writing,
we'll close the file.
To write out each
order, we'll loop over
each menu item in
the order dictionary,
and write that item to the file.
If we look at the result we
only have the menu item name,
but we also need the price.
So we actually have to loop over
order.items to get the key end
value from the dictionary,
which here is the menu item
name and the price.
We'll do for item
price in order.items,
so that we can access the
menu item and its price.
And inside the for loop, we'll
write the item with its price.
And our resulting sales
log file is coming along,
but we'll also want
the total in there.
So we'll create a variable
to add the total to,
and for each order we'll
add the item's price
to the total inside
of the for loop.
Then after we've written
each individual order,
we can write the total.
That looks good.
Now let's see what
happens when we
call this function twice for
two different customer orders.
When we do that, we
actually overwrite the file
with the new customer's order,
which is not what we wanted.
This is because we had the
mode set to W for write,
which overrides the file.
Instead we can
change the mode to A
for append, which
will add the new order
to the end of the file.
Now that our new
order is appended
to the end of the file, we
can also add another new line
to separate the orders better.
Great.
Now our sales log is
looking and working right,
and it's time for you
to practice writing
to files in the challenges.
Good luck.