Welcome back.
In this section, we'll
be covering exceptions.
If we try to open a
file that doesn't exist,
we get a File Not Found Error.
It would be great if we could
recover from this type of error
and continue with our program.
Try, except allows
us to do just that.
Anything we put in the try
block is potentially error prone
code, like opening a file.
It's like we're
saying, try this.
And if you get an error,
print the error message
in the except block.
And then continue with
the program as usual.
Python has over 60
types of exceptions.
Here's some of the
ones we've seen before.
Exceptions like file not found
error, index error, key error,
name error, and value error.
Let's look specifically at
handling this value error next.
A value error can
occur when we try
to convert a string to a
number and the string actually
contains a word
instead of a number.
Like here we're asking the
user to enter the price.
Since we know the specific
situation can cause a value
error, we're specifically
checking for a value error.
If the user enters
a number, the price
is printed out as expected.
If the user doesn't
enter a number,
like here, the word
oops, our error message,
not a number is printed.
Instead of creating a
custom error message,
we can capture the
error as a variable
and print it inside
the except block.
So here, the user enters yo.
And we get the error could not
convert string to float yo.
That's it for Level 4.
Now it's trime
for-- time for you--
OK, that's it for level 4.
Now it's time for
you to practice
try except in the challenges.
Have fun.