Welcome back to
Flying Through Python.
In this section, we'll be
comparing and combining
lists and dictionaries.
Just like we can compare strings
and numbers for equality,
we can also check if
two lists are equal.
For two lists to
be equal, they have
to have exactly the same items
in exactly the same order.
So if my list has one,
two, three, four, in order.
And your list is reversed,
checking if the two
lists are equal returns false.
If we add another list,
his list, with the same
ordered one, two, three, four,
and then check for equality
with my list, we get true.
But how does this work for
comparing dictionaries?
We created a simple dictionary
here with the key and value
as the same numbers for
numbers one through four.
Then we created the same
dictionary in reverse order.
Since order doesn't
matter in dictionaries,
the dictionaries
are actually equal.
If this bothers you, think
about looking up the key one.
Would you get the same value?
Yes, you would.
You'd still get the value one.
Let's say we have three
different menu lists,
breakfast, lunch, and dinner.
How would we combine
these into one list?
A list is a container
of anything you want,
so you can even have
a list of lists.
Let's say for our
food truck, we want
a list of menus, the breakfast,
lunch, and dinner menus.
And each menu stores
a list of food items.
Then, if we print the
menu at index zero,
we get the breakfast menu.
Index one returns
the lunch menu.
And index two returns
the dinner menu.
A list of lists is sometimes
called a two dimensional list.
So how would we get an element
from one of these inner lists?
Like spam and jam.
First, we need to access
the inner list which
we can do by writing menus,
square bracket, zero.
So now that we have
that list, we just
need to get that second
item, spam and jam.
And we do that by using
index one in the inner list.
So menus, zero, one,
gives us spam and jam.
We could make this
code even better
if we didn't have to just know
that the breakfast menu was
at index zero, the lunch
menu was at index one,
and the dinner menu
was at index two.
We could use a dictionary
where the key breakfast has
the value of the list
of breakfast items,
the key lunch has the value
of the list of lunch items,
and the key dinner has the value
of the list of dinner items.
That makes it much
easier to find each menu.
Now that you've seen
comparing and combining
lists and dictionaries,
it's time for you
to give it a try
in the challenges.
Good luck.