Welcome back to section three
of Flying Through Python.
Now let's get back to our
Spam Van ordering system.
We said before that we
want to create functions
for any code that serves
a specific purpose.
So let's think of
all the things we
want to do with our
Spam Van system,
and create a function for them.
First, we want to print
or display the menu.
Second, we want
to take an order.
And third, we'll
calculate the total bill.
Of course we could do more
things, like collect payment
and add tips and so on,
but this will do for now.
So let's get started
implementing our functions
for each one of
these three actions.
We'll start with printing
our menu, which we wrote code
for in level 2.
We'll take that code, and put
it inside its own function.
We'll type def print menu,
as the function name,
and we'll need the
menu as a parameter
so that we can print it.
Notice the contents of
the function are indented,
and we don't need
to return anything
because we're just printing.
Second, we'll want to take
the ordering interface
that we created in level 2, and
put it inside its own function.
We'll call it "get order."
And it will also need
the menu as a parameter
so that we can check that the
customer's order is actually
on the menu.
And we'll return what the
customer ordered, which will
be stored in the orders list.
Let's look at our Spam
Van sales program so far.
We've left out the
contents of our functions
so that it's easier to
see the overall program.
In main, we start with our menu.
We call print menu and
pass it the menu printer.
Now our customers
can view the menu.
Then we call the
get order function.
Also passing it the
menu as a parameter,
and saving the resulting order
list to the order variable.
Then we print out their order.
Finally, we want to calculate
the customer's total bill,
which we haven't
written code for yet.
In order to do that, we'll need
the orders list, and the menu
to look up each item's price.
We haven't sent two parameters
into a function before.
All we need to do is
separate them with a comma.
We'll also need a total
variable to sum up the total.
And we'll loop over each
order in the orders list
and look up the items price,
and add it to the total.
Finally, we'll return
the total bill.
Let's look at running this
function with an example.
The customer's order is
cheeky spam, pip pip spam,
and knackered spam.
And we have a menu with prices.
The first time through
the loop, order
will be the first
order: cheeky spam.
We'll find it in the menu
and get its price as $1,
and add it to the total.
The second time
through the loop, order
will be pip pip spam.
We'll find it in the menu,
and get its price as $3,
and add it to the total.
And the third time
through the loop, order
will be knackered spam,
we'll find it in the menu,
and get its price as $4,
and add that to the total.
And finally we would
return $8 as the total.
If we look at our final
program, we print out the menu,
get the customer's
order, and then print out
what they ordered
and the total bill.
Now let's look at our Spam
Van ordering system in action.
The custom orders smashing spam,
cheerio spam, and yonks spam.
Then their order is printed
out, and the total of $8.
That's it for level 3.
Now it's time for you to master
functions in the challenges.