Welcome back.
In this section, we'll be
creating our own module.
As our spam van script
continues to grow,
it's going to get really
hard to read and maintain.
Right now this one script
is responsible for printing
the menu, taking
orders, sales reports,
and now accessing the
menu from the network.
As our programs
get longer, we may
want to organize them
into several files
or separate modules
for easier maintenance.
We can organize
our program better
by separating getting
customer orders,
accessing the menu
from the network,
and sales reports in
the separate modules.
A script containing
definitions is a module
and can be imported by another
script or another module.
And as long as these files
are in the same directory,
we can import them into
the spam van script
just by writing import
and the module name.
We'll start with creating
the orders module now.
First, we'll take all of
our definitions pertaining
to ordering and put them
in our orders module.
Then the spam van script will
call the orders functions
from that module and
hold our main function.
Now we have our separate files:
orders.py and spam_van.py,
but there's a little problem.
When we run spam van,
we get this error.
The reason is we forgot to
import the orders module.
Import orders will be able
to find our orders model.
But even still, if we run
this, it doesn't work.
We need to add orders dot
before each of
the functions that
are part of the orders module.
Now our program can
find the functions
within the orders module and
will run just as it did before.
It prints out the menu,
gets the customer's order,
and prints out the bill total.
That's it for Flying
through Python.
Good luck in the rest
of the challenges,
and I'll see you in
the wrap-up video.
Sorry.
I couldn't remember
how to segue.
Dictionary-o.
Dictionary-o?
Comparing.
Creating from the--
We then put--
You're not going
to read your joke?
No.
Like, I tried.
It's not a good joke.
I, like, tried to come up with
stuff, and it was terrible.
Break a leg.