[SINGING] Cheerio, pip pip,
let's code some Python Files.
We'll use quick lists, and
loop with fors and whiles.
Use modules we can,
with functions write them on.
Come join the Spam Van
and Fly Through Python.
Welcome back to
Flying Through Python.
I'm Sarah Buchanan.
And this is level
5, covering modules.
The Spam Van is now a franchise,
and each one of the vans needs
to download the daily menu
from the headquarters website.
To do this, we can use
the Python request module.
Modules are libraries
that contain functions.
We've seen them before when we
used the random module to get
a random number, and
importing the math module
for more math functions.
Instead of rewriting
the complicated code
to do these tasks, we
can import a module
that does them so we don't
have to reinvent the wheel.
Unlike the math
and random modules,
the request module does not
come pre-installed with Python,
so we'll have to install it.
Pip install is a
convenient command
for installing Python modules.
It downloads the necessary
files and installs
the package for you.
Just type pip install and
the name of the module.
And when you hit enter, you'll
see the status of the download
and when it's
successfully installed.
To check out all of the
available Python packages,
you can visit the link below.
Before we use our
request module,
let's talk about what
a request actually is.
An HTTP request happens when
you ask a server for data.
Our server will send
back data in JSON format,
making it easy to build a menu.
JSON is a standard way
to format and share data
and is often used
to exchange data
between a client and a server.
It uses a combination of
lists and dictionaries
where the keys and
values are all strings.
When we get our
menu in JSON format,
it will look identical to
a list of dictionaries,
where each dictionary is a menu
item contained within a list.
Now let's figure
out, specifically,
how JSON will be used
to store our menu.
If we wanted to store more
information about a menu
item, its name,
description, and price,
we could do this with a
dictionary that has three keys.
Name, description and price.
And then the values are the
items actual name, description,
and price.
For instance, for
the first item,
the name is spam n eggs.
The description is,
two eggs with spam.
And the price is $2.50.
Then to print the name
followed by the price,
we just use the key name
and use the key price
for the first item, and the
same for the second item.
Since we're going to have
a lot of these menu items,
it makes sense to
store them in a list.
And we'll call this
list, menu items.
Then to get the first item, we
would use menu items index 0.
Then to print that
item's name, we
would look up menu items index
0, and then use the key name.
To get its price, we
would use the key price.
And its description, we
can use the key d-e-s-c.
And we can do the same thing
for the item at index 1,
and now we have a fully
descriptive menu printed.
We can also put these
dictionaries directly
into our list instead of
creating variables for them
first.
Now our data is
formatted exactly how
we'll get it as
JSON, which is great,
because this is how we'll
get it from our web server.
Now, instead of hard
coding this list,
let's get it from
our HTTP request.
To create our request, we first
import the request module.
Then we call request.get
with our URL as a parameter.
Next, we'll call the
JSON method to get
the response in JSON format.
If we print this out,
we'll have a list
of dictionaries,
which we'll want
to parse into a prettier
format for a menu.
To print today's menu,
we'll loop over our list
and get each item's name,
description, and price.
Great, now we just need to
format this a little better.
So we'll add in
some punctuation.
As we've done before, we'll set
sep equal to the empty string,
and use a colon and dollar
sign just to make it look nice.
Now we have our daily
menu downloaded straight
from the headquarters website.
And we look at our
program in action,
it downloads the menu from
the server and prints it out.
Now it's time for
you to practice using
a module in the challenges.
Good luck.
.