[SINGING] Cheerio, pip pip.
Let's code some Python files.
We'll use quick lists and
loop with fors and whiles.
Use modules we can with
functions write them on.
Come join the Spam Van
and fly through Python.
Welcome back to
Flying through Python.
This is level 3
covering functions.
If you remember from
level 2, we wrote code
to calculate the
average of a price list.
And let's say we also
want to write code
to calculate the average
daily customers in a week.
And we also want to
write code to calculate
the average daily sales.
We are essentially
copying and pasting
almost identical code to average
a different list of numbers.
Wouldn't it be great
if we could have
just one piece of code that can
average anything we ask it to?
We could do this
with a function.
Functions are like mini-programs
that perform a specific task.
And we want a function that
will average a list of numbers.
If we had that, we could
write that code once and then
input our prices list and get
out the average of our prices
list, input our number
of daily customers list
and get out the average
daily customers.
And we could give it
any list of numbers,
and it would output the average.
We've actually been using
functions all along,
like print, which takes
in a string or value
and outputs it to the console.
And range, which here,
takes in the number 10
and returns a list
from zero to nine.
But how can we make
our own function?
First we want to
define three things.
One, what is the
name of the function?
Two, what data do we
send into the function?
And three, what data
comes out of the function?
The name of the function we
want to create is average.
And this is how
we'll call it later.
Every function starts with
def, then the function name,
parentheses, and a colon
marks the beginning
of the function's code.
Then inside the
parentheses, we want
to give the function
any variables
or values it needs to work with,
which are called parameters.
For our average
function, we will
want to give it a list
of numbers to average.
Functions can also return a
value, but that's optional.
We want our average function to
return the average of the list.
So we're going to return the
variable "avg," short for average
at the end of our function.
Also note that, just like
conditionals and loops,
all of the code inside
the function is indented.
Now let's take our
previously written code
from level 2 that calculates
the average of our prices list
and put it inside our function.
We don't have to
create our prices list,
because it's been passed to
the function as a parameter.
And we're not going
to print the average,
instead we're going to return
that average we calculated.
Now that we've created our
function, how do we use it?
Functions don't run
until you call them.
So outside of our
function, in our script,
we can create a numbers list
that we want to average.
Then we'll call our
average function
and pass it our numbers list.
And then we'll create
a variable my_average
and assign the value that our
average function returns to it.
If we print my_average,
we get the value three,
which was the result our
function gave back to us.
Awesome.
It worked.
Since we want our function to
work on other lists of numbers
other than prices, we can
change the name of our parameter
to be more general.
So we'll change
prices to numbers.
And in our for loop,
we'll change price to "num."
So our function
still works the same,
but the variable names are more
general to reflect that we can
pass in any list of numbers.
For example, we could use it to
pass in a list of daily sales.
And daily sales
doesn't have to match
what it's called
it in the function,
as long as it's a
list of numbers.
Now let's look at our
entire program in action.
Since a function doesn't
get run until it's called,
in this example, the first
line of code that would run
is defining our price list.
Then we call our function
to get the average.
We do this by typing
the name of the function
and we put the parameter
prices in parentheses.
This is basically passing
the value to the function
so it can use it.
Then the program
goes to the function
that we just called and
goes through each line
of the function until
it returns a value.
The value average is
returned and stored
in our result variable.
And finally, we
print out the result.
Now that we know how to
create and run functions,
it's time for you to give
it a try in the challenges.
Good luck.