Welcome back to Flying
Through Python. This
is Section 3 covering while
loops. For our Spam Van,
we want to create an
ordering interface that
allows customers to order as
many menu items as they want.
A for loop wouldn't
really be good for this,
because we don't know how
many times we want to loop.
If we see the program we're
going to make in action,
we keep asking the
customer if they
want to order anything else
until they type q for quit.
This would be a good
situation for a while loop.
For loops allow you to loop
a certain number of times,
whereas while loops
continue looping
while a condition is true.
Let's look at a simple
example of a while loop.
We'll create a
program that increases
x while it's not equal to three.
So it will stop when
x is equal to three.
When we run this, x starts as one.
We print x as one and
increase it to two.
X is still not equal to
three, so we go in the loop
again, print x as two,
and increase x to three.
Then x not equal to three returns
false, so we exit the loop.
Now that we know how
while loops work,
let's use them to create
our ordering interface.
We'll create an orders
list to save the orders.
And ask the users what they
want to order using input.
And while their order is
not equal to q for quit,
we'll keep looping.
Inside this loop,
we'll write code
to add their order to a list,
if it's on the menu of course,
and to keep asking
the customer if they
want to order anything else.
First, we'll try to find
their order on the menu
by using menu.get.
If it's in the dictionary,
we'll add the order
to the orders list.
Otherwise, we'll print that
the menu item doesn't exist.
If we don't ever change the
customer's order in the loop,
it will never be q for quit,
and we'll have an infinite loop.
So we better ask the customer
for their order again.
We'll use input again. This
time inside the loop task,
to as the customer if they
want to order anything else.
And we'll also print
the orders list
as soon as we're done with
the loop with print orders.
If we look at our program
in action, it works great.
We can even have the
customer enter something
not on the menu, and we will
let them know it's not there.
Even though our program's
working perfectly,
we could write it differently
to express more clearly that we
want the loop to run forever
until the customer enters
q for quit.
If we use while true
instead of checking for
quit in our while
statement, this
will create a loop
that runs forever.
And then we can still check
if the user enters q below.
And if so, we'll
break out of the loop
by using a break statement.
A break statement exits the
loop immediately, but still
continues running the program
normally outside of the loop.
This program works exactly
the same as it did before,
but it's just an alternative
way of doing things.
We have another problem.
We ran out of cheeky spam.
And we want a way to check if
the customer orders that, so we
can let them know
that we're out.
We can add if order equals
cheeky spam print "Sorry,
we're all out of that!"
And then we can use
a continue statement.
Like break, a continue
statement stops the loop,
but instead of exiting
the loop forever,
a continue statement jumps
back to the top of the loop
and continues running.
Let's look at our
program in action.
So we run our program, and the
customer enters Cheeky Spam.
And whoops, we see we've
created an infinite loop.
If this happens to
you, don't panic,
just press Control-C
to exit your program.
The problem was we didn't
give the user an opportunity
to change their
order, so it was set
to Cheeky Spam for eternity.
What we can do is
move the line of code
that asks for their order
to the top of the loop,
then check if it's Cheeky Spam.
And then we'll also
check if they quit.
And the rest of our code
for finding their order
and adding it remains the same.
Looking at our final
working program,
we see if the customer
order Cheeky Spam,
we let them know it's out.
We can also let them know if
something's not on the menu.
And then when we quit, we
tell them what they ordered.
That's it for Level 2: Loops.
Now it's time for you
to practice while loops
in the challenges.
Break a leg.
[LAUGHTER]