Hi, friends and welcome to
JavaScript Best Practices.
This short collection
of tips and tricks,
do's and don'ts, is intended to
accomplish two things for you,
the JavaScript developer.
First is to help you become
fluent in and cognizant
of the available constructs
within the JavaScript language
and to help you use
good judgment when
you engage with those tools.
The second thing
is to, of course,
help you build the safety, the
performance, and the quality
of your applications
in large and small ways
not just for your users, but
also for you as the developer.
Now, this course requires
a very firm foundation
in the basics of the
JavaScript language.
And if you lack that,
make sure you head over
to the JavaScript road trip
course which will help give you
a firm foundation in
those basics for use
with the concepts
of this course.
And with that, it's time to
move forward with your journey.
Welcome to the land
of best practices.
[SINGING] Find the sword syntax
first for the useful tools
that you may need.
Wear the pendant of performance
for efficiency and speed.
Cautions crystal clears the sky
with triple equals try/catch
cache.
Avoiding stuff that sucks and
parsing better numbers
out of stretch.
Alas, the golden shining
mail of modularity,
where namespace close or
imports long defend integrity.
For polished jewels
in JavaScript,
the treasure trove this is.
Now raise your sword
and strike your shield
with these best practices.
Hello travelers and welcome
to this, the first portion
of your journey to the land
of JavaScript best practices.
In this first level, we'll be
examining alternate methods
of syntax that will help
you organize lengthier
bits of conditional code into
more concise, informative,
and legible blocks
of functionality.
At code school, we
know that staying
fluent and aware of what's
even possible within a language
is a best practice itself.
Cultivating a thorough knowledge
of what's even available to you
within the JavaScript
language helps you become
a more versatile, a well-rounded
developer, especially when
you might see these constructs
out there in the wilds
or even just in code that
you were hired to maintain,
but that you didn't
build yourself.
Now, as with any tool, there are
good uses and not so good uses.
And we'll do our best to
provide you with your best bets
while we bring you up to speed.
And with that, it is time to
tackle the ternary conditional
logical assignment
and the switch block.
Good luck finding
the sword of syntax.
Hey everybody.
Welcome to JavaScript
best practices.
This is the first level,
the sword of syntax.
I'm Jason Millhouse.
And in this first
section, we'll be
examining the
ternary conditional.
In order to do that, we're
going to take first a look
at the standard
conditional block.
The first thing we'll do here
to set up our conditional block
is to declare a variable
called, isArthur.
And we're going to set
that equal to false.
Next, we'll declare
a weapon variable.
Then, in our conditional
block, we'll say if isArthur.
We're going to
assign that weapon
variable to be Excalibur.
Otherwise, if it's
not Arthur, then we're
going to assign Longsword
to that weapon variable.
Now what you should
notice here is
that this sort of takes
two blocks of code just
to get one assignment finished.
That's sort of a little long
in terms of code length.
So let's see what we can do
about using a syntax trick that
will make this
significantly more concise.
To build a ternary conditional,
the first thing you'll do
is place a condition down
at the front of your ternary
conditional build.
Following that
condition is going
to be a question mark operator.
That's going to
divide the ternary
conditional into the condition
and the actions to take.
Next up, you're going to
have a pair of expressions
that follow that question mark.
These are going to be
separated by a colon.
One of these will be picked
as the conditionals result.
As you can see, if
the condition is true,
then we will get this left
side of the colon as a result,
and if the condition's
false, we're
going to go ahead and
get the right side.
So let's see how our current
conditional block can translate
into the ternary
conditional format.
You can see here, we're going
to stick our condition, which
is isArthur, single variable
with a Boolean value.
And then on the left
hand side of the colon,
we're going to put
Excalibur because that
is what we want to be the
weapon if isArthur is true.
On the right hand side,
we're going to put Longsword.
That's what should happen
if isArthur is false.
Now if we were to enter
this on the console,
since isArthur's
currently false,
we're going to go ahead and
get the right side returned
from this ternary
conditional, the Longsword.
Now by itself, this ternary
conditional expression
will return the right answer.
But what happened to
storing it in weapon
which is what happens in our
original conditional block?
Well, we can do that too.
Let's check it out.
So what we've got now is we've
got that var weapon declared.
And we're going to go ahead
and assign it immediately
upon declaration to the result
of the ternary conditional.
So after choosing the
appropriate sword here,
the compiler is going
to go ahead and assign
that choice
immediately to weapon.
And if we were to console log
out what the current weapon is,
we could see that the current
weapon is the Longsword.
Cool thing about
ternary conditionals
is that we can also use them
together in concatenation.
Let's check it out.
If we kind of scoot our
stuff over here, get rid
of that weapon
variable, and just place
the ternary conditional down
in the place of that weapon
variable, we can
see that-- uh-oh.
What the heck man?
We got Excalibur out of this.
What happened?
Hm, let's see.
Problem here is that that
cool question mark operator
has a lower precedence than the
plus concatenation operator.
Hm, that's interesting.
What does that mean?
Well, what happens
here is the plus sort
of only knows how to
evaluate a variable
and add it to a string.
And that's all going to
happen before the question
mark actually gets to
check any condition at all.
So what we got here is current
weapon as a string being
concatenated with
isArthur the Boolean
before any kind
of check happens.
And that current weapon
false is just a string.
So now that question mark
is looking for a Boolean,
but it finds a string.
So what does it do?
Well, it turns out that
in JavaScript, any value
will evaluate to truthiness
if it is not the falsy values.
The falsy values are false,
zero, undefined, not a number,
the empty string, or null.
So in this case, the question
mark looks at that string
and says, hm,
truthy value, so I'm
going to take the left hand
side of our ternary conditional.
Well, how the heck
can we fix that?
Well, since the
ternary conditional
can be evaluated
as an expression,
we can also group
it as an expression.
So let's throw some
parentheses around this guy.
And you can see now
that when we log it out,
we get exactly what
we wanted which
is an evaluation of the
variable only for the ternary
conditional check, and
we get current weapon
is the Longsword.
So what happens if
the King shows up?
Well, let's change
isArthur to true,
which means that we got
King Arthur on hand.
And when we evaluate
it, you can see
we get the current weapon is
now Excalibur just as we wanted.
Turns out that we can make
compound ternary conditions
as well.
We can use any compound
Boolean expression
as the condition to check
for our ternary conditional.
So let's do that.
What we've got here is
a variable called isKing
and we've set that
equal to false.
So what that means is
we've got some dude named
Arthur but doesn't
happen to be the King.
Maybe he was named
after the king,
but he's not the king so he
shouldn't get Excalibur, right?
So let's see what
we can do with that.
You can see we've put a
double ampersand, the double
and, right down there
next to isArthur.
And we've put isKing
next to it to make sure
that both of those
things are true before we
select a condition.
Once we've done that,
the question mark
takes a look at isArthur, finds
true, takes a look at isKing,
finds false though, and so
that whole compound conditional
evaluates to false and
we'll choose the right hand
side of the colon,
or the Longsword.
Now if we set
isKing to true just
to kind of show the other
possible result here,
we'll get the compound
logic evaluating
to true on the left hand side
of the question mark, which
means that the
ternary conditional
will return just what we
expect for the king, which
is the sword, Excalibur.
Something you might
see very often
out there in the
JavaScript wilds
is that ternaries can also
take action in their results.
That means that any
executable statement
can fall in the left hand
side or the right hand side.
Meaning when we
check the condition,
we can actually take action,
not just return some value.
So let's take a look.
So we're going to scoot
our stuff over here.
We've got isArthur
and isKing moving
to the left as our
compound conditional check.
And now on the right hand
side of our question mark,
we're going to alert "Hail
Arthur, King of the Britons!"
if both of those things on the
left hand side of the question
mark are true.
And if not, they will say,
"Charge on, ye Knight,
for the glory the King."
And you can see, since both of
our variables are now true--
apparently we've got
the King in the house--
we get an alert that
comes out and says,
"Hail Arthur, King
of the Britons."
If we change isKing to false--
we've got that dude Arthur
again, not the king,
just some random--
and we execute the
ternary conditional,
you can see that we
get the correct alert
for that situation.
Ternaries can
offer a concise way
of deciding which function
to choose on the fly.
They provide a slightly
different format
for picking immediately
invoked functions
based on some conditions.
Let's check that out.
So we'll scoot
our stuff up here.
And you can see now on the right
hand side of our question mark,
we're going to put an
immediately invoked function.
What's it going to do?
It's going to alert,
Hail to the King.
And it's also going to
log out the King's weapon.
Following the colon
now, we're going
to put another immediately
invoked function that's
going to alert for
the regular knight,
as well log out that their
weapon is the Longsword.
Remember that if you want to get
an immediately invoked function
expression, you'll need
to add the parentheses
behind the expression
to call that expression.
If we were to evaluate
the situation,
you can see that we
would get, "Charge on,
ye Knight, for the glory the
King," since isKing is false.
We'll also get a
console log-out that
says the current
weapon is Longsword.
Now, ternaries can also
take multiple actions.
We want to show you
that, but we also
want to caution you that
that can get very dense.
So sometimes a
conditional block is
better for this
particular situation,
but you should know to be very
fluent that multiple actions
can be taken inside of
each result in a ternary
conditional.
So here you can see
after the question mark,
we've got a
parenthetical expression
that has two executables
statements in it separated
by a comma.
So if it's Arthur
and it's the King,
we want to assign Excalibur
as that individual's weapon
and Goosewhite as that
individual's helmet.
On the other side of the colon,
we've got the same format.
And we're going to
give the regular knight
the weapon of the
Longsword as well
as an Iron Helm for his helmet.
So if we were to check
out isArthur and isKing,
you can see one is
true and one is false.
So if we were to
log out the weapon
and the helmet
situation, we would
see that we would get the
current weapon is the Longsword
and the current helmet
is the Iron Home.
That's because both of
our executable statements
in the false part of our
conditional executed.
One more thing you
might see associated
with ternary conditionals,
especially under the hood
of some JavaScript
frameworks, is
the nested ternary conditional.
A ternary can actually
hold other ternaries
within each one of the
possible responses.
You don't want to do
this too much because it
can get very dense and
slightly challenging to read.
And we always want to be
worried about legibility, right?
But we want to make
sure, again, that you're
fluent with this type of code.
So we're going to
scoot our stuff down.
And you can see that we have
added a variable, isArcher.
And we're going to set
that equal to true.
Now, in the false portion of our
outermost ternary conditional,
we're going to slap down
that isArcher variable
as the condition for a new
ternary conditional to check.
That's right.
We're trying to keep
this organized, right?
And you should too, so you
want to use indentation
as your friend for legibility.
Following that
isArcher variable,
we're going to place
another question mark.
That means that question
mark is looking only
at isArcher for a truth value.
And then we'll build a second
nested ternary conditional
after that question mark.
You can see that if
we have an archer,
we want to instead
assign the weapon
to be the Longbow and its
helmet to be a Mail Helm.
And if it's false, that means
where you don't have the king
and we also don't
have an archer, which
means that we have
just a regular knight,
and they should get the
Longsword and the Iron Helm.
Taking a look at our
existing Boolean variables,
we've got isArthur's
true, so apparently it's
a guy named Arthur.
But he's not the king
because that's false.
He is, however, an archer.
So he is Arthur the Archer.
Yeah, cool.
So anyway, since we've
got Arthur the Archer,
we're going to go
ahead and log out
what his weapon
and his helmet is.
And you can see
that what happens
is since isKing is
false, we're going
to go ahead and check the second
nested ternary conditional.
We find that the isArcher
variable is actually true.
And so we assign
Longbow as the weapon,
Mail Helm as the helmet.
And if we were to log
out his current weapon
and his current helmet, we
get Longbow and Mail Helm
for Arthur the Archer.
Yeah, so welcome to the end
of ternary conditionals.
Have some fun with
these challenges,
and we'll see you back
in the next section.