Welcome back to the Sword
of Syntax, JavaScript Best
Practices.
I'm Jason Millhouse.
You are extraordinary
JavaScript developers
getting more extraordinary
as the days go by.
In this section,
we'll be talking
about logical assignment, a
very valuable and often used
tool in JavaScript.
Let's take a look.
So all those logical
operators that we
use in standard
conditional blocks
and ternary
conditionals, in fact
can make assignments much
shorter, even shorter
than ternaries can.
All right.
I'm going to establish
an armory variable here.
And we're going to add a
property called addSword.
That addSword property
is going to be a function
and it will take in a
sword parameter, obviously.
Now take a look at
this first cool line
of the addSword function.
What is this doing?
It's kind of spooky.
I see this.swords three times.
Well, what it's doing is
examining the armory object
and seeing if a swords
property actually exists.
And if it does, then
what it's going to do
is just return that
exact same contents
of that property to
the property itself.
That may sound kind
of weird, but here's
what's cool about this
ternary conditional.
On the right hand
side of the colon--
meaning if the swords
property does not exist--
we're going to create
a brand new empty array
and pass it back to
the swords property,
thereby creating a new property
if it did not exist before.
So in other words, this
first line is saying,
does the swords property exist?
If so, just go with that.
If it doesn't, create
a new empty array.
That's what this
ternary conditional
is accomplishing for us.
Now your question might be, how
does the ternary conditional
know, looking at
this.swords, whether that
means there's a
property there or not?
Well, remember that
the ternary conditional
is just looking
for a truthy value.
And if something is there
that's not undefined
or not a number or all
those falsy values,
it will think that there's
something true there
and go with the true option.
Very useful.
Now here's where the money
is in this actual function.
Now that we've built a swords
property-- whether it's
the old one or a new
empty one-- we're
just going to push
the sword that's
the parameter into that list
of swords that we have built
or the one that we had.
Now this section is about
logical assignments,
so what we're going
to do is transform
this ternary statement
into a logical assignment.
Now this ternary
conditional works just fine.
It will evaluate whether
a property exists
and either assign
an empty array or go
with the pre-existing property.
But we can eliminate a
read of the sword property
through a logical assignment.
Let's take a look.
So first, we will get rid of
the question mark, the condition
to check, as well as the colon.
And we'll scoot some
stuff over here.
Now in between the
second this.swords
and the empty array, we'll
stick a logical OR operator.
Now, when used in
assignment, the OR operator
is going to select
the very first truthy
value that it finds.
Can you see how that works?
Now when used in
assignment, that OR operator
that you've seen
before will actually
try to select the
very first value
it finds that's not falsy.
In other words, it's looking
for the very first truthy value
that it can grab onto for
the purposes of assignment.
So this may be
new for you, let's
take a look at what happens if
the swords property is empty
and does not exist.
If I got this.swords is set
equal to either the existing
property or the
empty array, what
will happen when we
get to this.swords?
It will be undefined.
That is falsy.
The OR operator will ignore
it and instead select
the empty array
which is not falsy.
So what happens as a result?
The empty array gets
assigned to this.swords.
Now your question might be,
well isn't the empty arrays kind
of falsy?
I mean, there's nothing in it.
No, it doesn't care that
the array itself is empty
because the array is just a data
structure which is not false
at all.
So what happens if the
swords property actually
has something, it's
actually got some contents?
Let's take a look.
So now when I set up
my logical assignment,
I will get some array that's
got some swords in it,
or the empty array.
And since the array
with some swords in it
is truthy instantly
to the OR operator,
it's going to take that
and assign it directly back
to this.swords.
A mistake often made with
OR logical assignment
is that developers
sometimes think
that both of the contents
of the logical assignment
get examined.
That's not true.
Because in this case, as soon
as it finds a truthy value,
it will instantly
make the assignment.
That process is called
short circuiting.
What does that mean?
It means that the empty
array in this case
will never even get looked at.
So now we're going
to take a look
and see what happens when we
try to use our addSword function
with its logical assignment.
So we'll scoot our little
armory object in here.
It's got our addSword
function at the bottom, right.
No swords property yet.
So now we call the addSword
method using the Broadsword,
trying to pass the Broadsword
sword into the list.
So our logical
assignment triggers.
It looks to see if
this.swords is there.
And it is not.
And since it's not,
we'll take a brand
new, fresh, clean,
empty array and pass it
to the this.swords
property which
will be created on the fly.
Following that, we'll just
push the Broadsword to it.
And you can see that Broadsword
gets added to the empty array.
Next, to further
populate our swords list,
we'll try to add the
Katana to our swords array.
Function gets called.
Katana gets passed in.
In the logical assignment
line, now this.swords exists.
That means that the OR operator
sees this.swords and says, oh,
got something that's
true, so I'm go ahead
and assign that back to
the this.swords property.
You can see that the Katana
gets added to the array.
And now if we add the
Claymore, the same process
that occurred for
Katana will repeat
and we will get the
Claymore added to the array.
Same thing with a Scimitar
because this.swords
exists for each one
of those additions.
And now if we were to log out
our armory.swords property,
we can see we've got the full
array with every last sword
that we have added.
Something to note
here is that the order
that we have placed our
choices definitely matters.
We want to make sure that
the empty list is only
chosen as the very last resort.
We always want to go
with the existing swords
property in this case.
So order definitely matters
in your logical assignment.
Now to really see that the
order does in fact matter,
let's take a closer look
at that OR assignment.
The OR's going take that left
most truthy value every time.
And if none exists,
it's always going
to be that last falsy value.
So let's see what would
happen if we switched up
the order of the assignment.
So we'll switcharoo here,
put our empty array first
and this.swords last.
So what happens now that
the empty list is first?
Well, when used in
assignment, the OR operator
is going to try to take
the very first truthy
value that it finds.
And what is an empty array
all day every day forever?
It is a truthy value.
And so every single time
that this logical assignment
takes place, we're just going
to get that empty array over
and over again.
Let's see what happens.
Well, when we try to add
the Broadsword this time
using the addSword
property, yup, we're
going to get an empty list.
No problem.
We're going to get that return
to the this.swords property.
And there's our
nice empty array.
Then Broadsword gets pushed
into that empty array.
So everything appears
to be working right.
Hm, what's going on?
So now what happens
when we add the Katana?
Well, this logical
assignment's always
going to short circuit on
that truthy empty array
because it's not falsy.
So we try to add that
Katana and-- wah-wah.
We get an empty list,
brand new and fresh inside
of our swords property.
We have lost our Broadsword man.
It's like it never happened.
Then we push our Katana into
that empty array and trudge
on to further data destruction.
Because when we continue to add
the Claymore and the Scimitar,
what would happen?
Well, we'd get that empty array
destroying our existing sword
collection every single time,
all because that empty array is
truthy and short
circuits the check.
Then, of course, we log
out our armory.swords
and what do we see?
Well, one piddly little
Scimitar for the entire armory.
That is bad news
for master armorer
who now has lost all of
his swords, which probably
sucks if you're the armorer.
So make sure that you
put your default cases
at the end of your
logical assignments
and be very careful to
construct them well.
To further refine our
understanding of this OR
operation, we're going to
look at some other arrangement
of truthy and falsy values
just to see what they produce.
So here in our first box we've
got the variable, result1,
getting the result of the
logical assignment between 42
and undefined.
Well, 42 will cause that OR
operation to short circuit.
And if we logged it
out, we would get 42.
Undefined is never examined.
Next, in result2, we're
looking at an array
with some strings in it, as well
as zero on the right hand side.
Well, the array full of strings,
totally truthfully, we're
going to go ahead and take that.
And the zero is never
examined, again,
because of the short circuit.
Finally, we got result3
which has an object in it.
Object is definitely truthy.
On the other side
is the empty string.
That empty string is never
examined for the same reason,
because of the short circuiting.
So when we log out result3,
we're going to get the object.
What happens when
we switch it up?
So in the first
one, when undefined
is on the left of the OR, the OR
sort of ignores the undefined.
Can't find a truthy value.
Let's see what we got
on the other side.
We've got a 42.
And so 42 is truthy, we'll
pass that back to result1.
When we log it out, we
see we still get 42.
In result2, the array is
on the right hand side now.
And since zero is falsy,
the OR will take the array
and pass it back to result2.
Lastly, the empty
string is falsy.
And so we're going to take
that object on the right hand
side of the OR which
gets logged out.
Important thing to remember
about OR operations
is that the very first non-falsy
value will be accepted.
So your next question
may be, well,
what happens when
they're all truthy?
When all elements
are truthy, we'll
get the very first
truthy value found.
For example, if we've
got both King and Arthur
in our logical assignment, we're
going to go ahead and take King
because that is the first
thing, the first truthy
value that we find.
In result2, if we had Arthur
first and King second,
we would take Arthur because
it's the first truthy
value that we find.
The moral of the story
is that short circuiting
will occur even if both
of the values are true.
Now, the OR logical assignment
has an interesting behavior
when all elements are false.
It will examine
every possible entry
and then take the very last
one if nothing is true.
So in this case, you
see we log out result1.
And this logical assignment's
way of returning a false value
was taking the very
last available entry
since nothing else was true.
In result2, we put the empty
string first and undefined
last.
You can see result2,
however, becomes undefined
because that was the last
thing, the last resort that it
had to attend to.