So now that we've done kind of
a deep dive on the "OR" logical
assignment, what about "AND"?
What about a double
"AND" logical assignment?
Totally possible.
Let's check it out.
The "AND" operators' going to
find the rightmost "truthy"
value or the very
first "falsy" value.
Sort of the opposite
that the "OR" does.
If you look at this
"AND" logical assignment,
for result1, you'll
see that it takes
"undefined" as an
answer, because as soon
as it has found a faulty
value, it short circuits.
Knowing that there is no need
to check any further values,
because it's already
found something
that's going to cause the
whole compound to be false.
In other words, 42 is
never even examined.
In result2, you can see that
the 0 is the first "falsy"
value obtained, and since now
we can't make a truth value out
of that compound, we're
just going to take that 0
and assign it back to result2.
In result3, we got the
empty string first.
No matter that there's
an object next.
We're just going to take
that empty string, because we
obviously can't
complete the true value.
If we switch it up, we find that
we get the same exact results,
because a compiler is seeking
to find only "truthy" values.
And when it finds that
something is false at any point,
it will assign that false value
right back to the variable.
When all of the
elements are "truthy",
"AND" will return the
very last "truthy"
value found for
assignment, which
is what makes it often very
useful, and very functional,
in code.
So let's take a look at
this first one, here.
On result1, since "King"
is "truthy", and "Arthur"
is "truthy", what the
variable will receive
is actually Arthur.
We've examined the "King",
found that it's cool.
We move over to "Arthur".
It's also cool, let's pass
that back to the variable
Notice if I switch
them up in result2,
and I've got "Arthur"
first and "King" second,
King gets returned after
a full examination.
Just to kind of compare
that with "OR"--
we had this little bit earlier.
You can see that, in
the "OR" situation,
with "King" and
"Arthur", we get King
because it is the
first "truthy" value.
I didn't need to
look at everything,
so I just took the
first one I could get.
In result2, I've take Arthur
for the same exact reason.
What happens when
they're "falsy"?
What happens when both
elements of an "AND" operation
are "falsy"?
You can see in
result1 and result2,
that we've short-circuited
on undefined,
and the empty
string, respectively,
because there's no need to check
for any further truth values
when we've already
found a false.
Let's contrast that
with the "OR" situation,
which needs to look
through all of its entries
before finally
returning a false value,
if that's all that was there.
So inside result1
and result2, we
get the empty
string for result1,
and undefined for result2.
Now where might you use
this "AND" logical operator?
It's very useful in
contingent assignments, where
one thing's got to be true
before this next thing can
happen.
The "AND" operator's
going to let
you check, as well, multiple
conditions before we actually
allow that assignment.
So let's take a look.
Here we're going to add some
functionality to our armory
object.
Namely, it's going to be called
a retrieveSword property, that
will hold a function.
The parameter for that
function will be a request.
That means, which
sword we would like
to get or check
out of the armory.
We've got an interesting
expression, here.
We're going to return the
result of a ternary conditional.
Let's check out how
we're generating
the condition for this
ternary conditional.
What we're doing
here is actually
checking to see, first, whether
the sword's array actually
holds the sword that we want.
So how do we do that?
We use the index of method,
which is a method of the array
prototype that will
examine an entire array
and return the very first found
index for any matching value.
And if it doesn't find anything
throughout the entire array,
it will return a
negative 1, which
may now be very
clear to you why we
use a greater than or equal
to 0 inside of our check.
If the index of method returns
a value that's positive,
that means that our
sword that we want
is somewhere inside of our
big, long swords array, right.
But if we get a
negative one, that
means a sword is
nowhere to be found,
and our ternary conditional
should return the false value.
Just to illustrate the power
of this index of method
for a moment, let's
pass "Claymore"
into the index of method
on the swords array.
What it's going to do is look
through that array over there
in the armory.
You can see that the
"Claymore" exists in index2.
Remember that
arrays are 0-based.
And it will return
that 2, so we know
the Claymore is
exactly in index2.
However, if we go hunting in
the swords list for a doughnut,
that's going to
return negative 1,
because hopefully there is
no donut in the swords array.
(JOKINGLY) Fight with doughnuts!
Now that you can kind of see
how that index of method works,
notice that our check in
our ternary conditional
is looking for a number that
is greater or equal to 0.
That means we want to
verify something actually
exists in the swords array.
If it doesn't, it should
be a negative number.
Now, on the left side of our
ternary conditional colon,
if in fact the sword
does exist, we're
going to use some index
cleverness to remove
the sword from the swords array.
Let's see how we can do that.
We'll use the splice method.
That's going to remove elements
anywhere inside an array
by first passing in the index
that you want to start at,
and following that
with how many items
you want to remove
at that index.
Let's just take a
look, for a second.
If we create a soldiers array--
we got knights, we got pikemn,
we got archers-- and we
splice that array at index1
for 2 units.
Now what does the
splice method do, here?
Well, it's going to go into
index1, which is pikemen.
It's going to take out
two entries, including
pikemen and archers.
And what does the
splice method return?
It returns those values
that it spliced out, inside
of their own brand-new array.
So how can we use this
cool splice method
to help us remove, gently, our
sword from the swords array?
Well, you can see,
inside the splice method,
that we pass in the index
of our requested sword,
using the index of method.
Following that, you
see that 1 right there?
That's saying, go to the index
where the sword is, and just
take out one sword.
That's all we
want, is one sword.
Now since the splice
method returns an array,
but we only want the
string of the sword,
we will need to access the
0-th index of the array that
gets returned that's what that
little bracketed 0 is doing
there.
It's going to return
us the single string
from inside the returned
array of the splice method.
Yay for code.
And then after the colon,
if we never found that sword
originally when we went to check
for it, we need to go ahead
and say, yo, man,
that sword ain't here.
That's going to be
useful when we actually
employ our double
"AND" assignment.
Now let's go ahead and try to
use our retrieve sword method
that we've added to the armory.
We're going to set up a
variable called, is knight here.
We're going to set
it equal to "true".
We only want knights to
be able to get swords out
of the armory.
We don't want serial
killers running around
with weapons from the armory.
That could reflect poorly,
and suck moderately, so let's
not do that.
The next thing we'll do is have
a variable called "weapon",
and we're going to set up
our very cool "AND" logical
assignment.
The very first thing that
that "AND" will check
is whether the person that's
asking for a sword is a knight.
Well, "isKnight"
is currently true,
so "AND" here is going
to keep checking.
And what is it checking on
the other side of the "AND"?
It's a call to a function.
OK, so let's see
what happens here.
If the result of our
retrieve sword function
happens to be a string, well,
a string is "truthy", right?
So we'll get precisely the
sword we're looking for,
because remember
that "AND" returns
the final "truthy" value
that it encounters.
Cool, so let's see
what happens when
we try to get this katana
assigned to the "weapon"
variable.
First, is there even a
Katana in the swords array?
Our index of method goes over
to the swords property, checks
the array, finds a katana,
ding, returns index1.
And since that is
greater than 0,
we get a truth value
in our condition,
and the ternary will
execute the splice method
on the left-hand
side of our colon.
Now let's see what happens when
we try to get the katana out
of the swords array and pass
it into the weapon variable.
So we're going to splice that
swords array exactly at katana,
and that's going to hand
us back another array.
And from that array, we're
going to take the string
at the 0-th index.
This will also remove
the katana from swords.
So now that retrieve
sword has passed back
a string katana,
which is "truthy",
and also "isKnight" has
a "truthy" value-- both
of those things are
"truthy", so we'll
take the last, the right-hand
side of the "AND" logical
statement, and put that
inside the weapon variable.
Check it out.
When we log out that
weapon, we see katana.
Woo hoo.
Cool, so we got the katana out.
What happens if we try to get a
rapier out of the swords array?
Well, we pass "inRapier"
into the function,
and the index of goes
over to the array,
and checks and sees--
wah, wah-- there
is no rapier in the array.
We need to make a purchase
order, I guess, or something.
But it's not there now.
So what's going to happen is,
that condition will be false.
And on the right-hand
side of the colon,
we will choose the alert method.
And once that alert
message is called,
you can see we get
our pop-up box.
But what happens
to retrieve sword?
What happens when the very
last thing it has done
is call an alert method?
Well, it happens to be that
it returns an undefined value.
Since that undefined value
is the very last thing
our "AND" value finds,
and it's "falsy",
it's going to toss that
undefined value over
into weapon.
And weapon will be undefined.
There will be no
weapon inside it.
Now you might ask what happens
when "isKnight" is false.
I mean, we don't want
some random dude coming up
to the armory and
requesting a weapon, right.
So if it's false, turns out
retrieve sword will never even
get called, remember, because
"AND" logical assignment will
take the very first "falsy"
value it ever finds.
So since "isKnight"
is false, that false
is going to get tossed over
into the weapon variable.
If we log out the
weapon variable,
we can see that
this becomes false.
An extra bit here.
Logical assignments are
actually extendable.
You can string together
as many operators
as is necessary to choose
whatever right assignment you
would like to.
So let's get our
stuff down, here,
and you can see that we've
got a new variable called
"armoryIsOpen".
And we're going to set
that equal to true.
Inside of our "AND"
logical assignment,
we're going to add
that "armoryIsOpen"
variable as a new condition.
This is an extended
logical assignment.
So now, if the armory is open,
which it is, and the person is
a knight, which
they currently are,
and if there's a "Claymore"
in the array for the swords,
and that gets returned,
then we'll take that sort
and assign it to
the weapon variable.
That happens here.
So you can see, when we log out
the weapon we get the Claymore.
So what happens when the armory
is closed, it's not open?
Well, we don't want to
be passing swords out
after hours, right.
So the double "AND",
that first double "AND",
will see that
"armoryIsOpen" false.
And that will
instantly get assigned
to the variable weapon
with a short circuit,
not looking at and the
other stuff that's present
in our extended assignment.
You can see that when we
log out the weapon this time
we get false, because
the armory was not open.
Come back when the
shop's open, man.
And you come back
after these challenges.
See you in the next section.
end