Hey, guys.
Welcome back.
I hope you enjoyed
that set of challenges
on logical assignment.
And now we'll be moving
into the switch block.
Let's take a look.
You can think of
the switch block
as a conditional for
multiple possibilities.
JavaScript has an alternate
way of taking action
based on values instead
of just Booleans.
So here we have eight
different regiments.
And each of those
regiments is supposed
to get a different weapon.
Each of the knights
in those regiments
needs to hold on to some
different killing device.
Let's say we had a
knight constructor,
and inside that
knight constructor
we were passed a
name and a regiment
in order to assign that new
knight to a specific regiment
and give them a name.
Then we have this
extra long series
of conditional statements to
check and see what the regiment
value is in order to assign
that knight the correct weapon.
So if we made a new
soldier variable,
and we assigned it a knight
from the constructor,
we would pass in,
let's say Timothy,
and he should be
assigned to regiment 2.
When we logged out
this soldier's weapon,
you can see that we
would get the Claymore.
But in this code, it's
tedious to type all of this
out, where you are
repeatedly using if and else.
And the processor has
to repeatedly check
the regiment value
over and over again.
We can use instead
a cool JavaScript
keyword that will jump directly
to the right action to take.
The switch key
word will allow us
to assign a weapon
based on a value itself,
but without the Boolean check.
First thing you do is
place down the switch
keyword, and then a
set of parentheses
which contain the value
you want to switch upon.
It signals to the compiler to
take some specific action based
on the value here, of regiment.
Now the switch block is going
to contain multiple cases.
And each one of
those cases is going
to be followed by
one of the possible
or desired values of
the switched upon value,
in this case, regiment.
Following that value,
you see a colon.
That separates the case and its
value from the action to take.
We're going to go ahead and
fill in every single case
here for our knight constructor.
You can see each
weapon is associated
with a different regiment value.
So now we feel pretty good
about our switch block, right?
So let's see what
happens when we create
a new soldier2 variable, and
assign to it a new knight
from the constructor.
It's going to be Richard, and
his regiment is going to be 4.
Now let's log out
his weapon, and we
get-- oh, man, a Morning Star.
What happened?
What is wrong with
our switch block?
Something that happens quite
frequently-- let's take a look.
You can see in case 4, Richard
should've got a Mace, right?
But he actually got the Morning
Star, which is in case 8.
Something unique happened
inside of our switch block.
The thing about JavaScript
cases inside of a switch block
is that they allow
fall-through to other cases.
You have to think of the
case keyword and its value
as this label that
identifies the starting point
for execution for the
rest of the block.
Now that fall-through is a
vestige from the very common C
language, around which
JavaScript is loosely based
and has a relationship.
It came about for
two primary reasons,
one people wanted to be able
to execute more than one case
at a time within a single switch
block, as well as the fact
that they wanted to be able to
have multiple case values take
the same action.
So we'll look at all those
useful situations in a bit.
But for right now, let's
take a look at this block
and see what we
can do to fix it.
Now as we said once a case label
has been selected by the switch
block, all of the other
labels that are inside
that switch block are
completely ignored,
because the switch jump on the
value has already occurred.
What that means for Richard, is
when his number 4 gets passed
in right now, the switch
block jumps to case 4
and assigns him
the weapon, Mace.
But then the case 5 label
is completely ignored.
And so he gets
assigned War Hammer.
Then he falls through to case
6, and gets assigned the Battle
Axe, then to 7, gets
the Halberd, then to 8,
and finally, gets
the Morning Star.
So fall-through can
be a little dangerous.
And we need a way to fix it.
And what will fix it?
The break keyword-- the
JavaScript break keyword
provides a very quick exit
from the switch block,
and any block.
Break will allow us to leave
an entire block of code that
contains it.
In this case, we're going
to use for the switch.
So let's space out
our constructor here.
We're going to shift things
around and give ourselves
a little bit more space.
And inside each case, we're
going to place a break keyword.
Now when we try to build our
knight object for Richard
and we pass in his
regiment 4, we're
going to jump all the way down
to case 4, give him a Mace,
and break instantly out
of the switch block,
since that was the only
case that was taken.
When we log out
Richard's weapon,
we get the Mace, as we
expected-- woo, hoo.
Now we want to back up for a
second, because fall-through
gets a bad rap a little
bit out there in the wild.
But it can be very
useful, and we
want to educate you on
the uses of fall-through.
What if multiple
cases, for example,
take exactly the same action?
We can creatively
use fall-through
to make that happen and
tighten up our code,
and make it more legible.
Let's take a look at regiment 7.
What if we didn't want regiment
7 to use the Halberd anymore--
we wanted them to
use the Morning Star?
Well, what we could
do is completely
remove all of the
contents for case 7,
including the break
key word, and stack it,
that case label, on top of
the case label for case 8.
By doing this, we've associated
all of the subsequent actions
with each of those cases.
Now you might ask,
well, what if I
wanted to move one of
those earlier cases
say, a regiment 4, who
currently is the Mace?
What if I wanted to
make a regiment 4
use a Morning Star as well?
Well, JavaScript doesn't
care about your case order.
So you can move around
your numerical cases
and place them
wherever you'd like.
Additionally, you can
stack as many cases
as you'd like on any
particular set of actions.
Fall-through can often be
useful if organized well.
So how does that affect Richard?
Well, if we made our
new knight object
using Richard and his
regiment number 4, now
you can see that he does in
fact get the Morning Star,
because of that
useful fall-through
we placed in our switch block.
Earlier, you may have
been asking yourselves,
what happens when the switch
block gets a value that's
not actually present as a case
inside of the block there?
Well, we have a unique
situation for that.
If a case value doesn't
happen to be there
in the switch block, no
action at all will trigger.
So if suddenly we passed in
Arthur, and he's the King,
well there is no
King regiment, right?
So his weapon at the end
of that object build,
would be undefined.
That's because the
weapon property is never
actually set to a value.
So we can fix that by
adding another case.
Notice here that this case
for the King uses a string.
And that's because a string
is a perfectly acceptable case
label.
In fact, JavaScript
will accept any value
that happens to be
matchable with what's
passed into its parameter.
Now when we call our
new knight constructor,
and it happens to be
Arthur, and he's the King,
we assign that result
to the King variable.
And we log out
the King's weapon.
We get Excalibur,
as we would expect.
What happens if
we've got a knight,
but he gets assigned
some regiment number that
doesn't exist?
Well, he's not going
to get a weapon, right?
And a knight that has no
weapon sure sucks a lot.
So let's see what we
can do about that.
JavaScript offers
this default case
to help us watch for
unavailable values,
and do something specific
when an unavailable
value is encountered.
We label a case with
default. And inside
there what we're going
to do is just alert
the armourer that
this dude we're
trying to make a
knight object for,
has apparently an
incorrect regiment.
And we will not
assign him a weapon,
so that the armourer
can make sure
that we get him into a regiment
where the right regiment
number exists.
So now if we try to
make a new knight
object for this
guy, Jerome, and we
try to pass in regiment
12, which there is none,
the default case is going to
be taken by the switch block.
And the armourer will
get a nice alert that
says, yo man I fixed Jerome.
Because that guy ain't
got a regiment yet.
You may notice on
our default case
that there is no
break statement.
What about that final
break statement?
Well, since no other case
exists after our last one,
there will be no
other executable code
inside of the switch block.
So that last break
statement is optional.
A second usage of
JavaScript fall-through
that must be tightly controlled,
but can still be very useful,
is that of hierarchical
code execution.
If you have a very
carefully organized block,
you can make all of least common
properties be added first,
and all the most common
properties be added last,
through the switch block.
Let's take a look.
Here we have a ceremonial
dagger constructor.
And that ceremonial
dagger is going
to be passed to each knight
upon their knighthood,
depending on their
particular rank.
Here you can see that the length
of the dagger is set to 8,
and the owner is set
to whichever knight
is passed into the constructor.
Now the quality of
the ceremonial dagger
will be built based on
the rank of the knight.
So if you could look at the
bottom of our switch block
here, you can see that we're
giving the lowest level, which
is just a regular knight.
We're giving that
knight 6 rubies
on their ceremonial dagger.
Now the next rank up is going
to be the Captain of a regiment.
Now the Captain of a regiment
should have something special
on their ceremonial dagger.
You can see that our Captain
gets exactly 1 emerald.
Now notice, there's
a fall-through
here, meaning that the
Captain will not only
receive 1 emerald, but since
there is no break statement,
they will also receive all of
the rubies that a knight gets,
because of the hierarchy
we've arranged our code in.
The next highest level
is the Field Marshal.
This guy's going
to get 4 sapphires.
If you're a Field Marshal,
you are sitting pretty.
Not only do you get 4
sapphires, but you also
get the 1 emerald of the captain
and the 6 rubies of the knight.
Above all of the Field Marshals
is the single High Constable.
And this guy gets 2 amethysts
on his ceremonial dagger
in addition to the 4 sapphires
of the Field Marshal,
the 1 emerald of the
captain, and the 6
rubies of the standard knight.
And if you are the King, the
man, the myth, the legend,
King Arthur
yourself, then you're
going to get 1 diamond
exactly in the pommel
of your ceremonial dagger.
Not only will you get
that diamond brooch,
you will get every other gem
assigned to every other level
of military officer.
So now let's make a new
ceremonial dagger for Jerome,
who is just a standard knight.
Now what happens when we
call this constructor?
It's going to jump straight
to the correct case
with no fall-through at
all, before or after.
Thus, all we're going
to get is 6 rubies,
and no other gemstones.
If we log out that
knight's dagger object,
now we can see that the length
is 8, the owner is Jerome,
and he has only 6 rubies.
If I make a ceremonial
dagger for Timothy,
who happens to be
a Field Marshal,
and we assign that to the
variable Marshal's Dagger,
then what happens
is the constructor
gets the 4 sapphires
for the Field Marshal,
the 1 emerald for the
captain, and the 6
rubies for the knight.
And if we were to log
out the Marshal's Dagger,
you can see that we would have
a length of 8, the owner's
Timothy, and we got 4 sapphires,
1 emerald, and 6 rubies.
Fall-through allows that Field
Marshal to acquire the lower
ranked gems.
Last, but certainly
not least, you
can see that if we
made the King's Dagger
for the man, the myth, we will
get a diamond, 2 amethysts, 4
sapphires, 1 emerald, and
6 rubies for his majesty.
Used in careful,
controlled, hierarchy,
fall-through can
be very valuable.
But you have to keep
a close watch on it
to make sure that
the hierarchy stays
stable during the maintenance
period of your code.
That is the end of the
entire Sword of Syntax level.
We hope you enjoy
these challenges.
And we'll see you back
in the next level.
See you soon.
Take 1 billion.
[LAUGHTER]
[BEEPING]
Index 2 of the swords away--
away-- does swords a way?
[BEEPING]
Especially in-- a-- ergh.
Don't put that in there.
[LAUGHS]
That's the first clip.
Yeah.
[LAUGHS]