[SINGING] Find the Sword of Syntax first
for the useful tools
that you may need.
Wear the pendant of performance
for efficiency and speed.
Cautions crystal clears this
sky with triple equals try/catch
cache.
Avoiding stuff that sucks and
parsing badder numbers
out of stretch.
Alas, the golden shining
mail of modularity.
When [INAUDIBLE] your import's
long, defend integrity.
For polished jewels
in Javascript,
the treasure trove this is.
Now raise your sword
and strike your shield
with these best practices.
In this level, we'll be looking
at speed-- how to improve it
and how to measure it.
Many new developers
think that the only way
to improve performance is
through complex algorithms that
manage data more efficiently
on the server side,
or through a generalized
improvement to the bandwidth
of a user's internet connection.
But there are subtle and
often overlooked methods
in the JavaScript
language that you
can begin to
incorporate immediately,
and that on a broader level
will have a noticeable impact
to the speed of your
web applications.
Additionally, often
it's very important,
especially in this
day and age, to test
multiple implementations
that produce the same result
in order to make the
best decision about which
implementation provides the best
user and developer experience.
To that end, we'll examine
ways to illustrate that speed
and time data so that
you can make the best
choice about which
implementation
is best for the task at hand.
And with that, I hope
you enjoy and hold
carefully to the
pendant of performance.
Welcome back.
This is level two of
JavaScript Best Practices.
I'm Jason Millhouse,
and this section
is about loop optimization.
Let's take a look at a
common for-loop scenario
where memory access may
not necessarily be ideal.
The first thing we'll
have here on the right
is a treasure chest object.
Inside that object, we'll
have 10,000 gold coins.
We'll have the crown of
speed as a magical item.
We'll have an
array of necklaces.
And we'll also have a
function called openLid.
Now, if we wanted to log out
all of the necklaces found
in our treasure chest, we
would have a little log here
that says you've found
the following necklaces.
Following that, we
could do a loop.
Now we've set up
our loop parameters
in a normal fashion
where we loop over
the entire length of
the necklaces array
and log out each
one of the necklaces
in that array in turn.
That would produce, you've found
the following necklaces-- ruby,
pearl, sapphire, and diamond.
Now, this is not the best way
to execute loop control because
at the start of each
potential loop cycle,
the program is going to
need to find and retrieve
several things.
First, it will need to
find the value of i.
Then it will need to locate
the treasure chest object,
within which it will need to
find the necklaces property.
After finding the
property, it will
need to reference the array
pointed to by the property,
and then finally, the length
because that's what we need.
So out of all those
steps, which ones
can we actually
eliminate safely?
Because any intermediary
step to finding what we want
is just lengthier,
processor death time, right?
So we want to make sure that
we can get rid of as much steps
as we can.
All we're interested in,
here in the loop control,
is that single length
value and the loop counter.
So we don't really need all
of these other little steps
that we take to find
that length value.
If we use cached
values to curtail
all of that lengthy
repetitive access,
you'll find that your
applications improve in speed.
What we'll do is we'll
scoot our stuff down here.
And we will assign the
length of the necklaces array
to this new variable called x.
This will use all of the
accesses that we had before,
all of those steps, but it's
only going to happen once.
Now, inside of our
loop, we'll use
that x variable as the
controlling parameter.
As a result, the majority of
all of those extraneous steps
have now been eliminated.
Every time you
help your processor
out with some savings, that's
going to mean more speed.
And so let's check out and
see what we've actually
saved on our moderately
simple example.
So now during loop
control, memory access
only needs to retrieve
the value of i
and then retrieve
the value of x.
Then, we do need to add
in our one-time cost
in creating our new x variable.
What does that mean?
That means well, we created
the variable x in memory.
That's a step.
And then there are
also the four steps
that we saw before in
actually retrieving the length
value from the array
inside the object.
Now if you can tolerate
a little math here,
we've got two steps
for every loop.
That means that we're going to
do four executed loops and then
a single check to
stop, so that's
five total starts of
the loop parameter.
So 2 times 5 is 10
steps for the processor
just in memory access.
Then we'll add in
those five extra steps
in the creation of
that extra x variable,
so a total of 15 steps
of strictly memory access
to execute just one loop.
Seems pretty good.
Let's check out the difference.
In our previous version, we took
25 steps to figure that out.
So the difference, of course,
is 10 steps of savings.
Now that may not
seem like a lot,
but let's check out
what happens when
we grow our data considerably.
What if we had 10,000 necklaces?
With large data amounts,
this improvement
is really going to
improve results.
You can see that when we
have five steps times 10,000
executed loops
plus 1 check stop,
we get 50,000
memory access steps.
Oh my god.
But when we have two steps times
10,000 executed loops and 1
check stop, we only have 20,000.
Then we add in our
paltry five extra steps
to create that x variable.
See how that doesn't
matter very much?
And we get 20,007
memory access steps.
Now, what's the
difference there?
30,000 steps of savings.
You can see how you're
assisting the processor
quite a bit by caching values.
So we've saved all
of those steps.
Really cool.
But we can be even
better organized
if we place that control
variable that we've
created inside the
parameters of the loop.
Let's take a look.
First, we'll scoot our
treasure chest down here.
And we'll give ourselves a
little bit more space inside
of our loop parameters.
And surprise!
A comma is going to allow us
to execute multiple statements
within that very first
parameter of our loop.
Now what we can do is scoot our
variable over and bring it down
into the first
parameter of the loop.
A cool thing here
is that we can now
get rid of this var that's
on the outside of the x.
It's now unnecessary
because that comma
is going to tell the compiler
that more variables are
about to be declared,
and maybe even assigned.
By creating both of these
variables in the loop
parameter, we now have
signaled that they're actually
only intended for
use inside this loop.
We've also limited
the processor burden
of declaring multiple variables
with that var keyword.
Now something to
take note here is
that JavaScript doesn't have
any natural garbage collection.
That's right.
If we were to-- check
this out-- log out
the x variable after
our loop, we get a 4.
And that's because JavaScript
does not scope to block.
So any of the variables that
you declare inside your loops,
they're going to be
available after the loop.
Mm-mm.
Weird.
And they may actually
override preexisting globals,
so you have to name your
variables very carefully.
Now you may have noticed
that a good approach to take
when dealing with this kind of
repetitive data access at depth
is to store in a local variable
any property or object or array
item that is used more than
once inside of a function.
So the moral of
this story is, try
to avoid that repetitive,
repetitive, repetitive access
at depth.
And in our current code, we
can even find a new place
to further streamline
this process.
Let's take a look.
See that console log in there
with treasureChest.necklaces?
That's another access of a
property within an object.
And we're going to do that
every single time, looks like,
in the loop, right?
So we want to try to avoid
that repetitive access.
Let's see what we can do.
So we'll make a new variable
and we'll call it list.
And it's going to be
the array of necklaces.
And we'll just assume
that this list variable's
going to get used some
place later in our code
that we don't see yet.
But by creating
that list variable,
we now can use it
inside of our log
without accessing the
treasure chest object.
Now you can see if we drop that
list variable down and scoot it
over, we will be logging out the
ith index of the list variable.
And we've avoided
that extra step
of accessing the
treasure chest each time.
On a broader level,
there are other ways
to optimize the loops
that are inside your code.
And one way is to
make sure that you're
choosing the best kind
of loop for arrays.
If you want to just deal with
each index inside the array,
your best bet is to
stick with for-loops
instead of for/in loops.
Now, to see why the
regular for-loop is
often better for
performance, let's
go ahead and add a few methods
to the array prototype.
Here we go.
Here we have a new
method on the array
prototype called countType.
And you don't really
care what it does
or what the code is
inside this function.
You just need to know
that it would now
be available to all arrays
inside of our program,
including that necklace array
over inside the treasure chest.
We'll scoot that down.
And we'll also add
another prototype method
called removeAll.
You don't care what it does,
but you can check it out
later if you'd like.
Just know that it's
another array method
that we have added to
the array prototype.
So now that we have added a
couple methods to our array
prototype, let's
see what happens
when we change this
existing loop structure that
lists all the
necklaces to one that
uses instead a for/in approach.
You will see in a moment why
this kind of sucks and it's
going to impact the
performance of your code.
So we get rid of all of
our loop parameters here.
And in their place,
we put for p in list.
That means for every
property inside the list.
And that is going to come
in very key in a second.
If we were to now
run this code, and we
would see the results of our
console log, we would see,
you found the
following necklaces--
ruby, pearl, sapphire,
diamond, removeAll, countType.
Well, I don't want
the removeAll necklace
and I also don't want to
wear a countType necklace.
But the reason this
is happening is
because using a property
approach to access indices
is going to result in
adding in all the methods
that have been added
to the array prototype.
So if there's ever any
additional methods on the array
prototype, those are going
to be included inside
of your properties.
Very strange if you
only were concerned
about the indices of
your array, right?
The reason that
is, because methods
that you're going to
add to the prototype--
not the existing methods,
but the ones that you add
to the prototype-- are going
to become innumerable just
like the indices in the array.
Now, the moral of the story
is that you really should only
use a property approach
when you really
want to get to every single
property of that array.
Otherwise, stick with
a for-loop and you
will have exactly the
functionality that you desire.
We're going to give you
a few challenges on loop
optimization, and we'll see
you back in the next section.