Hey, guys.
Welcome back.
This is section two of The
Pendant of Performance.
In this section, we'll be
talking about script execution.
Script placement inside
of your HTML files
very much impacts performance.
So let's take a closer look
at how a browser actually
retrieves and acts
on the scripts
that you place inside your HTML.
When a browser tries
to access a page,
it's first going
to send a request
to the server for the document
contained at whatever URL
you're trying to get to.
The server, of course, is
going to find that document--
hopefully-- and pass
it back to the browser.
Then, the browser begins
to parse the document.
And that's where things
can get a little bit
crazy on the performance side.
The document could need any
variety of important things
that make a website
awesome, such as CSS style
sheets, images-- tons
of images, actually--
and of course, scripts.
Under normal circumstances,
a modern browser's
going to be able to
download up to six
components at the
same time, in what's
called a parallel download.
But when the browser
finds a script
to download in the
page's code, all
that parallel downloading
halts-- that's right,
stops-- until the script
is finished loading.
This can mean super slow load
times for your site, sometimes.
Now, where would we find
such troubling scripts
that have some sort of adverse
impact on our performance?
Any scripts that are high
in the head or the body
tags of your HTML
page can potentially
have a performance
impact, if they are not
absolutely necessary.
And even if they are
Let's take a look at
this website, here.
We've got The Third
Regiment's page.
Right after that
first heading, you
can see that script tag that
looks for sparring.js inside
of The Third Regiment's website.
That seems harmless
enough, right?
We'll just get a
quick download of it,
and then we'll just
get on with our lives.
It'll be great.
But what happens if
that sparring.js file
is processing tons of really
time-consuming, data-intensive
problems.
In order, perhaps, to
make use of a bunch
of data that's on the website.
For example, it could
be building a huge array
of soldiers from
some separate file.
It could be calculating all
of the possible unique groups
for sparring groups of
2, sparring groups of 3,
sparring groups of 4,
out of all the knights.
Whoo, that's forever.
Randomizes the order of
those sparring groups,
if they're having
some sparring day.
Collects groups in pairs, in
order to have larger matches,
for whatever reason.
And more processes, more
processes, more processes.
It goes on forever, right.
And while that script
file is handling
all of those
data-intensive processes,
everything after
that script file,
namely the rest of your HTML
page, is going to stare at you.
It's going to hang,
and it's going
to wait for all of
that to be done.
The result, of course, is
poor load time, and probably,
poor user experience.
So we want to avoid
that, and figure out
some ways that we can avoid it.
Let's check it out.
One great solution
is to relocate
all of those
work-intensive scripts.
Any script that's
not really essential
to the immediate loading and
presentation of your web page
should be moved
as low as possible
in your parsing
of your HTML page,
so that that page can be present
for the user immediately.
Let's check it out.
So what we'll do is, we'll
push up that paragraph
to be right after
the first heading.
And we'll move the
script down right
before the end of
the body tag, which
is a great place for
work-intensive scripts.
Now, most of the
visual information,
all the other components
of the site, that's
going to become
available for the user
to check out while the
data is being processed.
Very valuable.
A second, short solution
for this kind of problem
is to use the HTML5 async
attribute inside of your script
tag, which will allow
the rest of the page
to load before the
script actually runs.
So let's examine that one, too.
We'll push our
paragraph back down,
and we'll move our script
back to its original location.
Now what we're going
to do is, we're
going to add an async
attribute inside that tag.
And that's going to prevent the
script from blocking the page's
load for the rest of the page.
We've got that async
attribute dropped in there,
but even though it's
in the back here,
you can put that async attribute
as an attribute any place
that you want inside
your script tag.
So what's going to happen now?
Well, the browser's going to
parse all of that initial HTML.
And then it's going to
reach the script tag,
and it's going to say, oh,
let's go get that script file.
And then it runs to
get the script file,
but then sees the
async tag and says,
well, we need to load the
script file at the same time
as the rest of the HTML
to be parsed on this page.
This allows the
rest of the document
to get parsed, loaded,
and ready for the user,
while any contents
of the script file
are being processed
in the background.
So async will give us much less
of a processing time delay hit,
and can allow scripts that
need to be high in the page
to avoid hurting initial
load time too much.
Cool.
So that's the end of
this very short section
on script execution.
We're going to hand you
off to some challenges,
and then we'll see you
back in the next section.