Hey, guys.
Welcome back.
This is section three of
"The Pendant of Performance."
This section is called
"Short Performance Tips,"
which means that we're
going to be giving you
a few easy implementation
switches that
will affect your
performance positively.
Let's take a look.
The first thing we
want to give you
is this idea that
inheritance can
help your memory efficiency.
You want to beware of
taking single objects
and loading them
up with repetitive
code that could be sourced
and held somewhere else,
ideally a prototype.
Taking a look here, we've got
the signal fire constructor.
That's right.
We're going to be building
some signal fires.
You can see that it takes
an ID for the signal fire,
as well as a certain
amount of starting
logs that the fire gets.
Additionally, you can see there
are three other methods that
are added in here-- add logs,
light fire, and smoke signal,
which have all sorts of unique
functionality for the signal
fire.
Now, the thing about
those three functions
is that we don't need to
build all of those methods
within every single
signal fire object
because it would use
extra memory to store
that functionality
within every object,
and it would also
take longer to create
when we're calling
the constructor.
So, if we have this
world-spanning signal fire
system with multiple
fire objects,
we'd have to replicate
all of that functionality
within each one of
those signal fire
data structures,
which would suck.
So, let's take a look at a
way we can prove that memory
efficiency using inheritance.
The way that we can avoid all
of that repetitive memory usage
is by using a prototype for
all of our shared stuff.
We want to give
the common methods
that each one of these
objects will share--
we want to give
that to a prototype,
and then just have
all the objects
inherit from the prototype.
Let's check that out.
So, we'll scoot down our
smoke signal function here,
and then we'll scoot over
our add logs and light fire
methods.
Then, we'll get rid
of these equal signs
and replace them with colons.
And then, we'll
wrap the whole deal
in the signal fire prototype.
And now, all of
these methods can
be inherited by every
signal fire object.
So now, if we have fireOne, and
fireTwo, and fireThree created
through new constructions
of signal fires,
you can see they all
start with an ID,
as well as as many starting
logs as they have each.
And then, if we were to
call add logs on each one
of those signal fire objects,
each of those signal fires
would be accessing the
method contained only
in the prototype object
for the signal fire.
Additionally, if fireThree
saw some goblins and needed
to alert their nearest neighbor,
we could send a smoke signal
on goblins, and we would
get G-O-B-L-I-N-S-!
because goblins are serious.
Moral of this short
story-- make sure that you
add all common
functionality to prototypes
so that every single data
structure that's inside
of a class of objects
doesn't contain
that shared
functionality itself.
The next sure performance
tip that we want to give you
is that adding individual
DOM elements to the DOM
is not always your
safest, fastest friend.
We want to make
sure that you know
that each new
addition to the DOM
is going to cause
a document reflow.
Ew, that's terrible and can very
often hinder user experience.
Take a look at this website
over here on the right.
It's a knights of the
week site, apparently.
And we have an unordered
list element there
with an ID of kotwlist.
Later on, there's
a script tag that
calls the kotw.js
file to be loaded.
Let's take a look at that file.
Inside there, we grab that
unordered list element
and assign it to
a variable list,
and then we've got this list
of the knights of the week.
There they are Jenna
Rangespike, Neric Farthing,
and Darkin Stonefield.
Next, we've got a FOR
loop the loops over all
of the knights of the week,
and first, for each element,
creates a list item element
and then adds a text node
with that particular knight's
name to that element,
and then adds the element
itself to the unordered list
element inside the HTML page.
Now, each time that
list is appended,
you're going to access
the DOM, and you're
going to cause an
entire document reflow.
That's not as speedy
as we'd like it to be,
especially if our list
was 4,000 knights assigned
to this regiment for printout.
That would suck, so we don't
really want that to happen.
Let's take a look at a
way to speed that up.
Cool thing about HTML is
the document fragment,
which can be used to
insert a whole bunch
of conjoined additions all at
once, instead of in pieces.
Fragments are like
invisible containers
that hold multiple DOM elements
without actually being a node
itself.
They're very cool.
Let's take a look
how to use them.
So what we're going to do is
we're going to create an extra
variable here called fragment,
and then we're going to use
the .createDocumentFragment
method to assign a new fragment
to that variable.
What that fragment is going to
be is sort of a staging area.
It's going to hold all of our
new LI elements for our page.
Now, on the inside of our loop,
instead of adding our created
element with the knight's
name as a text node
to the actual unordered
list element--
we're not going to
do that anymore.
We're going to now
put that element
inside the fragment
as a staging area.
Now we'll need to add another
line right after our loop that
will finally add the
fragment that contains all
of our elements to the document.
Notice that this is
happening in one fell swoop.
We're only touching the
DOM one time in order
to add all of those elements
to the unordered list.
Now, we're going to give you
a little bit of a side bonus
best practice here.
We want to make sure that you
declare variables as few times
as possible.
That's because every time you
use one of those VAR keywords,
it's going to add an extra
look up for the JavaScript
to parse there, and that can
be avoided with those comma
extensions that we saw in the
first section of this level.
Let's take a look.
All right.
So we've got already VARs
on list kotw and fragment.
And if we take the VARs
off of kotw and fragment,
we can put commas-- comma
behind the list variable,
as well as behind
the kotw variable.
That will show that we're
declaring multiple variables
in a row, just as we did in that
looped optimization segment.
Now, using these commas is
really great for legibility
for when other developers are
looking through your code.
They can see that you've
got a nice list of variables
stacked using commas.
Now, because of that
processor burden,
you want to avoid
declaring IN loops.
You want to try to anticipate
your variable needs so
that you're not
causing the parser
to look that variable keyword
up over and over again, right?
Let's take a look at that.
Here, you can see
our VAR element,
and that variable is
going to be declared
every single time
our loop executes.
That means we're going
to need to look up
what the VAR keyword
means every time we
want to declare that element.
Now, some will argue that
declaring variables right
when they're needed is very
useful because it tightens
the understanding of
your code so that people
can see that you've declared
this variable right where
you have needed it.
But you want to
kind of weigh that
with the trade-off of
the processor burden.
Now, since our script here
is sort of very small,
we're going to go ahead
and declare that element
outside of our loop and then
use the element inside the loop.
So first thing we'll do is
we'll get rid of the VAR
on that element inside
the loop, and then we
will add the element to
the list of the variables
outside the loops.
That's a great trade-off.
Because we've got
such a short script,
we've opted to avoid
processor burden instead
of having the element declared
exactly where it is used.
Now, the goal here
is to make sure
that you anticipate which
variables you'll need ahead
of time so that when
you encounter loop
environments in your code,
you won't need to re-declare
those variables over and over.
The last little
performance tip we
want to give you in this
section is that we should always
make efficient
choices when we're
trying to figure out how to
concatenate a set of strings
that we have.
In building strings, there
are several different methods
that will yield uniquely
different results in terms
of execution speed, so
let's take a look at that.
Here, we've got three new
variables-- knight, action,
and weapon-- each with
a string inside it.
Next, we'll have a
variable called turn,
and what we're going to do
is concatenate all three
of those variables together to
create Jenna Rangespike's turn.
Now here, the standard
concatenation operator
has been optimized in
most browser versions.
That's an ideal
choice if you are
using a small number of
string concatenations.
One more time, the
concatenation operator
will probably be
your best bet if you
have just a small amount
of strings to concatenate.
However, if we had
a variable that
consisted of an array of
multiple hundreds of HTML
elements-- for example,
if we were pooling
HTML elements together
to build a new page--
we may want to loop
over that array
in order to put all of
those elements together.
So here, you can see we've got
a page variable starting out
at the empty string.
And then, we loop over all
of those array elements
forever, concatenating.
And that's going to
get the job done,
but there is another method that
will enjoy a performance boost,
specifically when your strings
are inside of an array.
You always want to decide
what's better before reaching
specifically for that
concatenation operator.
When you are trying to
concatenate the strings that
are inside an array's
content, instead,
use the native join
method on arrays.
That's going to be inherited
from the array prototype.
Here, you can see us use the
join method on the new page
build variable.
And what that's going to do
is concatenate each index
of our new page build
array, and those indices
are going to be
joined by any string
that you pass into
the join method.
Here, you can see we've got
the new line going in there,
so as to put a new line between
each element of our new page
build long string.
When your strings
are in an array,
this method is going to be
extremely faster than using
that concatenation operator
over and over again,
in most of the tests that
we've designed for it.
Also, it's a little bit easier
to read because a developer can
understand exactly what you're
doing, rather than trying
to figure out what your loop
is trying to accomplish.
Now that we have joined all
the elements of our array using
new lines and put that
into our page variable,
if we were to log
that page out now,
you can see that our
HTML page is grouped
very nicely with new
lines in between as one
long string-- super cool.
And that's the end of this
short performance tips section.
We're going to give you
a few challenges so you
can illustrate your learning
with these magical things,
and then we will see you
back in the next section.