Hey guys.
Welcome back.
This is section four of
the pendant of performance.
In this section,
we'll be examining
how to test the
speed of your code.
Very often, it's
very valuable to test
your current implementation with
other potential implementations
in order to see which
provides the best
performance, and therefore,
the best user experience.
So let's build a little code
and then test its speed.
Here we go.
So remember that
Knight constructor
that we used in level one?
Well, we're going
to use that again.
So let's get it
up here and we're
going to move it
down to the side.
We're going to examine a very
simple console method that
will assess the time any code
we build is going to run.
Let's see how it works.
So we've got a variable here
called firstRegimentNewbs.
And that's an array
of all these guys
that are about to
become knights,
but they're newbies--
Grimble, Jark, and Bunder.
And in the very next
variable we have
is the master list of all of
the firstRegimentKnight objects,
in which there are
tons of Knight objects.
Next, we got a loop that
loops over all of the newbies,
creates a new Knight
object with that newbie
and the regiment number, and
pushes the new knight object
to the list of existing knights.
This is the code we're
going to test for time.
We're going to scoot
down our loop here.
And right before our loop,
we're going to put console.time.
Yes, the console.time
method will take any string
and start a timer with it.
You can see here
that we've got time
to add, and then a certain
amount, and then Knights.
So it's going to
say time to add,
three Knights, in this case,
because firstRegimentNewbs
has three Knights in it.
Following the loop, we're
going to use console.timeEnd,
passing in the exact same
string, which is key, in order
to cause the timer
to stop and close up.
If we were to run
this code now--
which we did on our
browser-- we got the time
to add the three Knights
was 0.036 milliseconds.
Not very much time, right?
console.time will automatically
preface the time measurement
that it finds with the
string that you passed in
as a parameter.
And it will follow that
string automatically
with a colon to separate
the numerical portion
from your label.
Just to show that it would take
a little bit longer time if we
added a newbie to the
firstRegimentNewbs array,
we're going to add Ernst
Breadbaker over here
on the back end of that array.
And now when we run this
code, you're going to see that
the time to add four Knights
is now 0.040 milliseconds,
just a little bit worse
in terms of performance.
One thing to notice.
The string was automatically
changed to four Knights instead
of three because we used
a concatenated length
inside of our time and
timeEnd label parameters.
As you can see,
console.time is going
to let us compare
implementations.
And that timing feature's
going to help determine which
code produces the best
experience for either you
or your users.
To demonstrate
console.time's usefulness
in comparing
implementations, we're
going to get rid of
this new guy variable
that we declare each
time in the loop.
Remember that extra declaration
kind of sucks a little bit.
So we're going to
get rid of that guy.
We're going to scoot
over our new Knight
call on the constructor.
Then we're going to push that
down into our push method.
So now firstRegimentNewbs
is pushing directly
on the result of a call to
the Knights constructors
with no intermediate
variable necessary.
Kind of cool.
Let's see what happens.
When we run
console.time, we find
that we get the time
to add four Knights now
is 0.029 milliseconds.
Slightly better than that
0.040 that we got before.
Now, times are going to
vary, of course, by browser,
but ours was just
slightly better
when not using that extra
variable declaration.
If this process was
replicated 10,000,
100,000 times, you can see
that there would be probably
a significant time
difference that
would make it very
useful for your website.
One important and useful
feature of console.time
is that you can have multiple
of them run at the same time.
Since timers are created
and labeled by that string
that you pass into
the parameter,
you can stack a whole
bunch to produce
layers and layers of time data.
So let's take a look at that.
We'll scoot our stuff
out here to give us
a little bit more space.
And now we're going to add
a second regiment of newbs.
Yeah, there they are-- Jenner,
Tar, Cromer, Stim, Vorn,
Rack, Brock, and
Arden are the new guys
for the second regiment.
And they're going to be
added to this variable,
the secondRegimentKnights, which
holds a whole bunch of Knight
objects for the second regiment.
What we're going to
do first is we're
going to start a
brand new timer that's
called Total completion time.
That's going to help us find
out the entire amount of time
for all of the operations
we're about to produce
inside this code.
Both parts of our existing
timer for the first regiment
additions are just
going to stay in place
like we had them before.
Then we're going to
recreate that process,
but this time for just
secondRegimentNewbs instead
of firstRegimentNewbs.
The loop is nearly the same.
The process is the same.
It's just that the labels are
going to be slightly different.
And once those
additions are done,
we're going to stop that
second regiment time.
Finally, at the very end, we'll
just wrap up the master time
with that total completion time
label and a console.timeEnd.
That's going to wrap up the
timing of the entire operation.
When we run all of this code,
we get three different lines.
The first one we get is when the
very first console.timEnd shows
up, which says the time
to add four Knights
was 0.031 milliseconds.
Then later, we will
get the time to add
eight Knights is
0.063 milliseconds.
Finally, we will get
a total completion
time of 0.324 milliseconds.
That seems kind of weird.
What happened?
Because the 0.031 and 0.063
don't add up to the 0.324.
Hm, what's going on?
We got to remember that setting
up those timers, when it's
a layered, will
also take time too.
So the production
of the timer itself
is often included in
layered timing data.
Be aware of that.
Not only will all of those
extra layers of time measurement
create a little bit of overhead
in your master time data,
but even running the same
test over and over again
will not always produce
the same values.
So what we're going to do
here is start at the top
and end at the
bottom and take out
all of those
internal measurements
for the first and
second regiment.
And we're going to run
that test multiple times.
The first time that
we run it, we're
going to get the
total completion
time of 0.069 milliseconds.
But then if we run
it again, you can
see that that time
drops a little bit.
Third time, drops even more.
But then on the
fourth time, we're
going to get more
than the first time.
The point here is that
if we want more accuracy
in our estimate,
we're going to need
to use the average
of multiple tests.
Now, console.time is a
good quick and dirty way
to just figure out how much time
generally your code is taking
just to get kind of
a basic estimate.
But it's not going
to let us have access
to the numerical data that it
returns in a way that would let
us manipulate it mathematically.
So if we want a vastly
improved accuracy in our times,
and therefore our comparisons
of potentially our user
experience, we're going to need
to take a more advanced track.
And that happens in
the next section.
But for now, some
console.time challenges.
And we'll see you
back real soon.