Hey, guys.
Welcome back to the last
section of a level two.
In this section,
we'll be learning
about how to build a generalized
speed class that will average
that times that your
code takes to run.
So, in our last section, we
looked at a quick and dirty way
of finding how long
your code actually
takes to run inside the
console using console.time.
In this section,
we will actually
be averaging multiple
times together
to get a really accurate
assessment of how
your code is performing.
Now, to get accurate average
measurements for your code,
we're going to need to be
able to retrieve and use
actual numerical time data.
This is data that we can
actually manipulate, right?
So, first thing we're
going to do here
is examine the
JavaScript Date object,
which will provide us
with that numerical data.
If we establish a variable
here called rightNow
and we set it equal
to a new Date object,
you can see that if we logged
out that rightNow variable,
we get a whole bunch of
date information back.
You can see it was Monday,
April 10, 2014, when
we called this console.log--
gives you a time value as well
as a time zone.
Now, the new Date
object is immediately
going to capture the
current date and time,
and that's going to be measured
in milliseconds since 12
o'clock AM on January 1, 1970.
Apparently, that's
when they thought
computers should use time.
1970-- that's when time
began for computers.
Now, the cool thing
about numerical date data
is that if we put a unary plus
operator in front of our Date
object variable,
it's going to ask it
for the specific
value in milliseconds.
That means that this
line of console.log
is the same exact thing
as declaring a new Number
object on the date variable.
Now, when we get
that logged out,
we see that we get something
like one trillion milliseconds.
So, there's a few
of those in there.
Now, since we know we already
want an actual number and not
all of that
interesting date data,
we can go ahead and
assign the variable
to be the numerical version
of our new Date object
just by moving that plus over
to be in front of the call
to new Date.
So moving forward, we can
even declare an end time--
a new time-- on
a new Date object
using that same plus
new date syntax.
We're going to get a millisecond
value for that particular time,
and now, you can probably
see what's coming
and how we're going to use this.
We'll declare a new
variable called elapsedTime,
and we set it equal to
endTime minus rightNow.
And what does that give us?
That gives us the
amount of time that
elapsed between when we
first declared our first Date
object and our
final Date object.
Cool.
So now, we know how to generate
Date objects that will hand us
data that we can
manipulate for time,
and that will let us see
how much time has passed
between two events in code.
So now, with that, we can begin
to create our very first speed
test class.
Let's take a look at that.
So, the first thing we'll do
is we'll establish a SpeedTest
constructor function,
and inside the parameters
of that function, we will
have three parameters,
testImplement, and that will
be the specific code that we
want to test for
performance speed.
We're going to encapsulate it
in its own function later on
and pass it in as an expression.
The second parameter
is called testParams,
and that's going to
represent whatever
parameters our
test code actually
needs in order to
work correctly.
This might be an
array of values,
or it might be a single
value that testImplement
will need in order to work.
Finally, the last
parameter is the amount
of repetitions because why?
The higher the repetitions
that we use, the more reliable
our average is
actually going to be.
So now, let's flesh out
what each individual speed
test object will
actually look like.
Here, you can see we've
got testImplement going
in a testImplement
property of a new object.
Same thing for testParams.
But then here, in our
repetitions property
of our speed test
object, we're going
to allow the repetitions
to be optional,
and we're going to use our
logical assignment best
practice to do that.
You can see that if the
speed test constructor gets
past some repetitions,
we're going
to go ahead and take
those repetitions
and assign it to the property.
However, if whatever user
is using the speed test
doesn't pass in any
repetitions, we're
going to go ahead
and just default
that to be 10,000 total
repetitions so that we
get a good, reliable estimate.
And finally, we'll set
up an average property
and assign it to zero at first,
before we have calculated it.
All right.
So that's our SpeedTest
constructor function.
What we're going to
do is size that down.
Scoot it over here.
And now, we need a method
inside of our speed test object,
but we're not going to add that
to the constructor function
because we want every
single speed test object
to have this method
or access to it.
So, we are going to give that
to the speed test prototype.
We're going to use our
best practice of adding
very commonly used
methods to the prototype.
So here we go-- building
the speed test prototype.
You can see on the inside here,
we've got an inherited method
called startTest,
and we're going
to use that to begin to start
the process of calculating
an average speed for some
sort of test implementation.
First thing we're going to
do inside our start test
inherited method is
establish these variables.
The first two will be our
actual, numerical Date objects.
They will start our
clock and stop our clock.
Notice also that we have
declared those variables
using a comma separation
instead of using multiple var
keyword look-ups.
Yeah, that's our best practice.
That last variable,
sumTimes, is going
to be the variable that sums
up all of the times for all
of the repetitions that we do.
Next, we'll loop
over the full amount
of requested repetitions.
Notice that we have used our
best practice of no repetitive
property access at depth.
We have cached that
value, and we'll
use that value in
our loop parameters.
Here's where we actually
use our beginTime variable.
Notice what we do.
We establish a new
Date object, but we
want the numerical version
of it so we can do math
on that numerical
data, so we put
that plus unary operator in the
front of our new Date object.
Next, this is where
we run the actual code
for this particular
repetition inside of the loop.
Notice that we
pass the testParams
into the testImplement function.
Then, of course, we need another
numerical Date object in order
to stop the clock.
Finally, we'll do
endTime minus beginTime,
which will, of course, give
us the differential in terms
of time.
It will tell us
the elapsed time.
And we'll add that into
the sum of all times
for all repetitions.
And, of course,
taking the average
is just going to be the sum
of all the times divided
by the amount of
repetitions that we used.
Finally, we'll return a message
that says the average execution
across however
many repetitions we
used was this amount of time.
Cool.
So let's test an implementation
using our new speed test class.
The first thing
we're going to do,
though, is we're going to build
some code that lacks some best
practices and then
test that speed.
Let's see what happens.
We'll scoot our
prototype down over here,
underneath our
constructor, and then we'll
give ourselves some
data to start off with.
You can see we've got our
variable, FirstRegimentNewbs.
That's an array list
of four guys that
are new to the first
regiment and need
to be added to the list
of first regiment knights.
You can see there,
the next variable
is the
FirstRegimentKnights list,
which has tons of knight
objects inside it.
And here comes the
code we want to test.
We want to loop over all of
the existing newbies, right?
And notice, no
best practice here.
We're just going to use
that repetitive access
at depth that kind of sucks.
We're going to do that
and see what happens.
Additionally, inside
the loop, we're
going to establish a new
variable every single time,
and that's going to be a
new Knight object using
the name inside the
newb list and whichever
regiment he needs to be
assigned to, which, of course,
each time here is
the first regiment.
Following that, once we've got
a new knight inside our new guy
object, we're going to push
that to the FirstRegimentKnights
list.
That's our simple
method for adding
all of the new guys as
brand new knight objects
to the knight list.
Now, in order to
test this block,
we've got to be able
to pass all of it--
the whole block-- into
the SpeedTest constructor
as its own function, right?
We're going to create an
entirely new SpeedTest
object from the constructor
and make that a new object in
[? NoBPTest, ?] but we need
our code to be its own function
expression so that
we can pass it
in to the SpeedTest constructor.
So we'll scoot our
FOR loop down here.
We will make a new
variable called NoBP
and wrap it in an anonymous
function, its own little module
here, and we're going
to assign that function
expression to a variable.
Now, once that code is inside
that anonymous function,
we can very easily
pass it around
to whatever other function
we would like to pass it to.
So you can see inside
of the SpeedTest call,
we've now got NoBP
as the implementation
that we want to test for speed.
Now, since our
SpeedTest constructor
lumps all of our test
code's important parameters
into one testParams
property, we need
to modify our function
in order to be
able to use just one
array of important stuff.
So, we've got here inside
of our anonymous function
a parameter called the list
of params, just one parameter
array.
We'll scoot our stuff
down here, and we
will make that
parameter array become
the lists for the tests--
lists for test variable.
And inside that array,
we've got both of the arrays
that our testable code will
need in order to operate.
Now, that list, that
array of arrays,
is going to be passed in to
our SpeedTest constructor
to be all of the parameters we
need for our testable function.
But we now need to modify all
of our internal variable names
in our function to match that
parameter name we created
that's just one array,
so let's check that out.
Well, FirstRegimentNewbs is the
first index of our parameter
array, so that's going
to become list of params
on the zeroth index
for both of the times
that we access the
FirstRegimentNewbs data.
Scoot that over.
And now, of course,
the first index
of our new, single
parameter array
is going to be the
FirstRegimentKnights array,
and we'll scoot that over.
Bring our SpeedTest up here,
and we're ready to roll.
Let's see what
happens when we test
the speed of our prepared,
albeit terrible, code sample.
Oh, and one thing to note
here-- in creating our SpeedTest
object, we opt to not pass
in any repetitions amount.
So therefore, in our
logical assignment,
in the construction, we're
going to actually get 10,000
from our logical
assignment operator.
Cool.
So we'll have to start the test
by calling the startTest method
on our new SpeedTest object.
We get average execution
across 10,000 repetitions.
It's 0.0041.
Not terrible, but
we can do better.
Notice, however, that we
have about 10 times the speed
improvement already
over the estimations
from console.time, a little
bit of an indicator about how
much time it really takes to
establish a console.time timer.
Now, what happens
if we actually want
to specify how many
repetitions we're going to use?
We want to be a little
bit more accurate,
so we're going to pass
in 100,000 repetitions.
We get the average
execution is now 0.00478,
and our newer estimate
actually brings
us ever closer to the truth.
We can rely a little bit
more on that estimate.
Cool.
Now, here's where the money is.
Let's go back and refactor
our code a little bit
and put some best
practices in there,
and see how much
our speed improves.
First thing we'll do is
we'll cache that loop control
variable, so we'll scoot
our i plus plus over here.
And now we're going to establish
that new x variable, where
we cache the length of
the newbs array, which
happens to be in
list of params zero.
We'll loop over
that new variable.
Next thing we're
going to do is get rid
of that internal
variable declaration.
Not only are we not going
to declare that variable,
but we're going to get rid of
the interim storage entirely.
We're just going to create
the new Knight object
and instantly push that
into our new nice array--
magical and efficient.
Now, we probably need to change
the names of our test function
and our SpeedTest object
because it no longer
has no best practices.
Now, it has some best practices.
So, we'll call it BP and BPTest.
And now, when we actually
call our startTest
on our BPTest object
on 100,000 repetitions,
we get 0.00274, which is a
significantly better execution,
especially if this process
were replicated a few gazillion
times up in a program.
Now, the important thing
about a simple class like this
is it's very reusable
for any particular code
that you want to test
so long as you group
the parameters for your testable
code into an organized list
so they can be passed
into the function
that you put your
testable code inside.
And that is the end of
our performance level.
We're going to give
you a few challenges
to test your knowledge with
your new SpeedTest class,
and we'll see you back
in the next level.
See you soon.
Protheth-eth-eth.
Pro-theth.
Not suck this time.
Suck less.
Some people-- winter's coming.
Suck is coming.
[LAUGHTER]
end