[SINGING] Final Sword of Syntax
force for the useful tools
that you may need.
Wear the Pendant of Performance
for efficiency and speed.
Cautions Crystal clears the sky
with triple-equals and try/catch.
avoiding stuff that
sucks and parsing
badder numbers out of stretch.
I lost the golden shining
Mail of Modularity.
When namespace closure imports
long, defend integrity.
For polished skills
and JavaScript
the treasure trove this is.
Now raise your sword
and strike your shield
with these best practices.
No best practices
course would be
complete without a
section that warns you
of the dangers that lurk
within the seemingly
harmless aspects of a language.
So in this level,
we'll first examine
how to craft the most careful
comparisons between our data
values so that we get the
results that we expect,
as well as how to provide
our programs with the most
effective response to the
errors that can and will
rear their ugly heads.
Next, we'll look at some
badly misused methods
within JavaScript, as well as
some alternate methods for how
to avoid the negative
consequences of that misuse.
Lastly, we'll turn to numbers,
within which JavaScript
sometimes has some
unexpected results.
And we'll outline ways
to improve our experience
with that numerical data.
So if you're ready,
it's time to look
within the Crystal of Caution.
Hey, guys.
Welcome back to
JavaScript Best Practices.
This is level three--
the Crystal of Caution.
In this section,
we'll be examining
how to make careful comparisons.
Now, you might be aware,
but not all equality quality
comparisons are equal.
The triple equals
comparator in particular
is going to compare both
type and contents for us.
So take a look at
these two comparisons.
In this first comparison,
we've got the string four
being compared against 4, the
number 4, with a double-equals.
And that returns a true,
which is kind of weird.
Double-equals tries to help
us out with some type cores.
Any it thinks you want to
know whether four is 4.
But that's not always
the help we want.
Over here on the
other comparison,
we've got the string four being
compared with triple-equals
against 4, and we
get false, which
is exactly what we wanted if we
wanted to know whether we have
both similar type,
as well as contents.
Looking at a few
more of those, you
can see the true and
false comparisons
with double- and
triple-equals here.
And double-equals
thinks true and false
are both 1 and 0, whereas
triple-equals does not.
That's because by historical
convention within computer
science fields, true and
false have traditionally
represented 1 and
0 respectively.
Triple-equals, however,
it doesn't care.
It first sees a Boolean
and then a number
and it says, yo, those
things ain't the same, sorry.
If you want to see
something really weird
about type coercion,
check out the string
that only has escaped
characters in it.
Well, the JavaScript
interpreter thinks
that you want to know
whether that string that
has really no contents
in it is equal to 0,
and so that's going to return a
true, which is slightly weird.
So the triple-equals
in that case
would help us out and return
that those two things are not
at all the same.
The important thing here
is that triple-equals
seeks a very "strict" equality,
ensures comparison reliability
in all of these environments
where the data types that you
get back or receive from
places may be unknown, right?
It's very helpful.
Let's say we had a website
with some fields in it.
It was a new
registration website
for knights that are about
to become nights, but have
to complete a certain
amount of requirements
in order to become a knight.
Take a look at this function
called count entries,
it's going to take in
an array of responses
from those fields
called knight responses.
It's also going to take in a
value that we're looking for.
We're trying to count
with count entries
how many of the responses
are the value in question.
Inside, we establish
a count variable
and we also cache the length
of our knight responses away,
and then we loop over that
array to count exactly how
many responses are the
value that we seek.
Finally, we return
the count variable.
Cool, so our knights need to
have all these knightly tasks
completed in order to be able to
participate in their induction
in order to be
inducted as a knight.
So I'll fill in my stuff here.
And I am Jason Millhouse.
And my regiment is 1
and my squad is 12.
And I have a squire--
my squire has already
been assigned to me.
And I also have a weapon issue.
However, I have not completed
my captain's interview yet.
So as these fields
gets submitted
through the behavior
of the website,
we're going to get
an array compiled
that has all of my
responses in it.
We've got Jason
Millhouse as the name.
1 as my regiment, 12 as my
squad, and true, true, false
for the yes/no answers.
Now, if I wanted to know
how many completed tasks
I had actually performed, then
I could call count entries
on my fields' responses and
tell the count entries function
that I wanted to know how
many of my completed tasks
were true.
Then if I were to log out,
my non-completed tasks I get?
Three?
Well, that's not right.
I've got two yeses and one no.
It shouldn't be 3.
So what happened?
You probably can tell.
Over here in our function, we've
got a double-equals comparison
of a knight responses
entry with a value.
But guess what happens
as a result of that?
When I get to that number
1 for my regiment value,
my count variable is
going to be incremented,
because the double-equals
type course is
my 1 to be a true value.
And when that actually gets
compared, it returns true.
So let's go ahead and
fix that situation.
If we throw out
the double-equals,
insert a triple-equals,
now we get
exactly what we're looking for.
A 2 comes back from
our console log.
That's because the string
"1" is not, in fact,
the same thing as
the Boolean true,
and we get a false
through that comparison.
The moral of this
story, my friends,
is that you should
always be very careful
when you are checking
in your comparisons
and that very often the triple
equals comparator is the best
practice in most unknown data
type environments and even
in known data type environments.
The next comparison
we want to check out
is what happens when we need
to verify an object's class?
What if we want to
execute operations
only if an object has
been built by some kind
of specific constructor, right?
Or whether it has a
specific prototype.
Let's take a look at that.
Let's say, we had two
types of armor here.
We got leather armor
and we got chain mail.
Leather armor's got
body style, num buckles,
num [? spalders. ?] Chain
mail's got what type of metal
is, the link diameter,
whether it's got a hood on it,
how long the skirt is.
Now, where are all
of the objects that
come from these constructors?
Well, they're in a
variable called armor
list, which is a mixed
up list of the kingdom's
armories available
armor objects.
And underneath that,
we've got our newbs array,
which is a list of
knight's objects.
And these guys ostensibly
need some armor
in order to be a knight.
But, well, knights only
get chain mail, right?
So how can we find which
armor objects actually
are chain mail
using comparisons?
Well, if we just loop over
the entire armory's list,
passing out armor to
knight's nilly-willy,
some might end up
with leather armor,
or even worse, what
if they ended up
with a helmet for
their body armor?
That would be really
challenging and problematic.
So enter the
instanceof operator.
It's going to help
you precisely identify
your objects in all cases.
You want to use this operator
to ensure that you're examining
precisely which object
your code should expect.
So let's build a function here
called assign knight's armor.
And we're going to pass
in a list of nights
and we're going to also pass in
the list of all the armor that
is available.
We're going to go ahead
and cache our array links
for efficiency ahead of time.
You can see we've got x
getting knights.length and a y
getting armoravail.length.
Now we'll loop over every
knight that needs some armor.
We've got a nested loop here.
And for you one
of those knights,
we'll then check
through the armor array
to find some chain mail.
Inside that loop,
we're going to check
if the armoravail on a bracket
j for whichever loop index we've
arrived at is an
instance of a chain mail,
if it's an instance of
the chain mail object.
Then we will assign a new armor
property to whichever knight
we're looking at.
Notice the i-th index there,
which signals the outer loop
or which knight
we're looking at.
Then we will splice that armor
right out of the armor list.
And we will return an
object from the array
that gets returned from splice.
And then we will pass that
chain mail object straight
into the armor property
of whichever knight
we're looking at.
Notice that the i-th
index signals which
knight we're looking at.
Now, since we've taken an
object out of our armor area,
we need to go ahead and
modify our cached link
so that every time we get to
that innermost nested loop we
don't go out of bounds
on our array of armor.
And since the current
knight has some armor now,
we can go ahead and break out
of the innermost for-loop.
Cool, we got a function time
to give some of these newbies
some chain mail, man.
So let's fill the list with
a little short example.
And we'll check out the results
of our armor identification
process.
So let's build a couple sample
arrays for our instance of test
here.
We're going to have
our armor list.
It's going to have a leather
armor, a chain mail, a leather
armor, and another chain mail.
And then we have a
newbs array, which
got two new knights in it.
Cool.
Now we will begin our assignment
knight's armor function.
We will pass in our newbs array,
as well as our armor list.
So the first thing that happens
is for that first knight,
we look for the very first armor
object in his leather armor.
So what happens, when
we get to if armor avail
instance of chain mail, that's
going to return a false.
And so we will skip
that object entirely.
And the loop will move
to the very next object,
which is a chain mail.
And that's exactly what
we want for our knight.
And so that chain
mail gets assigned
to our very first knight object.
You can see now that the chain
mail pieces out of that array.
So the next thing that happens
is we break out of our loop,
so that we can move
towards the next knight,
because our first night
already has his armor.
And then we look again
throughout the armor list
to find a new chain
mail for our new knight.
Well, the first thing we
get to is a leather armor.
That's no good.
Then we get to a
leather armor again.
And that's because the
previous chain mail has already
been given to the first knight.
Finally, we get to chain mail.
And that means that
our armoravail instance
of chain mail will
now return true.
And so that knight
gets a chain mail.
And we are good to go.
That chain mail gets
deleted from the array.
And if we were to log
out our new armor list,
we can see we've only got two
leather armors in there now.
No more chain mail objects.
Thank you very much instanceof.
Cool other thing.
If we were to log
out, let's say,
our first night,
which would be newbs0,
we'd probably see a
bunch of other properties
inside that object and also
in armor property with a chain
mail object.
Cool thing about
instanceof as well
is that you can check the entire
inheritance chain with it.
An object happens to be an
instance of all the prototypes
from which it
inherits properties,
which is very useful.
If you need to make
sure an object actually
has access to
properties before trying
to call those properties, as
it happens very frequently.
So if we built a
armor constructor,
and it had a
location, and we just
give it a location property.
And we also built
an armor prototype,
that had, apparently,
the put-on function.
So that any armor anywhere
could call the put-on method.
Now, we've got a
prototype for our armor
and a constructor for it.
And then we build
prototype objects
for the leather armor and
chain mail constructors.
And these new prototypes have
as their prototype the armor
prototype.
We do that using the
object.create method, which,
as you may know, takes
in a prototype upon which
to base the newly created object
that comes back from the call
to object dot create.
This makes the armor
prototype the parent prototype
for both leather armor and chain
mail, which makes sense, right?
And then over, if we had
a King's mail variable
and we assigned to it a
new chain mail object--
and we're going to pass in gold,
because the King's mail should,
of course be gold.
He's got a 2-inch link
diameter, as well as
a hood on that chain mail and.
His screw length is 36
inches for full protection.
This particular
usage of instanceof
can be very useful if you have
to make sure an object actually
has access to some properties
before you try to call them.
Then if we were to log out,
whether the King's mail is
an instance of
armor, we get true.
And that's because every chain
mail everywhere will always
be a child of the
armor.prototype.
So now that you have a
little bit of experience
with some comparison
best practices,
we will send you over
to the challenges
and see you back real soon.