Welcome back, friends
at home, to level three,
The Crystal of Caution.
In this section we'll be
examining exception handling.
Well, what is an exception?
Exception is a run-time error.
And we need to distinguish
a run-time error
from a syntax error.
So let's take a look at that.
Here on the left we've
got some broken JavaScript
in our alarm.js file.
You can see we've got an
alarm declared nicely,
with a nice string and
a semicolon, we're good.
But then we got
this alert that's
missing a right parentheses.
This sort of syntax
error will not even
make it past the
interpreter for the console.
It will be marked as
invalid JavaScript
and we'll get a
little report back
in the console to
tell us that we
did something sort of screwy.
Over here though,
in alarm2.js we
have an alert call
on an alarm variable
with the closed up
parentheses and a semicolon,
we're all good there.
The interpreter
is going to think
this is completely
acceptable JavaScript.
But then it's going
to run and find
that alarm has had no
declaration by the time
that that alert is reached.
That is a run-time error.
And it's the sort we
want to catch in our code
and then control
once we have it.
So we're going to scoot our
run-time error over here.
And we need to start thinking
about what we can do about it.
Well, we want to be thoughtful
at all times about controlling
program flow after
run-time errors occur.
And like other
languages, JavaScript
has a very unique mechanism
for being able to find, catch,
and recover from those
errors as they occur.
To start looking for
errors in our code,
the first thing we'll
uses a try block.
What's a try block?
It's like a test
zone for your code.
It's like a stage that you can
start running your code on,
and it gets examined.
And if errors come back
then we can catch those
and do something about them.
And if all goes smoothly
here, inside of our try block,
and the global alarm variable
happens to exist when it runs,
then we're good to go.
If something goes wrong
in that try block,
however, the try block
will throw an error message
containing details over to it's
a very close buddy, the catch
block.
You see, the catch block
has an error parameter.
And as a parameter object
within the catch block
that error can be used
in any sort of messaging,
or even in conditions to
take specific actions.
What does this allow us
to do as programmers?
It allows us to have broken
code exit more gracefully,
or take better action in
the event of some error.
Here you can see that
if alarm did not exist,
then we'll get a pop
up that says, uh oh.
And then it reveals that
there was a reference error
because alarm is not defined.
The cool thing about
errors is that there
are multiple types
of errors which
can allow us to take very
specific, informed action based
on which type of error occurs.
You want to use Javascript's
multiple error types in order
to handle errors as
gracefully as possible.
Let's take a look at using
some different error types
by scooting down our code here.
And inside of our
try block, now, we're
going to establish a new
Hall of Fame variable.
And inside there are going
to be two new guys who
are going to be added to
the Knights Hall of Fame.
We've got Dask Frostring
and Render Tallborn.
Now let's say we wanted to add
those new Hall of Fame guys
to an existing list
of Hall of Fame guys.
Well we would use the concat
method, which would just
put this array onto
an existing array.
Well, we hope that that
array exists, right?
What error types might we expect
if this was our JavaScript
file?
Let's take a look.
So let's say, for some reason,
that list had not actually
ever been defined yet.
Or that the master
Hall of Fame had
been redefined as something
else in some other file.
And if that's the case,
when we try to access list
to call a concat
property on it, we're
going to get a reference error.
Additionally, if the list is
not even an array or string,
because maybe it had been
overridden by something, whomp
whomp, then there won't
be a concat method
to actually call on the list.
And so we will get a
different kind of error
called a type error.
So say one of those
errors actually occurred.
Well we need to plan for
inside of our catch block,
which will get the
error after the try
block has thrown
the error to it.
So if the error that
got thrown happens
to be an instance
of a reference error
then we'll alert a message
that says, first the error.
And then we'll say the
Hall of Fame roster
does not exist as list.
Check for a relocation
in the master document.
That's giving us important
information about what to do.
It's giving us action
to take, directing us
as a developer, if
an error happens.
But if the error happens
to be a type error,
right, then we'll
alert that error again.
And this time we'll put a
more informative message
for the type error, which
says, alas, the Halls list
has no concat method.
So please check for a
disastrous overwrite.
Since we know it's a type error,
we know we probably don't got
a concat there, which means
that our list is very likely
overwritten.
So let's take a look at what
happens in the first case, when
we would try to get
a reference error.
Well, we wouldn't try to
get a reference error,
but say it happened.
We would redefine our list
variable as being Hall.
Let's say somewhere,
globally, our list variable
got redefined to be Hall.
Woop, there's all of our
Hall of Fame existing
inside of our Hall variable.
Well, when that happens we
go to call list-- not there.
We get a reference error.
And we get our pop up back that
says the Hall of Fame roster
does not exist as list.
Please check for a relocation
in the master document.
So that's the first
kind, which is cool.
We caught that error and
we exited gracefully.
Next, what happens if
list is still there,
but now it's a stupid number?
It's 12.
There are 12, list
is 12, 12 is list.
Well, when we get through that
catch we'll get a type error.
And we'll get the exact
right pop up message back,
object 12 has no method concat.
Well yes, no, it
certainly doesn't.
Alas, the Halls list
has no concat method,
check for a
disastrous overwrite.
This particular
error message sort of
directs us exactly
where to take action
so that we're not left fumbling
in the dark about where
to start debugging.
Now we kind of hinted
earlier at something
that might happen here.
What happens if list got
rewritten to be a string?
This code would run
just fine because list
as a string definitely has
a concat method to call.
The code would run
just fine, and it
would avoid the catch block.
But likely, it wouldn't
do it as expected.
So let's check out what
happens in that case.
Down here we have three guys
inside the Hall of Fame list
that is now a
string, notice it's
been formatted with some
new line characters.
And what we're trying to do
that now with the concat method
is to put an array on the
back end of that string.
Let's see what happens.
Well the elements of the
array get separated by comma,
and get instantly added to the
string, no space, no new line,
nothing.
Just some weird-y
addition of two guys
to the back end of
our list string, yuck.
So we probably need to do
something about that in order
to make sure that we
don't have a string,
and in fact that
we have an array.
Here we go.
The thing you want
to take note of,
as a result of that
string possibility,
is that JavaScript will not
pinpoint every single error
that could ever happen,
right, inside your code.
Instead, you want
to use conditionals
and the throw keyword in order
to craft the right exception
scenario based on what you
think your code should do,
which means you need to have a
real intuitive knowledge of all
the places that
errors might occur
in your environment of data.
To illustrate how to use these
throw keywords, let's go ahead
and scoot our catch block down
here, and reformat our try
block to really pinpoint
errors on a better basis.
The first conditional
we've got here
is just our standard, if the
list happens to be undefined,
then we'll go ahead and
throw a new reference error.
That means the
list doesn't exist
but we're trying to
concatenate on it later.
So instead, we
throw a reference,
error as we did before.
That's just the same
thing that the try block
did in our first instance.
Next we've got
another conditional
that first checks to see if the
list is an instance of array.
And if that's not true,
meaning if it is false,
then we will throw a new type
error to the catch block.
Now it's important to note
that as soon as the try
block reaches any throw
keyword, anywhere,
it will instantly
stop what it's doing,
take that error that it
found, or that it's supposed
to be throwing, and throw
it to the catch block.
And then the catch block will
retain control of execution
throughout the rest
of the process.
Something else we
should do here,
now we've got our errors a
little bit more pinpointed
and correct.
We should modify this
final error message down
at the bottom, where it
says, alas, the Halls
list has no concat method.
We should modify that.
Let's try to make
that more accurate.
Since we got a more clearly
defined problem up here,
our program should be able to
provide more accurate debugging
information for all cases
that we could expect.
So now, if our Hall of Fame
list was in fact a string,
for whatever reason, then we
would get an error message that
says, alas, list exists,
but, you know what?
It's no longer an array.
So please go and check
to see in your debugging
if somehow it got
overwritten somewhere.
It's important to note that
it is our more clearly defined
problem that has
allowed us to have
more accurate debugging
instruction for all
of the cases that we
could conceivably expect,
in this case.
So now, if we had a list
that was a string instead
of an array, we would get
the error message exactly
like we want it.
And now, as we went back to
correct our program somewhere
in our JavaScript
files, we would
go to make sure that our
list had not become suddenly
a string, or modify
this code to match
the fact that is a string.
A cool extra thing about
the try/catch block
is that it has a secret friend
called the finally block, which
will allow us to take action
regardless of any error that
may have occurred
inside the try block.
If the try block
executes smoothly
we'll go to the finally block.
If the try block does
not execute smoothly
and we go to catch block,
after the catch block
we'll go to finally block.
The finally block
just says, we're
going to do whatever
is inside this block,
regardless of what
happened before.
So here you can see
our finally block,
which has got a console.log
on the list in it.
And that's going to
execute whether try
meets with success or failure.
This is important because now
we will know what list contained
at the end of this execution.
It may have been that we
get all of the new guys
added to the list, no problem.
And this log will log
out every last member
of the Hall of Fame.
Or we could get undefined
if there is an error.
Or we could get a string
if it was a string.
Or we could get that
crazy number 12.
But the point is that
we are able to see
what happened to the list
variable, if anything.
What if we wanted to
try more than one option
within our try/catch system?
Well, nested try blocks,
which are totally allowable,
can be found within
outer catch blocks
so that if your first
choice doesn't work,
you may be able to
try something else
before you just gracefully
exit on some error.
Let's take a look at that.
So we're going to build a
new function here called
change inner HTML by ID or
existing, which is the longest
function name known to man.
And with that function
what we're going to do
is look up some text element
either by its current ID,
or by its existing inner HTML.
And then we will
update the inner HTML.
Now here our existing parameter
is going to be optional.
That's going to be just an
extra search possibility in case
the ID for the element we're
looking for is not found.
So now we've got our
try block here, inside.
And in that we have a
variable called new element.
And we're going to set
that equal to undefined.
We're going to use that later if
we need to make a new element.
Following that,
we're going to try
to set the inner
HTML of the element
that we find with the ID
to whatever the update is.
In other words, if
the element is found,
we'll just update
its inner HTML.
Now for the errors.
What happens if we catch
an error from this?
Well the first thing we want
to do is not exit the program
or return a message or anything.
We want to try something else.
So we've got a try block
that happens immediately
after some error in our first
try block has been caught.
In this case, we may know
the existing inner HTML
instead of the nodes ID.
And it may have been passed
in as an optional parameter.
So we want to try
searching based
on the existing inner HTML.
First thing we're going to do
inside of our nested try block
is we're going to get every last
element of the document using
that star inside, get
element by tag name.
We'll pass all those
to an elements array.
And then we'll search
each of those elements
for a matching inner HTML.
And if we find a match
we'll change it and exit.
Another cool thing we'll do is
that since we don't have the ID
variable, right, we
couldn't find it,
then what we're going
to do is record whatever
ID is at that text
element inside our ID
variable for later use.
But inside of our
loop, if we ever
reach the end of that list,
then the element location
has failed, and we
need to do something.
And what we'll do is we will
throw a new custom error.
That's right.
In addition to all of those
native JavaScript error types,
we can create custom errors
with all these custom message
properties.
And we're going to use that
custom message property
inside of our nested
catch, which is upcoming.
Now in our new
nested to catch block
you can see that our error
parameter is called error2.
That's because we
want to distinguish it
from the previous error.
We need to give those two
parameters, those two errors,
different names for
use in their blocks.
What we'll do is we'll alert the
message associated with error2.
And we'll also tell the user
that we are creating a new text
node.
That's because if no element
was found with our existing
inner HTML, or the
ID in this case,
then what we're going to do is
we're going to make a new text
node for used somewhere
outside the function.
And we're eventually going
to return that value.
Lastly, we will get
to a finally block.
And remember, the
finally block's
going to execute regardless
of what happens in the try
and catch nested blocks.
Here you can see in
our finally block
that we check to see if the new
element is no longer undefined.
And if it's no longer
undefined, what do we know?
We know that we
made a text node.
But if that new
element was undefined,
it means we did not create a
new text node because it already
existed, the one we
were looking for.
So what we do is we
log out a notification
that the requested
element was updated.
And what we'll do is we'll use
either the ID, if it exists,
or the existing HTML that
we found the element with.
Notice our cool best practice
of using default assignment
to the existing if the
ID was never found.
So let's say in some
website we called
change inner HTML
by ID or existing.
And we called it
with an ID of age.
And let's say that that
age ID did, in fact, exist.
We also passed in
and update, meaning
we want the new inner
HTML to be age is 35,
and the old one,
which was age is 34.
What will happen in this case
if age did in fact exist?
First thing the
function would do
is go to its first try block.
And it would find the
element, no problem,
and set the updated inner
HTML to be age is 35.
And we get that logged out.
But what happens if
age does not exist?
Well, the first
thing that happens
is we go to the try block.
And it doesn't work
out because it never
finds the element
with that exact ID.
So it'll throw an error.
And it goes to the
next catch block.
Inside that catch block we
first go to a nested try.
So it searches through all
of the existing elements
but does, in fact,
find an element
that has an existing
HTML of age 34.
So what happens?
We get a check and we roll
all the way to the finally,
because we break out
of the loop and don't
need to go to the next
nested catch block.
Once we're in the
finally block we
log out that we
modified the element age
34, meaning we
chose the existing
label in our logical assignment,
with inner HTML age 35.
So before we chose the ID to log
out, because it was available.
But in this case,
we're going to default
to the existing inner HTML
because the ID was not in fact
available.
And lastly, we look
at the situation
where age does not
exist as an ID anywhere,
nor does age 34 exist
as some existing HTML.
So now let's check
out what happens
on this run in this situation.
The first thing we do is
we hit the first try block.
But there is no age ID anywhere.
So we go to the catch block.
And we assemble all the
elements, check them all out
to see if there is an
existing HTML that has age 34,
there is not.
And so when we don't find any
element with that existing HTML
our new custom error's going to
get thrown to the nested catch
block.
Then we will get a new
message alerted that says,
yo, an existing
element was not found
and we're creating
a new text node.
Then we will pass control
to the finally block where
when we discover that new
element is no longer undefined
we will just log out that we
are returning a new text node.
And now you are so dangerous
with, or maybe less dangerous,
with try/catch and
error generation.
So we will send you
to some challenges
where you get some work on
protection in error generation.