Hey guys, welcome
back to section three
of level three,
JavaScript Best Practices.
And what would a best practices
course be without a section
on what not to do.
And that is the section,
stuff that's sometimes sucks.
And the first kind
of sucky thing
that we're going to look
at is the with statement.
JavaScript's with keyword
is sort of unreliable.
And it's often
very expensive too,
so it is generally
avoided in practice.
Let's take a look
at what it does
and how to avoid it's pitfalls.
Here we've got a drawbridge
object with some properties.
It's got soldiers, and
there's eight of them there.
It's got a capacity
of 20, meaning
20 people can go on this object.
It's also got an open method,
which will of course alert
a message that opens
the drawbridge.
Now if I were to
use a with block
on this a drawbridge
object what it will do
is take the entire encapsulated
environment of the parameter
object-- in this
case the drawbridge--
and use it to build
a new local scope
within its bracketed
block, which
is kind of processing expensive.
You can think of
that with keyword
as asking the interpreter
to do operations
with the name of
this data container
as the header syntax on
each piece of data, sort of.
Right now, inside
this block, because I
am with-ing on the drawbridge
I can call the open method.
And no object name is necessary
when everything in the object
is already treated as
being local to that scope,
that block.
And I get my alerted message
that the drawbridge has opened.
Err, bang.
Now you might think
wow, cool, yay,
I don't have to use
the object name.
That's so great.
Not great.
What happens when I try to build
a new property close right here
inside that with?
I'm building an
anonymous function there.
And I've got the
close mechanism,
it's going to go, yun, yun,
yun, yun, yun, yun, clack.
Building new properties
in the object on the fly
is not going to work
like you might expect to,
since we seem to be in
the scope of that object.
No, let's see what happens.
Turns out that if
we actually want
to build some property
on the fly like that,
it's not considered as a
new property on the object.
It's, in fact, considered as
some new random global variable
to be created, yay.
The thing about that is,
though, that any new variables
are, of course, added to
the surrounding scope, which
is slightly counter intuitive
and certainly not what
we were looking for.
So beware of that.
Thus, if we actually did want
to add that to the object scope,
we've still got to do that
either right upon construction,
or with a declaration, or
with some on the fly daughter
bracket syntax.
Now with has sort of
an admirable goal.
It's trying to limit redundancy.
Because you know,
nested objects are
very frequent in JavaScript.
And with is trying,
trying, to help
avoid all of that deep
access repeatedly,
and typing all of that access
over and over again, right?
We're going to scoot our
drawbridge object a little bit
further inside of some
other objects here,
and see how with is
sometimes used poorly
to handle these
nested scenarios.
You can see that our
drawbridge is now
contained within a keep, right?
And they keep has
soldiers of its own,
and a capacity of its own.
And the keep itself is contained
within a castle object, which
has soldiers of its own,
and capacity of its own.
Drawbridge is way down in there.
Now over here on the right
we're going to write some code.
We going to establish a
reinforcements variable,
that's 12 guys.
These are some guys they need to
be reinforcing the drawbridge.
So we're going to right if the
castle.keep.drawbridge.capacity
is greater than or equal to the
castle.keep.drawbridge.soldiers+reinforcements--
which is awful and
terrible, right?--
then what we're going to
do is we're going to call
castle.keep.drawbridge.open.
Obviously, you can see that this
is really irritating to type,
and keep typing
forever on, right?
Which is awful.
So if we need access to
the drawbridge object
from the global
scope, it's going
to be very redundant to try
to keep getting to that.
With is trying to
avoid all of that.
So what some people might do
here is put all of this code
inside of with block,
and make the reference
object be
castle.keep.drawbridge.
Let's check it out.
So all of those
castle.keep.drawbridges
go away.
Now this is much more
terse and legible, right?
It makes a lot of sense to
use with, every day, all day.
Problem here is that
with will always
make it unclear which properties
or variables are actually
modified elsewhere.
If we can't read a program,
right, and be confident
that we know what's going on
inside of any block of code,
then we are never really
sure the program is working
like we intend, or like
we desire for it to.
If you've got a developer
gal coming in here
to look at this
code, it's not going
to be immediately
understandable to her
where the soldiers
or the capacity
was located in this case.
We happen to know, the designers
of the code happen to know.
But anybody that's trying
to maintain your code
may not know.
And that makes it very difficult
for large scale projects.
In particular here,
check out that soldiers
that's getting modified with
the plus equals reinforcements.
We're actually not sure
where that soldiers variable
is getting modified.
What if the soldiers
property was not
actually in the drawbridge?
Maybe it gets added on the
fly, only in times of war,
or something like that.
So what we want to give you
here is this best practice
of using variables
to cache your objects
to avoid the with pitfalls.
This is just like
the caching that you
saw in the loop
optimization segment, right?
It lets us avoid
a bunch of typing.
But it's also very
clear in its indication.
Let's take a look.
So what we do here is we
show with block the door.
Good bye with, peaces out.
And now we're going to establish
a new variable called O.
And we're going to be
assign to that variable
the castle.keep.drawbridge
object.
That means that
entire object is now
contained within
the single letter O.
So now we scoot
our code over here.
And we drop in a bunch of
O dots where necessary.
Now with all of
this cached clarity,
the team members on
our very large project
will be able to understand all
of our code's functionality
more precisely, and understand
where stuff comes from
and what you're referring
to in your code.
Also, yay bonus,
no lengthy typing,
no long nested object names
are needed in this case.
Moral the story, cache
objects where possible
and avoid the with statement.
The second, somewhat
sucky thing,
that we want to talk about
here is the eval statement.
Now eval kind of
gets a little bit
of a bad rap in the
JavaScript field,
probably for good reason.
Because it can very much
effect legibility in your code
as well as significantly impact
your ability to debug and incur
a bunch of performance
penalties for you,
which are often terrible.
So let's take a look at
why eval should be avoided.
Take a look at this
function here, called
assign regiment motto.
It's going to take in the
number of the regiment
as well as the motto
for that regiment.
Not eval method is
going to take a string
in as a parameter, any string.
And it will start up
the JavaScript compiler
and treat that string as
if it was some line of code
to actually execute
in JavaScript.
If we passed in the
regiment number two, as well
as the best of the best,
which is their motto,
into the assigned regiment motto
function, this is what happens.
The eval method takes all
the pieces of that string
and puts them together
into one string.
So what we get out of that
is a regiment2 some object
somewhere, dot motto,
referencing the motto property,
becomes the string
the best of the best.
This may seem
great but it really
opens up a lot of
possibility for error.
What if there was, for
example, an apostrophe existing
in the motto?
For example, what if the
first regiment's motto
was the King's own?
See that apostrophe in there?
Well, what happens here is
that the resulting code, when
it finally gets
eval-ed, will actually
be invalid because of
that extra apostrophe.
It's going to make the compiler
think the string is complete
until it sees more stuff.
And then it's going to mark
the code as invalid JavaScript.
Whomp, whomp.
Something else to
note here is there
we may not have any idea at all
what broke our code, especially
if the data that gets
passed in as motto
is not something
we ever examine.
Was it number that was busted?
Was it motto that was busted?
Was it something else?
It gets really in the way
of us being able to debug.
Eval can be useful in a
tiny fraction of the ways
that it actually gets used.
For example, we use it
here in our executor
to evaluate your
code at Code School.
But mostly, eval is like taking
a bazooka to a beehive, OK?
It's bad news.
You want to try not to do that.
Though it may end your
existing problems,
it's probably not the ideal
way to solve that problem.
And furthermore you may
end up with more problems
then you started with.
But if eval is a
must for some reason,
you want to eval as
little as possible.
It might be useful for dynamic
code, or uncontrollable data.
But it's still treating
the string as a program
to very expensively compile.
So in those cases where we
can't avoid an eval statement,
for whatever reason,
and we usually can,
we at least want to
minimize the operations
that that eval statement
needs to engage
in when it's a little,
mini program starts up.
That's going to benefit us in
having added debug capability.
You can see here that instead
of including the entire portion
of the string
inside that string,
we only eval the
regiment and its number,
and know that the motto
will be available.
Thus we can just take the motto
that we pass into our function
and assign it to
that motto property
once the regiment object
had been evaluated by eval.
And now if I were to log out
console.log regiment2.motto you
can see that I get, the King's
own, complete with apostrophe,
no problem.
And the best practice
we want to give you here
is that for all those basic
mappings between objects
and numbers, you want to instead
use your data structures.
Eval is most often misused
with just that sort of mapping,
trying to get objects
with numbers on them.
So we want to make
sure that you try
to use arrays, which
are much more efficient.
Let's take a look.
We'll start up a variable
here called regiments.
And we'll put all of
the regiment objects
inside that array.
And then there's no need to
number the variable name,
if your objects are
already in order.
You want to build your own data
with all of its usage in mind.
Inside our function now we can
just do regiments, and then
call the index on
the number passed in,
dot motto equals the motto.
And instead of eval, we can
use that associative nature
of the array to build all
the dynamic mapping that we
could ever desire.
Really cool,
referencing an array
is much faster than parsing and
running an entire new program
within your program.
But, but, but what if I need
to read and write JSON data
that's all stringy?
Chill, homey.
Using eval to parse
your JSON is typically
regarded as very vulnerable,
often very unsafe, right?
Because eval is going to
evaluate any script that gets
passed in.
Let's take a look.
So here I've got some
string-ified JSON data
being assigned to the
variable regiments, JSON.
You can see inside this
string-ified JSON data
that eventually it's going to
become an object that contains
other objects, which are
the numbered regiments.
If I wanted to eval
that and pass it back
to a regiments value I could.
But what if this data
came from somewhere
else, as does a
lot of JSON data?
Well that could be a potential
vulnerability, right?
Because you have no idea what's
coming in terms of a script
through code injection.
Bad news.
Avoid it.
But what can I do
if I actually need
to use JSON data that
has been string-ified
and I need to parse it?
Well, you can use
JSON.parse to insure
only the JSON is accepted.
JSON.parse will only
recognize JSON and now
compile and scripts, avoiding
all those security issues
from malicious incoming data.
Additionally, there's going
to be some libraries that
used to employee
eval under the hood,
but now use JSON.parse
in all of those places,
and that includes jquery.
You can see here, that
if I call JSON.parse
on regiments JSON
all of that code
would become a very
nice regiments object.
The moral of the eval story is
that there is usually always
a way to circumvent
the use of eval
through the proper
use of data structures
or other methods
designed specifically
to do what you're
trying to use eval for.
So try to stay away from it.
Next up, the third
slightly sucky something
that we would like
to make you aware of,
is leaving off your
brackets in your code.
Just because we can
leave curly braces off
of a single statement
block of code
does not mean that we
should because it's cool.
Check this out.
In JavaScript I could
write if is King,
then I could make
the weapon Excalibur.
Else I could make the
weapon the long sword.
Notice I've got no
brackets on this code,
because it is true that
when a condition or a loop
has only one
statement to execute,
the brackets are not necessary.
But using curly braces is
not just about excellent code
organization or excellent
code legibility,
although it is
about those things.
It is also about being a
very good team player, right?
It's about having very
good code citizenship.
And here's why.
But what if new code
needs to be added, man?
If you require bracket
analysis in order
to ensure that every
new bit of code
is properly scoped
to the right block,
you'll be very unpopular.
So say there's a new guy, right?
And he's coming in to work on my
terribly unbracketed code here.
And he needs to add some
functionality that's
been requested.
So he puts these
two extra statements
into both the if block
and the else block.
Turns out though that this else
is now going to cause an error.
That's because it looks
for a preceding if block
and doesn't find one.
What?
I see an if block there.
Oh guess what,
since there are no
brackets around those
extra two statements
that else block doesn't know
which if it's associated with.
That's because
those two statements
he added in the if block are not
actually part of the if block.
But even though we
found that error
through the else erroring
out, missing brackets
don't always generate errors.
Sometimes we get perfectly
valid JavaScript,
especially in the example
of conditional blocks.
And then we get a whole bunch
of undesired executions.
Let's take a look.
So we'll get rid of
our else block here.
And now you can see we've just
got the if is King portion.
Now even if it is King
is false, right, well we
will skip the weapon
equals Excalibur.
But we will get the
alert to be called.
We will also get
a call to remove
from armory the sword Excalibur.
That's because without the
else to trigger an error,
the JS interpreter just sees
this code written like this.
If is King, assign
Excalibur to the weapon,
and then who cares if
it was is King or not,
do these two steps,
alert this message
and remove from
armory Excalibur.
So undesired executions
often suck, right?
So please, be cool,
bracket your code.
It's better for organization.
People can read
your code better.
And it will often prevent
errors you did not
know we're going to happen.
Brackets are a two character--
tap, tap-- sacrifice
that is going to help
you in the long run.
We're going to give you some
challenges now about stuff that
sucks.
And we'll see you back
in the next section.