Hey, guys.
Welcome back to level three
of JavaScript best practices.
This section, the final
section of level three,
is about Number Nonsense.
So in JavaScript,
decimals are actually
kind of crazy because JavaScript
uses binary floating point
values to handle all of its
decimal based operations.
If we pull up a
little console.log
here, of a simple
addition, 0.1 plus 0.2,
well that's just
0.3-- oh, uh, what?
There's a 4.
There is a 4.
There was no 4,
there is a 4 now.
I don't know where it came from.
Well, I kind of do.
It's binary floating
point values, right,
which are used primarily
for performance because they
do enhance performance
in a lot of ways.
But there's
definitely a trade off
between performance and
accuracy in this case.
Taking a look at a
couple other examples,
if we did 0.1 plus 0.2 plus 0.3
we get 0.6-- oh, there's a 1
there.
There's a 1.
There was not a 1.
Now there's a 1 in that spot.
Crazy.
One of the crazy things
about binary floating point
is that they're not even
associative in this case.
If I tried to add 0.1 and
0.2 over here in parentheses
and then add 0.3 well, I
get the same exact thing
that I got before
without the parentheses.
But if I try to add 0.1 to
the grouping of 0.2 plus 0.3,
magically I get what
I'm expecting, 0.6.
Fine, I'll just
jump off a bridge.
Everything will be just fine.
Now, floating point arithmetic
using binary numbers
inside of a computer's
arithmetic logical unit, that's
slightly outside the scope
of JavaScript best practice.
Wouldn't you agree?
So what we're going
to do is give you
a little bit of resources at
the end of the course for you
to go research floating
point arithmetic,
because all
developers should have
a passing familiarity with it.
Instead, here in
this course, we're
going to give you some ways to
kind of constrain JavaScript's
occasional number nonsense, as
well as get consistent results
regardless of the
internal operations.
So first, we'll talk
about a few methods
that help improve your
decimal visualization.
First there is
the toFixed method
that's going to allow
us to select precisely
the amount of decimal
places we want to display.
Over here you can
see we're storing
the result of our crazy
0.1 plus 0.2 addition
in a variable called a number.
And then we're going to
log out, num.toFixed1.
That means we want
exactly one decimal place
to be shown on our number.
And we get 0.3, exactly
what we would like.
You can stick any
amount of decimal places
in there that you prefer.
If we pass a 4 in
to num after we
have created a new addition
on 0.1, 0.2 and 0.3.
We can see we get 0.6000,
for four total fixed decimal
places.
Important to know
about toFixed is
that it's going to round to the
very last indicated positions
that you have provided.
So, if you're
dealing, for example,
with percentages of
money, then toFixed
can handle that hundreds
rounding for you at any time.
Here we've going to
function called tax.
It's going to take in any
price of some object as well
as the tax percent that
that object is subject to.
On the inside, you can see
that we return the price times
percent divided by 100,
which will give you
exactly the tax that you need.
But we're going to return it to
a fixed decimal place of two.
That way it is in money terms,
with two decimal places.
You can see here, if we
call the tax method on $9.85
as well as with a 7.5% tax
rate, what happens on the inside
as we get 9.85 times
7.5 divided by 100.
But that's going
to give us 0.73875.
Now, our toFixed
with two in it, is
going to look at the
third place to ensure
two places will be
correctly rounded.
And since 8 is greater than
5 the 3 will increase to 4.
And we'll get 0.74.
But, look, that's a string.
Hm, what can we do about that?
How are we going to use
a string numerically
if we wanted to do
other operations?
Because if we had a mailed
glove that cost $9.95
as well as some armor
tax that was 7.5%
and we wanted to know the total
price of this mailed glove
in this shop, we would add
the mailed glove variable
to the results of
our tax method,
thinking that we would get some
number out of the tax method.
But what that would
actually do-- ooh,
that escalated quickly--
it would give us 9.850.74.
What?
Weird.
That's because it
tried to concatenate
a string to a number.
Thus we will need a new
method to help use the rounded
value in further
math operations.
A cool method that will
help us out with that
is called parsefloat.
It's going to turn
strings that have decimals
into numbers to be used.
A combination of
toFixed and parsefloat
will let us use values of
exact length in all of our math
operations that we might desire.
So you can see I've
added a parsefloat
around my mathematics
as well as my toFixed.
And what that's
going to do is it's
going to return an
actual decimal value back
from the tax function.
So now when I pass
in 9.85 and 7.5
I'm going to get 0.74 the
number, 0.74 the number,
instead of 0.74 the string.
That makes it very usable
in the addition math
that I've got doing
with mailed glove.
So you can see when
I log that out I'm
going to get 10.59 in money.
And now we're good for
display or other usage
inside of totals.
Parseint is also a
very valuable method
that will convert
numerical strings.
But instead of looking for
a floating point number,
parseint is going to seek the
very first available integer
on the front of any string.
So here you can see, if I've
got parseint on a string 88
it's going to return
a very nice 88 to me.
But if I pass in
a string that has
an integer on the front parseint
is going to try to help out.
It's going to try to
provide any integer that
begins a string of
other characters.
That's slightly weird,
very often dangerous.
Same thing with parsefloat, too.
If I pass in a sentence
here 3.28084 meters
in a foot parsefloat is going to
look for the termination of all
of the numbers after any
decimal point is encountered.
Something to note,
if a string does not
begin with an acceptable
value for either method,
however, you'll get that
JS value not a number.
More on this in a little bit.
One thing we want you
to know about parseint
is that it will trim
off any decimals
it encounters without rounding.
So if I were to
pass in this string,
9.85, I'm going to get 9 back.
That may not be what
you were expecting
if you thought 9.85
should become a 10.
So watch out if
you're using parseint
in a rounding situation.
Now although parseint
is often super valuable,
it can cause some
unexpected value errors
that we want to
make you aware of.
That's because parseint will
accept octal, or hexadecimal,
or decimal values.
Thus we want to use this with
a little bit of caution here.
Check this out.
Say that we've got a user age
variable that takes some data
from a user, but that
the user, for their age,
actually made an error in typing
and put in 021 instead of 21.
If we use parseint on user age
in modern ECMAScript 5 systems,
it's going to give you
exactly what you want.
It's going to trim that 0 off
the front and make it a 21.
Pretty cool.
But if we use
parseint on user age,
and we're in an
older system, it may
think that you
are trying to pass
an octal value, which is base 8.
And it's going to
try to help you out
with a conversion back
to the decimal value.
Whomp, whomp.
And it's going to give you a 17.
Now if this was a dude
registering on a cruise ship,
and he put in 21, but
the system thinks he's 17
he's going to have a uniquely
different experience there.
Now this situation
very much points
to the idea of
progressive enhancement
in internet
technology, which means
we need to keep all of
our user's possible errors
in mind at all times.
When dealing with our string
to number conversions,
it's going to be very prudent,
very helpful, cautious,
to make sure that we pass
in a defining radix value.
The radix value is going
to tell parseint exactly
which base in which you want
your value to be treated.
So here you can see we've got
a parseint method on that 021
string.
But now we're going
to pass in 10.
And that's going
to say, yo, I want
this to be a decimal value,
whatever you get out of it.
So parseint's going to take
that radix value, look at it,
say OK, decimal value,
got it, and send it back.
And we get 21.
Always do this when you cannot
be assured of a browser version
or a user's input.
In other words, forever.
Another cautionary tale we want
to tell here in this section
is that of testing
for number presence
before you try to do an
operation with that number.
Now, using not a number to
check if values actually exist,
that seems like a good idea.
Not a number, If I can use not a
number that should work, right?
Usually tries to kill you.
Take a look at this.
If I do typeof not a
number that's a number.
The typeof not a
number is a number.
OK, so if I got
console.log not a number,
triple equals not a
number, I'm trying
to see if not a number
is, in fact, not a number.
And guess what?
That's false, not a
number is not a number,
is not not a number, something.
Right, crazy.
And then if I use that is
not a number method, which
a lot of people turn to, on
the string 42, that's false.
Because this is a string.
This is a string.
And it's not a number.
It's not a number
because it's a string.
I don't know.
Yeah, it's kind of crazy
in the number environment,
especially with not a number.
And it turns out this is not
a number method is actually
looking strictly for the
value not a number itself.
Fun.
What we want to give you here
in terms of best practice
is please, for your own
sake, do a double check
to avoid insanity.
If you're unsure
about the data type,
but you're very highly
reliant on the fact
that it is a number,
you got to use typeof
and is not a number
as a best practice.
Let's check that out.
So if I build, over
here, is a function that
says is this actually
a number, don't lie,
and I pass in some
data, right, what
it's going to do is
it's going to return
the Boolean result of this
compound conditional in here.
First thing it does is it checks
to see if the type of data
is in fact a JavaScript
number value, right?
Not only does that
have to be true,
but we also have to make sure
that the data is not, in fact,
not a number, the
value, NaN, right?
Because look up at the top.
type of not a number,
that's a number.
So if I just check to see
if the data is a number,
I could be screwed if my
value is actually NaN, right?
So we want to do
both of those checks
to actually make
sure that we have
the number that
we're looking for.
Checking that out over here, if
I call is this actually number,
don't lie on 640, I get a true
because, cool, that's a number
and it's also not NaN.
If I call that method
on the string 640,
well the first part of
my condition, my compound
conditional, breaks
because typeof data is not
in fact a number.
And so I get false.
And now here's
where the money is.
This is where you have avoided
getting any wrong answers back.
Is this actually a
number, don't lie
on not a number, that's
going to be false,
because the second part of
our compound conditional
will not be correct.
Now if you want a
little leniency,
especially for form data, which
we know can come back crazy
all the time, then you
want to use parse methods.
If numerical data may show
up some time as a string then
you want to parse your data
before you do your check,
and also add additional checks.
So let's check it out.
We're going to build a function
here called check valid zip.
We're going to check on a
valid zip code in some field.
First, we'll actually
get the entered zip code
from the value of
the zip ID element.
Next, we will try to
parseint on that entry
and pass it to the
user zip variable.
Then, we'll get a
try/catch block going.
Oh, we're back to those, huh?
If is this actually a number,
don't lie on user's zip,
meaning we do actually
have a number here,
then what we're
going to do is check
to make sure the length of
that zip code is only five.
So we've taken the
user's zip, we've
fixed it to a zero
decimal length.
And if that length happens
to be five of that number,
then we will actually
get the number five out.
And we will return true,
our valid zip is cool.
Otherwise we're going to
throw an error that says nope,
it ain't good.
And then, in that
second else block,
we're going to throw an error if
our is this actually a number,
don't lie method found out that
our user's zip was not in fact
a number.
And then in our
catch block we'll
just handle the
error gracefully,
telling the user to
please enter a valid zip,
do it, and return false
from check valid zip.
We could put a bunch of other
error responses there as well.
So now, over here, if
we got a zip code field
and we enter 32803, then
we get a true value back
because we have a length
five on our zip code
and it's actually a number.
But, if when we were
entering that zip code
we hit 3280 and our finger was
actually hitting this Shift
key, and we put 3 down
and it gave us a number,
and we entered that, we
would get a false back
from our check valid
zip because we do not
have an actual number going on.
Yeah.
So that is the end of
the Nonsense of Numbers,
and also the end of
the Crystal of Caution.
We will give you some challenges
on crazy number stuff.
And we'll see you back
in the next level.
[BEEPING]
Just kill me now.
T-shirt objects,
or something nuts.
[LAUGHING] Why would there be
t-shirt objects in the armory?
[LAUGHING]
[BEEPING]
I D or-- [COUGHING]