[SINGING] Find the Sword of Syntax first
for the useful tools
that you may need.
Wear the pendant of performance
for efficiency and speed.
Caution's Crystal clears the
sky with triple equals and try/catch
Avoiding stuff that sucks and
parsing badder numbers
out of stretch.
Alas, the golden shining
mail of modularity.
When namespace closure imports
long, defend integrity.
For polished jewels
and JavaScript,
the treasure trove this is.
Now raise your sword
and strike your shield
with these Best Practices.
Well friends, your journey
here is almost complete.
In this last level,
we'll be taking a look
at the module design
pattern in JavaScript.
First, we'll look closely at the
basics of a simulated namespace
in JavaScript, which is the
foundation for any module.
Thereafter, we'll look at how to
create public and private state
data through the use of
anonymous closure, which
can sometimes be
very hard to grasp.
Next, in keeping with our best
practices of clarity and data
protection, we'll examine
the use of global imports
which will allow us to
carefully and clearly use
external data inside
of our modules.
Lastly, augmentation
will wrap things
up so that you can add
functionality and properties
to your modules,
even after they've
been built inside other files.
So you've got your sword.
You've got your pendant.
You've got your crystal.
Now it's time to don
the mail of modularity.
Hey guys, welcome
back to level four,
the final level of
JavaScript Best Practices,
The Mail of Modularity.
In this first section,
we'll take a look
at the basics of a namespace.
You write a JavaScript file,
I write a JavaScript file,
everybody writes
a JavaScript file.
And conflicting code
within those files
can cause overwrites.
JavaScript files often have
conflicting global elements
if they're not built well.
And that can overwrite
existing very important data.
Let's take a look at that.
So say we had a Hall of
Fame website document here.
You can see various HTML
elements, as well as
some unordered lists
and some script
files that we call just before
the end of the body tag.
Let's say that this
first script was
built by the same author
who built the entire HTML
structure.
And that's going to
report the current members
of the Hall of Fame.
Later, she asks a
colleague to please
build a short file
that's going to list
just the requirements for
Hall of Fame selection.
So in the first file,
the HALLOFFAME.JS file,
we've got a list of all the guys
that are in the Hall of Fame
currently.
To add those guys to the
unordered list in the HTML
document that has the
id hof, h-o-f, we'll
get that element
by id and store it
in a variable called h-o-f, hof.
Next, we've got
a fragment, which
will help our best practice of
touching the DOM as little as
possible and then
an element that we
will use to add a list item.
But then her friend comes along,
and we get the REQUIREMENTS.JS
file.
And inside that, you can
see the reqs list there,
an array of stuff
that a knight has
to do to get into
the Hall of Fame.
That's be a cool kid.
Slay the dragon.
Good at Swording.
Right?
Stuff knights should
be able to do for sure.
And then, though, we have a new
list variable being declared
and assigned that's going to
pick up that unordered list
under selection requirements
with the id of reqs, r-e-q-s.
Now, the existing list that
was in the previous file gets
overwritten due to hoisting:
both of those variables would
be global, and since one was
declared after the other,
the second overrides the first.
Now, is that big deal here?
Well maybe not in this
case because the first list
is already done being used.
Everything that had happened
inside the HALLOFFAME file
is already done
and ready to roll.
And so declaring that
new list variable
inside of the REQUIREMENTS.JS
file is not such a huge deal.
But there are ways in which
this could become a huge deal.
So let's take a look at those.
What if HALLOFFAME.JS only
really provided a global method
for displaying the h-o-f members
instead of just displaying them
immediately as soon as the
script file was loaded and run?
Instead what it does is
creates a global function
called displayHOF,
display Hall of Fame.
So we scoot our
reqs list down here.
And now we're going to put
a button under the Honorable
Members header.
And on the click of
that button, we're
going to actually call using
inline JavaScript
displayHOF. So when the
button is clicked,
that's when the members
of the Hall of Fame
actually get displayed.
Now what kind of problems
might this cause?
Well, by the time that
both of those script files
have been retrieved, loaded,
and run, displayHOF,
the new function, the global
function, is going to be in memory
and ready to be used upon
the click of that button.
But now that that
second REQUIREMENTS file
has created that second
list global variable,
it overwrote the first.
And so displayHOF
would no longer
find the exactly correct list
of knights in the Hall of Fame.
Instead, it finds
that other global
created in requirements.js.
Well, what can we do about that?
Well, enter the simulated
JavaScript namespace?
Though a namespace is
not really native so
to speak to JavaScript,
the namespace concept
that is found
throughout programming
can limit global impact
and also provide us
with some data protection.
So to build that
namespace, we're
going to rewrite our
HALLOFFAME.JS file.
And the first thing
that we do, the key
to creating a namespace,
is a single global object
and that's commonly called
the wrapper for the space,
for the namespace.
By convention, you
will very often
see a namespace
capitalized entirely.
Now, all the variables
that were formerly
declared in the global
scope will now just
be properties of the
HOFMASTER namespace.
Additionally, the
displayHOF function
will also belong to the
HOFMASTER namespace, which
means we'll need to reference
the calling object on all
the needed variables using this.
Now that that function and
all of the necessary variables
are actually encapsulated
within the hof master namespace,
we're going to need that
HOFMASTER name as a header syntax
in order call that
displayHOF method.
What does that mean?
It means that the
name of the namespace
will act as this shield,
this armor around your data.
By using that mini-environment,
sort of a data container,
it's going to add a
layer of protection
that we don't always get if
we just incorporate everything
as a global variable.
So now, if our globally
unfriendly file
tries to make an impact
on that document scope,
the master
information, the one we
cared the most about, the data
that we enjoyed the most, we
wanted that to stay very
protected, that doesn't get
impacted at all.
Now, ideally, all of
your JavaScript files
will incorporate a
namespace of some sort
because a namespace
is really going
to reduce your global footprint
on the entire application.
This is very useful for
very large web applications.
It's also going to keep your
data grouped very carefully
around their intended
functionality.
That's really important.
So here you can see, to rewrite
that REQUIREMENTS.JS file,
we've given it a REQUIREMENTS
namespace, notice all caps.
And inside there, of
course, are the bunch
of properties and methods
that the requirements, things,
need in order to be
produced in our HTML.
What do you notice here?
Well, namespaces tend to
remain agnostic of each other,
right, unless the file builders
are building those namespaces
specifically to work
with each other.
And that's very useful
for data protection.
Another thing to note about
namespaces that's cool
is that nested namespacing is
very frequent in JavaScript
and especially in
a module pattern,
more of which we'll be
discussing as the sessions move
forward in this level.
Now, nesting namespaces provides
even further organization, even
further grouping and
protection, as well as
keeping the variable
names very intuitive
if you need them to be.
This means that you could have
multiple list variables inside
of multiple namespaces without
each impacting the other.
For example, here, we've
got a new BIOGRAPHIES
namespace as a property
of the HOFMASTER
namespace, a new layer of scope
groups all that related data,
but it shields it
by requiring all
of the namespace references.
You can see here in my call to,
HOFMASTER.BIOGRAPHIES.unfoldBio,
I can pass-in a list
variable that incorporates
the knights who are
in the Hall of Fame,
but I need to use that
HOFMASTER reference in order
to make it happen.
That's going to distinguish it
from the HOFMASTER list which
you can see holds the
knights, and the list
inside the biographies
namespace which
holds only some useful list
of biography data about each
of the knights that are
in the Hall of Fame.
So that is a quick
and dirty exposure
to the idea of the namespace
concept inside of JavaScript.
Now, we're going to send you
to do some challenges to work
with some namespaces.
And we'll see you back for
the rest of the level soon.