Welcome back.
Hope you enjoyed
working with namespaces.
We're on, inside of
our module pattern,
towards anonymous closures.
So far, we have
only seen a module
that has public properties.
The thing with a
namespace, though,
is that you really have to
hope that no one else ever uses
the name you've created
for your namespace
inside your application.
Take a look at this
ARMORY object right here.
The ARMORY namespace we can
infer because of the capitals.
Now this namespace has a
bunch of public variables
and methods, which can still
be accessed by any code that
happens to know the name of
the space and its properties.
What if we don't want that?
What if we want some privacy to
our data inside our namespace?
First, we need to decide which
properties should be public
and which we don't want anybody
to see and should be private.
So taking a look at these, we've
got a weaponList and an
armorList.
And since an accurate
list of weapons and armor
is really, really
important, right,
to accurate armory service-- I
mean, when you run your armory,
I'm sure that that's
what you need--
these arrays should
be very private.
Rolling on down, you
see makeWeaponRequest
and makeArmorRequest.
Well that seems to be
something that should be public
because the whole
reason an armory exists
is because we want people to
be able to make requests to get
weapons and armor out
of the armory, right?
And then, finally, removeWeapon,
replaceWeapon,
removeArmor, replaceArmor.
That's really messing with our
data, with our list, right?
So we probably want these
to be private as well.
Because making any
modifications to the master list
should be a task that only the
module takes care of and only
the module can call into being.
This is an excellent case of how
public methods and values often
and sometimes
should be triggering
the use of private
methods and values.
So in our case,
our public methods
are going to signal the private
methods to safely modify
the private data.
Here you see each
request method,
meaning makeWeaponRequest
and makeArmorRequest,
each of those is going to make
some reference in its code
to the remove/replaceWeapons.
Those are going to have access
to the weapons and armor lists.
That makes closure
very valuable.
Let's see how.
The closure feature
in JavaScript,
which you may remember
from JavaScript Roadtrip,
has a feature that will allow
us to privatize properties.
As a first visual
step, check this out,
we'll wrap the entire
set of properties
in an anonymous immediately
invoked function expression.
Stay with me on that.
So what we got here is
function at the front,
but notice it's wrapped
inside of a left parenthesis.
And then at the back, we
close that left parenthesis
with a right parenthesis.
And then immediately
call the function
by providing another
calling set of parentheses.
This is an immediately
invoked function expression,
which you probably saw or
remember from Roadtrip.
Now, we will turn all of our
desired private properties
of the old ARMORY
namespace, we're
going to turn those
into local executable
code inside our new function.
Right?
And those local
values and methods
that now belong to
the function will
be closed up into the
ARMORY's namespace
once the ARMORY
object gets returned.
Here, the list of data
become a local variables
for the immediately invoked
function expression scope.
That's going to
make them private.
We'll do the same thing for
these function expressions
down at the bottom: removeWeapon,
replaceWeapon,
removeArmor, replaceArmor.
We want all those to
be private so we're
going to make those local
executable code as well.
Again, these will belong
only to the function
instead of directly
to the namespace.
Stay with us.
Next thing you should
probably do, although it's not
really required, it's
just good habit,
is to pull every
private value and method
to the top of the function.
That's going to help us
with code organization.
And it's going to put all the
closure values near the top
and near each other
for easy reference.
So let's scoot those over.
And here is where the money is.
In order to make some of
the properties public, which
is obviously our
remaining ones, we're
going to return an object
that holds those properties.
So let's add those public
properties to their own object
and return it.
And that becomes
the ARMORY namespace
once the immediately
invoked function
expression finishes and returns.
What you can see is that
once the function completes
and returns that object, it
will be immediately handed over
to the ARMORY variable
and become the new ARMORY
namespace, complete
with public properties,
make weapon requests, and make
armor requestsm as well as all
of that private data that
no one will ever see.
What we want you to notice about
this really powerful element
of the module pattern is
that the closure now produces
all of your desired
private methods and values.
All of the function's
local variables
get pushed get bound down
into the returned object
into that scope.
But those properties are
never actual properties
within the object itself.
They're there,
though, and they're
visible to enable
to be referenced
by only the members of
the object's local scope.
And with that, the
basics of our module
are actually now complete.
Our sensitive data is
private by closure.
And our public properties
are accessible through only
the namespace.
So now, if we call
ARMORY.makeWeaponRequest
on the weapon excalibur,
well the ARMORY namespace,
which is that
small object there,
calls its makeWeaponRequest
property method.
Next, makeWeaponRequest
will call removeWeapon,
which is invisible, in order
to try to get excalibur.
Next, if some
conditions are met,
namely if the weapon
exists in the weaponList
and if it should be checked
out to the person who's
making the request, then the
invisible removeWeapon method
deletes and retrieves
the object from
the invisible
closed-up weaponList.
weaponList returns that
object to the removeWeapon
function scope.
Then, of course, removeWeapon
will return that object for use
to the scope of
makeWeaponRequest.
And then the ARMORY
namespace can
decide what to do
with excalibur.
Short and sweet, that's
anonymous closures.
And now we will give
you some experience
with those in the challenges.
See you back for
the next section.