Welcome back.
Hope you enjoyed working
with anonymous closures.
And now we're on
to section three,
discussing global imports.
So our current module seems
only need local variables.
Right?
But if we look a little closer
in one of these methods,
we might find that
a global variable
is involved in one of them.
Let's say that there was some
global variable called wartime,
and it currently is
set to true, which
means the kingdom is at war.
Turns out, inside of our
make weapon request function,
if it's wartime, we want to
let civilians have weaponry
to protect themselves.
So our Make Weapon
Request function
checks to see if war exists.
And if so, we'll let both
knights and civilians
have weaponry.
First thing that happens
is at the local scope
of the namespace
would be checked
to see of wartime
existed anywhere
inside of that namespace.
And then if that namespace
happened to be nested,
we would go into that
scope and check that scope
to see if it's there, all the
way up to the global scope.
Now, standard global
use in a module pattern
can cause two problems.
The first is that when non-local
variables are referenced inside
of a module, the entire
length of the scope chain
is checked for that variable.
First, in this case for
wartime, the local scope
of the namespace
would be checked.
They'd look around the armory,
see is wartime is there.
It's not.
And then if that namespace
happened to be nested,
then the outer namespace
would be checked too,
and so on and so on
and so on until we've
reached the global scope.
Now, that search is going to
happen every time wartime is
encountered throughout
the entire module.
That's a very expensive
process if there
is any sort of namespace
depth or multiple
references across the module.
Problem number two is
that lengthy namespaces
mean that global
variables can possibly
have unclear scope
leading to code
that is really tough to manage.
Developer gets
into your file here
to maintain your
armory module, sees
wartime, this file is very
long by the way, so is
the global file.
Doesn't know where
wartime is coming form
or what changes he can make
to this particular file.
It's really important
for developers
who are maintaining
your code to be
able to place the source
of your variables data.
You don't want them to have to
look through tons of code just
to figure out where
the data came from.
Or what's worse, they may
actually make terrible changes
to data they think is local.
So for clearer, faster
globals in your modules,
we want you to use
a global import.
Now while devs may still
need to review code--
and who doesn't, we all need
to review code constantly--
importing globals,
though, creates
much faster local variables that
are also more clear insource.
The first way we want to
incorporate a global import
is to add a parameter to the
wrapper immediately invoked
function.
Here you can see we're
passing in the war parameter.
Now, we've got one
parameter here,
but you can create
just as many parameters
as globals there are
that you're importing.
So since we're importing
this parameter war,
we're going to need every
place that we make reference
to that global to change
its name to the parameter.
Here you can see in
our IF statement,
we've replaced wartime with war.
And here's where the magic
happens for global imports.
We're going to use our calling
parentheses on are immediately
invoked function expression
to actually pass-in
the global that we
want to become war.
And which one is that?
Of course, it is wartime.
So now we have passed wartime
in to our immediately invoked
function expression.
Wartime becomes
war as a parameter.
And war gets used
throughout the entire scope.
Yeah, imports!
As a result of importing
two, the variable
that you need from the
external scope gets
closed up as a local value.
It's just another piece of
data boxed up in the closure.
Cool little bonus about that is
that the function's parameter
creates this modifiable
value inside the local scope
of your namespace.
That's pretty cool.
And the global value
that you passed-in stays
protected if it needs to be.
Great.
So now you've got anonymous
closures for module patterns,
as well as how to get your
globals in there through using
global imports.
We're going to give you some
challenges on that topic.
And we'll see you back
for the very last section.
See you soon.