Welcome back.
Hope you enjoyed working
with your global imports
in your anonymous closures.
In this section,
we'll be talking
about how to augment
your modules.
So yeah, modules
often need to have
additions to their
existing properties.
If you've ever worked in some
large code base of document,
you're going to know
the value of splitting
functionality
between many files.
So here, in our armory.js
file is all that code
that we built in the
last two sections
where the armory module is.
Over here, we'll have
a global kingdom.js
where all of the behavior
globally for the kingdom
is kept.
And there, you can see our
global variable wartime
with the truth value
signaling we are at war.
Now, providing extra
properties for existing models
can be done through a
process called augmentation.
In a separate file,
we'll keep a function,
which will add values or
functionality to our existing
armory.
Here, we have the
warchest.js file.
That's going to
be augmenter file.
It's going to add
functionality to the armory
in the event of war.
Now, augmentation is almost
done like a re-creation
of the existing namespace.
You can see here
that we're going
to be using the same sort of
immediately invoked function
expression that's going
to return something
to the armory existing
global namespace.
That's why there's no of VAR key
word on that armory variable.
Inside of our
function, now, we're
going to pass the old namespace.
Right?
And since it is our old
namespace and existing
as a global, we're going
to go ahead and need
to use our import knowledge.
And we'll import that
old namespace as a local
in order to make
some modifications
to a temporary object
that it creates.
Of course, in order
to augment our module
and return a new module with
all the old stuff in it,
we're going to need to
pass in the old module.
And there it is, armory.
Notice the result of this
immediately invoked function
expression that
uses the old module
will be eventually
an object that gets
returned and stored back in
the old armory namespace.
So what's the stuff that we want
to close up and add in here?
Well we got some
local variables here
called oil barrels of
which there are 1,000.
We've also got some
catapults to add to our war
chest-- stone sling, rock
reign, and the giant's arm.
We've also got a new method
called Assign Catapult.
That's going to take in
some regiment number,
and it's going to
hook a regiment up
with a sweet catapult
and, of course,
some oil barrels to
toss at some orcs.
Notice here that our public
functionality, namely
the Assign Catapult
method, is being
added as a property on the
old namespace object, which
is local to this function.
So once we've added all
of our new private values
and all of our new
public functionality
on the existing
object, then we'll
return the modified module.
Because now, old ns has an extra
public property, as well as
these new closures-- oil
barrels and catapults.
Now, augmentation is super cool.
It's great.
Right?
It adds functionality
whenever you need it.
And it's especially great
for public functionality,
but we want you to be
aware of one thing.
And that's that
previous private data
from your old file
and your old function
that you used to build
your original namespace,
all of that private
closure data will not
be accessible to any of your
new properties in your new file.
The augmented properties
will have access
to their new private state.
And all those public
methods over here
will also have access to
the private data right here.
But none of these
public or private values
will have access to the closed
data from the previous file.
Taking a look, remember
that closures are always
produced by the function itself
and never the returned object.
So if we build a new function
expression in our war chest
file, right, it's not going
to recreate all those closure
references back to
the old function that
was made in the previous file.
Very important to note.
That means that any new
properties, not going
to have any access to all that
old private data that we made.
They will still be there.
The earlier public
properties that we
had produced in the previous
function, all the references
to the closures will
still be there for that.
But any new properties
will not have access
to the old closed data,
only to its new closed data.
So the best practice here
with regard to augmentation
is to group your file content
around your needed data.
Any cross file private state
build that you could manage
won't even have the
level of privacy
of just a single closure.
And often, it leads
to hard to manage code
figuring out how the modules
are augmenting each other
or referencing each other.
So the best practice is just
to keep your file grouped
around data that's
related to each other
and that need each other.
You can see here, though,
in our cool warchest.js file
that Assign Catapult
doesn't need
any access to the
old private data.
So we don't have any
broken references,
and our file is grouped
very well for augmentation.
So now we will send you over
to work on your augmentation
skills in the challenges.
And that, ladies
and gentlemen, is
the end of JavaScript
Best Practices.
Thanks so much for hanging
with us here at Code School,
and we'll see you real soon.
Sorry had to belch.
Course code.
What's code?
Cood.
I'm going to reveal
your code now.
Ah!