[SINGING] Put down your
brains and your entrails.
It's time to stop
and learn some Rails,
‘cause we got
something new to grab -
it's Rails for
Zombies by Envy Labs.
You're watching
Rails for Zombies.
This is Level Four
where we're going
to be talking about Controllers,
the braaaains of the application.
Makes you hungry, don't it?
Your controllers
are typically where
you use models to get
data out of the database
and you use Views to
display the data that
comes out of the models.
It'll make more
sense in a minute.
So we're going to use this
brain icon, because it's
kind of the brains
of our application.
Here we are back
with our browser,
and we have our four
components of our application.
We've talked about the models, we've talked about the views,
and now we're going to talk about the controllers, which
go about there.
Back in our show view,
here's the code that we had.
Now there's something in here
that smells like rotten brains,
and it's basically that
line right there where
we call the tweet model.
That really shouldn't be
happening in our view.
Because, as I said
a minute ago, it's
our controller that should
be calling the models.
When a request comes
into our application -
let's call it "tweet/1" -
before getting to our View
it's first going to
hit a controller.
In this case, it's going to
look inside of the controllers
directory, which
is created for us,
for a file called
"tweets_controller.rb."
Only then is then going to
render out the show view.
There's no coincidence
here that our URL
has the word tweets
in it, as does
the name of our controller, as
does the folder for our views.
We don't have to map
any of these things
together if we use conventions.
That's why sometimes people
say that Rails follows
convention over configuration.
If we can follow some
intelligent defaults
or convention, then we
can avoid configuration.
But what belongs inside
of our controller?
Well, let's write it out.
Inside of our
controller, we're going
to find that it has a
class of TweetsController,
uppercase Tweets,
uppercase Controller.
And that extends from
ApplicationController.
The next step to
define our controller
is to define a show method.
Sometimes we call
the methods inside
of our controllers actions.
We can use the two
terms interchangeably.
Now there's no coincidence that
this method we just defined
called "show" happens to be the
same name as our view show.
One maps to the other.
Inside of this show method
is where we typically
call our models and get
data from the database.
So we're going to move up our
tweet call into our Controller,
like you see here.
Now when a request
comes in, it's
first going to go and
call that show method
inside of our controller.
It's going to run that code.
And once it gets to the
end, it's then, by default,
going to go look
for our show view
and render that
out to a browser.
You might be wondering, what
about the variable scope?
How is it that our view has
access to that tweet variable?
Well, that's actually
a good question.
Because this code
as-is wouldn't work.
We need to add an at symbol
in front of each of these.
So when we add an at in front
of a variable inside Ruby,
it turns it into an
instance variable.
This is how we grant the
view access to variables.
So because inside
of our controller
our tweet has that
at symbol, we can now
access that tweet
variable using that
at symbol inside of our views.
But what if we don't
like that default?
What if we don't want it to
render out the show view?
Instead, we wanted to
render out status.html.erb.
Well, we can specify that
inside of our show method
by simply writing
render action status.
This will then render
out our status.html.erb.
This code works
great as-is, but you
can see that we're
only ever rendering
the tweet with the ID of one.
But what if we wanted to go
to any one of these other URLs
and specify the ID of the
tweet that we want to see?
How would we look that up?
How would we use that
parameter out of the URL?
Well, it turns out if we
write URLs like this, Rails
will generate for us a new hash
called "params," which contains
a hash of the value passed in.
To access that value to
load the proper tweet,
all we need to do
in our controller
is specify params id.
That's going to look
up the proper tweet
and render it out to the page.
Let's look at a few more
examples with parameters.
If we had a URL
like you see here -
and we're just using standard
URL query parameters -
Rails would create a
parameter hash for us,
which might look something
like this, which we could then
use inside of our controller,
if we set it up properly,
to create a new tweet.
So you can see here,
we're creating a tweet,
and we're grabbing the
status out of the parameter
to create that tweet.
However, often in
Rails our parameters
might look something
like this where
we have a hash within a hash.
You see that?
So how would we access a status
of this to create a tweet?
Well, we could write
Tweet.create status params
tweet status, like you see here.
So we have to specify
two keys to get
to the value we want inside
this hash within a hash.
There's an alternate
syntax we can use here,
because our tweet method
is expecting a hash.
So we can just
specify params tweet.
And what it's going
to send it to create
is the hash which
contains status, "I'm dead."
You see how those two
lines are equivalent?
But I think the second one is
better because it's obviously
writing less code and it's
not recreating a hash.
That's pretty advanced.
Now, before we move on,
There's something a little
rotten about this code.
Users might be able to set any attributes
by sending in additional keys and values
for this hash on the URL.
Luckily in Rails 4,
we're required to use strong parameters,
which makes our code more secure.
We'll also need to specify the parameter key
that our action is expecting.
In our case, we're going to require
that the tweet key is sent in
from our hash.
We also need to specify the attributes
we'll permit to be set from this hash.
We'll simply call these two methods
on our parameter hash
and now our code is a lot more secure.
If there were multiple things
we needed to permit on this hash,
we could use an array
like you see here
allowing us to set the status and location
on the tweet.
We only need to use strong parameters
and require and permit
when we're setting multiple attributes
when we're creating or updating.
One of the reasons
people use Rails
is to create backend APIs.
It's great for that if you're
building an iPhone app,
an Android app, or just
need to provide a developer
API to your web service.
You might want to supply XML.
You might also want
to supply JSON code.
So let's show you how easy
it is to do that with Rails.
If we want the JSON
representation of our tweet,
we could send in the
URL tweets/1.json.
Then inside of our show method
we need to add some code.
We need to tell
our Rails app what
formats this can respond to.
So first, we're
going to say that it
responds to the format of HTML.
Now that hash sign there,
that's just a comment.
That actually has no
effect on anything -
it doesn't even
have to be there.
But a lot of times
you'll see people
will add a little
reminder that it's
only because we write
format.html that it will try
to render out
show.html.erb by default.
Now here comes the JSON part.
We need to tell our application
that this method responds
to the JSON format.
And when it does, we
want to render out
the JSON representation
of this particular tweet.
And that's all there is to it.
The request goes through,
and it renders out
the JSON representation
of this tweet.
Then if we want this
to respond to XML,
our request might
have 1.xml in it,
and then inside of
our method we need
to write format.xml, render
the XML format of this tweet.
And then that renders back out the proper XML for this tweet.
In a typical Rails
application, you're
going to see a lot of
the same Controller
actions inside the Controller.
Let's go over some of these.
First you have the
index action, which
is going to list all the
tweets, the show action
to show a single tweet, the
new action to show a new tweet
form, the edit action to
show an edit tweet form,
the create action
to create a tweet,
the update action
to update a tweet,
and, finally, the destroy
action to delete a tweet.
As you might imagine,
most of these actions
are going to have views
associated with them that we'll
need to write.
We already wrote
some of the URLs
which will call these actions.
For example, when we
list out the tweets,
remember that edit link?
When we click on
that link, it's going
to go into our
tweets controller,
it's going to call
the edit action.
So inside of that
method, we need
to first retrieve the
tweet that we want to edit,
so we're going to go
ahead and do that like we
did a moment ago,
getting the parameter ID.
And then it's going to go and
render the edit action, which
might look something like
this where we have a form
and we can click that
update tweet button.
But we're not going to
define that in this course.
If we go to slash tweets
in our application
and we get our
listing tweets form,
right now we can click Edit and
Destroy on any of these tweets.
But obviously we don't
want to allow anyone
to delete or edit
anyone else's tweets.
We need to add some sort
of simple authentication
so that when they click on one
that doesn't belong to them
it shows on the screen, "Sorry,
you can't edit that tweet."
How might we do that?
To implement this
authorization, we
need to add some code
to our edit action.
Inside here, we're
going to check
to see if the user's current
session zombie_id is not
equal to the current
tweet's zombie_id.
What is session,
you might be asking?
Well, session works
like a per-user hash.
Every user gets their
own session hash
that we can store things in.
And that's what we usually
do when somebody logs in.
We set a variable
on session that
maybe has their zombie_id in it.
So we're checking to see
if the current user is not
the person who
posted this tweet.
And if they're not, we
need to send a message.
We do that by setting
a flash notice.
And we say, "Sorry, you
can't edit this tweet."
What is flash?
Well, flash is another
one of these helper hashes
that we can use in Rails to
send messages back to the user.
Next, we need to redirect
the user out of this action,
because we don't want
to render the Edit page.
We don't want to
show them that form.
They're not allowed to see it.
So we're going to redirect
them back to the tweets path,
you know that whole
tweets listing page.
redirect_to allows you
to redirect the browser
to a different action.
There's an alternate shorter
syntax for these last two lines
of code.
We can actually write
redirect_to tweets_path
and send them the notice
as a second argument.
Our next step before we
jump into the browser
is we need to
specify in our layout
where we want this
notice to show up.
It doesn't just
show up by default.
So we're going to specify
here if a flash notice exists,
if there's a message waiting
for the user in other words,
then go ahead and print it
out to the screen like so.
Now if we go hit Edit
and our session zombie_id
doesn't match the zombie_id
of the current tweet,
well, it's going to redirect
us back to this listing page
and give us this flash notice.
Sweet.
We did it.
Now if we jump back into
our tweets controller
and we define the
rest of these actions,
we would quickly find
that some of these methods
have a lot of the same code.
Both Edit, Update,
and Destroy need
to look up the current
ID of the tweet
and need to check authorization.
And we don't want to have to
write that code over and over
again.
Remember, Rails is D.R.Y.:
Don't repeat yourself.
So how might we be able to
get rid of that repetition?
If we took a look
inside these actions,
we would see that the first
thing that all of them do
is fetch the current tweet.
Hmm.
So that's duplication
right there.
Let's move that
up into a method.
We're going to
call it get_tweet.
And now we're going to
write some code that
says before every
action call get_tweet.
If we left it like this, this
means before every action
in here it would call
this get_tweet method.
But we don't want it to
happen before every method.
Instead, we only
want it to happen
with Edit, Update, and Destroy.
So we use that code right there.
The other bit of code we
would see over and over again
is the authorization code.
Remember, it looks
something like this?
Let's go ahead and wrap that
in a method called check_auth.
And now we'll have
another before action.
We'll say before
action call check_auth,
again only for Edit,
Update, and Destroy.
And now we've dried up our code,
eliminated that duplication,
and now when we go
into our browser,
when we click Edit on anything
we're not supposed to edit,
we get back, "Sorry, you
can't edit that tweet."
That was a lot of information.
But don't worry, you'll get it.
Go exercise your brain
in the next challenges.
It'll make it more delicious.