[SINGING] Designing emails
can be really tough.
Client preprocessors
can be pretty rough.
To code email for
all their devices,
cut the design into many slices.
Mark it up in tables
with inline style,
with media queries
into one big file.
To win, you'll train
and learn the details —
Unmasking HTML Emails!
Welcome back.
In level one, you learned
how to defeat one opponent
by countering the
preprocessing skills of Gmail.
In this level,
you're going to learn
about multiple opponents, and
their secret weapon, the Word
rendering engine.
In order to defeat
them, we're going
to be recreating our header
using tables for layout.
In this section, we're going to
focus on Outlook 2003 and 2013.
The reason that we're
focusing on both of these
is that they use different
rendering engines.
Prior to 2007, Word
used Internet Explorer 6
for its rendering engine.
2007 and later uses
Microsoft Word.
You can see here that we
get unexpected results
when word processing software
is rendering our HTML and CSS.
Our stars' width is
correct, the styles
are missing from the
background of it,
and our padding is missing
from our paragraph tag.
The reason all this happens
is that Word lacks box model
and positioning support.
Everything that you
can think of that you
would want to use to
create a layout in CSS
is not supported by it.
So we can't set specific
heights, display options,
floats, or positions.
We do get minimal support
for width and padding.
However, they're not supported
on div element or paragraph
tags.
They are, however,
supported on table elements.
You should absolutely avoid
using tables for layout
when building web pages.
However, they're a necessity
for HTML emails because
of the lack of CSS support.
Tables typically use
many semantic elements
to create their structure.
However, this is too
much code for what
we need for our layouts.
We're going to use simplified
tables, in that we're only
going to use the table element,
table row element, and table
cell element.
Many clients apply default
spacing in order to space
out tables.
We're going to need
to counter this.
In order to do that, we're going
to use HTML attributes, border,
cell padding, and cell
spacing, and set them to zero.
With those set, you can see
that we no longer have any space
in between our table cells.
Here's an example
of our simplified
table with our reset
attributes, and this table
is what we're going
to use to contain all
of the content in our email.
Because every
table that we write
has to have these
reset attributes,
sometimes we're going to
shorten that up, like this.
Here, we've taken all of
our content from level one
and put that into a table cell.
We've then added a width
of 600 to our table.
As you can see, the width is
being restricted to 600 pixels.
However, our styles are
still not displaying
the way that we want to.
One example is that the
background styles for our image
are still not
rendering properly.
The Word rendering engine
has very minimal support
for styles on any HTML elements,
except for the table and table
cell.
This means we need to divide our
content into individual table
cells that can be styled.
Let's take a look at how
this would affect our header.
We can create our header as a
single table with three rows,
each with a single cell.
Let's take a look at
how that looks in code.
The first row has a cell
that contains our image,
the second row has a cell
that contains our title,
and the third row has a cell
that contains our paragraph.
We're not going to use
the H1 and paragraph
elements so that we don't have
to counter any styles that
will be added on by clients.
Earlier, we applied our styles
directly to our image tag.
However, to get
the best support we
want to apply our
background color and padding
to the table cell.
Now, you may wonder
why we also don't
move display: block and max-width:
100% up to the table cell.
This is because, while it
wouldn't cause a problem
in this example, if we were
in a multi-column layout,
that could break the
layout in some clients.
Moving on to styling our title,
this would be the same process
as we did earlier,
except that we're
applying all of those
styles to the table cell.
The one nice thing
is, we no longer
have to include
reset CSS in there,
because we're not getting
any default styles applied
to our cell.
Like before, this text has a
combination of layout styles
and font styles, and we're
applying them all directly
to the table cell.
Like before, we're going to
apply our text-align: center
to our containing element,
but now our containing element
is a table instead.
You may wonder why we wouldn't
bring all of our font styles
up to the table level and
allow them to only be set once.
Here are some
examples of some
webmail clients,
and the default styles
that they would
set to table cells.
As we saw earlier,
Gmail will actually
set font family of Arial.
This means that if
we ever have a table
cell without the font
family set on it,
it will default to Arial.
AOL goes one step
further, in that
they would set the color
to black on any table cell
that we do not have
a color set on.
These examples make
it clear that we
need to default to setting
font styles on our table cells.
In level one, we used
margin: 0 auto in order
to center our
containing element.
Now that our containing
element is a table,
we're going to use an
HTML attribute, align,
with a value of center.
With that attribute applied,
our table is now centered.
The final step in recreating
our header with tables
is to add our background.
In order to do this, we're
going to wrap our container
table inside of another
table, and we're
going to apply our background
to that outer table.
Remember, it's always
important to continue
testing how your changes
affect multiple clients.
Here, we can see that our layout
is looking great in Outlook
using Internet Explorer
as a rendering engine,
Outlook using Microsoft
Word as a rendering engine,
and Gmail using Chrome's
rendering engine.
There are some small
differences in the font styles,
but we'll tackle those later.
Now it's your turn to
recreate the header using
tables for layout.