Welcome back to level two.
Now that we've recreated our
header using tables for layout,
we're going to continue building
out the content of our email
using multiple tables and
nested tables to create columns.
It's important to know that each
section should use a new table.
We used one table
for our header.
Now we're going to
add another table
to hold the image
of our luchadores,
and then create a third table,
with two nested tables inside
of it, one each for
each content area.
Here, you can see that we
have our wrapper table,
our header content
table, and we're
adding a table right below
that to contain our image.
If we wanted to create
space between our image
and our header, we would
normally use margin.
However, we get varied results
in clients when using margin,
and outlook.com specifically
doesn't support it.
Instead of relying on
margin to create space
in between the two tables,
we're going to use padding.
Here, we're going to add
padding to the cell that
is containing our image.
Next, we want to
create a table that's
going to have two columns.
Up until this point,
we've used a single cell
to contain our content.
However, we can
use multiple cells
and rely on the default behavior
for them to align side by side.
Knowing that we want
each area of content
to have its own
table, we're now going
to put a table inside the
first cell of our new table.
This new table is where
we'll apply our styles.
For our second
column, we're going
to repeat this same process,
adding another table
within the second cell, and
using that table to style
the content in
the second column.
To ensure that we have
an exact amount of space
in between our
two columns, we're
going to use padding on
the two-column cells.
On the first one, we're going to
add padding right of 10 pixels,
and on the second
one, we're going
to add padding
left of 10 pixels.
This creates a total
of 20 pixels space
in between the two columns.
Styling the content for column
one is a review of the things
that we have already done.
The first and last rows
each contain a cell
with an image for our border.
The second row
contains our date,
and the third row
contains our month.
For the first half of
content in column two,
we're using the same
approach that we just saw.
Moving further
into the table, we
have a row with a cell that
has multiple font styles.
In order to do this,
we need to wrap a span
around each area of text that we
want to be styled differently.
Here, you can see
that we're using
two spans to apply
different font families
and different font sizes.
All of our hard
work has paid off.
Here, you can see that our
layout looks great in Outlook
using IE and Outlook using Word.
Now it's your turn to go
back into the challenges
and create multiple
columns using tables.
And le-- Ugh.
Heh.
Oh, I was so close.
With that "Uh-tribute."
now our table is centered.
Ah, da--