[SINGING] Designing emails
can be really tough.
Client preprocessors
can be pretty rough.
To code email for
all their devices,
cut the design into many slices.
Mark it up in tables
with inline style,
with media queries
into one big file.
To win, you'll train
and learn the details —
Unmasking HTML Emails!
Welcome back to
Unmasking HTML Emails.
This is level three.
In your first two levels,
you had some really tough
opponents.
Compared to them, the
opponent in this level
is going to feel a little bit
more like a sparring match.
Here, we're going to use
media queries to adjust
our layout for smaller screens.
We can see here that
our text isn't as big
as we had expected it to be.
These are set at
very high values,
and yet they're very
small and fitting
in a single line on the phone.
This is because we are setting
fixed widths on our layout.
So we're telling the phone
to display this table at 600
pixels, but it only has 320
pixels available to view it.
What it does to correct this
is, it shrinks the email
down so that everything can fit.
Our solution for
that is to use CSS
to force the width of the table
to be 100% of the container.
This is okay, because
any client that
would support media
queries will also support
putting CSS in a style tag.
Once we create our
rule, we can apply that
to each table using
a class attribute.
You can now see that our table
is taking up the full width,
and our fonts are big like
we expected them to be.
While we do want these styles
to apply to any client that
does support media
queries, we don't want
it to always impact our tables.
We only want this width of
100% to apply when our screen
size is less than
600 pixels, so we're
going to use a media query
with a max width of 600 pixels
to hold our rule.
We want a little bit of space in
between our table and the edges
of the client.
In order to do that,
we're going to move back
up to the table that's
containing all of our content
tables, and on that
first cell, we're
going to apply padding of 10
pixels to the left and right.
If we scroll down to our
two columns in our email,
we would hope that,
on small screens,
they would stack like this.
However, right now,
they look like this.
To fix this, we're going
to add a class with styles
to make each column display
block and width 100%.
We'll then apply that
class to each table cell.
Now you can see that
the two columns are
stacked on top of each other.
Now that the two
columns are stacked,
we have an alignment
issue, and this
is from when we
created a padding
right on the first
cell and a padding left
on the second cell.
We don't need that padding
when we're on a small screen.
Removing the padding can be
done by adding a property
to our stack column
class, and using
our important declarative.
Our two columns are now taking
up all of their available space
with no padding.
Our layout is now
working properly.
We can add some details to
improve the overall look
of the content.
In between our two
columns, we want
to add some vertical space.
You'll probably
recognize this solution.
We add a class to
our media query,
and then apply that
class to a table cell.
Here we can see that we
get inconsistent results
with our font family.
There are a few places where
our font family that we
set of Arial Black is missing.
This is because it's not
available on the system,
so we need to create
better fallbacks.
This would need to be updated
on every cell and span that
contains the font
family Arial Black.
We're showing you
the first cell,
but you would actually
have to apply this
to every cell and span
using that font family.
Now that we have a
good fallback font,
we see that our
text is very big.
It's readable, but we'd like to
have that fit in a single line.
We would follow the
same process as before,
where we create a class
and apply that class
to the table cells.
For this specific content, this
is a long, arduous process.
We're just showing
you one little sample
of an area between 321 pixels
and 375 pixels, and the values
that we would need to fit that
text in one line right there.
In styling an email
across many breakpoints,
you're going to have to
repeat this same process
for multiple properties.
Here's another example
where we adjust padding
for our small screens as well.
Now it's your turn to
jump into the challenges
and improve your
small-screen experiences.
Client that was-- ugh.
I rolled my eyes.
Layout is ac-- ugh.