[SINGING] Designing emails
can be really tough.
Client preprocessors
can be pretty rough.
To code email for
all their devices,
cut the design into many slices.
Mark it up in tables
with inline style,
with media queries
into one big file.
To win, you'll train
and learn the details —
Unmasking HTML Emails!
Welcome back.
This is level four,
and in this level,
we're going to have
a few rematches
with prior opponents.
They've learned your
tricks, so you're
going to have to come
up with some new skills.
We're going to use conditional
styles, conditional content,
and learn how to counter
some client features.
We know that Word-based
rendering engines have issues.
Now we're going to focus in
on correcting a few of them.
We can see that our text
is too big in Outlook 2007
and in Outlook 2010, as well
as having multiple line height
issues in both clients.
Taking a look at one of their
teammates, Outlook 2013,
we can see that it has
some of those issues,
but not all of them, and then
adds additional issues where
line height is being
applied differently
to a border and images.
We need a way to target
individual Outlook clients,
and lucky for us, there
are conditional comments.
The simplest conditional
comment that we will use
targets all versions
of Microsoft Outlook.
If we want to target
specific versions,
we can use operators, like
this GTE operator that
checks for all versions of
Outlook that are greater
than or equal to version 12.
We can use the
conditional comments
to fix the font problems.
We are having problems
with Outlook 2007 and 2010.
We're going to use an
operator to target Microsoft
Outlook greater than
or equal to version 12,
and less than version 15.
This gives us our
versions 2007 and 2010.
Inside our new
conditional comment,
we're going to redefine
our email slogan class,
and apply properties necessary
to get that text on one line.
Versions of Microsoft
Outlook that
use Word as a rendering
engine render line height
differently than browsers.
It's almost like they
knew this, because they
added a vendor-specific
property that we
can use to tell Word to
set our line height exactly
to pixel values.
We're going to use a
conditional comment
to target all
versions of Outlook
using Microsoft Word as
the rendering engine,
and apply this property
to table cells.
Here, you can see
that our line height has
improved on our email titles.
Now that we have our
line height looking good,
we can use that same conditional
comment to add properties
and reduce padding on
specific text areas.
We're going to set the padding
bottom of our email title
to zero to trim up that space.
Because we use this
vendor property
and set our cell's line
height to 14 pixels,
that affects all of the
text within the cell.
This property is not
supported on inline elements,
so we can't apply
it to our spans.
Instead, we need to change our
line height to accommodate all
of the text within the cell.
We would do this by grabbing
the highest value, which,
in this case, is 32 pixels.
Now that we know the size to
use, we can create a class
and apply that to
the table cells.
We fixed all of our
line heights or text,
but there's an unusual case in
Outlook 2013 with empty cells.
If a cell is empty,
Outlook ignores the height.
This doesn't require
conditional comments or fixing.
We just need to add a non-
breaking space in there
for Outlook to
recognize the height.
Outlook 2013 also
has some weird things
in the way it treats
line height for images.
To correct this, we
need to treat images
like they were text, and
apply a font size and line
height that's equal to
the height of the image.
If we look at our
email in Outlook
using Internet Explorer
and Outlook using Word,
we have a very
consistent experience.
Now it's your turn to
use conditional styles
in the challenges.