Welcome back.
In this section, we're
going to continue
adding content to our email.
We're going to use conditional
content to add a button that
will work in multiple clients.
Typically, the way that
we would add a button
is we would add an anchor
tag and apply styles to it.
This would work in
any clients that
use browser-based rendering
engines, but as we've learned,
these styles would not apply
to the Word rendering engine.
What we need is a way to write
code that Microsoft Word would
apply these styles.
If you're interested in
learning that language,
you can look forward to
our future course, Try VML.
Of course, I'm kidding.
We would never
create that course,
and no one really wants
to write this code,
so we're going to do
that in a different way.
Luckily, there's an
excellent resource
on the web created by Stig
at Campaign Monitor called
buttons.cm.
This allows us to create a
button using a GUI to enter
values, and outputs two
versions of a button —
one that would use VML and HTML
that will render in the Word
rendering engine, and
one using just HTML
that would render in all
other rendering engines.
Our first step would be to take
the code from the generator
and put it into a table
cell in our email.
Once that code is in,
we can test and see
that we have a
consistent experience
across multiple clients.
While we do have a
consistent experience,
it doesn't match our design
exactly how we want it to,
so we're going to need
to update the code.
The first area that
we're going to update
is the center tag
within the VML tag.
We're going to add our font that
we want on the button of Arial.
We're going to up the
font size to 20 pixels,
and then add in our text
transform uppercase.
The interesting
thing about this is
that, if you now test
in multiple clients,
you would only see these
changes in clients using
Word as a rendering engine.
This is because
the VML is wrapped
in a conditional tag that
is targeting specifically
Microsoft Outlook.
Updating the style of our
button in the remaining clients
is as easy as editing our HTML.
The one interesting thing to
note is the reason that these
styles get hidden from Microsoft
Word is the special vendor
property mso-hide:all;.
Taking a look at our
email in multiple clients,
we now see that we have
a button that works well
in Outlook using Internet
Explorer and Outlook using
Microsoft Word.
Now it's your turn to use
VML and HTML to create
a bulletproof button
in the challenges.