Welcome back.
In this section, we're
going to complete
the content of our email and
correct some problems that
sneak in along the way.
While you were completing
the challenges,
we added some new content.
We've added a phone number,
an unsubscribe link,
and some contact information.
To do this, we created a
new table with three rows,
with one cell each for
each bit of content.
In looking at the code that
we wrote for the phone number,
we added this as plain text.
However, if we test
it in Apple Mail,
we're surprised to see
that it's now a link.
What's happening here
is Apple's preprocessor
adds HTML to convert
that text into a link.
Now we have a link
in our email, but it
doesn't match our design.
We don't have access to the
HTML that created the link,
but Apple Mail does support
CSS in the style tag,
so we can target all anchor
tags and apply a color to them.
Now that we see this,
we're thinking maybe
it would be better if
this text was white.
We still don't have
access to the HTML
that created this link, but we
know where it's going to be,
so to counter this behavior, we
can wrap the phone number text
in a span and then
use that class
to give that text
a specific style.
Now we can see that
our phone number
link has changed to white, while
the unsubscribe link remained
purple.
This is exactly what we wanted.
Sometimes you want to set font
size smaller than 14 pixels.
Unfortunately, some
clients won't allow this.
To show an example of this,
we have set our font size
to four pixels.
If we were to view this email
in Gmail using Chrome,
we would see that it's rendering
the text at four pixels.
However, if we look
at it in Apple Mail,
we can see that it's not, and
it's adjusted it to 14 pixels.
There are vendor-specific
properties
that exist to override
these defaults.
WebKit and Microsoft allow
a text size adjustment
to none, that would
make it so our text will
render at the specific
pixel value that we set.
With this property
in place, we can
see that Apple Mail will
now render our footer
text at four pixels.
If we look at our email
in Gmail using Chrome,
we can see that there was no
link added to the phone number,
and our font sizes are
the way that we want them.
If we then look at
it in Apple Mail,
we see that we do have our
link, with our white color
and our smaller text size.
Now it's your turn
to tackle some edge
cases in the challenges.
Take that, slide.
Go to your home.
What is he talking about?
Where —
In this section,
we're going to — ooh.
Hey.