[SINGING] Designing emails
can be really tough.
Client preprocessors
can be pretty rough.
To code email for
all their devices,
cut the design into many slices.
Mark it up in tables
with inline style,
with media queries
into one big file.
To win, you'll train
and learn the details —
Unmasking HTML Emails!
Welcome back.
This is level five.
In modern front-end
development, it's very popular
to use a mobile-first approach.
In this approach, you
would create a layout
for small screens using
a minimal amount of CSS.
You would then add
CSS via media queries
as the screen size grew.
Without consistent media query
support in email clients,
we have to take a
different approach.
In this level, we're going
to create a two-column
layout that functions
as a single column
layout without media queries.
Let's first take a
look at why we would
want to use this approach.
So far, we've been able to
use media queries to create
a good experience
on small screens.
However, without
media query support,
the small-screen
experience varies.
In the Gmail
application, we can see
that our email is zoomed out.
In the small-screen
version of outlook.com,
we see that they
don't zoom our email,
but they also don't
force our widths at 100%,
so you would actually have to
pan in order to read the email.
Zoom is the first problem
that we want to fix.
In order to do this, we need
to convert our table widths
to fluid widths.
For our header table, we
would set the width to 100%
and apply a max
width of 600 pixels.
Looking at that in
the Gmail client,
we can now see that
there's no more zoom.
One unfortunate thing about
lacking media query support
is we have no way of
conditionally changing
our font sizes.
Here, we can see that our title
text was set to 74 pixels,
and without media
queries, it's going
to remain that way
in every client.
This is the first problem
that we weren't able to fix.
However, having the text large
makes it more readable than
when it's zoomed out and small,
and this is a good trade-off.
Continuing down the
content of our email,
we would apply those
same styles to our table
that's containing our image.
So here again, we're
applying width of 100%
and max width of 600 pixels.
And this maintains
no zoom in Gmail.
Without media queries, a
table row with two cells
will always align horizontally.
The content in each of these
cells is set to 300 pixels,
causing a total
width of 600 pixels.
Our available area is only
320 pixels, triggering zoom.
We need a way for these
two content tables
to stack on top of each
other without media queries.
Without media queries, table
cells won't stack vertically.
However, there is a way to
make tables stack vertically
if there is not enough
horizontal space,
or stack horizontally
if there is.
The way that we do this is
assigning a value of left
to the align
attribute of a table.
We have our table of content.
We're going to take
that table and nest it
in a table with a width of 300
pixels and set to align left.
We're then going
to take that column
and nest it in a container
table with a width of 100%
and a max width of 600 pixels.
Next, we're going to
repeat the same thing
for the second column.
We have our table for content.
We're going to nest
that in a column table,
and then we're going to
nest both of those tables
in the same container table.
Now we have both of our content
tables stacked vertically
without media queries.
While we're focused on creating
this layout without media
queries, we want to keep
in mind how this is going
to affect our other clients.
Earlier, we had
classes with styles
that forced our
columns to full width
and provided some
vertical spacing.
To make sure that
those are still
available for our
other clients, we
need to add them back
to our tables and cells.
We've fixed our
stacking problem,
but we've created a new problem.
When the horizontal space isn't
enough to hold both columns,
but it's bigger than
each individual column,
the two tables
are going to align
to the left of the client.
If we really want those
two columns centered,
the solution is somewhat hacky.
What we would do is
take each table column
and wrap it in a div.
We would then apply display:
inline-block to those divs.
We can then set
text-align: center
on the containing cell, which
will shift both of those divs
to the center.
We've now run into
another edge case problem.
Outlook.com's preprocessor
removes margin properties
from our inline styles.
However, it won't
remove the property
if you use a capital
"M" for margin.
To fix the layout
for this table,
we're going to change the "m" to
a capital "M" for Margin: 0 auto.
Our multi-column layout is
now working as a single column
layout without media
queries on small screens.
Now it's your turn to make
that happen in the challenges.