Welcome back.
In the last section, we
made a lot of changes
to our layout to
improve small screens.
Unfortunately, this caused a lot
of problems for larger screens.
We're going to go through and
make one more round of changes.
The first problem
that we run into
is something we almost expected.
We know that Outlook
doesn't support max-width.
However, the way
we're going to fix it
is going to be completely
different from before.
We know that this
problem only occurs
in Outlook or clients that
use IE as a rendering engine.
We're going to create a new
conditional comment that
targets Outlook
and IE, and applies
a table only when those
two conditions are met.
We also need to go outside
of our content table
and close the table
that we created.
While we're only showing you the
solution applied to the header,
we have to repeat this process
for every content container
table.
Now we're going to
tackle another edge case
problem in clients using
the Word rendering engine.
When two tables have the value
of left on the align attribute,
Word adds extra spacing around
each table with border spacing.
This extra spacing makes
the two widths larger
than their container, so
they won't stack properly.
This solution is a weird one.
We're actually going to go back
to using two cells to align
our columns, but
we're only going
to do that when clients
are using Microsoft Word,
as their rendering engine.
Here, we're using a
conditional comment
to target all of the clients
using Microsoft Word using
a close cell, and then
opening another cell
to surround our two tables.
Our earlier hack, where we used
two divs with display inline
block actually created
another problem for us.
With our two tables
aligned, they
would be side by side
in our desktop view.
However, display inline block
also adds a little bit of space
around a container.
The solution for this
is, again, very weird.
What we can do is we can
tell those two divs to have
a font size of zero.
This will make clients not
render that extra space
around them, and this won't
impact our content styles
because we have all
of our styles inline
on the table cells
nested within them.
Now we have another
edge case problem
that's specific to one client,
but this time it's Yahoo Mail.
Our entire layout is
being aligned to the left.
If we inspect the CSS,
like we did before,
we can see that Yahoo is
applying margin: 0 to tables.
This overrides our
align: center.
Since this problem only
occurs in Yahoo Mail,
and Yahoo does support
CSS in a style tag,
we can make our fix
in one location.
We're going to add CSS that
targets tables and set
margin: 0 auto with an
important declaration.
This will override Yahoo's CSS.
Our final step is to add
our remaining content
to the bottom of our email.
This is a repetition of
what we've already done,
where we're going to
apply our width of 100%
and our max width of 600
pixels to each table.
It's been a long battle,
but now our email is
looking great in small-screen
clients and large-screen clients,
with or without media queries.
Now it's your turn to make
that final round of changes.
Chk chk, boom.
Oh, this is it.
Ahem.
Oh, man, I was — I
almost dropped the mic.
Pick it back up like, "Aw, sorry."
I'm sorry.
I still need that.