[SINGING] No one's
buying all your widgets,
and you're losing people quick.
They're lost inside
your website, and they
don't know where to click.
If you had learned
about your users,
you'd know where you went wrong.
They'd be engaging
with your content,
and I wouldn't sing this song.
User-centered design helps
improve communication,
navigation, pagination,
Architect your information.
Add a motto or a tagline,
with search so they can find,
A better website is defined
with The Elements of Web Design.
Welcome back to Level
Three, Section One, Forms.
Let's get started.
We need to create our
peer review feature,
and it starts with a form.
So what happens when
we click this button?
So let's create the form.
A great way to start
is by sketching.
Let's add in all the content
we think we need for the form.
OK, great.
So now we've implemented our
form, but there's a problem.
Users are saying that
it's hard to use.
We understand that when
they're looking at the form,
their eyes are moving
in a zigzag pattern.
This is making it hard
to read the form, which
makes it hard for users
to engage with the form.
To fix this, we will move the
labels above the input fields.
This makes it easy
for users to read down
the form in a list-like pattern.
The easier it is to use
the form, the more likely
they will be to engage with it.
The next thing we need to do is
remove any unnecessary fields.
Since the users
need to be logged in
to participate in
the peer reviews,
we don't need to ask for
their first and last names.
We can also remove
the Location field,
since it's irrelevant
to what we're asking.
Removing any unnecessary
fields increases the likelihood
that users will actually
engage with the form.
All right.
Now that we've
simplified the form,
it's much more
attractive to fill out.
We've removed any
unnecessary fields.
We've improved the readability.
And we've added the user
account information to it.
This is a great improvement
to the form's usability.
Making required fields
generally results in users
skipping optional fields.
But by making
optional fields, users
are generally more inclined to
fill out the form completely.
It's a best practice to avoid
creating required fields.
If a field isn't required,
just make it optional.
People are more likely
to fill it out anyways.
If the user runs into
an issue with the form,
an error should be displayed.
Keep in mind that the error text
should be clear and helpful.
Never blame the user.
It's important to
understand the error.
We need to give them
contextual feedback.
There are a number
of ways you can
ask a user for their information
when you're creating a form.
Let's take a look at our form.
It looks like we
have two options.
No, I'd rather not
receive the newsletter,
and Yes, sign me up
for the newsletter.
That looks a little confusing.
We're asking the user
to read this information
and make a decision.
It's less likely that they're
going to click on anything.
This is where explicit
choice comes into play.
Research has shown that when
a default choice is offered,
most people do not
deviate from it.
So in our form, we have
the newsletter pre-checked
for the user, making
far more likely
that the user will opt into it.
The decision has simply
been made for them.
This is called explicit choice.
Now let's think about the
buttons we want to create.
We want to make sure
users understand
why they're clicking
it, and what's
going to happen after they do.
A few things to keep in
mind when creating buttons
are, younger and
older users generally
tend to have a hard time
targeting the mouse.
We want to make sure buttons
are large and easy to click.
For example, the top four
buttons are very big.
They have a lot of space where
you can target the mouse.
Where the bottom two
aren't quite as easy.
There's not a lot of padding
on the one to the right,
and the one to the left
is just an underline.
These are less
likely to be clicked.
We also want to
try and avoid using
confusing or cutesy terms.
Links should be very
clearly labeled,
and users should
undoubtedly understand
what will happen after
they click the link.
And always make sure
you use the hand cursor
when a user hovers over a link,
so as to signify the button
is clickable.
If you hover over your button
and the pointer doesn't appear,
you can use the
cursor property in CSS
if you're familiar with it.
With certain forms, confirmation
messages can be very useful.
But it's important
not to overuse them.
You should never use
a confirmation message
when you can easily give
the user the option to undo.
It's best to use the
confirmation message
when the user is doing
something that's irreversible.
For example on
Skype, the user must
confirm that they want
to mute the conversation.
If the user didn't realize
they muted the conversation,
you may think there's an issue
with Skype and get frustrated.
Apple uses a
confirmation message
when a user tries to
delete older messages
from the messaging app.
This is to ensure users
understand exactly what will
happen when they do
this, and prevent them
from accidentally deleting
information that is important.
We will use a confirmation
message on the peer review form
when users are checking out.
This will let them know
that they are being charged
and will help prevent
user confusion in dealing
with accidental
checkouts and refunds.
We want our users to feel
a sense of accomplishment
when they fill out the form,
so we'll congratulate them.
This is called a mini win.
It will help reassure
them that the task was
completed correctly,
and condition
them to continue the behavior.
Finally, let's talk
about accessibility.
Accessibility refers
to making your web
page more usable for
everyone, including
people with disabilities.
It's a huge subject and
shares responsibility
between design and development.
At the very least, let's
consider these three things.
Never put text in an image.
Screen readers should
be able to tell the user
everything they need
to know without having
to fill out the form.
Avoid low contrast
text and input fields.
It makes it hard on people with
bad vision or color blindness.
Make sure all fields are
laid out in a logical way,
asking for the right
information at the right time.
And always, always,
always test your forms
with accessibility tools.
One of my favorites is Wave.
You can paste your URL
at wave.webaim.org.
It will return a lot
of valuable information
to ensure everyone has a
great experience on your site.
You can also test your site
with the Color Contrast Analyzer
tool.
This looks at all the
colors on your website
and measures the
difference between them.
If there's not enough contrast,
the edges don't light up,
and you may want to increase
the color contrast there.
All right, that's the
end of Section One.
Let's go try some
challenges, and I'll
see you in Section Two.
.