[Singing] No one's
buying all your widgets,
and you're losing people quick.
They're lost inside
your website,
and they don't know
where to click.
If you had learned
about your users,
you'd know where you went wrong.
They'd be engaging
with your content,
and I wouldn't sing this song.
User centered
design helps improve
communication, navigation,
pagination, architect
your information.
Add a motto or tagline, with
search so they can find,
A better website is defined
with the Elements of Web Design.
Welcome back to the
Elements of Web Design.
In level two, we're
going to start
with information architecture.
So let's get started.
Now that our site is
really taking off,
we want to organize our content
into what is called information
architecture.
This is the process of
organizing and labeling
the content to make it
easier for users to find.
Information architecture
is all around us.
If we look at this train
map in the city of Yokohama,
we can see that all train
routes are organized
into color coded lines.
We can also see that all
transfer stations are clearly
labeled, and all stops
are clearly labeled.
This makes it easy
for passengers
to get from one side of
the city to the other.
Airport signage uses
information architecture
to help passengers find
where they need to go.
They do this by putting
the primary action
in the center of the sign using
large text and secondary action
towards the outer sides of
the sign in smaller text.
They also use iconography
to help non-English speaking
people find where
they would like to go.
Our website's
information architecture
needs to help you find
the content they're
looking for in the
four primary ways
that users generally
search the web.
The first is known items-- this
is when we know what we want
and we know where to find it.
The second is
exploratory-- this is
when we know what we want but
we're not really sure where
to find it.
Good labeling comes
into play here.
The third is
unknown-- this is when
we don't know enough about
what we're looking for,
and we're not sure
how to search for it.
And the last is
re-finding-- this
is when we're looking for
content we've already seen.
Let's take a look at
a real-world example
for each of these--
starting with known items.
If I know what
I'm searching for,
I could use A to
Z index navigation
to find the specific thing
that I'm looking for.
Search is also a good tool since
users know specifically what
they're looking for.
And lastly, quick
links can be used
to help users find
what they're looking
for is quick as possible.
If we know what we
want but we're not sure
where to find it, we
can explore the website.
Search, again, is a
great tool for this,
because it helps users find
what they're looking for.
Navigation is important,
because if the user doesn't
know exactly what
they're looking for,
they probably have a
good idea of where to start.
And related information can help
users find content that they
may also be interested in.
If we need to find something
we don't know much about
or where it's located, we might
need to use the unknown search
method.
There are two ways we can do
this-- with simple language
and customer communication.
Simple language
helps users find what
they're looking for through
basic nontechnical labeling.
Customer communication,
or personal communication,
is a powerful tool for companies
that offer complex services.
Clearly giving people the
ability to reach out to someone
and get help puts users at
ease and helps them find
the resources that they need.
The fourth method
for finding content
is re-finding-- looking for
content we've already seen.
If we look at my
Amazon profile, I
could see my recent
shopping history.
Now that we understand
how people find content,
we can start creating
our website's information
architecture.
Often when organizing a site,
people will use Post-it notes
to define and label pages.
This allows them to stick
to post it notes on the wall
and visually see the
site's structure.
Let's take a look at how
to do this on our website.
First, let's
identify our content.
We need to put all of our
pages on individual cards--
like this.
Now, we can sort them into
piles of similar pages.
This is an exercise you
can do with real users.
Have your users organize
the cards in a way
they understand it.
Then have them organize the
piles in order of significance.
Run this test with
five to eight users
and look for
correlating patterns.
With the results
from our users, we
can now see how they see
the site being laid out.
The cards highlighted in
green are our top level pages
and will most
likely be the links
in our persistent navigation.
Now we can start
building our sitemap.
Sitemaps are like a floor
plan for our website.
It gives us a visual
representation
of the site's organization
and how different sections
are linked together.
Support, articles, and
dashboard will make up
our persistent navigation.
And we will use the logo to
link back to the homepage.
Now that our top
level pages are set
as the persistent
navigation, we need
to add the rest of our
content to the sitemap.
This will be the sub-pages that
are under our primary content.
Once you've got a good sitemap
in hand, everyone on the team
can use it to reference and
stay synced up while they're
working on the site.
The hierarchy of the
information in a sitemap
tells us two things--
what sections
will need to be in the primary
and secondary navigation
and where intersection
paths will
need to be added to make
the appropriate sections
of the site accessible.
When you're reviewing
a sitemap, make
sure all important
sections, subsections,
and pages are represented.
Now that our secondary content
is added to the sitemap,
you may ask, how do we add
that content to the page?
The answer is with
secondary navigation.
This navigation only appears
in the article section
of our site.
In this case, our
sidebar navigation
is allowing us to filter our
article feed by category.
If we were to click
on the dashboard,
this navigation would go
away and display the content
associated with dashboard.
One of the biggest
problems on the web
is understanding where you
are in context to everything
that's on the site.
One way to combat
this issue is to make
it clear by highlighting or
using active states on links
of the pages you are on.
These location markers should
be easy for users to see.
When we look at the location
markers on the website,
we can see that it follows
along with the sitemap.
From the homepage, we
enter the article page.
And then from the
article page, we've
gone into the polymer page.
This will help give us
a clear understanding
of where we are within the
information architecture.
So at this point,
our website consist
of three primary sections--
the persistent navigation,
the sidebar navigation, and
the actual page content.
Something you will
want to make a habit of
is displaying the page
title for your web page.
You should always display
a title for your web page.
This should always
match the name
of the length that was
selected to get to that page.
The title needs to
frame the page content
below the persistent navigation
but above the actual content.
Below the page title is
the actual page content--
like these articles
associated with polymer.
This is our visual hierarchy.
We have four main sections--
persistent navigation,
sidebar navigation, a
page title, and then
the article feed.
Here on REI's site, you
can see the same structure.
They have the
persistent navigation
at the top, the
sidebar navigation
to the left, a page title,
and then all the page content
below that.
The benefits of information
architecture are twofold.
They help us organize our pages
and create our navigation--
which we did through
creating the sitemap
and laying out our pages.
And the benefits are they help
our users understand where they
are and where they need to go.
Why don't you try playing
with information architecture
in the challenges.
And I'll see you in
the next section.