Welcome back.
Now let's get started on Section
Two: Designing and Testing.
Now that we have
our two personas,
how do we use them
to create wireframes?
The answer is a user-centered
design approach.
User-centered
design is a process
in which the needs, wants,
and limitations of the user
are given extensive attention
at each stage of the design
process.
Having the personas in
place is the foundation
of a user-centered
design approach.
There are five
primary steps that we
need to take to build
and test a feature.
We need to identify
the primary feature.
We need to understand why a
persona needs that feature.
Then we need to research,
sketch, and test our design.
We will start by identifying
the first feature to build.
So let's take a look at Walter
to see what we can find out.
It appears that Walter
has limited time
to spend on a product, based
on the information provided.
We know he wants to stay up
to date on the latest trends
and breakthroughs, and
he would like the ability
to read stories on his iPad.
Now in June's
persona, we can see
that she wants to read
stories on polymer
and read articles on her phone.
If we look back at the
design brief from Amanda,
we can see that she wants
users to easily find and read
articles.
When we look at our
personas, we can
see that they want
the same thing this
is the primary feature
of the product,
and this is where we will start.
Now we can move to
step two: understanding
why personas need this feature.
So why do our personas
need this feature?
Well, if we look
back at Walter, we
can see that he wants
to quickly find and read
the latest stories,
primarily on his iPad.
And June wants to read stories
specific to her discipline
and typically on her phone.
With this information,
we know they
need to find and read articles,
and mobile's important as well.
Now that we have
the why, let's look
into how other people have
solved it for their users.
Tumblr is a well-established
blogging platform
with a large user base.
If we look at their
site, we can see
that they have a
large search bar
at the top of the screen and
category links in the top left.
Another cool feature
is the ability
to look at your search terms
and find similar searches
that you can explore.
This can help keep
users engaged,
and they're more
likely to find content
that they're looking for.
Below the user section
are filters to help
refine your search.
And search results are displayed
on cards in a four column
layout.
This can help maintain
a recognizable pattern
on desktop and mobile.
Medium is another
well-established blogging
platform.
They rely on search and group it
with user-focused interactions,
like writing a story,
notifications, and a link
to your profile.
Below that, they
encourage you to connect
with a social account, so
they can prioritize posts
from people you know.
A feature like this can
help cultivate a more
personalized
experience for users.
Below that, they
display top stories.
And they use a two column
layout to display their content.
Now that we've done
a little research,
we can start sketching
out our ideas
and testing with our users.
Here's what a rough sketch of
our website might look like.
Sketching is a great way to get
out ideas with low commitment.
And sketching can be
done as a group exercise.
It's important to
design for mobile
when working on features.
You can see ours here.
Designing for mobile will
keep your design focused
on the user's needs and prevent
bloat in the design process.
Wireframes are another
great solution.
They allow us to test
and refine navigation,
see how content lays
out on the page,
study and rapidly refine the
interface in the interactive
elements, and evaluate
the overall effectiveness
of the page layout
and usability.
A few of the more popular
tools used for wireframing
are OmniGraffle,
Sketch and Balsamiq.
These tools can help you
quickly get out ideas
and get them in front of users.
I also want to note
that when testing,
it's important that
you use real content.
Users have to know
what they're looking at
and how to interact with it.
You should never use lorem
ipsum or any kind of filler text
when you're testing
your designs.
Alright,
now that we have some wireframes
to test against, let's
get them in front of users and
start getting some feedback.
We created two designs to test.
First, we need to print
out each wireframe.
In our first design,
we went with a large search
across the top and
a two column layout
with sorting and categories
in the aside div.
In the second design, we
put search and sorting
in the top aligned
navigation with categories
below that in a
secondary navigation.
We also went with a three
column tiled layout.
Now that our wireframes
have been printed,
we are going to conduct
what UsabilityHub coined
the five second usability test.
We will put them in
front of our testers
and ask them these
three simple questions.
What does this feature do?
What do you like about it?
What don't you like about it?
Five second tests
help us understand
peoples' first impressions
of our designs.
The five second test will help
you discover if your design is
understandable and easy to use.
A few things to keep in
mind when testing are,
you're testing the
feature not the user.
Always remain neutral.
Listen and watch.
Never jump in and assist or
lead the user in any way.
Take good notes.
Capture what they do
and what they say.
And try to test between five
and seven users at a time.
OK.
So I've conducted
some user testing,
and here are my results.
I can see that neither
was a home run,
but we could take the
pros from both designs
and create a new design.
You should test through
the entire design process,
from sketching to live code.
Testing the entire
process ensures
that you are on the
right path, and you
are building a product
your users actually want.
Understanding who your
target audience is
and testing your designs
are the core principles
of a user-centered
design approach.
Now let's jump into
some challenges,
and I'll see you
in the next level.