[SINGING] No one's buying all your widgets,
and you're losing people quick.
They're lost inside
your website,
and they don't know
where to click.
If you had learned
about your users,
you'd know where you went wrong.
They'd be engaging
with your content,
and I wouldn't sing this song.
User-centered
design helps improve
communication,
navigation, pagination,
Architect your information.
Add a motto or a tagline,
with search so they can find,
A better website is defined
with The Elements of Web Design.
Welcome back to The Elements of
Web Design, level four, section
one, Mobile Best Practices.
Let's get started.
If we look back at
our personas, we
can clearly see that our users
want a great mobile experience,
but where do we start?
We start by ensuring that
our website is responsive.
If a user visits our web page
on a desktop or a mobile device,
they need to have the
same positive experience.
If you would like to learn
more about responsive design,
I would suggest the Code School
course, Journey Into Mobile.
It's a great starting
point to learn
more about responsive design.
It's important that when
you're creating a mobile app
to go along with
your web product,
that the experience
on the app is
consistent with the
experience on the website.
This will ensure users
know how to use the product
with little explanation.
Although our interface may
change between devices,
we need to ensure that our
content is seamless across all.
For example, when you read
an article on the mobile app,
it appears in the Recently
Read Articles on the web app.
It's important that you
design for the user's context
and not for the device.
We need to look at
the who, what, when,
and where to understand
their context.
For example, we know our
users want to read articles
from the app, but
they would also
like to create and
publish articles,
so we need to build
a feature for that.
One way we can improve
the mobile experience
is by allowing the user to
access the device's hardware.
If they're working
on a article, they
could use the camera
to take a picture
to show what they're working on.
One thing we should think about,
whether we're building a web
app or a mobile app, are icons.
There are really only three
icons globally recognized.
It's the house button for home.
It's the magnifying
glass for search.
And it's the printer for print.
To ensure users understand
the icon, it's best practice
to include a text
label when possible.
A site can really benefit
from having good icons.
Icons make good targets.
They're typically
large enough to touch.
They're also great
because they're
fast to recognize at a glance.
And icons can be
visually pleasing,
and enhance the overall
aesthetic appeal of our design.
When creating
icons, you typically
want to keep the design
simple and always
test them with your users.
Because icons are
generally small,
you don't want to
use a lot of detail.
Here, you can see the difference
between two book icons.
Let's look at the Blinkist app.
It uses clean, simple
icons with labels
to help users quickly learn
and understand the app.
External triggers can
be used to engage users.
They live in the
user's environment
and they help motivate
them to take action.
A good example of
an external trigger
is using the social
buttons on an article
to tweet about what
they've just read.
Internal triggers can play
into external triggers as well.
Say a friend of yours
tweets that they just
read an awesome
article about inks
being used to create circuits.
Since you trust your
friend's opinion,
you're more likely to
engage with that content.
Successful products do a great
job of triggering our emotions.
When I complete a run on
Runkeeper, I feel accomplished.
When someone likes a post
on Twitter, I feel happy.
When I'm uncertain about
a piece of information,
I could always Google it.
Good triggers prompt action,
while vague ones, just
annoy users.
It's important that there's a
clear action to the trigger.
The trigger we set up in our
mobile app occurs when a user
we follow posts a new article.
We get a push notification
that we can swipe,
and it will take us to
the article to read it.
This is a good, simple
personalized message
with a clear action.
Another attribute of
a good notification
is to create intrigue.
One way we can do this is by
notifying users of the most
commented articles of the week.
This will be tempting to engage
with because the user will
want to know what
everyone is talking about.
It plays into our basic
human sense of curiosity.
With all that said, the most
important aspect of the app
is how we onboard users.
If the onboarding is
difficult or annoying,
no one will ever know
how cool our app is.
But there are a
few things we can
do to help users
get into the app
and understand how to use it.
The first thing we need to
do is make the signup process
as simple and easy as possible.
One way we can do this
is to ask for users
to enter their email
if they want to login.
Then we can send them an
email with the link that
logs them into the app.
This way if the user
has a complex password,
they don't have to enter
it with their thumbs.
Another way to add ease to
the onboarding experience
is to create a
self-paced tutorial
where users can understand the
primary functions of the app
and quickly get acclimated.
Make sure you're only showing
the most important actions they
will need to perform right away.
The more advanced features
can be explained later
when the user has become
more familiar with the app.
When utilizing the
tutorial approach,
make sure to use
a big, bold button
to guide users through the app.
Each view should have
one clear primary action
the user needs to take.
Guide them every
step of the way.
Get them excited.
For our tutorial, once
the user is in the app,
we will show them a list of top
thought leaders for the user
to start following.
This will help
personalize the content
to the user's interests.
Now keep in mind a lot of
this is best practices.
It's always important
to remember,
whenever you design
anything, you
want to get it in front
of users, test the idea,
and validate it.
This will ensure that your
product is on the right track.
And this is the basic principle
of a user-centered design
approach.
Thanks for taking The
Elements of Web Design course.
Now we have a few
more challenges,
and I'll see you in
the wrap-up video.
Can I do that one again?
I kind of ended it like, mreh.
What's the motto?
I don't know.
What's the motto with you?
That's a joke.
[LAUGHTER]
If we-- I got the joke now.