Welcome back.
Now let's get started on
Section Two, Navigation.
All right, our site
is doing great.
We have tons of people
writing articles,
but it's creating a problem.
It's becoming harder for users
to find the content they're
looking for.
We could use navigation
to solve this.
Let's first look at our
persistent navigation.
As we pointed out
in the last section,
we should have a logo that
links back to the home page.
We should also have a
top level navigation.
And now we've added
a utility navigation.
This includes utilities
like Login and Contact,
which are links to parts
of the site that aren't
part of our content hierarchy.
It's a good rule of
thumb to only accommodate
fortified utility links in
the persistent navigation.
And lastly, you always
want to incorporate
a search function which should
be at the top of every page.
Now that our persistent
navigation is in good shape,
we should also include
a descriptor navigation
on the home page.
This will give people
coming to the site
the ability to quickly
start interacting
with the content
that interests them.
This is commonly
seen on the web.
If we look at the
Smashing Magazine site,
we can see that they
separate their content
into topics of interest
like Coding, Design, Mobile,
and Graphics.
Spotify does this as
well by organizing
their content into genres like
Mood, Party, Pop, and work out.
When it comes to
the dashboard, we
want to focus on a
verb-based navigation.
This is a good choice
for the dashboard
because a lot of the
links are actionable.
For example, the right link
in the top right corner.
You frequently see
verb-based navigation
on financial sites using words
like Invest, Bank, Trading.
And we also need a
user-based navigation.
This helps users find
content based on their needs.
In our case, we will
define two types
of users, people that
have done a study and need
people to peer
review, as well as
people that want to get paid to
help someone with their study.
User-based navigation
is a common convention
of pricing pages, where
pricing is divided out
based on the user's needs.
On the Litmus the
site, we can see
that they use Premium, Plus, and
Basic to create their user base
navigation.
It's also important to keep
in mind that some users prefer
to use Search or some prefer to
use the persistent navigation.
They're split about 50-50.
In the case of Apple,
they know that some people
want to explore and use
the persistent navigation
while others know exactly
what they're searching for
and should probably
use the search.
Keep in mind that
people are also
influenced by the size
of the search field.
Smaller search fields will
get one word searches,
while longer fields will
typically get phrases.
Now that our site is
easier to navigate,
we need to make it easier
for them to find the content
that they're looking for.
But why is this important?
It turns out research has
shown that people usually
see a very small number of
items in each search result set.
As Jakob Nielsen wrote in
Prioritizing Web Usability,
"Viewing frequency drops off
rapidly after the first page.
More than half of all
users didn't scroll at all.
So only 42% of users
will see any information
on the second screen.
So we need to provide a means
of moving content the user is
looking for to the first page."
One way we can do
this is by sorting.
In our case it is Recent,
Popular, and Most Commented.
It is important to keep in mind
that sorting does not remove
entries from the data set.
It only puts the
data in a new order.
Filtering, on the other hand,
is useful in a different way.
Filtering actually
reduces the amount
of content being displayed.
We will be using our
top six categories
to filter our content.
With both methods
being used together,
users can quickly find the
most popular physical articles
or the most recent polymer
articles in just two clicks.
Another powerful method
for sorting our content
is with meta filters.
This is also called tagging.
When users can tag their own
content with relevant keywords,
it makes the content
more searchable.
We can tag articles with the
writer's name, school, or work,
so that users can just search
articles from Stanford,
or just search articles
written by Jacqueline Olson.
Meta tagging is extremely
powerful on commerce sites
with a lot of content.
For example, Urban
Outfitters allows
users to filter
information based
on the article of
clothing, color, or brand.
This allows users to filter out
items they're not interested in
and moves the items
they are interested
in to the front page.
Even with the ability
to reduce content,
we will still need
a way of dealing
with a large list of content.
Pagination is a
universal option.
So we will use pagination to
give users the sense of control
and make it easier for
them to access the results.
Plus, Google search uses
pagination, like you see here.
We can also use
tabs for sorting.
They clean up the
page and they're
easy for people to understand.
To summarize, top
navigation standards
help users find what
they're looking for.
Descriptor navigations
help with page discovery.
You should use
verbs in navigation
for actionable links.
Navigation links and search
are equally important.
Sorting and filtering help
connect users to content.
And tabs can really
help clean up a page.
So now that we know a little
more about navigation,
let's do some challenges and
I'll see you in the next level.
SERPS uses--
SERPS.
SERPS is such a weird word.
I'm going to be a much
better speaker after this,
I think, without a doubt.
Was that too marble mouthy?
Homepage design.