Welcome back to level three,
section two-- Homepage Design.
Let's get started.
So now that we've hashed
out our main features,
we need to make sure that our
homepage is well-designed.
Users need to be able to
answer these questions.
What is this?
What do they have here?
What can I do here?
Why should I be here?
And where do I start?
Let's start with search.
The search function should
always be prominently featured.
If we look at the Airbnb
site, we find a custom search
with added features to
help the users perform
the necessary tasks to
find a rental property.
On our site, we will add a
standard search field as well
as a search by category feature.
This will allow users to view
content in a specific category.
Next, we want to
create a tagline.
A tagline is generally
towards the top of the page
and explains the product
or service being offered.
If you look at Bohemian
Coding's Sketch 3 landing page,
you can see the tagline,
"Professional digital design
for Mac."
It's also important to
explain the difference
between a tagline and a motto.
A motto is generally
used with bigger brands
and explains the
company's ethics,
whereas a tagline is explaining
the product or the service.
If we look at Ford's site,
we can see their motto,
"Go Further."
Since our site is a
new product, a motto
wouldn't make much sense here.
So we'll go with a tagline.
But before we mock this up,
let's consider one more thing--
a welcome statement.
Welcome statements and taglines
tend to overlap at times.
They are typically
a short description
of the site displayed
in the upper left
or upper center of the page.
They tend to be a more complete
and concise explanation
of the product or service,
and should help guide the user
into the next step.
If we look at the user testing
site, we can see the tagline,
"Give your users a great
experience," paired
with the welcome statement
of, "Get videos of real people
speaking their thoughts as
they use websites, mobile apps,
prototypes and more!"
This quickly explains what the
product is in one sentence.
We will add our tagline,
"Blogging for Chemistry,"
under the logo, and a
welcome statement that
reads, "Read the latest insights
from the chemistry industry
or share your own."
This should clearly explain
what our service is to anyone
who comes to the site.
Another important
feature of the homepage
is the signup and login feature.
This needs to be prominently
displayed on the web page,
and users need to know
why and how to use it.
Both LinkedIn and Facebook
have large signup forms
at the top of the page that
show up when the users are not
logged in.
It's critical for
both of these sites
to make it as easy as
possible to sign up.
Because without an account,
you cannot participate.
While it is not necessary
to sign up for an account
to view our content, it
is still an important part
of our site being that
users need to create
content for others to read.
So we will create a
signup section just
below the header
that is displayed
if the user is not logged in.
Let's give them multiple
ways to sign up,
as well as an option to sign in.
We need to make sure there is
a clear understanding of why
you would create an account.
We can accomplish this with the
"Add to the Conversation" text.
By doing this, we hope to make
it easy as possible for users
to get involved.
Another important
feature of the homepage
is time-sensitive content.
This shows users that the
site is active and updated
frequently.
If we look at The
New Yorker site,
we clearly see The
Latest section.
And every article under
it shows a date and time
stamp that shows how current
or relevant that content is.
On our site, we will add
a "Top Stories" section
to show what
content is trending.
And below each title we
will display a time stamp
to show users that the content
is recent and relevant.
Lastly, you should always
have a way for users
to discover new content
and features without having
to come back to the page.
You can do this typically
with a newsletter.
This will help users to
re-engage with your product
without actually having
to come back to the site.
If you look at both
MaterialUp and CSS tricks,
they both give you the option to
sign up for a newsletter, where
they send you the latest
content to your email,
in hopes of re-engagement.
We will use the same model
by adding a newsletter signup
to our page.
We will clearly state what
you get-- the top five
stories of the week.
It tells users how frequently
they will receive emails--
weekly.
And it tells the user that
they will never be spammed.
Awesome.
We have our homepage.
It's clean, clear,
and straightforward.
Typically, if I go
to a website and I
don't understand
what I'm looking at,
I get frustrated and leave.
But if I go to the website
and it's clear what to do
and what services
they provide, I'm
more likely to have a
successful experience.
Steve Krug calls this "the big
bang theory of web design."
The idea is, the first few
seconds you spend on a website
or web page are critical.
The homepage should be focused.
If you try and get a user's
attention with 100 things,
they won't know what to look at.
Try to focus on one or two
things and direct them to it.
That's it.
We have our homepage.
So let's do some challenges, and
I'll see you in section three.
Good luck.