Hello and welcome back to level
three, section three-- Pricing
Pages.
Let's get started.
Now that our peer review
feature is doing better,
we want to expand the offer
and create tiered pricing.
This will help different
people with different needs
have access to the peer review
and get people on a budget
some different options.
The first thing we need to do
is make sure page influences
decision.
There are a few ways we can
do this-- offer content that
answers a person's
question and helps
to make an informed choice.
Here we can see the
price clearly displayed
at the top and everything that
we will get in a bullet form
beneath it.
We can also influence decision
by offering recommendations.
Users value advice from experts.
We will do this by
clearly displaying
our most popular option
and encouraging people
to get started for free.
We will also describe
the benefits.
People want to know
what's in it for them.
This might include extrinsic
rewards like money, rebates,
or helping users get published.
You can also appeal to a
user's intrinsic motivations
and values.
The TOMS website does this
by helping people in need
with the purchase
of a pair of shoes.
You can also influence users
by reframing the message.
You can push people towards
a specific choice using
scarcity, social motivators,
social comparison,
and social proof.
Here you can see we
will use social proof
by creating testimonials that
display beneath the pricing
table.
Take a look at
Indiegogo's website.
It uses several methods
to influence our decisions
to back a project.
Donation recommendations
are reinforced
with behavioral
science techniques--
like social proof with how
many people have pledged
and scarcity with
a limited time.
After a person has made
the decision to act,
the next step is
to help them follow
through-- making the action
as easy and barrier-free as
possible.
One way is try for free.
Also, you want to shape the
experience in a way that
facilitates action.
Common techniques include
walkthroughs, callouts, ,
and pre-determined defaults.
Here, we are splitting
up our content
into small actionable chunks.
This makes it more
approachable and more likely
that the user will
complete the process.
You can also encourage
people to plan,
set goals, and
commit to actions.
Send reminders.
Follow up on their
progress over time.
It's important that you trigger
actions at the right moment.
Timing is critical.
You should always trigger
people to take an action when
they're able to and want to.
For example, users need
to create an account
to post articles.
So when the new user is
interested in contributing
to the site and clicks
on the "Write an Article"
button, a modal will drop
down asking them to sign-up.
The user is free
to explore the site
and read as much as they want.
And we will never try
to make them sign-up.
Only when they want
to do something
that requires an
account, we we'll
ask for their information.
Two more concepts
we should consider
when creating pricing
pages are the paradox
of choice and
progressive disclosure.
This will help reduce the
cognitive load on the user
and help facilitate action.
The more options
you offer someone,
the harder it is
for them to choose.
This is called the
paradox of choice.
If the user can't
decide, they will leave.
Choosing from three
things is much easier
and will increase the chances of
the user deciding and following
through.
According to Jakob Nielsen,
on the average web page,
users have time to read
at most 28% of the words
during an average visit.
20% is more likely.
Progressive disclosure means
that we reduce page details
to a minimum.
We only show the basic content.
This will help users
facilitate their objectives.
Make sure to only show what
is necessary on each screen.
If people are
making a choice, try
to only show them
enough information
to allow them to
make that choice.
Avoid the tendency to over
explain or show everything
all at once.
Most people will only
consider the choices
they are offered-- even if
other possibilities exist.
All choices should
bring the user closer
to their goal as well as ours.
Then we can help lead a
user to the choices that
are best for them.
Keep these things in mind
when creating your own pricing
pages.
Now let's get our hands
dirty with some challenges.
And I'll see you in level four.
Good luck.