[SINGING] No one's
buying all your widgets,
and you're losing people quick.
They're lost inside
your website, and they
don't know where to click.
If you had learned
about your users,
you'd know where you went wrong.
They'd be engaging
with your content,
and I wouldn't sing this song.
User centered design,
helps improve communication,
Navigation, pagination,
Architect your information.
Add a motto or a
tagline, with search
so they can find a
better website is
defined with The
Elements of Web Design.
Welcome to The
I'm Paul Hershey.
As the internet
has evolved, users
have become less tolerant of
bad design and bad experiences.
And this is why we need to plan
our experiences for end users.
That's where the elements of
web design come into play.
In this course, we'll cover
persona creation, user testing,
site organization, wire framing
and sketching, navigation best
practices, form design,
home page best practices,
pricing page design, and
mobile design best practices.
If you haven't taken Code
School's Fundamentals of Design
course, I'd highly recommend it.
It's not necessarily a
prerequisite to our course,
but it will give you the
fundamentals of typography,
color, and layout.
Taking both courses
together will give you
a better overall understanding
of the design process
when you build your
products and websites.
This is neither a
UI or a UX course,
though I do want to make a
distinction between both.
UX, meaning user
experience, is the process
of understanding the end user.
It's creating personas, creating
experience maps, and testing.
On the other hand, UI,
or user interface design,
consists of interaction
design, usability design,
visual hierarchy,
and icon design.
As well as color
and type choices.
There's a lot that
goes into this
to ensure that a
product or service is
easy to use and understand.
This course will be
a very broad overview
of both of these disciplines.
It would be impossible to
teach them both in one course.
My goal is to give you
a common sense approach
to design when you're creating
your websites and products.
With that said, let's
get started on level 1
with personas.
Our client Amanda has brought
us a new project that she
would like us to design.
It's called ChemCraft.
It's a social blogging platform
for the chemistry industry.
We will spend this course
building out her design.
She wants to make sure that
users can easily find and read
articles, can publish
their own articles,
have a dashboard where
they can see analytics,
and have the ability to
purchase peer reviews.
So with all that
information, are
we ready to start wire framing?
Probably not yet.
Before we get started,
we need to understand
who our target audience is.
So let's figure this
out for ChemCraft.
We need to understand things
like how much work experience
they have, what their
professional background is,
what their needs
and interests are,
how they are currently
trying to meet those needs,
and when and where they
would be using this service.
So how can we gather
persona information?
Well, we can start by
making educated assumptions,
we can conduct a focus group,
we can interview current users,
or we can work with a
third party research team
to gather information.
But we don't have any users yet.
So how can we gather this
information and organize it?
The answer to this is to
create an assumption persona.
Once our site is up and running,
and we have real users on it,
we can use the data and
get a clear understanding
of who our users actually are.
Nevertheless, it is
always a good idea
to create assumption personas
at the beginning of a project.
They will help to
ensure that we're
creating a product
for someone we
believe will actually use it.
So what exactly is a persona?
Personas are descriptions
of users within our target
audience.
They generally consist of
a pull quote, an image,
a fictitious name, a job
title, demographic information,
and their goals
and their concerns.
So let's start with a
pull quote and an image.
The image helps us
identify with the user,
and the quote should summarize
their needs and goals
into a single sentence,
and it gives a persona
further personality.
Next, we have attributes
like a fictitious name, age,
job title, and general
demographic information.
This will help us better
understand the user's lifestyle
or work situation.
We also need to think
about the end user's goals,
or what they want to accomplish
when performing tasks
on our website.
This will help us identify their
needs when we build features.
And finally, we have
a list of concerns.
These, like goals,
are typically a list
of product related concerns from
the end user's point of view.
We're going to try
to answer questions
like do they have to use
this product for work?
Or will it primarily be
used on a mobile device?
So here's our first persona.
Walter.
He's a department manager, and
he's married with two kids.
We know his reasons
for using the site are
to read about the
latest trends, share
his knowledge with the
chemistry community,
and find people to conduct
peer reviews for him.
We also know he has a need
to co-author articles, read
articles from his iPads,
and he wants the ability
to save articles to read later.
I went ahead and
created another persona.
June.
So we can see that June
is an intern at DuPont,
and is single with no kids.
She is fresh out of college
and new to the industry.
We also know that she
wants to follow her peers,
get paid to participate
in peer reviewed studies,
and comment on articles
she is reading.
And she wants the ability
to read and write articles
from her phone as well as be
alerted when new articles are
written by users she follows.
When creating personas, you
want to have a minimum of two,
and a maximum of four.
Personas give
everyone on the team
a common understanding of
who they're designing for.
When you're working
on your product,
you can ask questions
like will this
solve the problem for June?
Or does this solve a
pain point for Walter?
They make them feel
like real people.
Some other benefits
of creating personas
are they separate
you from your work
and prevent you from assuming
you know what the user wants.
They also allow you to
empathize with the user's needs.
They provide a focus
for decision making
and help to
personalize the user,
and they create a
shared understanding
of who the user is.
So hopefully you can see that
it's very valuable to do this
before we create
our wire frames.
Countless organizations
make decisions every day
based on personas they've
created for their users.
From Apple to Southwest,
and Nike to Spotify.
Now let's work on
some challenges,
and I'll see afterwards.
Good luck.