Welcome to ES2015, The
Shape of JavaScript to Come.
I'm Carlos Souza
and in this course
we're going to be learning
some of the new features
of the JavaScript language.
[SINGING] We've
had about enough,
JavaScript is getting tough,
ECMAScript is the solution.
Join the revolution.
Let your objects fill the
gaps inside the Sets and Maps,
use OOP patterns to the max.
New class and module
syntax, const and let
will do the thing, to
stop the hoisting.
With pure arrays struggling
is destructuring.
Keep your JS nice and
lean by using ES2015.
This is definitely
not an intro course.
For those of you that don't feel
comfortable reading and writing
JavaScript
applications, I highly
recommend you check out the
JavaScript Road Trip series.
It's a slower-pace course
that goes over the very basics
of the JavaScript language.
Once you're done with that you
come back and take this one.
ES2015 is the most
extensive update
to the JavaScript language since
it was first published in 1997.
You might have heard
it by the name ES6,
but this is the old name.
The committee decided to
change from version number
to year of release to better
reflect their plans to release
a new version every year.
Which is great news
for us developers.
This course covers some of
the most interesting features
of ES2015, like new ways to
work with variables, functions,
more efficient data
structures, and a new way
to write asynchronous code
using generators and promises.
By the end of this
course you'll be
writing faster, cleaner,
and less error-prone
JavaScript code.
So let's get started.
In this level we'll
look at two new ways
to declare variables,
using let and const.
We'll see how they can help us
write better JavaScript code
and work around some well
known JavaScript gotchas.
Throughout this course
we'll be looking
at features of a forum.
This should be a pretty
common application for most
of us that use the web.
We'll focus on
client-side JavaScript.
In other words JavaScript
that runs in browsers.
But most of the code
that we see here
should be supported
by server-side engines
like Node.js.
The first feature that
we're going to be looking at
is loading user
profiles on the sidebar.
Here we can see the page for
the topic and In Hybrid Moments,
Give me a Moment.
This page is initially loaded
with a post and its comments,
those two are the most
important parts of this page.
Once the page loads we'll
run a JavaScript function
called loadProfiles
that builds the sidebar
widget with the users
active on this post.
This list allows
us to quickly see
who's participating
on this current topic.
The function responsible for
building this sidebar widget
is called loadProfiles.
We load this function in our
HTML page using the script tag,
and call it passing an array of
names, Sam, Tyler and Brook.
Now let's take a
look under the hood
and see how this function
might be implemented.
The loadProfiles function
takes one argument, userNames.
And the first thing we
do in the function body
is check to see if there's
more than three userNames.
If so, then it
might take a while
to grab all the information
for these users.
So we want to show a
spinner on the page
with a message that says,
"This might take a while."
This is so we can give our
users immediate feedback
on an action that might take
longer than they expect.
Otherwise, if it's not
more than three users
then it should
load pretty quick.
So we'd give it another message
saying, "Loading Profiles."
Then we'll do some
stuff after that,
like fetching the
user information,
and building the sidebar widget.
But for now let's just
focus on this initial part.
Now let's go ahead
and run our function,
giving it in an array with
four names, Sam, Tyler,
Brook and Alex.
And here's each step of
how this function is run.
First, because we have four
names it executes the if block.
Inside this block we
declare and assign [a value]
to the loadingMessage
variable, and then
call the _displaySpinner
function.
The else block is
never executed,
and none of the code inside
the else block is run.
However if for
some reason we try
accessing the
flashMessage variable
from after the else block, then
our code will print undefined.
The C icon here indicates
a console output.
The fact that we see undefined,
as opposed to an error message
or have a program
crash, might be
surprising for some of us
coming from other programming
languages.
The same thing happens if we
try accessing flashMessage
from inside the if block.
We wouldn't get an
error, just undefined.
So why does this happen?
Why are we able to
access variables
from outside the blocks where
they were defined, and not
have our program crash?
Well, one thing that JavaScript
does before executing our code
is move all the
var declarations up
to the top of the nearest
enclosing function,
on what is known as hoisting.
Before our loadProfiles
function is executed,
it's transformed
into code like this.
And this explains
why variables declared
using var inside blocks,
like if, and else,
are still accessible from
outside those blocks.
They're visible to the
entire function, which
might cause some unexpected
behavior like the one we just
saw.
One way you can fix this
unexpected behavior is
using a new keyword for
variable declaration, let.
The let keyword
defines new variables
scoped to the nearest
block, not function.
So we go back to
our loadProfiles
function and change our
variables to use let.
Unlike var, variables declared
with let, are not hoisted
to the top of the function.
Now that we're using let,
loadingMessage and flashMessage
are trapped inside of
their nearest curly braces.
If we go back and run the
loadProfiles function again,
we'll see that flashMessage is
never declared or initialized.
Now if we try and
access this variable
from outside the conditional
we'll get a ReferenceError.
And this behavior
is closer to what
we would see in other similar
programming languages.
And now it's time for
you to learn by doing,
by practicing some of the things
we learned in the challenges,
and I'll meet you back
here in the next section.