Welcome back.
And in this section,
we'll learn how
let can help us solve
some issues in for loops.
When using var and
for loops there's
some unexpected behavior.
Let's take a look at
the following code.
Still inside our loadProfiles
function we have a for in loop
that goes over each name
on the userNames array.
For each run it assigns an
array index to the i variable.
Then it calls the underlying
_fetchProfile function
which accepts two arguments.
First, is the server URL
to grab the user's profile.
And the second is
a callback, that's
run when we get a response
back from the server.
Inside our callback we
access i again, and log
a message to the console
saying which users
info. was just fetched.
When we run our function with
the same four names, Sam, Tyler,
Brook and Alex,
we see an output
that looks like this:
"Fetched for Alex"
is repeated all four times.
Kind of weird, let's take
a look at why this happens.
Again, the var i
declaration is hoisted
to the top of the function.
And the same i
variable is shared
across all runs of the loop.
So we have a single i variable,
and for each run of the loop
it is modified before
calling the function
and registering, not
executing, the callback.
On the first one i is assigned
the value of the first index 0.
_fetchProfile is called,
and the first callback
is registered,
again, not executed.
This happens three
more times, and i is
incremented on each iteration.
Only after _fetchProfile
has been called four times
do the callbacks
start being executed.
To clarify where
the bug lives let's
look at this execution
in another way.
When callbacks begin
to run, the i variable
holds the last value assigned
to it from the for loop.
All callbacks are
accessing the same element
at index 3 of the
userNames array.
And this is the reason
we see the last argument
of the function
repeated all four times.
This is a very tricky
problem, but it's
easy to solve simply
by replacing var
with let inside our for loop.
Using let, a new i variable
is created on each iteration.
And there's no sharing between
different callback functions.
From the i variable the
first callback function
will always read 0.
The second will always read 1,
the third will always read 2,
and the fourth
would always read 3.
Remember let declarations
are not hoisted.
A new i variable is created
for each run of the loop,
and each callback receives
their own version of i.
We run our function
again, and it now
prints all four names properly.
Fetched for Sam,
Tyler, Brook and Alex.
Lastly, variables declared
with let can be reassigned
but cannot be redeclared
within the same scope.
Here we declare flashMessage
and assign it the string "Hello".
Then we re-assign a
new string, "Goodbye".
We are allowed to do that.
However if we try redeclaring
the flashMessage using
let again we'll run
into a TypeError.
Now from inside a new scope,
like the loadProfiles function
for example, we can
declare a new flashMessage
with let and will not
run into an error.
Now it's time for you to
exercise what we just learned
about let in the challenges.
And I'll see you in
the next section.