Welcome back.
In this section, we'll
look at the second type
of variable declaration
added to JavaScript, const.
Let's go back to
our loadProfiles
function and take a look
at the very first line,
if userNames.length
greater than 3.
The number three in
this if statement
is what we call a magic number.
It's a literal value, but
it doesn't tell us much more
than that.
It's not clear, especially when
someone other than the author
reads this code.
If we need to use the
number 3 multiple times
in this function,
then we'll be making
things even more confusing.
We'll need to remember the
reason behind each occurrence
of the number 3.
For example when we read this,
if someValue greater than 3.
Is this 3 serving the same
purpose as the one above,
or is it different?
If we change one, should we
change the other one as well?
You see where I'm
going with this?
By using magic numbers
like this we're
making this code hard to read
and even harder to maintain.
We can fix this by using
a new declaration, const.
const allows us to create
a read-only named constant.
Let's go ahead and create
a const name MAX_USERS,
and assign 3 to it.
We'll then use our new
constant in the first if block,
and right away we can tell
our code reads much better.
Although we are technically
writing more code,
it is code that is much,
much easier to understand.
As it turns out,
the second block
is using the number 3 with a
completely different purpose.
It is not using 3 to refer
to the max number of users,
but instead to the
max number of replies.
So we'll give it its own
constant, MAX_REPLIES.
Now if we have to go back and
change either one of those,
it is clear that we don't
have to change the other.
Constants cannot be reassigned.
In this example we're
initializing MAX_USERS to 3.
If you try assigning
a new value, 10,
we'll probably run
into a syntax error.
The outcome will vary depending
on the JavaScript engine
that you use.
Some will raise errors while
others will silently fail.
But one thing is for sure,
MAX_USERS will always be 3.
Another important
feature of constants
is that they must be
assigned an initial value.
In this example we first
declared MAX_USERS,
and then assign the value
to it on the following line.
This code will generate an
error and will not work.
Similar to let, constants
are block-scoped,
which means that
they're not hoisted
to the top of the function.
In this example MAX_REPLIES is
declared inside the if block.
If we try and access
it from outside the
if block we'll get a ReferenceError
saying MAX_REPLIES
is not defined.
In most cases let and const
will behave very similarly.
When deciding to choose
one versus the other
consider the semantics.
In this code, we used let for
loadingMessage, currentAge,
and totalCost.
Because those are
variables whose values
can be changed throughout
the lifespan of this program.
On the other hand we use const
for MAX_USERS, SEPARATOR,
and ALLOW_EDIT, because
we want to express
the idea that those are values
that should not be changed.
We've reached the
end of this section.
Now it's your turn to practice
working with constants
in the challenges.
Kind of weird, why does
this happen? [GIGGLES]
Kind of weird, right?
Why does this happen?
To practice-- to
practice some constants.
To practice-- to practice come
constants and the challenges.
Yes.