[SINGING] We've
had about enough,
JavaScript is getting tough,
ECMAScript is the solution.
Join the revolution.
Let your objects fill the
gaps inside the Sets and Maps,
use OOP patterns to the max.
New class and module syntax,
const and let will do the thing,
to stop the hoisting.
With pure arrays struggling
is destructuring.
Keep your JS nice and
lean by using ES2015.
You're watching ES2015 The
Shape of JavaScript to Come.
I'm Carlos Souza,
and in this level
we're going to be
looking at what's
new in functions, the foundation
of the JavaScript language.
Let's go back to our
loadProfiles function.
This function is expected
to be called with an array.
In this example we pass in an
array with three elements, Sam,
Tyler and Brook.
When used properly like this,
this code works just fine.
However what would happen
if we called this function
with no arguments, or with
an explicit undefined?
Well, if we did that
our code would break.
We would see a TypeError
similar to this one,
Cannot read property
'length' of undefined.
Looking at the
function signature
we can notice that
this function expects
to be called with one argument.
JavaScript, however, will
allow us to call this function
with no argument.
And the only reason
we'll see a TypeError
is because we're trying
to access the length
property on the argument.
When calling a function
with no argument,
userNames will
actually be undefined.
And that's why we see an error
message that looks like this,
Cannot read property
'length' of undefined.
In this example it is
not always safe to assume
that userNames will always
be assigned a value.
Historically, a common
practice for validating
the presence of function
arguments in JavaScript
was to check for them
as the very first thing
in the function.
In this example we are using
typeof to check whether
the type of userNames is
different than 'undefined'.
If so, then return the
value from that variable,
otherwise we return a
default value of empty array.
This solution works, but as
you can see it's pretty verbose
and doesn't scale well for
checking multiple arguments.
We could make this
code better by using
a new feature of JavaScript
called default parameters,
which help move default
values from the function
body to the function signature.
We'll go ahead and assign
an empty array to userNames.
This empty array
will be used in case
no argument is passed when
loadProfiles is called.
Now if we called loadProfiles
with no arguments,
it will set a default
value of empty array.
The default value
for userNames will
be used even if we
explicitly pass in undefined.
Now let's take a look at a
new function, setPageThread.
Here's how we call it.
The first argument is
a string, in this case,
"New Version out Soon!".
The second argument is what
we call an options object.
This object holds configuration
settings set by the caller
to be used by the
rest of the function.
It's pretty common to use an
options object as an argument
like we see here.
We want to avoid accessing
the options object
properties directly, so we
assign each of its properties
to local variables in order to
make our code easier to read.
We can give our options
object a default value
using the new default
parameters feature we just
learned, in case this
function is called
with just the first argument.
That's cool, but one issue
with using the options
object like this,
is that it makes
it tempting to keep adding more
options than what we really
need.
From the caller's perspective
it's also unclear
what the options are just
by looking at the function
signature.
And while it is a good practice
to assign to local variables
instead of reading directly
from the options object,
it does force us to write
boilerplate code like this.
A new feature in
JavaScript allows
us to get around this issue
it's called named parameters.
Using named parameters
for optional settings
makes it easier
to understand how
a function should be invoked.
Here's what it looks like.
We use curly braces to group
all the available options
or functions [it] accepts
as variables.
Now we can tell which options
are available by looking
at the function signature.
It makes your code
easier to read.
Each option is available
from the function
body as a local variable.
So we don't have any more
of that boilerplate code.
From the caller's perspective, the
function call remains the same.
Let's call it and
see what happens.
For the first argument we'll
use the string "New Version out
Soon!"
And for the second
argument we'll
pass an object, just
like before, with values
for popular, expires,
and activeClass.
Each property of the
object is matched
with the available options
in the function signature.
And then we can see the values
printed out to the console.
Now what happens when the call
setPageThread but leave out
some of the available options?
Well, let's see.
We'll call the function
with the first argument
just like before.
But for the options object,
which is the second argument,
we'll only pass a value
for the popular option,
setting it to true.
We'll leave out expires
and activeClass.
When we run our code the
function does not error out,
it prints out undefined
for the two options
that we didn't specify a value
for, expires and activeClass.
It is not safe, however,
to omit all arguments
when invoking a function with
named parameters like this.
If we tried calling
setPageThread
with just the first
argument and nothing
for the second argument,
we'll run into an error.
The error we see
will vary depending
on where we run our code.
Running this code
through Babel and Node,
which we'll talk more about
at the end of this course,
gives us a TypeError.
To get around this is
actually pretty simple.
Remember default parameters?
That's exactly what
we'll use here.
The entire second
argument to setPageThread
will be assigned an empty
object as the default value.
Now when we call
this function again
with just the first argument we
can see it doesn't raise errors
anymore, it prints the value
for the first argument,
and undefined for
all named parameters.
Now it's time for
you to practice
some of the things we've
learned about functions
in the challenges, and I'll
see you in the next section.