Welcome back.
In this section, we'll look
at some more new additions
to functions.
But before we do that, let's
look at another feature
from a web forum, tags.
Tags are a very useful
feature in web applications
that have a lot of reading
content, like web forums.
They allow us to
perform faster searches,
and to filter results
based on specific keywords.
Tags basically help
us find stuff faster.
So let's see how we
can add tags to our forum.
We want to write a displayTags
function that looks like this.
It should except one
tag, songs, or two tags,
songs and lyrics, or three,
songs, lyrics, bands, or four,
or as many tags as we give it.
This type of function is
called a variadic function.
Variadic functions can accept
any number of arguments,
and they're not
specific to JavaScript,
so you might have used
them in other languages.
In previous versions
of JavaScript,
here's how we could have
implemented our display tags
function.
In this example, we're
using the arguments object,
which is sort of like an
array, but not an actual array,
and corresponds to all arguments
passed to the function.
We use a for loop to grab
each individual element
and pass it to the underlying
add topic function.
Assume this function
is defined elsewhere,
and all it does is add
a tag to the HTML page.
There's a couple of
issues with this function.
First, the function
signature isn't clear.
Looking at the
function signature
gives us the impression
that this function
takes no arguments,
when in fact, it accepts
a variable number of tags.
Second issue is that any changes
to the function signature
will break our code.
If we wanted to
change our function
to accept a target element
as the first argument,
this would break our for
loop, since index zero
of the arguments object
would no longer be a tag,
but the target element instead.
Now let's see how we
can solve these issues.
We'll use a new
feature of JavaScript
called rest parameters,
which allows
us to represent an indefinite
number of arguments
as an explicit array argument,
a real array this time.
This way, changes the
function signature
are less likely
to break our code.
Let's add a parameter to
the function signature
and name it tags.
We'll prefix it with these
three dots over here.
The three dots make
tags a rest parameter,
which means it will group
all arguments we pass
to this function into an array.
Now from the function body,
tags is just a regular array.
So we can use the for
loop just like before,
navigate through
each individual tag,
and pass it to the
_addToTopic function.
Now that we have our tags rest
parameter, any changes made
to the function signature,
like adding a target element
as the first argument, will
not affect our for loop.
It's worth noting that
rest parameters must always
be the last parameter
in a function.
In the second example, we're
grabbing every argument
passed to the display
tags function,
except for the first one.
Now we can use our
display tags function
to add one tag, songs, or
multiple tags, songs, lyrics,
and bands.
Let's say that the list of tags
is now available from an API
and we'll use an
existing function,
getRequest, to get the
list of tags for each topic.
Don't worry about
the implementation
of this function,
all we need to know
is that it takes the URL
path as the first argument.
In this example, we're
grabbing all the tags
for the topic with ID 17.
What we get back in
our callback function
is a response object
with the tags property,
except that it gives us
the tags as an array.
If you remember, our
displayTags function
is a variadic
function, which means
it accepts individual
arguments, not an array.
So how can we convert
the array that we
get back from the server
into individual elements
as expected by the
displayTags function?
We can do that using
the new spread operator.
The spread operator allows us
to split an array of arguments
into individual elements.
The syntax for the
spread operator
should look very familiar.
It's those same three dots we've
used before in rest parameters,
but this time used in the
function invocation, not
function definition.
Prefixing the tags array
with these three dots
in the function call is the
same as passing each element
in the array as an individual
argument to display tags.
Think of the spread
operator like opening up
a box of thinks, extracting
each element out of that box,
and passing them as individual
arguments to the function
where it's being used.
To recap, the syntax for rest
parameters and spread operator
look pretty much the
same, the three dots.
However, rest parameter is
used in function definitions,
whereas the spread operator is
used in function invocations.
Same syntax, but
behaves differently
depending on where it's used.
Now let's go back
and take another look
at the code used
for displaying tags.
Our code works, but here's
a problem, every time
you want to add
tags to our page,
we must remember to
type all this code.
Functions like get request
and display tags are actually
implementation details.
Our lives would be a lot
simpler if all this logic were
encapsulated inside a new
abstraction, or JavaScript
object, like TagComponent.
JavaScript objects can help
keep your code encapsulated,
organized, and easier to
write automated tests for.
Now, let's see how it can
write our TagComponent object.
We start with a
constructor function
function called TagComponent.
This function accepts target
and urlPath as parameters
and assigns them to
instance properties.
Then, using the
function prototype,
we add an instance
method call render.
Property set on the
constructor function
can be accessed from render,
and from any other instance
method on TagComponent.
In this example, we are
reading this.urlPath
from render, which was set
from the constructor function.
To use our new component,
we create a new object
with new TagComponent.
Passing the target element
and URL path as arguments,
and assign the return
object to a variable
we call tagComponent.
Then, from the
tagComponent object
we can call the render method.
So far so good, but let's
touch on a well known issue
in JavaScript.
If you've written
enough code, you've
probably been bit by this one.
From inside the
getRequest callback function,
one might think we can call
other properties from
TagComponent like
this.targetElement,
but we actually cannot.
The problem is that the scope
of the TagComponent object
is not the same as the
scope of the callback run
by getRequest.
So this.targetElement from
inside the callback does not
exist, and returns undefined.
There's a new type of
function in JavaScript
that we can use to fix this
bug, it's called arrow function.
To change our current function
to an arrow function is simple.
We get rid of the
function keyword,
keep the data
argument in params,
and use these two
characters, that
look like an arrow, the equal
sign, followed by the greater
than symbol.
Arrow functions have what is
called a lexical binding, which
means that they bind to the
scope of where they're defined,
not where they run.
Our new arrow function binds to
the scope of the TagComponent
object.
Now, when we call
this.targetElement
we'll be
referring to the same
this.targetElement that was
assigned from the constructor
function.
When we run our code we
will see it successfully
renders the tags to the page.
That's it for this
level, now it's
your turn to practice your
knowledge in the challenges.
And I'll see you
in the next level.
Do you remember-- Almost
singing Michael Jackson there.
Do you remember the time--
Do you remember the
time-- That we can
use to fix this abominable bug.
It's a very strong
term, like kids
will be crying and [BLEEP].