[SINGING] We've
had about enough,
JavaScript is getting tough,
ECMAScript is the solution.
Join the revolution.
Let your objects fill the
gaps inside the Sets and Maps,
use OOP patterns to the max.
New class and module syntax,
const and let will do the thing,
to stop the hoisting.
With pure arrays struggling
is destructuring.
Keep your JS nice and
lean by using ES2015.
You're watching ES2015, The
Shape of JavaScript to Come.
I'm Carlos Souza,
and in this level
we'll be learning
about additions
to object and template strings.
The first thing that we're
going to look at in this level
is a new way to create objects
and assign property values.
Here we have the
buildUser function,
which takes two
parameters, first and last.
It appends first and
last names putting
a blank space in the middle.
And then assigns it to a
local variable, fullName.
Finally, it returns an
object with the first, last
and fullName properties,
and whose values
come from local variables
with the same name.
To use this function we call
it with any two arguments,
like "Sam" and "Williams"
and get back a return
object with properties
for first, last and fullName.
Notice that when
creating the return
object from the function body
we tend to repeat names a lot--
first, first, last,
last, fullName, fullName.
That's kind of a lot of code.
We can make this code shorter
with the new object initializer
shorthand.
Instead of repeating
names we can
use a single name
that is used for both
the property and the value
that's being assigned.
As you can see way cleaner.
Now this only works when both
properties and values have
the same name,
but you soon start
noticing that this
happens a lot in our code.
If we run our buildUser
function again,
we can see our
code still produces
the same expected output.
We can create objects
like this anywhere,
not just in function returns.
Here we create an object with
the name, age and friend
properties.
And assign it to
the user variable.
From this variable we can
call properties name, age
and friends.
As you can see in this
example, creating an object
using the new
syntax is basically
half the size of what it used
to be with the old syntax.
Now let's look at the other
side of the operation,
reading properties from objects.
In this example the buildUser
function returns an object.
And from this object we
read the first, last
and fullName properties.
And assign them to local
variables with the same name,
first, last and fullName.
We can now write this
code in a much better way
using object destructuring.
We use a single let
declaration, which
takes a list of property
names in curly braces.
This automatically assigns
to the first, last
and fullName local
variables, the values
from properties with the same
name from the object returned
from buildUser.
If we run this code
we can see it still
prints the expected output.
Not all properties have to
be destructured all the time.
Sometimes all you
might want is a subset
of the properties returned by
an object, and that's fine.
We can select the
properties that we want.
In this example we don't
need first or last.
So we can leave them out
and ask just for fullName.
Or we can grab only last
and fullName from the return
object leaving first out.
Let's do a quick recap
since these two things
look very much
identical, but are
used in different scenarios.
We use the object
initializer shorthand
to assign from variables to
properties on a new object.
And object destructuring is used
to read from object properties
and assign two local variables.
Now let's look at something
that you and I certainly
do quite a lot.
Which is assigning a function
to a property on an object.
Our buildUser function now takes
three parameters, first last
and postCount.
It assigns to fullName
just like before,
and sets the ACTIVE_POST_COUNT
constant to 10.
The return object is using
the new object initializer
shorthand we've just learned
for first, last and fullName.
And then returning a
method called isActive.
We create this method by
assigning an anonymous function
to the isActive property.
As you can see, we're adding
a function to an object
by specifying the property name,
and using the full function
definition, including
the function keyword.
In this new version
of JavaScript
we can make this code
shorter and easier to read.
Here's how I can assign the same
function using a new shorthand
notation.
The function keyword
is no longer necessary.
All we need is the name of the
property followed by parenths
and then curly braces.
That's it, less characters
and easier to read.
One last thing that we can
change in our buildUser
function is how we create
the fullName string.
There's a new
feature in JavaScript
called template strings
which are string
literals with support
for string interpolation.
Instead of appending
strings using the plus sign,
we can wrap the entire text with
backticks, not single quotes.
Any JavaScript that needs to be
evaluated inside of that text
is wrapped in dollar
sign and curly braces.
Template strings
can also be used
to make multi-line text
easier to work with.
Here, this very
long text can all
be placed between two backticks.
Any new line characters
will be preserved.
If we print this
to the console, we
can see that it outputs the
text and preserves the newline
characters.
Now it's your turn to head
over to the challenge section,
and practice some of the things
we've learned about objects
and template strings.