Welcome back, and
in this section,
we'll be looking at a new
function added to JavaScript
called Object.assign.
In order to understand the
importance of Object.assign,
we're going to look at one of
its most useful use-cases,
writing flexible and
reusable functions.
In this example, we want to add
a countdown timer to our forum.
The timer will display
the time left for users
to undo their post after
they've created it.
Once the time's up, they
can't undo the post anymore.
Let's look at some code.
We'll write a countdown
timer function,
but we'll use it not only
in our forum web app,
but also in other
web apps that we
work on that require a
similar timer functionality.
For that to happen, the
countdown timer function
needs to be able to
accept different settings.
It needs to be able to be
called as simple as this,
taking a target element
as the first argument,
and the initial time in
seconds as the second argument.
And it also needs to be called
like this, with the first two
arguments, and then an options
object with specific settings,
like a container class.
Or, passing a custom
container class,
specifying a different
timeUnit, and also
a new timeoutClass.
As you can see,
our function needs
to be invoked in
many different ways.
These custom options will vary
depending on the application.
For functions like
these that require
high level of customization
and reusability,
it is OK to use
an options object
instead of named parameters.
Too many named parameters can
make functions hard to read.
Having a single options
object makes it easier
to customize to
different applications,
so we'll give our
countdown timer
an options object as its last
argument after target and
timeLeft.
When calling this function, some
options might not be specified,
so we need to account for
that using default values.
Here's one way we can do that.
We read each property
in the options object,
and then do a short-circuit
evaluation with a double pipe, ||,
to check for the presence
of a value passed in.
If a value wasn't
specified, the property
will return undefined, which
evaluates to false so it
will give it a default value.
In this code, the
container property
has a default value
of ".timer-display".
timeUnit has a default
value of "seconds", and so forth.
This works, and you've probably
seen and even written code
like this many times.
The issue here is that we have
default strings and numbers
all over the place, which makes
this code hard to understand
and difficult to maintain.
Let's fix this.
The first step into
making this code
better is to use a local object
to group all the default values
for this function.
We'll call our object defaults.
Its properties will be named
after each of the options
our function accepts, and we'll
assign them their default
values.
Grouping default
values in an object,
like this is a common pattern
found in many large projects,
and can help us write
more idiomatic JavaScript.
We're still not done
here, but we can already
tell that this code requires
a lot less brainpower for us
to understand.
The next step is to
merge the options passed
by the caller of this
function with the existing
values in defaults.
It needs to work like this.
We'll grab our default
properties assigned
to the defaults
variable, and then
merge them with the properties
from the options object passed
by the caller of the function.
One very important detail is
that all duplicate properties
found in the options object must
override those from defaults.
Lastly, we'll assign the results
to a variable called settings.
So this is what
we want to happen,
but how can we write this code?
Well, this is where
Object.assign comes in.
Object.assign copies properties
from one or more source objects
into a target object.
It takes care of the
whole merge process
that we just talked about.
In this code, we'll
use a blank object
as the target object, which
will be modified and used
as a return value
for this operation.
Next, we can pass as many
source objects as we'd like.
This is a variadic
function, which you might
remember from the last level.
The source objects
remain unchanged,
and we'll look at the importance
of this in just a second.
Finally, we assign the result
value to the settings variable.
settings will hold
merged properties
from defaults and
options, and this
is the object we'll refer
to throughout the rest
of the function.
A neat feature of
Object.assign is
that in case of duplicate
properties on source objects,
the value from the last
object on the chain
will always prevail.
In this example, duplicate
properties from options3
will override properties
on options2.
Those from options2
will override
options, and et cetera.
Object.assign is
pretty flexible,
and there's a couple
of different ways
that we might see it being used.
First, we could use an existing
object as the target object,
like defaults.
While it would still
perform the merge correctly
with the options object, it
would also mutate defaults.
This means that
after the merge, we
would not be able to go back
and access the original values
for defaults.
Then, there's a style
that we use in our code.
We give Object.assign
a blank target object,
followed by source objects.
Then we store the return
value of the function call
in a new variable,
which we call settings.
Now this one feels right.
It's a more functional
approach, because it
avoids relying on side effects
while it still preserves
the original default values.
A variation of this version
is declaring a blank settings
object first, and then using it
as a target for Object.assign.
Here, we have the benefit
of the original value
not being changed,
but I'm personally
not a fan of this
style of coding,
because it relies on side
effects being applied
to the settings variable.
We're not using the
return value, which
feels to me a little sketchy.
We've mentioned accessing
original default
values a couple of times.
Now, let's look at when
that might be useful.
Preserving the
original default values
gives us the ability
to compare them
with the options
passed as an argument
and act accordingly
when necessary.
In this example,
right after we merge
options using Object.assign,
we check the value of timeUnit.
settings.timeUnit
holds the value
that will be used
throughout the function,
and defaults.timeUnit holds
the original default value.
If the caller of this function
passed the value for timeUnit
that's different than
the default value,
then this comparison
will return true.
If that happens, we run
a conversion function.
This would not
have been possible
if we didn't have access to
the original default values,
and that's why it's important
to keep them around.
Finally, let's run our
countdownTimer function.
We'll pass it a target element.
This one, with a
class of .btn-undo.
Give it 60 seconds, and
specify a container class
of .new-post-options.
Inside our function, the value
used for the container option
will be the one passed as an
argument, '.new-post-options',
and not the default
timer display.
Since we didn't pass
anything for timeUnit,
it will keep its default
value of "seconds".
If we print these
to the console,
we'll see ".new-post-options"
options and "seconds".
That's it for this level.
Now it's your turn to exercise
your knowledge [of] Object.assign
in the challenges.
Awesome.
The honey boo-boo GIF, awesome.