[SINGING] We've
had about enough,
JavaScript is getting tough,
ECMAScript is the solution.
Join the revolution.
Let your objects fill the
gaps inside the Sets and Maps,
use OOP patterns to the max.
New class and module syntax,
const and let will do the thing,
to stop the hoisting.
With pure arrays struggling
is destructuring.
Keep your JS nice and
lean by using ES2015.
You're watching ES2015, The
Shape of JavaScript to Come.
I'm Carlos Souza,
and in this level,
we're going to be looking at
some new additions to arrays.
When working with
arrays in JavaScript
it is not uncommon to access
elements by their index.
In this example we have
an array of users:
Sam, Tyler and Brook.
We assign them to local
variables a, b and c using
their indices 0, 1 and 2.
This works but it's more
code than we actually need,
and also if we add more
elements to the array
we'll need to remember
their exact index in order
to read their values, which
doesn't scale very well.
A new feature of
JavaScript called
array destructuring
allows us to rewrite
this code in a much better way.
Instead of accessing
elements by their index
we declare our local
variables in a single line
of code between square
brackets and assign them
our users array.
JavaScript will try to match the
number of variables on the left
to the number of
elements in the array.
As you can see
variables a, b, and c
were signed Sam,
Tyler and Brook.
It's so easy to understand
and requires a lot less code.
Win win.
If there are any values
we're not interested
in we can discard them during
the assignment operation.
If we don't need a
store say, Tyler,
we can declare the first
variable a, then a comma,
followed by a blank
space, followed
by the second variable b.
We run this code and
we see "Sam Brook".
Tyler was discarded.
Poor Tyler.
We can do some pretty
neat stuff by combining
array destructuring
with rest parameters.
Remember them?
Here we assign the first
element from our array, Sam,
to the local variable, first.
Then we use rest parameters
with that three dot syntax
to assign all the remaining
elements from the array
to the rest variable.
When we print this out we can
see the single element Sam
and the array ["Tyler","Brook"].
Another place we can
use array destructuring
is when returning
values from functions.
We can use them to assign to
multiple variables at once.
Here we have a function
called active users which
returns an array
with three elements:
Sam, Alex and Brook.
When we run this function we
can assign the return value
to a variable, active.
We print out active
to the console
and we see the array
["Sam", "Alex", "Brook"].
So far nothing new.
Pretty straight
forward, but watch this.
Instead of using a
local variable active,
we can instead use
array destructuring
to assign to multiple
individual variables at once.
The variables a,
b and c now hold
the value for each of
the strings in the array.
We print this out, we see the
strings Sam, Alex and Brook.
Now, let's look at a new
type of loop in JavaScript
called for of which can be used
to iterate over property values
and offers a better way to work
with arrays and other iterable
objects.
We'll learn about those
later in this course.
Here we have an array of
names, Sam, Tyler and Brook.
To loop over its elements we can
use the well known for in loop.
For in returns the
index for each element.
We assign it to the index
variable on the loop
and then use the index to access
each element from the names
array.
So first, we're assigning the
index value to a variable.
And then second we
are using that value
to read from the array.
Two steps.
Now with for of, we don't
need to go through the index
anymore.
It reads each element
directly from the array
and assigns it to
the name variable.
That's only one step.
So using for of we can loop
over arrays writing less code.
So can we use for
of with objects?
The short answer is no.
We cannot use for of with
plain JavaScript objects out
of the box.
If we try doing so we run
into an error like this.
The error says post[Symbol.iterator]
is not a function.
Interesting.
Let's talk about where
this error is coming from
and how we can use it to
help determine whether or not
an object can be
used with for of.
Essentially, in order to be able
to work with for of, an object
needs a special function
assigned to the
Symbol.iterator
property.
Checking for the presence of
a function in this property
is the simplest way
to know whether or not
an object works with for of.
As we can see here
our names array
has a function inside the
Symbol.iterator which means
we can use it with for of.
Now, let's run the same check
on a plain JavaScript object,
post.
If we check for the typeof of
the Symbol.iterator property
from the post object we'll
notice it prints undefined.
Nothing is assigned
to the property,
so the post object will
not work with for of.
Lastly, let's take a look at
Array.find, a new method that
makes it easier to
find a specific element
in an array which satisfies
a provided testing function.
Here we have an array of
objects with login and admin
properties.
First user is Sam,
who is not an admin.
Second user is Brook,
who is an admin.
Then Tyler, who
is also an admin.
In order to find the first
admin in the users array
we can call the find method
and give it a testing function.
Notice that we are using
an arrow function here.
In this case, not for a
scope reason, just because it
reads better this way.
Inside the testing function
the first return value
that evaluates to true will
cause the argument object
to be returned.
In this example, when
user.admin returns true,
the find method returns
that user object.
We assign it to
the admin variable
and print it to the console.
We can make our arrow
function even shorter
by omitting the parentheses for
the user parameter, the return
keyword, and the curly braces.
As we can see, the
output is still the same.
Now it's your turn to play with
some arrays in the challenges.