Welcome back.
In this section, we'll
be talking about Maps.
Maps are a data structure
composed of collections
of key/value pairs.
They're present in many
other programming languages
and are useful to store simple
data, such as property values.
A Map stores collections of
unique keys mapped to values.
Each key is associated with
one and only one value.
In order to find a
specific value in a Map
we give it its key and then
receive the value in return.
JavaScript developers
are first exposed to Maps
through objects.
And while it is possible to use
objects as key/value stores,
there are some issues with that.
The biggest issue when
using objects as Maps
and what may get some
of us by surprise,
is that its keys are always
converted to strings.
Let's take a look at an example.
We have two different
objects, user1 and user2.
Next we have an object
called totalReplies,
which we'll use to map users
to the total number of replies
they have on our forum.
user1, Sam, doesn't visit
the forum very often
and has only five replies.
We'll use the user1 object as
key and assign it the value 5.
Tyler on the other
hand, is pretty active
and has 42 total replies.
We'll use the user2 object as
key and assign it the value 42.
Now watch what happens
when we try reading values
from totalReplies.
When we use user1 as key the
value that we get back is 42.
And then user2 also returns 42.
So although we're assigning
two different values
to each one of the keys, the
last value that we assign
overrides all the
previous values.
This happens because
behind the scenes
JavaScript converts both
objects to this string,
object Object between brackets.
And this is why we
see 42 printed twice.
If we ask for the total list
of keys in the totalReplies
object using Object.keys,
we'll see an array
with only one element,
that same string,
object Object within brackets.
To get around this
issue we should
stop using JavaScript
objects as maps right now,
and start using a new
data structure called Map.
The Map object is a
simple key/value data
structure that allows any value
to be used as key or a value.
When we use objects
as keys on a Map
they are not
converted to strings.
Let's change totalReplies
from an object to a Map.
To add entries to a Map
we use the set method,
which takes two arguments,
a key and a value.
Just like before, we'll assign
5 to user1 and 42 to user2.
We can read the
values from a Map
using the get
method, which takes
a key as its only argument.
When we call get with
user1 we receive 5,
and when we call get
with user2 we receive 42.
As you can see these
two values are properly
assigned to different keys.
So we mentioned that we should
stop using JavaScript objects
as Maps.
However, there's one exception.
Most of the time you will
want to use the Map data
structure, which is
when keys for the Map
are unknown until run time.
In this first
example we use a Map
to store the most recent
post for each author.
First, we create a new Map
and assign it to recentPosts.
Then, we call a createPost
function defined elsewhere
in our code and give it a callback.
Inside the callback we
use the recentPosts
Map to store the
message for this author.
Here we don't know
what data.author
is going to be until we
actually run this code.
On the other hand, when
storing pre-defined settings
it is OK to use an object, like
we do here with userSettings.
In this code the keys per page
and showRead are pre-defined.
We know exactly what they are
just by looking at this code,
We should also use Maps when
all keys are the same type
and all values
are the same type.
For entries on our
recentPosts Map
we use data.author for keys
and data.message for the value.
Suppose we had another
place in our code
that also added entries
to recentPosts,
like a WebSocket
connection receiving push
notifications from the server.
In this example an event
coming in for a new post
sends data in the same format
as your previous callback.
So we can also use
data.author as key
to store the value
for data.message.
Assuming responses from the
API are always the same,
all keys from our recentPosts
Map will be the same type,
and all data associated with
them will be the same type too.
This helps keep
our Maps consistent
and easier to work with.
On our object example both
our keys are the same type.
However, perPage is
assigned a number, 15.
And showRead is assigned
a boolean, true.
Two different types.
So using an object here instead
of a Map is our best choice.
Another neat thing about Maps
is their ability to be used with
for...of.
In this example, we
create a new Map,
mapSettings, and add
three entries to it.
We can loop through Map
settings using for...of.
And each run of the loop
returns a [key, value] pair
for an entry in the Map.
Inside our for loop we'll
use array destructuring
to assign to both the key and
value local variables at once.
When we run this code, we can
see that it successfully prints
each entry to the console.
JavaScript has also added
a special kind of Map
called a WeakMap, where only
objects can be used as keys.
Primitive types such as
strings, numbers, and booleans
are not allowed to
be used as keys.
In this example, we have a
user and comment objects.
We create a new WeakMap and
assign it to mapSettings.
We can use the same set and get
methods to store and retrieve
values.
But if we try using
a string as the key
we'll run into an
error like this.
Primitive data types
are not allowed
to be used as keys on a WeakMap.
One difference between
a WeakMap and a Map
is that all methods on
a WeakMap require a key.
Methods like get, which
return an entry, has,
which checks for the
presence of a key
and returns true if there's
an entry for that key or false
if there isn't, and delete,
which removes an entry
and returns a boolean based
on whether that entry existed.
Another big difference is that
WeakMaps are not iterable.
If we try using them for...of
we'll run into an error like
this.
MapSettings[Symbol.iterator]
is not a function.
So what's the deal
with WeakMaps?
Why should we use them
in the first place?
Well, WeakMaps are
better with memory.
They're called weak because
they hold a weak reference
to the objects used as keys.
In this example, we have a
userObject and a userStatus
WeakMap.
The user object is
being used as the key
to one of the entries in the [WeakMap]
and assigned the value, "logged".
Now after some other
function is finished
and when nothing
else in our code
is referencing the user
object, this object
becomes eligible for
garbage collection.
Once that happens the user
object is removed from memory
and the garbage collector
knows to come and remove
the entry associated with that
user object from the WeakMap,
as well.
Freeing up even more memory.
So WeakMaps are memory efficient
because they don't prevent
the garbage collector from
collecting objects currently
used as keys, but that are no
longer referenced from anywhere
else in the system.
That's it for this section.
Now it's your turn
to play around
with Maps and WeakMaps
in the challenges.