Welcome back.
In this section we'll
be talking about Sets.
But before we understand
the need to use Sets let's
go back to arrays and look
at some of their limitations.
Arrays in JavaScript are super
simple and very easy to use,
but one thing that they don't do
is enforce uniqueness of items.
In arrays duplicate
entries are allowed.
In this example, we
have a tags array.
We use the push method
to add the strings
"JavaScript", "Programming",
"Web "and then "Web" again.
If we print the length of this
array we'll see it prints four.
It includes "Web "there twice.
If we need to prevent
duplicate entries
from being added to a
collection, instead of arrays
we can use Sets.
Sets store unique values of any
type, whether primitive values
or object references.
Here we create a new
Set object and assign it
to the tags variable.
We can use the add method
to add elements to a Set.
So we add the strings
"JavaScript", "Programming",
and then an object with the
version property set to "2015".
Then we try adding the
string "Web" there twice.
The second "Web" is ignored.
We can verify that by checking
the size property on the tags
object.
Total items is 4 not
5, so our last attempt
to add "Web" to the Set
was completely ignored.
Set objects are iterable so
we can use them with for...of
and destructuring.
Here we use for...of to read
each tag off of the tag Set
and print them to the console.
Then we extract
elements from the Set
using the destructuring
assignment.
We grab the first four
values of the tags
Set and assign them to the
variables a, b, c and d.
We print them out to the
console and everything
works as expected.
Similar to WeakMaps we also
have WeakSets which are more
memory efficient type of Sets.
Here we create a new
WeakSet and assign it
to the weakTags variable.
If we try adding a
string to it we'll
see an error like this
one because only objects
can be added to a WeakSet.
A WeakSet gives us two
more methods to use.
has, which returns
whether or not
an object is part of the
weak Set, and delete,
which removes an existing
object from the WeakSet.
Again, WeakSets only allow
objects, which allows entries
on a WeakSet to be garbage
collected once they're not
being used anywhere
else in the system.
WeakSets differ from Sets
in a couple different ways.
They cannot be used with for...of
and they offer no methods
for reading values from it.
If we try using
them with for...of we
run into an error like this one.
Well, if we can't read
values from a WeakSet,
when should we use them?
To illustrate a good use
case for using WeakSets
let's take a look at another
feature from our forum.
Here in this page we
see a list of posts
and what we want to do here
is add a different background
color to the posts that have
not yet been read by the user,
like this first one.
Doing this can
help users identify
unread posts much quicker.
Now let's see how
we can implement
this feature using WeakSets.
Now, one way that we could
implement this feature
is by changing a property on
each post object, like isRead.
Once a post is clicked, we
Set this property to true
for the given post.
Then in the section that
renders the list of posts,
we check for the isRead
property on each post.
If a post has not
been read yet then
we can add a new CSS
class to each DOM element.
The issue with this
code is that we're
changing or mutating a
property on each post object
unnecessarily.
Using immutable
objects in JavaScript
is a common practice that should
be favored whenever possible.
Doing so makes your code
easier to understand
and leaves less room for errors.
Now, let's see how we can use
WeakSets to improve this code.
Although WeakSets
cannot return entries,
we can use them to create
special groups from existing
objects without mutating them.
We'll start by creating a WeakSet
named readPosts, then
each time a user
clicks on a post
we'll add the post object
to the readPosts WeakSet.
No changes are made to
the post object itself.
Now back to the function that
renders the post, instead
of checking for
a property we use
the has method to check
whether an object is
present on the WeakSet.
If not, then
we add the CSS class
to the post element.
So while we can't read
values from a WeakSet,
we can use them to
create groups of objects
and later check for the presence
of those objects in the group.
That's it for this
level, now it's
your turn to test your knowledge
about Sets in the challenges.
And start using a new data
structure called a Map.
[LAUGHING]
To fix this, we should
stop using Maps.
To stop this we
should stop using
JavaScript objects
as maps right now
and start using a
new data structure
added to JavaScript
called drum roll Map.
Do that one again.