[SINGING] We've
had about enough,
JavaScript is getting tough,
ECMAScript is the solution.
Join the revolution.
Let your objects fill the
gaps inside the Sets and Maps,
use OOP patterns to the max.
New class and module syntax,
const and let will do the thing,
to stop the hoisting.
With pure arrays struggling
is destructuring.
Keep your JS nice and
lean by using ES2015.
You're watching ES2015, The
Shape of JavaScript to Come.
I'm Carlos Souza,
and in this level,
we'll be talking about classes.
We seem to be doing pretty
good with our web forum,
and some companies
have approached us
with the interest of adding
sponsored advertisement.
Here's how this
feature would look.
On the sidebar, there
would be a small widget
below the list of active users.
Nothing too intrusive,
just a small HTML snippet.
Let's see how the code
for this could look,
first using functions.
A common approach for
encapsulation in JavaScript
is using a constructor function.
The SponsorWidget
constructor function
takes a name, description,
url, and we assign them
to instance properties
with the same name.
Then, we have a render function.
The best way to add this
function to SponsorWidget
is via its prototype.
And invoking the SponsorWidget
function looks like this.
We call SponsorWidget with new,
assign it to a temp variable,
and call its render function.
This returns the
final HTML snippet.
This works, but adding
functions to the prototype
requires quite a bit of
coding and some repetition.
We can do better.
Using the new class
syntax, we can
write object oriented JavaScript
code in a much simpler way,
that looks familiar to those
coming from other object
oriented languages.
At first, I was a little
skeptical, but turns out,
now I use this
syntax quite a lot.
To define a class, we use
the class keyword, followed
by the name of the
class, SponsorWidget.
The body of the class is the
part between the curly braces.
Instance method
definition in classes
look just like the method
initializer shorthand
in objects.
Now, let's talk
about the constructor
your method which is a method
for creating and initializing
an object.
The constructor
method runs every time
a new instance is created
with a new operator.
Inside the constructor
method is a good place
to assign the instance
variables that we want to access
from other instance methods.
To create an instance
of SponsorWidget,
our code looks just like before.
We invoke the SponsorWidget
function
with the new keyword,
which returns
a new SponsorWidget
object that we
can call the render method on.
Properties, or
instance variables,
set in the constructor
function can
be accessed from all other
instance methods on the class.
For example, we set
this.url at the constructor,
and read it from
the render function,
using the same
this.url name.
Same thing with
instance methods.
_buildLink can
be called by other methods
with this._buildLink.
Currently, there are no access
modifiers in JavaScript,
like private and protected, like
we do have in other languages.
So in case you're wondering,
prefixing a method
with underscore is just
a popular convention
that we use to indicate
that a method should not
be called from its public API.
In this example,
_buildLink
is being called from
inside the SponsorWidget class,
because it's a private method.
The class syntax is not
introducing a new object model
to JavaScript.
It's just an alternative
to write the same code
over the existing
prototype based model.
It's what we call
syntactic sugar,
because it's just a sweeter
way to write the same thing.
One benefit of using
the new class syntax
is that we can use
class inheritance
to reduce code repetition.
Child classes can
inherit and specialize
code that's defined
in parent classes.
Here, we can see that
Widget class sets
the this.baseCSS property,
and it has the parse instance
method.
The SponsorWidget class is a
specialization of the Widget
class, and inherits this.baseCSS
and this.parse.
PromoWidget and NewsWidge
behave the same.
We call these three classes
subclasses of the Widget class.
To create a subclass, we
use the extends keyword,
which causes a class to
inherit methods and properties
from a parent class.
In this code, we can
see the class widget,
with its constructor method
and the parse method.
Then, SponsorWidget,
which extends widget,
defines its own
constructor method.
And the render method.
The render method can
access this dot parse,
and this dot base CSS, which
are defined on its parent class.
These are inherited properties.
All child classes must
call the super method
as the first line
in the constructor.
This method causes the
parent classes constructor
to be invoked.
We pretty much always
want this to happen
before any code in our
child class starts to run.
From outside the
constructor method,
we can also use super,
but as an object.
It holds a reference to the
object from the base class.
So it can call methods
defined up on the chain
like we see over here.
Super dot parse is calling
the parse method defined
on the widget class.
That's it for this section.
Now, it's your turn to play
with classes and the challenges,
and I'll see you in a bit.