Welcome back.
In this section, we'll
learn about modules.
Up until now the simplest way
to load the JavaScript libraries
on our page was to add them
to the global namespace using
script tags.
Let's look at this example.
Here's a snippet of HTML where
we import all the JavaScript
libraries our app depends on.
We use the HTML script
tag with the src
attribute pointing to the
file where each library lives.
In this example
we're loading jQuery,
underscore, and another
library we call flash-message.
To use these libraries
we simply reach out
to the global namespace
and access the $
for jQuery, the _
for underscore and the flashMessage
function from our
flash-message library.
Writing programs that
depend on global variables,
like we're doing
over here, means
being vulnerable to
unexpected side effects
and potential naming conflicts.
Let's see how we can use
the new JavaScript module
syntax to write better code.
We'll start by creating a
module for our flashMessage
function, which, as
the name implies,
will be responsible
for displaying
flash messages on our web page.
We create a file called
flash-message.js.
Inside this file we define
an anonymous function,
which takes a message
as an argument
and calls the global
alert function,
passing in the message.
To make this function
available to the outside world
we use the export
keyword, which exposes it
to the module system.
Then, we specify the
default type export
which is the simplest
way to export a function.
Next, we'll create another
JavaScript file called app.js
which will serve as the entry
point for JavaScript code
and where we'll import
other modules from.
Now, to import these modules
we'll use the import keyword,
then specify a new
local variable,
in this case flashMessage,
and use the from
keyword to tell the
JavaScript engine
where the module can be found.
The flashMessage variable
now holds the function
imported from the
flashMessage module
so we can use it to invoke the
function passing in the string
"Hello".
Because our flashMessage
module is using the default type
export we could've named
our flashMessage variable
anything.
Now, to run this code we
go back to our HTML page
and load both the flash
message module and app.js.
And as we can see,
the string "Hello"
is successfully
alerted to the page.
Now you might be thinking
that this HTML is pretty
much the same as it was before.
However, in this
version, we're not
adding to the global
namespace, which
makes our code more
encapsulated and protects us
from any potential
naming conflicts.
From inside our modules
we have total control
over what we expose
to the outside world.
Now, let's go back
to flash-message.js
and declare another
function, logMessage.
Simply declaring this function
does not make it available
outside of this module.
It's encapsulated, hidden
from the global namespace.
The default type export
limits the number of functions
that we can export
out of a module.
So in order to be able to
export any number of functions
we need to change the type of
export that we're using here.
In order to export multiple
functions from a module
we can use named exports.
So let's do that in the
flash-message module.
First, we'll give our first
function a name, alert message.
Now, we have alertMessage,
which uses the alert pop up,
and logMessage, which
uses console.log to print
the message to the console.
Then, we'll remove
the default type
and use just the export
keyword.  This way
we can use named exports.
Back to app.js, our functions
are ready to be imported.
This time they must be
assigned to variables
with the same name, as
we can see over here.
They need to be
wrapped in curly braces
and separated by a comma.
Once we import
them we can simply
call these two functions.
Now, if we load our
HTML page again we'll
see both the alert
pop up and the output
printed to the console.
Another way that we could
import our functions
is by importing the
entire module as an object
and then calling each
individual function
as a property on that object.
Here we use import * to
import the entire flashMessage
module as an object and use
the as key word to tell it
which variable to
assign the object to,
in this example flash.
Then we can call the
alertMessage and logMessage
functions as properties
from the flash object.
Lastly, I want to show
you a quick refactoring
that we can use to make this
code even easier to read.
Notice here that we're
repeating the export keyword
for each named function
that we want to expose.
We could make this
code shorter by moving
these multiple exports to
a single export statement.
Export can take
multiple function names
inside curly braces and
separate it by a comma.
This version involves
a little less typing
and it's easier to read as well.
Our code in app.js
remains the same.
We still import our
functions just like before.
Now it's your turn
to practice working
with modules in the challenges.