Welcome back.
In this section,
we'll learn how we
can use modules to encapsulate
constants in classes.
You probably remember when
we talked about constants.
Here we have a loadProfiles
function,
part of the
load-profiles module which
declares two constants,
MAX_USERS and MAX_REPLIES,
and assigns a value for each.
Then on the list-replies
module we
define the MAX_REPLIES constant
again and on the
display-watchers module we
define MAX_USERS again.
You might be thinking, I
thought we couldn't redefine
constants, what's up with that?
You were right, we cannot
redefine constants within
the same scope.
But here we have three
different functions,
each with their own
scope, so this code
is technically correct.
However, it's
unnecessary duplication
that can lead to bad code.
The issue here is
that if we ever
have to change the value
of any of these constants
we have to remember to
change every occurrence
of that constant, which entirely
defeats the purpose of using
constants in the first place.
A simple way to fix this
is to create a module where
we can define our constants.
This allows them to be used from
other places in the application
while hiding implementation
details:  their values.
So we create a new module named
constants.js and move our code
over there.
We use the export keyword
followed by const, then
the name of the constant and
then assign it its value.
Or we could also use
the single exports
syntax, whichever you prefer,
both of these work the same.
Now back to our load-profiles
module.
We can use the import
statement just like we
were doing before.
We import MAX_REPLIES and
MAX_USERS from the constants module
and then we can use them
throughout our function.
Same thing with the list-replies
module and display-watchers
module.
We import MAX_REPLIES on
the list-replies and
MAX_USERS on display-watchers.
All modules are
now using constants
defined in a single place.
So if we ever need to
update the value for any
of these constants,
all we have to do
is go back to the constants
module and update there once.
All changes will be
reflected automatically.
Pretty cool.
Lastly, let's see how we can
export classes from modules.
Here's a version of our
flash-message module rewritten
to use the class syntax.
We have our class definition,
class FlashMessage,
with a constructor setting
the value for this.message.
Then we have two
instance methods,
renderAlert and renderLog.
Both part of the
FlashMessage class.
To export this class
we use the export
keyword with the default
type export right
before the class syntax.
Remember, because we're using
the default type export here,
we can assign this class
to any variable name
once it's imported.
Now, from app.js we can
import FlashMessage
using the same import syntax.
The name of the class
here could be anything,
but we'll stick with FlashMessage
just for consistency.
The only thing different
from the function version
is that we must create
an instance of the
FlashMessage using new.
Once we do that we
can call methods
like renderAlert and renderLog.
When we load our page again,
we can see both the pop
up alert and the message
printed to the console.
Just like we do with functions,
we can also export classes
using named exports.
First, we define
our class and then
we use the export statement with
the name of the class wrapped
in curly braces.
This exports our class
to the outside world.
Now that we're
using named exports
we must go back to app.js
and wrap our class name
in curly braces.
And the name of the class here
needs to be the exact same name
that we use in our module.
If we load our page,
we can see the output
is the same, alert pop up and
message printed to the console.
That's it for this
level, now it's
your turn to go back
to the challenges
and practice some more.
Typing this
SponsorWidget.prototype
every time is not cool.