[SINGING] We've
had about enough,
JavaScript is getting tough,
ECMAScript is the solution.
Join the revolution.
Let your objects fill the
gaps inside the Sets and Maps,
use OOP patterns to the max.
New class and module syntax,
const and let will do the thing,
to stop the hoisting.
With pure arrays struggling
is destructuring.
Keep your JS nice and
lean by using ES2015.
You are watching ES2015, The
Shape of JavaScript to Come.
I'm Carlos Souza
and in this level,
we'll be talking about Promises,
iterators, and generators
and these are pretty
advanced topics
so we'll move a little faster
doing the parts that we learned
in previous levels.
If some of it does
not make sense
I recommend that you go
back and redo those levels.
At the end of this
course we'll also
be pointing out some
additional material
that can help fill in the gaps.
In this first
section, we'll talk
about Promises which are finally
incorporated into the JavaScript
language after a long period
of being tested and deployed
to production with polyfills.
To understand why Promises
are a good alternative
to callback based code let's
take a look at an example.
Something we do a lot on the
web is clicking links, pictures,
or typing on input
boxes, text areas
and when these
actions occur they
might trigger other
actions like fetching data
from a backend API.
While we wait for
the response we still
must be able to
interact with the page.
If we mess up and
write bad code, code
that blocks the page, we can
make elements non responsive
and affect user experience.
Here's how some of
that code might look.
In this first example, we
can see a synchronous style
function that must wait for
the return values in order
to continue execution.
While we're waiting for
getPollResultsFromServer
to resume the page freezes.
Once the browser blocks
executing a script
it stops running other
scripts, rendering elements,
and responding to user events
like keyboard and mouse
directions.
That's why we write
code that avoids
blocking the main
thread of execution
and looks like this instead.
In the second example
we pass a callback
to be run by the
getPollResultsFromServer
function.
The function is now responsible
for executing the call back
whenever it's done fetching
the results from the server.
This style of code is sometimes
referred to as
continuation-passing style.
This is because
we tell a function
how to continue execution
by giving it or passing
it a callback.
One big issue is that
it could easily grow
to code that looks like this.
First, it's nesting a lot and
making it super hard to read.
Next, we have to
check for errors
on every single callback.
Promises were
brought to JavaScript
trying to offer solutions
to these issues.
They bring in a new abstraction
that makes it easier
to write async code.
This is the code that we'll
learn how to write together.
So let's get going.
We'll start implementing
our function by returning
a new Promise object.
The Promise constructor
takes an anonymous function
with two callback arguments
known as handlers.
They are responsible for
resolving or rejecting
the Promise.
These handlers are
just functions,
so we can call them and
optionally pass arguments.
We call resolve when
the non-blocking code is
done executing or reject
when an error occurs.
Promises go through
a life cycle.
When we create a
new Promise it's
automatically set to
the pending state,
Then it can do
one of two things.
It can become fulfilled when
we call resolve or rejected
when we call reject.
One thing to know
about Promises is
that whenever we return a
new Promise object we're not
returning a result,
we're returning
a future value such
as the eventual result
of an async operation.
For that reason, our
function no longer
needs a callback as
the second argument.
To help us keep track of where
we are in the Promise life
cycle we'll use this graph here.
And because we just
created a Promise,
it starts on the pending state.
Now inside our
Promise function we'll
write some
XMLHttpRequest code,
which is the code that's
going to fetch results
from the server.
This should be pretty familiar,
but we'll go over it anyway.
First, we define the url path.
Notice we're using
string templates here.
Then we create an XMLHttpRequest
object and tell it
what we want to do and what
to do once it loads back
the response.
If it's a successful response
within the 200 and the 400
status code range we
resolve the Promise,
passing in the response.
Since request.response
returns plain text
we'll go ahead and convert
it to JSON using JSON.parse.
By calling resolve we move the
Promise to a fulfilled state,
and once that happens
we can read the results.
So let's see how we can do that.
With our Promise
object in hand, we
can use the method called
then to read back the results.
This method takes a
callback function,
which will only be invoked
once the Promise is resolved.
Notice here that the argument
that is passed to the callback
is the same value that
was passed to the call
to result from inside
of the Promise.
No we're not free
from using callbacks,
but now we can start using
them in a much better way.
Another way that we can
write this code that
makes it even
better to work with
is without this temporary
variable fetchingResults.
We can get rid of it and
chain results like this.
I think it reads better.
If we need to we can pass values
from one then to another then.
Let's do that by filtering
our poll results to only
those coming from Orlando.
We'll use the filter function
to check for the right city
and then return
the result. Notice
we're using a one
line arrow function.
The value returned
from the first
then becomes the
argument to the next one,
which calls ui.renderSidebar
with the filtered results.
To reject a Promise we can
call the reject handler.
Let's go back to our
function and we'll
call reject on two places.
First, when the response
is not successful.
Then, when the onerror
event is emitted on our
XMLHttpRequest object.
In both cases we'll give
reject a new error object
as an argument.
Once reject is called from
inside our Promise execution
moves immediately to
the catch function.
It skips any other
then functions
that might be declared and
passes the Error object
as an argument to the
callback on catch.
We could make this
code a little easier
to read by first
declaring the functions
and passing them as
handlers to calls to then.
Here we declare the
filterResults named function and then
create a new ui object and
assign a renderSidebar
method to it using the new
method initializer shorthand.
Then below we pass
filterResults and ui.renderSidebar
as handlers to the then method.
The code still behaves the same
and the catch function still
catches errors from
anywhere up on the chain.
Now it's your time to
work on the challenges.
I Promise you'll
have a good time.  Get it?