Welcome back.
In this section, we'll
talk about iterators,
but before we do that let's
do a quick recap on what
we know so far about iterables.
We know that arrays are
iterables so we can use them
with for...of like
we're doing here,
looping through each name
element from the names array.
We also know that plain
JavaScript objects are not
iterable.
So they do not work with
for...of out of the box.
If we try using for...of to loop
through properties in this post
object we'll run into an error.
Iterables are
objects that know how
to return a special
object called an iterator.
An iterator is an
object that knows
how to access items from
a collection one at a time
while keeping track of
its current position
within that sequence.
Let's look at an example.
Here we have our names array
with Sam, Tyler and Brook.
We use for...of to loop through
each one of its elements.
Every time we use
for...of like this,
what we're really working
with is an iterator object.
If we were to write the code
for what's happening behind
the scenes in a for...of loop,
it could look something like
this.
First, we call the
function that's
assigned to the
Symbol.iterator property.
This function returns
an iterator object.
This iterator object
knows exactly how
to navigate through the elements
from the object it belongs to.
In this case, the names array.
To read an element from the iterator
we call the next method.
Now when we're using for...of
we don't have to call this next
method manually.
The loop takes care of
calling this for us.
And what we get back from
calling the next method
is an object with two
properties, done and value.
We'll talk more about these
two in just a little bit,
but for now all we need to know
is that while done is false,
the for...of loop will
keep reading values from
the iterator.
For our names array, once it
calls next for the first time,
it reads value and assigns
its results to name.
In this case, "Sam".
Then, on the second run
it assigns "Tyler" to name.
Then, on the third run
it assigns "Brook" to name.
Now in the fourth time it calls
next the return object has
the done property set to true,
which tells for...of that we
are done navigating through the
elements and we can break out
of the loop.
As you can see the iterator
object is pretty smart.
Most of the logic behind this
happens in the next function.
So let's dive a little
deeper into this function.
We've learned that each
time that we call next it
returns an object with two
properties, done and value.
And here's how they work.
done will be false
if the iterator
is able to return a value
from the current collection.
Here in our names array
with three elements done
returns false three times.
On the fourth time its past the
end of the collection so done
returns true.
The value property
is sent to the value
returned by the iterator.
For the first three
runs of the loop
it returns each
element from the array.
Sam, Tyler and Brook.
The fourth time it runs
through the loop the value
is set to undefined.
Now that we understand the
mechanics of the iterator
object, in the next method we
can write your own iterator
and return it from a
plain JavaScript object.
Therefore, making it iterable.
Let's see how we can do that.
Here's our plain JavaScript
object post with the title
and replies properties.
We've learned that
an iterator is
an object with a next
property returned
by a function assigned to
the Symbol.iterator property.
We'll do just that.
First, we add a function to
the Symbol.iterator property.
When this function is called,
it will return an object
with the next property.
For now we'll simply
write an empty function.
And notice we're using
an arrow function,
and we'll see why
in just a second.
If we try using our post object
with the for...of loop now,
we're still going to
run into an error.
However, we'll see a different
error message than the one
that we're seeing before.
It means we're on
the right track.
Next let's define
some things that
can help us navigate through the
sequence of values in our post
object.
First, we'll use Object.keys
to grab the list of properties
defined in our object.
This method returns an array.
Then, we'll create a count
variable and set it to zero.
This variable will help us
access the properties array
by their index.
Finally, we'll create
isDone and set it to false.
This is the variable that will
be used as a value for the done
property and we'll
set it to true
when we're done with the loop.
With these in
place, we can start
implementing the next method.
First, we check to see if we're
past the end of the collection.
If so, we'll set
isDone to true,
which will cause the script to
break out of the for...of loop
once we return from this method.
Then, we return the object with
the done property and the value
property.
We use the count
variable to grab
the value for the
next property and then
increment count so
the next time it runs
it reads the following value.
And that's all there is to it.
Now we have a working
implementation
of the next method on a
plain JavaScript object.
Now if we try using the post
object in for...of loop,
we'll see that it properly
returns the value for each
property.
And since we've made
our post object iterable
we can also use it with
other new features,
like the spread operator.
If we wrap our post
object in square brackets
and prefix it with
these three dots,
we can read the
values as an array.
Or we can read from post using
destructuring, assigning
to local variables title
and replies at once,
like we're doing here.
That's it for this section.
Now it's your turn to practice
iterators in the challenges.