Welcome back.
And in this section, we'll
talk about generators,
which are a new type
of function added
to JavaScript that
make it easier
to work with iterator objects.
We create generator functions
with the function keyword
followed by a
*, then followed
by the name of the function.
Inside of a generator
function, we
can use the yield keyword
to return iterator objects.
Arguments past to
yield are automatically
assigned to the value property,
which we learned about
in the previous level.
For the function declaration,
it doesn't matter where
we put *.
It could go right before
the function name,
right after the
function keyword,
or right in the middle.
It doesn't really matter as long
as it comes after the function
keyword.
Generator functions
return objects,
which provide the same
next method expected
by for...of, the spread
operator, and destructuring.
This next method is the same
one we use with iterators.
In this example, the result of
calling the nameList function
is a generator object, which
then returns an iterator
object.
The first run of the loop returns
"Sam" and the second run
of the loop returns
"Tyler", both values
that were used as
arguments to yield.
We can also use our nameList
function with a spread operator
by wrapping it in
square brackets
and prefixing it
with the three dots.
This gives us a list of elements
in the form of an array.
If we print names
to the console,
we can see it prints an
array with "Sam" and "Tyler",
and we can also
use destructuring
to read from the
nameList function
and assign to multiple variables
at once, like we're doing here
with first and second.
We print them out to the console
and we see "Sam" and "Tyler".
Now that we've learned
about generator functions,
let's see how we can use them
to clean up our post object
code a little bit.
This is where we ended up at.
Using the power of
generator functions,
we can turn code like
this into code like this.
First thing we do is change
the function signature
to a generator function,
and to do that, all we need
is a star character, *.
Generator functions
can be anonymous.
Then, we replace our manual
crafting of the return object
with a simple for...of
loop that calls yield.
for...of will return the string's
title and then replies.
Each time, we'll use
each one of these strings
to look up the value
of their property
using the object this,
which refers to the post
object itself.
Then we'll pass the value
as an argument to yield.
for...of will loop twice.
On the first time, it will
assign the string title
to the variable p.
We'll use that string
to look up the property
value on the object this,
which refers to the post
object itself.
The same thing happens again,
this time with the string
replies.
This for...of loop is the same as
manually returning each value,
like we see over here.
Once we're done, we can
see our post object still
behaves the same.
That's it for this level.
Now, you head over
to the challenges
and I'll see you
in the outro video.
We'll start implementing
getPollResultsFrom-- [BLEEP] name,
man.
What the [BLEEP]?
Here's what you-- [GIBBERISH].
It could look like this.