[SINGING]
Learn to use fonts with
typography, a style guide
helps visual hierarchy.
With HSL build a color scheme,
and add a page layout to
complete the scene.
Combine these topics and
you will find the
Fundamentals of Design.
Welcome to the Fundamentals
of Design.
My name is Tim Dikun.
And in this course, we're
going to be covering the
basics of typography, color,
and layout in web design.
Before we jump into typography,
we're going to
talk about one of the most basic
principles in design and
that's the idea that
content is king.
The designer's one essential
task is to interpret and
communicate the content.
And this means that the design
must ultimately reflect the
spirit of the content.
What do I mean by this?
Let's say that I'm designing a
website for a design studio
with a formal mission statement
targeting business
leaders looking to bring
their company out of
the analog-only world.
The design might look something
like this, where
we've got elegant, simple, and
large type that intentionally
mashes with irregular shapes
to reinforce their grasp on
the tension between old business
and new technology.
Well, let's say that you're
designing a website for a
playfully-themed film festival
for horror entertainment
enthusiasts supporting local
business and the common good.
You might end up with
something like this.
Where you've got decorative
sketch type at varying sizes
and angles that creates a
haunted dynamic without being
overly dark or graphic so
as to remain inviting.
So, how does content influence
design, and what should you be
looking for as you're
preparing?
There are three main attributes
of content that
influence the design.
The first one is the
target audience.
What is their age, race,
gender, cultural niche?
Next, you've got the tone.
Is it casual or formal?
And lastly, you've
got purpose.
Is it informational or
conversion driven?
And only after you address
these questions about the
content are you ready
to begin designing.
So, let's jump into typography.
We are going to be putting
together what is known as a
style guide.
And a style guide is a reference
document with
multiple instances of typography
that you'll be
using throughout your website
or application.
And this is what your style
guide might look like if you
were designing a website that
has a lot of news articles or
even a blog.
You'd have your headline text,
your B-head or sub-head text,
your navigation text,
your body copy,
and your byline text.
Putting these together
beforehand is going to help
you avoid inconsistency
throughout your application
and create an overall better
design and better user
experience.
The first thing you need to know
about typography is that
some fonts are just plain awful,
and that good fonts are
often taken for granted with
the thousands of digitally
available free fonts.
So don't just choose a font that
you think looks cool for
your website.
Invest the time to get to know
the type faces and choose one
that really suits your
content well.
Typography is both verbal
and visual.
The reader first surveys the
overall graphical patterns of
the page, and then they parse
the language and read.
This means that different styles
of type, different
classifications of type, create
different moods that will
either serve your content
well or not.
So you must take the time to
know the different styles and
classes of type and choose one
that's really going to serve
your content well.
Let's look first the
classification of
type known as serif.
In a serif is a small
line tailing from
the edges of letters.
And any font that contains these
small lines is known as
a serif font.
And within the serif
classification, there are many
different styles of type.
Let's look at some
of those now.
The first one is humanist.
And a humanist font emulates
classical calligraphy and
contains some contrast in the
stroke that creates a very
classic and traditional feel
that's great for journalism or
historical applications.
A transitional serif has a much
sharper serif than the
humanist and has much more
contrast between the thick and
the thin strokes
of the letters.
That creates a very strong,
stylish, and dynamic feel
that's great for traditional
academia and legal
applications.
The modern serif has a very
thin, horizontal serif and
very high contrast between the
thick and the thin strokes.
That creates a very structured,
clear, and elegant
feel that's great for arts
and culture applications.
The last style of serif fonts
is Egyptian, also
know as slab serif.
And they're known for having
heavy, boxy serifs and almost
no contrast in the stroke.
That creates an authoritative,
yet friendly feel that's great
for marketing and promotional
applications.
The next classification
of type is sans-serif.
Sans is the French
word for without.
And so it stands to reason that
any font that is without
a serif is known as
a sans-serif.
And like the serif font, within
this classification
there are multiple
different styles.
The first one is humanist
sans serif.
And like the humanist serif font
it emulates calligraphy
and has minimal contrast
in the strokes.
And this creates a tension
between the perfect and the
imperfect that's great for
government or educational
applications.
The transitional sans serif
has very upright, uniform
characters and strong strokes
that creates an unassuming and
modern feel that's great for
technology and transportation
applications.
And finally, there's the
geometric sans serif, where
geometric shapes form the
backbones of the letters.
This creates a very strict
objective and universal feel
that's great for a science or
architecture application.
The final classification of type
that we're going to talk
about is script.
And script fonts mimic
handwriting or calligraphy.
They're really great for adding
a human element to your
website, but they're not
so great for body copy.
As you can see, it's quite
difficult to read.
Something you should know is
that comic sans is technically
a script font, not a sans serif
font, and should not be used
for body copy or really
anywhere ever.
When selecting typefaces for
your application, feel free to
mix and mingle.
Because while one type face is
often enough, adding another
can create quite the
beautiful effect.
Using a serif for the headline
and the intro paragraph on
this article and a sans serif
for the body copy is perhaps
the simplest and most
effective way to mix typefaces.
When mixing typefaces, there
are a couple of things that
you need to keep in mind.
And the first one is don't
choose two fonts
from the same style.
Like these:
We've got Epic, which is a
humanist serif, and Garamond,
which is also a humanist serif,
and they're are two
similar to one another
to really look good.
Like wearing a red shirt with
an orange tie, they clash.
Furthermore, don't choose two
fonts from the same class.
Unless you really know your
typefaces, it's very difficult
to choose two serifs or two
sans fonts that really
complement each other well.
Like here we've got epic, which
is again a humanist
serif, and agora, which
is a slab serif.
They don't combine well.
When mixing classes, find a
similar trait using fonts that
share one thing in common but
are otherwise different, like
a humanist serif and a humanist
sans, can create
quite the beautiful pairing.
And that trait can even be
largely abstract. Like these
two fonts Perpetua, which is a
transitional serif, and Gill
Sans, which is a humanist
sans, were both
designed by Eric Gill.
Similarities in chronology,
visual details, or even
typeface designer between
otherwise different fonts can
create great pairings.
All in all, you should strive
for contrast over harmony.
A good rule of thumb to follow
when mixing typefaces is keep
it the same or change
it a lot.
Look for emphatic differences
rather than mushy transitions.
And here's an example of a
content site that uses a
geometric sans sparingly as
headline and pull quote text
alongside a transitional serif
body copy font that creates a
really great pairing.
Or here, you've got a script
font next to a geometric sans,
which is about as much contrast
as you can get.
The variance in the handwriting
versus the
objectivity of the shapes
creates quite
the stunning effect.
But don't feel obligated
to pick two
fonts for your project.
A single typeface
is often enough.
And honestly, for the beginner
this is ideal.
Really practice and hone your
craft using the different
weights of just one font family
before moving on and
trying to incorporate
many others.
Here's an example of this:
The entire code school website
is designed using different
weights of just one sans
serif font family.
One final note about type on
the web before we conclude
this first video.
Make sure that you're using
web-licensed fonts.
Just because you have a font
on your computer, does not
mean that it's legal to put
it on the internet.
Now it's time for you to apply
some of these principles and
try your hand at mixing
typefaces.