Once we've selected a font, the
next thing we need to do
is set the sizes in
our style guide.
Before we talk about that, I
want you to take a look at
these two objects.
Think to yourself, how would
you describe these?
Would you say, a blue
and a green square?
Or maybe a big and
a small square?
Chances are that the first thing
that came to mind was
not simply two squares.
And this is because humans
create relationships.
It's how we process things.
We relate this to that in order
to understand them.
We can use this to our advantage
when designing by
creating visual hierarchy.
Establishing visual
relationships between elements
on the page is going to allow
your users to more quickly
process the information.
For example, let's say you've
got an informative site
promoting a new twist on a
traditional, every day item -
dipping sauce.
You might have something
like this.
You could have a design that
uses large, handwritten type,
and life-like photographic
elements strewn about in an
apparently chaotic manner in
order to add visual intrigue
to a mundane item.
What's significant about this
site is that it uses
differences in size to draw the
eye naturally from large
elements down to the small
elements, which helps the user
more easily process
the information.
Take, for instance,
this paragraph.
The amount of text isn't really
all that much, but if
this is the first thing I see
when I come to your website,
I'm leaving.
There's no visual indicator
that allows me to quickly
assess what the rest of
the content is about.
In order to really understand
it, I have to read all of it,
which is more of a time
commitment than you can
realistically expect
from your users.
Let's look at the same block
of text, but establish some
visual relationships.
By taking the first phrase and
creating a headline out of it,
we've created some variance that
gives the user something
to latch onto.
Now, instead of reading the
entire paragraph, they can
simply read the headline and
understand what the rest of
the paragraph is about.
So if you remember from the
first video, we're working
towards creating
a style guide.
And as you can see here, the
style guide already has some
variances in size.
So how did we get there?
Where do we start when it comes
to making typographical
size decisions?
We start with body copy.
This is a little bit tricky to
navigate, because there is no
golden standard for what size
your body copy font should be.
For example, this well respected
creative journal
uses body copy at 16 pixels.
However, this well respected
designer uses 26 pixels for
his body copy.
Personally, I think huge type
is annoying, especially when
viewing on a browser that's not
the full vertical height
of the screen.
For this course, we're going to
be suggesting that you use
16 pixel body copy font,
although each case needs to be
weighed individually.
Different contexts, different
websites will call for
different font sizes.
Once we've established the body
copy size, everything
else is set relative to that.
The next decision you'll need
to make is the size of the
headline, which can be anywhere
from 200% to 300% of
the body copy.
Everything else can be set
relatively in between there.
The b-head is at 150% of
the body copy, and the
navigational text is the same
size as the body copy.
Your byline text should be
smaller than your body copy by
2 to 4 pixels, or about 75%.
Once you've got your type sizes
set, it's time to move
on to leading.
Leading is the amount of space
between lines of text.
It's measured from baseline to
baseline, and as you can see
here, a baseline is the line
where the majority of the font
ends, with the exception of
characters like y, p, or g,
that have what is known
as a descender that
goes below the baseline.
Leading that is too large
negatively affects
readability, as the eye has to
move further between lines of
text, and can easily get lost.
On the other side, leading that
is too small can create a
cramped or claustrophobic feel
that rushes the reader, and
generally makes them
feel uncomfortable.
Remember, it's about visual
relationships.
Establishing a proper
relationship between the text
and the space around it is
going to increase user
engagement.
Good leading is around 120% to
150% of the body copy size.
Luckily for us, we don't
have to do the math.
By using the CSS property line-
height and setting it
relatively to 1.5 will ensure
that no matter what the font
size is, that the line height
will always be 150% of that.
Another visual hierarchy tool at
your disposal is using bold
or italic weights.
Using these different weights
can add emphasis and intrigue
to your design.
However, using too much bold
can muddy your hierarchy.
It's almost as if everything is
screaming at you at once.
Also, make sure your
bold or italics
compliment the natural value.
For instance, the eye naturally
expects the headline
to be bolder than the body copy,
so by using a thin font
for your headline and a bold
font for your body copy,
you're going to confuse
the user.
When using bold or italic
weights, stick to a less is
more approach that will really
enhance your hierarchy.
Now you can try your hand
at these concepts in the
challenges.