Next up is line-width, which
is put simply as the
width of the line.
Lines that are too short are
difficult to read, as the
user's eye has to move quickly
from line to line.
On the other side, lines that
are too long are also
difficult to read,
as the user's eye
can get lost easily.
Line-width is measured in CPL,
which stands for characters
per line, and 50 to 70
characters per line, including
spaces, is ideal.
Take, for instance, this
paragraph, which is set at 55
to 65 characters per line.
Note that if I were to increase
the type size, the
physical line with increases,
however, the characters per
line stays the same.
In CSS, this is controlled using
the max-width property,
or maximum width.
The higher you set your
max-width, the more CPL you're
going to have.
The lower it is, the fewer
CPL you're going to have.
Let's take a look
at an example.
If we've got a browser window
that's 1,000 pixels wide, we'd
need to set our max-width at
about 630 pixels in order to
maintain 55 to 65 CPL
at 26 pixels.
However, when viewing it on a
mobile device, if the font
size stays at 26 pixels, the
CPL will drop down to 20 to
25, which is far more cramped
than is comfortable for
readability.
To solve this, you can drop
the font size down to 16
pixels, which will give us a
CPL of closer to 30 to 40,
which is still not ideal, but
it's going to create a better
reading experience
for your user.
Let's take a look at
an example of this.
When looking at this website on
the desktop, the max width
is set to 730 pixels with a font
size of 22 pixels, which
averages 70 to 80 CPL.
However, when looking at it on
a mobile device, the width is
360 pixels, and the font size
drops down to 19 pixels in
order to maintain an average
CPL of 40 to 45.
This is a great example of
responsive design, which we
won't be going into
in this course.
However, there are plenty of
great resources out there,
including Code School's Journey
Into Mobile course.
I encourage you to
check those out.
And finally, Save the
Orphans & Widows.
A widow is a single word on a
line of text, and an orphan is
a single line of text
on a column or page.
And these are bad things,
because they impede the
natural flow of reading
for the user.
When dealing with orphans and
widows, know that there isn't
always a perfect solution.
Especially when dealing with
large blocks of content, they
can be very difficult
to prevent.
Try tweaking with the font size,
weight, line width, and
leading to fix the problem.
And at the very least,
make sure your
headlines are widow free.
Now try your hand at this last
set of typographical
challenges.