[SINGING]
Learn to use fonts
with typography.
A style guide helps
visual hierarchy.
With HSL build a color scheme,
and add a page layout to
complete the scene.
Combine these topics, and
you will find the
Fundamentals of Design.
You're watching the
These next few videos, we're
going to be going over color
and how to incorporate them
into your website or app.
Let's start with some
basic color theory.
There are two types of color:
color you can touch, like the
skin of an apple, and then
there's color you can't touch,
like the projected light
coming from a monitor.
Color you can touch is called
subtractive color, and color
you can't touch is called
additive color.
Subtractive color is controlled
using the CMYK
color space.
You may have noticed that your
printer at home has four basic
ink cartridges -
cyan, magenta, yellow,
and black.
And in theory, all of these
colors mixed create black.
Additive color is controlled
using the RGB color spectrum,
which stands for red,
green, and blue.
And in theory, all colors
mix to yield white.
Because we're dealing primarily
with web design,
we're going to be dealing with
the RGB color space.
Humans don't process color
in the terms of
red, green, and blue.
We actually process things in
the terms of HSL, which stands
for hue, saturation,
and lightness.
Hue is best visualized
on a color wheel.
You start at zero degrees, which
is red, and as you move
around the circle, you get
to different colors.
Each degree correlates
to a different color.
120 degrees is green, and 240
degrees is blue, perfectly
encapsulating the entire
RGB color space.
The S stands for saturation,
which is the difference
between a color and gray.
A hue at 100% saturation is the
most vibrant forum that
color, where at 0% is gray.
And lightness is the amount
of light in a color.
A hue at 100% lightness
is white and at 0%
lightness is black.
And 50% lightness is the most
vibrant form of that hue.
For example, let's say we've got
a color where the hue is
zero degrees, the saturation
is 100%, and the
lightness is 50%.
This is the most pure form of
red that we can get in HSL
color space.
But what happens if we increase
the lightness to 75%?
We actually get a color that
has more white in it, more
light in it, and so therefore
is more of a pink color.
In the same way, if we were to
decrease the lightness, we're
adding more black into that
color, and we're actually
getting a much darker red.
So now if we bring the lightness
back up to its
original 50% and instead of
messing with the lightness, we
drop the saturation down to 25%,
we get a very muted or
pastel red color.
And from there, if I were to
completely reverse the hue to
be 180 degrees, we actually get
a muted teal-ish color.
The HSL color space can be
visualized as a three
dimensional cylinder.
Let's walk through each
one of the dimensions.
The first one is hue.
As we talked about earlier, as
you move around the circle,
the hue changes.
Each degree is a different
color.
The second one is saturation.
If you visualize it as starting
in the middle and the
core of the cylinder and moving
towards the outsides,
the saturation increases
or decreases.
And the third dimension is
lightness, which starts at the
bottom of the cylinder and moves
up to the top, being
black at the bottom and
white at the top.
It's very inconvenient to view
this three dimensional
color space on a 2D monitor,
so usually a hue saturation
wheel and a brightness slider
does the trick.
Let's look at these in action.
For example, if I were to select
a color that has 240
degrees in hue and 100% for the
saturation, it would be here.
And if I were to set the
lightness at 50%, I get this
color, which is the purest
form of blue in
the RGB color space.
If I were to decrease the
saturation, the hue saturation
selector would move in towards
the middle of the circle.
And leaving the lightness slider
at 50% creates a more
muted blue.
Now, if I leave the hue and
saturation where it was at and
increase the lightness slider,
I'm adding more white into the
color, and I actually get
a very pastel purple.
You may have noticed that in
this course, we're using the
HSL color space, where L
stands for lightness.
If you were to open up Photoshop
or any other
application that has a color
picker, you would probably see
the HSB color space, the
B being brightness.
So what's the difference?
The difference is that with
lightness at 100%,
the color is white.
But with the brightness at 100%,
the color is simply the
most vibrant form of that hue.
It's time for you to try your
hand at mixing colors in these
different color spaces.