Now that we've learned the
fundamentals of color theory,
we need to start building
a color scheme.
And a color scheme is four or
five colors built into your
style guide.
These colors will be applied
to different elements
throughout your application,
such as buttons, text color,
or backgrounds.
The first decision you have to
make when creating a color
scheme is to choose
a base color.
And the base color is the
foundational color from which
the rest of the color scheme
will be built out.
When selecting a base color,
you have to realize that
different colors create
different moods.
And this plays itself out
in the world around
us on a daily basis.
Have you ever seen
this before?
A doctor's office painted red.
I'd venture to say you
probably haven't.
And that's because red is
the color of passion or
excitement, not the cool,
calming colors that you'd
expect from a doctor's office.
Or how about this?
A science fiction movie poster
that uses hot pink typography.
It's much more suited for
the My Little Pony
movie than Star Trek.
So, exactly what moods does
each color create?
Let's walk through them.
Red is the color of heat,
passion, and excitement.
And it easily grabs attention
and evokes a
certain speed and energy.
Orange is the color of
warmth and vitality.
And it is associated with
reliability and playfulness.
Yellow is the color of optimism
or creativity and
represents sunshine, cheer,
and happiness.
Green is the color of serenity
or health and connotes growth,
nature, and freshness.
Blue is the color of security,
truth, and stability and
implies loyalty, reliability,
and open communication.
Purple is the color of
spirituality, intelligence,
and wealth and can also mean
royal, sentimental, creative,
and sophisticated.
Pink is the color of youthful
intensity and conveys energy,
fun, and excitement.
And brown is the color of
durability or class, and
represents age, stability,
and relaxation.
Black is a color of power or
drama, and it's serious, bold,
and strong.
And white is the color of
simplicity and cleanliness.
And its message is youthful,
mild, and pure.
You must always remember to
keep culture in mind when
choosing a base color.
For instance, red in Western
societies, as we've talked
about, conveys an intensity
or energy.
But in China, it's the color of
good luck, whereas in South
Africa, it's the color
of mourning.
And in Russian contexts, it's
associated with communism.
Once you've selected a base
color, it's time to build out
the rest of your color scheme.
And there are multiple different
methods you can use
to determine what that color
scheme will look like.
Let's dive into a
couple of those.
A monochromatic color scheme is
a color scheme in which all
of the colors have the same
hue, and they vary in
saturation and lightness.
To use this, you'd start with
your base color, which you see
here in the middle, and create
four different colors, keeping
the hue constant and only
changing the saturation and
brightness.
Monochromatic color schemes are
the easiest to create and
work very well together.
But they often lack
the versatility
of other color schemes.
The next color scheme
that we're going
to look at is analogous.
An analogous color scheme,
similar to the monochromatic
color scheme, has colors
that vary in
saturation and lightness.
However, instead of the hue
remaining constant, the hue
both increases and decreases,
showing the colors adjacent to
it on the color wheel.
A complementary color scheme
also varies in saturation and
lightness, but differs in that
it has colors of the same hue
to the base color and colors
of the opposite hue to the
base color on the color wheel.
To find the colors opposite
hue, visualize it
on the color wheel.
Look to the exact opposite, or
180 degrees away from that
color, and you'll find
the opposite.
These are just three of the
methods that you can use when
putting together
a color scheme.
There are so many more.
Take the time to research and
learn about all of the
different color schemes
available.
Know that while a color scheme
can be objectively correct, it
can still be ugly.
For instance, this complementary
color scheme
uses very strange purples and
greens that would not actually
look good together
on a website.
When implementing color schemes,
know that they don't
need to be perfect.
You can use these methods,
such as complementary or
analogous, as a base and tweak
as needed to fit your project.
Now it's time for you to try
creating color schemes.