Now that we've learned about
color and color schemes, it's
time to combine that with
our knowledge of type.
The most important thing
to keep in mind is that
typography must have a high
degree of contrast between it
and its background.
Contrast is defined as the
difference in colors.
It can be a small difference
or a large difference, and
there could be differences
in just a hue,
saturation, or lightness.
A contrast of hue is when
two colors have the same
saturation and lightness,
but differ in
hue, as you see here.
A contrast of saturation is
when the hue and lightness
remain constant, but the
saturation changes from one
color to the next.
And a contrast of lightness
is when the hue and the
saturation remain constant, but
the lightness changes from
one color to the next.
The biggest contrast of them
all, black and white, can be
considered a contrast
of lightness.
Most contrasts are
multi-faceted.
It's very common to combine
contrasts of hue, saturation,
and lightness.
This contrast of hue for font
color and background creates a
contrast that is too low
to really read well.
However, if we make it a
contrast of both hue and
lightness, it becomes
much easier to read.
Furthermore, if we make it a
contrast of all three, hue,
saturation, and lightness, it
gets even easier to read.
There are standards for how much
contrast there needs to
be between type and its
background color.
It's called the WCAG, or Web
Content Accessibility
Guidelines.
These standards are put in place
to make sure that all
websites are legible
to all users.
Very simple, high contrast
colors, such as black and
white are the best.
Colors that are the same hue
but have a very high
saturation and lightness
contrast are a close second.
Some colors are intrinsically
difficult for humans to
distinguish, such as red and
green and blue and orange.
Especially for color blind
individuals, they're going to
have a very tough time
reading this.
Different colors have different
natural values.
For instance, yellow is a
naturally light color, while
blue is a naturally
dark color.
So creating contrast in which
the yellow is darker than the
blue creates a very awkward
experience.
If we fix the lightness to
correspond with the natural
values, making the yellow light
and the blue dark, the
type becomes much
more legible.
Some colors are considered
warm, and some
are considered cold.
The warm side of the color
spectrum is the red, orange,
and yellow side.
And the cool side is the green,
blue, and purple side.
Using contrasts of warm and
cool colors alone does not
create a legible contrast.
However, warm and cool colors
can be used to create depth,
as warm colors appear closer to
the screen or to the user
than cool colors do.
So use cool colors in the
background and warm colors in
the foreground.
The colors you use in your style
guide should reinforce
the visual hierarchy.
For instance, the backgrounds on
the Code School website get
progressively darker as you
scroll, which anchors the page
and create a more stable
viewing experience.
When trying to put type on an
image, avoid the use of drop
shadows and strokes, as
they can appear tacky.
Instead, treat the image
behind the text to
make it stand out.
Overlaying a pattern and
darkening the image can really
help the text pop.
When considering putting
type in an image, stop,
and don't do it.
Legitimate copy does not belong
in an image, unless
it's a hilarious picture of
a kitty cat, like this one
contemplating a serious life
decision as to whether or not
to buy a boat.
Taking a look at the Code
School's color scheme, you can
see that we use both
complimentary and analogous
colors, as well as including
high contrast text and
background colors.
Now, it's time to put your
knowledge of color and
typography to the test.