[SINGING]
Learn to use fonts
with typography.
A style guide helps
visual hierarchy.
With HSL, build a
color scheme.
And add a page layout to
complete the scene.
Combine these topics, and
you will find the
fundamentals of design.
You're watching part
three of the
Fundamentals of Design course.
In the next few videos, we're
going to be walking through
different layout concepts.
Layout is fundamentally an
exercise in visual hierarchy.
Yet again, you arrange the
elements on the page to direct
and engage the user's eye.
Let's look at some of the basic
elements of a website
and how they might be laid
out on the page.
Because English is read from
left to right and top to
bottom, users generally start in
the upper left hand corner
of the page and move
out from there.
So a good place to start is by
placing your logo or your
brand in the upper
left hand corner.
It's important to note that a
brand is not just a logo, and
that every pixel on the page
should reinforce your brand.
But including a logo is
a great first step.
Once you've placed your logo
on the page, it's time to
place your navigation.
Because navigation varies so
much from site to site, there
are no real set guidelines
on how to place it.
It's all about making something
complex as simple
and consistent as possible.
Navigations can be horizontal
or vertical.
For instance, horizontal is
ideal for navigations with
only a few items.
However, vertical works well,
in a similar fashion.
Vertical really excels when
you've got a lot of nested
pages, though if you drop your
horizontal navigation below
the logo, a tiered system with
lots of items works as well.
Both layouts are great for drop
downs or fly outs, such
as Amazon's vertical fly out
navigation that works really
well and ESPN's great horizontal
drop down menu.
It's important to note that
vertical navigation isn't
really used all that much.
And while it does work, make
sure you've got a really good
reason to use it.
Once you've got your logo and
your navigation placed, it's
time to place your
main content.
And the main content can be
placed under a horizontal nav
or next to a vertical nav.
Whatever you do, make sure that
the content within the
main content container
reinforces the hierarchy.
So, what exactly does
that mean?
The eye will follow directional
cues of elements
on the page.
So make sure that all those
directional cues are pointing
to your content.
For instance, you can see here
this businessman on this photo
is looking away from
the main content.
So the user's eye is going to
start in the upper left hand
corner, and as it moves down,
it's going to notice the
businessman and where he's
looking and follow it off the
page and not engaging
with your content.
To improve upon this, if the
businessman was looking at the
content, you'd start in the
upper left hand corner and
move down, notice where he's
looking, and be encouraged to
engage with the rest of
the content more.
We can make this even better
by making the content first
and the directional cues
reinforce that content.
So here we start with the logo,
and as our eye moves, we
directly engage with
the content.
And if, by chance, our eye was
to bounce far to the right,
the directional cues
of that image lead
us back to the content.
Secondary content should be
smaller and relegated to the
side, though it can also be
broken up into chunks and
placed underneath the
main content.
And finally, the footer anchors
the page and provides
quick hit information that
your user might need
quick access to.
And no matter what the layout
is, the footer should always
span the entire width
of the page.
Alright, now it's time for you to start
putting together some layouts.