Now that you've learned how to
order elements on the page,
it's time to talk about how to
align them to a grid, which is
the structural guideline
for organizing
elements on the page.
It is made up of a system of
horizontal and vertical lines
where the vertical lines create
columns with gutters in
between them that are used to
proportionally distribute
elements across the page, and the
horizontal lines are used
to create a baseline for text
that should be equal to the
line height.
Though baselines are
really difficult to
implement on the web -
the browser support
just isn't there -
use them in Photoshop or another
graphics software as a
reference when designing,
and do what you can
to carry them through.
The Apple store uses a grid
system to organize all of
their content.
When we overlay a system of
vertical lines, we can see
quite plainly the columns and
the gutters that they're using
to organize everything.
Grids come in many different
shapes and sizes.
The 960 grid system used to be
standard, but more and more
websites are leaving
behind fixed grids.
What do I mean by that?
With a fixed grid, the browser
can get bigger or smaller, and
the grid will remain constant.
But with a fluid grid, it grows
or shrinks with the
browser window, and columns are
either added or dropped to
better serve that size.
For simplicity's sake, in this
course, we're going to be
using a fixed grid.
Get used to working with a grid
here, but really do your
research and implement a fluid
grid in the wild, wild web.
You can use the grid to break
down your site into more
manageable chunks.
For instance, here we have six
columns grouped into halves, or
four columns grouped into thirds
or, further still,
three columns grouped
into quarters.
We can see that the Apple
store uses all three.
The very top row is broken down
into quarters with three
columns per element.
The second row is broken into
thirds with the main element
using up 2/3 of the width
and the other
element using one third.
Underneath that, we have six
columns grouped together to
create halves and so
on and so forth.
We can take all the elements
from the previous challenge
and lay them out on the grid,
giving order to the chaos.
And the grid is versatile
enough to accept all the
layouts we've made.
Also, avoid clutter by
respecting the gutters.
Don't put design elements or
type in between the columns.
Remember, we're establishing
visual relationships on behalf
of the user.
And by adhering to the grid,
we're creating relationships
between elements that make the
content easier to consume.
Now, try working with
the grid yourself.