In this last video on layout,
we're going to start by
talking about white space, and
white space is the empty space
around elements that can
increase readability and
create an air of elegance.
White space doesn't necessarily
have to be white.
Even on images with a strong
focal point, the plain area
around it is considered
white space.
White space in the design of a
website with a lot of content
can draw the user in without
overwhelming them.
Using white space at a high
level between major elements
in the design is essential,
but only if nuanced white
space between different elements
within individual
containers exists as well.
Finally, a good design is a
balanced design, and balance
is the equal distribution
of visual weight
throughout the design.
Designs that are not balanced
make us uncomfortable and can
have quite the disturbing
effect.
There are many different ways
to incorporate balance into
your website, and one
of them is symmetry.
Designs that need a more
stable and strong
organizational structure
tend to
incorporate a lot of symmetry.
This is the Envy Labs site.
You'll notice it uses a lot of
symmetry, because we're trying
to portray a sense of stability
and trust that will
win us new projects.
In the Beanstalk website,
there's an overall pattern of
symmetry that creates
a sense of balance.
Notice that the imagery does
not have to be in exact
reflection to be symmetrical.
Incorporating symmetry
into your design
is inherently balanced.
However, introducing
asymmetrical elements is
effective in drawing attention
and breaking monotony, though
it must still be balanced
on the page.
Let me show you what I mean.
Here, we have an unrepeated
large element that creates
asymmetry to grab attention and
create visual hierarchy
but, by adhering it to the
grid, brings a sense of
balance and order to the page.
Here's an example of asymmetry
demanding attention, creating
intrigue, and introducing white
space, and the density
on the other side of the page
gives it a sense of balance.
All of the principles that
we've talked about here
contribute to a sense
of balance.
Size, color, contrast, alignment
to the grid, white
space, or lack thereof, also
known as density, and symmetry
all work together to
create balance.
It's important to design
with intentionality.
If you can't defend the typeface
or the color or the
grid that you've chosen to
use for your project in a
conversational manner,
it probably
isn't the right choice.
Be able to know and talk about
why you make all the decisions
that you made.
One final note about design:
experiment often.
The first solution is
rarely the best one.
Don't rush the process and keep
trying different things
until you come up with the
best possible solution to
whatever design challenge
you are facing.
Now, it's time for a few
more challenges.
Good luck.