[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SINGING] It's time
to learn some Python,
a language to rely on, from
printing strings to math
routines, variables
on the horizon.
Start using True/False
and conditionals,
as you Try Python's
basic principals.
Welcome to Try Python.
I'm Sarah Buchanan, and we'll
be covering Python basics
in this course,
starting with Level 1:
Birds and Coconuts,
covering math and variables.
Before we begin
our Python journey,
let's go over why
Python is awesome.
Python is known for being
easy to learn, easy to read,
but it's also
incredibly powerful,
making it great for
beginners and experts alike.
It also has expansive
library support,
meaning you can
download libraries
for pretty much anything,
from image processing
to data analysis
to creating games.
With all of these great
reasons to learn Python,
let's get started.
Python is an
interpreted language,
and the interpreter
shell is shown here,
and we can type numbers
and commands into it
just like a calculator.
For example, we could type
35 into the interpreter,
and it'll just
return it back to us.
Any time you see >>>
like this,
it means we're entering
code into the interpreter,
and the green arrow is the
result of running that code.
For example, if we
enter a number 30.5,
we just get it back.
The interpreter will evaluate
any mathematical expression
we type in, and supports
basic operators like addition.
For example, we could
type in 3 + 5,
and we get the result of 8.
It also supports basic
operators like subtraction,
multiplication,
division, exponent, which
is **,
and negation,
which is just a minus sign.
Python has two types of
numbers, whole numbers
called ints and
decimals called floats.
Any time you see a number
without a decimal point,
it's an int, and we'll be using
those terms, int and float,
throughout the course.
In Python, just like any
programming language,
the order of operations matters.
In the expression on
the left, (5 + 7)
is evaluated first because
of the parentheses.
Then behind the scenes,
we have 12 * 3,
with a final result of 36.
Any time you see this icon,
that means we're showing you
behind the scenes steps.
On the right, without the
parentheses, 7 * 3
happens first.
So behind the scenes, we have
5 + 21, with a result of 26.
The order is an easy to
remember mnemonic: PEMDAS, which
stands for Parentheses,
Exponent, Multiplication,
Division, Addition, Subtraction.
Let's apply our Python math
knowledge to a common math
problem in the Monty Python
world: can a swallow carry
a coconut?
What we know is, a
swallow weighs 60 grams.
And we'll assume
that a swallow can
carry a third of
its weight, even
though that's dependent on
air speed and other factors.
If we divide 60
grams by 3, we see
that a swallow can
carry 20 grams,
but a coconut
weighs 1450 grams.
Obviously, a swallow
can't carry a coconut.
So how many swallows
would it take?
We divide the coconut's
weight, 1450,
by the swallow's carrying
limit, 60 divided by 3.
This will tell us
how many swallows it
will take to carry a coconut.
We get 8.06, which
seems way too low.
We may have messed up
the math somewhere.
If we take a closer look at
what got evaluated first,
we see we may have
made an error.
We actually want 60 divided
by 3 to be evaluated first,
and we can add
parentheses to fix this.
When we add the
parentheses, we get
the correct answer
of 72.5 swallows
to carry a coconut, which
is a lot of swallows.
And now it's your
turn to practice
writing your first Python
code in the challenges.
Have fun.