Welcome back.
We've calculated
how many swallows
it takes to carry a coconut.
Now let's see if
a single swallow
can carry any other fruits.
Repeating the same
calculations for an apple,
we need 6.4 swallows.
For a cherry, we
get 0.4 swallows.
And great!
We found one that works.
One swallow would be
able to carry a cherry.
However, looking back at
these three calculations,
we're repeating the same
60 divided by 3 a lot.
Wouldn't it be great if
we could store this value
and then use it when we need it?
We can do this with a variable.
A variable provides us with
a way to label and access
information.
We create variables
with the name
of the variable on
the left and the value
we want to store on the right.
This is called an
assignment statement.
Once we have created
our variable,
we can reference it and
get the value we stored,
which means less
repeated calculations,
and our code is more organized.
Using variables also
makes your code readable
by assigning meaning to values.
If we look at this line
of code, it's not clear
what we're calculating.
But if we use a
variable, we can infer
that we're calculating the
number of swallows required
to carry a cherry, and then
we can reference this variable
and get the value
we calculated later.
There are certain
rules for naming
your variables:
no spaces and you
can't start with a number
or a special character.
Other than that, it's
whatever you want.
For the most part,
you'll want to name
your variables
something concise,
but detailed enough that
someone reading your code
would be able to understand
what you're trying to do.
For instance, we could
have named our variable
swallow_carrying_limit.
But instead, to be
concise we named
our variable swallow_limit.
Pep 8 is a Python style guide
that recommends using lowercase
with underscores for spaces.
So if you want to
be Python stylish,
we recommend following
that suggestion.
Some people prefer
camel case which
is using capital letters
to separate words instead
of underscores, which works
fine, but following Pep 8
is more pythonic.
Let's apply what we learned
with the swallow problem
and see how many macaws it
would take to carry a coconut.
First, we'll declare
variables to store
all of our assumptions:  the
percentage of the weight they
can carry, the coconut's
weight and the macaw's weight.
Then we calculate the macaw's
carrying-limit as 300 grams.
We can then create a variable
for number of macaws required
and calculate the
coconut's weight divided
by the macaw's carrying
limit, and we get 4.8 macaws.
However, 4.8 means we
have part of a macaw.
It would be great if we
could round this number up
to 5 so that we know
we have 5 whole birds.
Often, we will want to
use functions not built
into the Python language.
Right now is a perfect time to
use the math library or module.
To use this module,
we just import it
by typing import math.
Math has a function called
ceil, short for ceiling.
And it just rounds up a number
to the nearest whole number.
Then we can write math.seal
and put the num_macaws variable
inside the parentheses.
And we get the result of 5.
math is part of the
Python standard library,
so it comes already
installed with Python.
To see other modules
installed with Python,
you can visit the Python
docs at the link below.
Putting this all together,
we get our final program
where we import math at the top,
and use the math.ceil function
at the bottom.
So now it's your turn to
practice some more Python
with variables in
the challenges.
Good luck.