[HORN PLAYING]
[SINGING] It's
time to learn some
Python the language to rely
on from printing strings
to math routines,
variables on the horizon.
Start using true,
false and conditionals
as you Try Python's
basic principles.
Welcome back to "Try Python."
I'm Sarah Buchanan, and
this is level two, where
we'll be talking about strings.
We've looked at
math and variables.
Now we'll be looking at
strings, which are just
a sequence of characters,
meaning letters, numbers,
punctuation or a combination.
The way you indicate a string
is a string and not a command
is by surrounding
it with quotes.
Either single or double
will work in Python.
You want to be consistent.
We'll use single quotes.
So here we create the string
'Hello world'
And we've also created
a string to store
the text of this
license plate, 'SPAM83'
In these examples,
the characters inside
of the open and closed
quotes are now strings.
Just like with numbers.
We can store strings
in variables.
Here we have the variable
first_name storing the string
'Monty' and the
variable last_name
storing the string 'Python'
Here we concatenated
first_name with last_name
into the variable full_name.
And if we look at the
contents of full_name,
we have 'MontyPython'
It doesn't have
a space in there.
We'd have to concatenate
that separately.
We can do that by combining
first_name plus a space
character plus last_name to
get the result of
'Monty Python'
As our programs get
longer, we won't
want to type
individual statements
into the interpreter.
What we'll want is a file
or script to hold our code.
This is what it'll
look like when we
have everything in one script.
We'll have the name of our
script above the file that
contains our code.
Here it's named script.py,
which stands for Python.
With the script, how
can we output the value
of the full name variable?
We can't just query the
variable name in the interpreter
as we've been doing.
We can use a
function called print
to output from a script file.
You write it by typing
print plus the value
or variable you want to
print in the parentheses.
We can put as many
arguments as we
want into the print function.
Just separate them with
commas and print automatically
adds a space between
your arguments.
So we don't have to worry about
concatenating a space here.
You're probably using Python 3,
but if you're using Python 2,
keep an eye out for these
Py 2 icons in this course.
To run our script, assuming
we have Python installed,
we go to the console and
type python and the name
of our script, and it will
print all of our output
to the console.
Let's demo running our script.
Here it's created in Idle, an
editor installed with Python.
Then when we run
our script, we can
see 'Monty Python' is
printed to the screen.
Let's create a script to
describe what Monty Python is.
We'll start the
script with a comment.
The pound symbol (#) means
this line is a comment
and doesn't get run.
A comment is a note to
yourself and other programmers
describing what you're doing
in case it's not clear.
We'll also create
variables to describe
Monty Python: their
name, description,
and the year they started.
We'll then concatenate all of
these descriptive variables
into a sentence.
But when we try to
run this, we get
an error:   "Can't convert
'int' object to str implicitly."
This is confusing
to the interpreter
because we're trying to
add a number to a string.
So it's not sure whether we
want to add or concatenate
the number.
We'll have to convert the
number to a string first.
We could add quotes to make
the year a string instead
of an int, but we really want
to keep numbers as numbers.
So we'll have to try
something else here.
Instead, we will
convert our number
to a string using the str
function around our year.
This will convert
whatever is inside
the parentheses to a string
and we get our desired sentence
printed to the screen.
We could have also
put our values
into a print statement
separated by commas,
and print would automatically
convert them to strings for us
and add spaces between them.
Let's also add some Monty
Python sketches to our program.
A good one is Hell's Grannies.
But if we run this,
we get a syntax error.
The problem is when
the interpreter sees
the apostrophe, it thinks the
quote has ended and doesn't
know what the s is.
We can instead use double
quotes to start our string,
and Python will look for
the matching double quote
to end the string.
Then Python knows the
single quote is literally
a single quote and
not ending the string.
Let's add another famous
sketch, the Dead Parrot.
And we can print
these two sketches out
with a space between.
This works, but
we want to format
it better to make it clear we're
printing two separate sketches.
We can add a special character,
a backslash (\) followed by an n.
This means newline.
The backslash encodes hard to
type characters like new line
into a string.
We just add this into our string
wherever we want a new line,
just like we would a space.
Let's also print the
heading, 'Famous Work'
Our sketches are
starting to look better,
but let's also
indent the titles.
We can indent the
sketches with \t,
a special character
that means Tab.
And we can see our result
now has the titles indented.
That's the end of section one.
It's time for you to practice
strings in the challenges.
Have fun.