Welcome back.
Behind the scenes,
strings are a list
of characters where
each character has
an index or a position
numbered starting from 0.
Here we see the string greeting
is 'HELLO WORLD!'
We can get the
character at index 0
by writing the variable name
greeting[0]
which gives us the character H.
Since this string
has 12 characters
and the first character
is at index 0,
the last character is index 11.
So greeting[11] gives us the character
exclamation point.
And greeting[12] gives us
an error, because there isn't
a character at position 12.
We can only look up characters
at indexes 0 through 11.
There are a few built in string
functions we'll want to use.
len, l-e-n, returns the
length of the string
inside of the parentheses.
So if we have the greeting
variable storing 'HELLO WORLD!',
len(greeting)
will return 12.
And then we can
print the result.
So this will print
12 to the screen.
Let's use this new knowledge
of strings to solve a problem.
We know a man that can
only say the ends of words.
He goes to say Good Evening,
and what comes out is od ning.
And we want to predict
what he's going to say.
If we look at the
first word Good,
we can get the last
half of the word
by concatenating the
characters at indexes 2 and 3,
storing this into
the variable end1.
And then we get the result
od, which is what we wanted.
Instead of looking up
individual characters
and concatenating them,
we can use a slice
to return part of the string.
For example, here we've
got the word Python.
Let's say we just want to
return the letters t-h-o
in the middle with one slice.
You can imagine this
slice having boundaries
surrounding these letters.
Notice this boundary comes
before the second index
and before the fifth index.
So the way we write
this slice in code
is the variable name,
word, square brackets,
our start boundary
index 2, colon,
our end boundary index 5.
Notice the boundary is
actually between indexes.
The first boundary goes
between the indexes 1 and 2,
and the last boundary
goes between 4 and 5.
That means the characters
that indexes 2, 3, and 4
are returned by the slice.
And here, that's the
letters t, h and o.
Looking at some more
examples, given the word Good,
the slice from index 0 to
2 returns the string G-o.
You can think of this as
putting a marker before the 0
index and a marker
before the 2 index,
and that will return the string
between the two markers, which
is Go.
We can also do a string slice
from index 2 to index 4,
and that will return
the string o-d.
There are some shortcuts
we can use here.
We can leave the beginning,
0, out altogether,
and that means start
at the beginning.
And we can leave the
end out altogether,
and that means go to the end.
There's a formula you can
use to figure out what
numbers to put into your slice.
The index of the
first character you
want colon the index of the
last character you want plus 1.
If you use that formula, you'll
always get a perfect slice.
Let's incorporate string
slices into our solution.
Instead of concatenating the
characters at index 2 and 3,
we'll use a slice
from index 2 to 4.
This will return the last
half of our word Good.
Let's also try our shortcut.
We can leave out the
end index, and the slice
will go to the
end of our string.
And we'll also add the
second word Evening.
We can print both
of our slices out,
and we get the result od
ning, which is what we wanted.
But wouldn't it be
great if we didn't
have to just know the
halfway points of our strings
were at indexes 2 and 3?
We're going to make our program
work better for all words
instead of hard coding the
halfway points of our strings.
We can calculate the
halfway index of our string
by using the len
function divided by 2.
However, division
returns a float.
So 4 divided by 2 is 2.0,
and 7 divided by 2 is 3.5.
And this is a problem,
because we can only
have an int or a whole
number as an index.
To solve this problem, we
can use integer division,
which is two division signs.
This will round down to the
nearest whole number or int.
So using integer division,
4 divided by 2 is 2,
and 7 divided by 2 is 3.
This is different
in Python 2, where
single division and integer
division are the same thing.
For end1, we replace the index
2 with our calculated halfway
value, and the same for end2.
Perfect.
We still get what
we wanted: od ning.
And our program will work
for strings of any length.
Now it's time for you to
practice string slices
in the challenges.
Good luck.