[SINGING] It's time to learn
some Python, the language
to rely on.
From printing strings
to math routines.
Variables on the horizon.
Start using True/False
and conditionals
as you Try Python's
basic principles.
Welcome back to Try Python.
I'm Sarah Buchanan.
And this is Level 3,
Conditional Rules of Engagement,
covering conditionals and input.
We've been hired by
King Arthur to help
with his rules of engagement
in order to reduce casualties.
If there's less than 3
knights, we'll retreat.
If there's more than 10
knights, we have enough
to queue the Trojan Rabbit.
And otherwise, we'll
try to sign a truce.
Making these decisions
in Python starts
with comparison operators.
There are six of these
comparators in Python:
less than (<), less than
equal to (<=), equal to (==),
greater than equal to (>=),
greater than (>), and one
you may have not seen
before, not equal to (!=).
These comparison statements
act as if they're
asking a question,
like is 5 less than 10,
and then give you a
True or False answer.
Here it's True.
Is 5 equal to 10?
False.
We can also compare things other
than numbers, like strings.
We assign our name
variable equal to 'Pam'
and then check is name equal
to 'Jim', which is False.
Is name not equal to 'Jim'?
That's True.
If we look at using all six
comparators on our values
5 and 10, we get a
mix of True and False.
For instance, 5 less than 10 is
True, 5 equal to 10 is False,
5 greater than 10 is False,
5 less than or equal to 10
is True, 5 not
equal to 10 is True,
and finally, 5 greater than
or equal to 10 is False.
These True and False
values are called Booleans.
Booleans are built in
types like the ones we've
seen before -- int,
float and string --
and can only be True or False.
No maybes.
We can also create a
variable to store a Boolean.
Here is_raining
stores the value True.
The place where we use Booleans
the most is in an if statement.
They allow us to decide whether
to run a certain piece of code
depending on whether the
statement is True or False.
Here num_knights is equal to 2.
So the conditional
num_knights is less than 3
evaluates to True.
So we run whatever is in
the indented code block
below, which, in this case,
prints the strings 'Retreat!'
and 'Raise the white flag!'
Here num_knights is 4.
So the if statement
evaluates to False,
and the indented
code block isn't run.
So nothing happens here.
It's important to know
that the program keeps
running after the conditional
as normal line by line.
So here,
print('Knights of the Round Table!')
gets run after the
conditional block.
Python whitespace is
also super particular.
If you use two
spaces on one line
and four spaces on the next,
your program will not run.
You must be very consistent.
PEP 8, the Python
style guide, recommends
four spaces for an indent.
Many text editors
will do this for you
when you tab so you don't have
to worry about counting spaces.
In order to continue
implementing
our rules of engagement,
we'll need something that
handles an otherwise condition.
In Python, that's
an else statement.
An else statement provides
an alternative thing
to do if the if
statement is False.
Here if num_knights is
less than 3, print('Retreat!')
If it's not less
than 3, print('Truce?')
Here num_knights is equal
to 4, so we print('Truce?')
It's time for you to do some
conditionals in the challenges.
Have fun.