Getting back to our rules
of engagement problem,
num_knights is now equal to 10.
And if you remember, if we
have at least 10 knights,
we want to cue
the Trojan Rabbit.
So we want to add
another conditional here
that says if there are
at least 10 knights, cue
the Trojan Rabbit.
It allows you to keep
checking more conditions
after the if statement is false
and before the else statement.
Here, if num_knights is less
than 3, we print('Retreat!)
Otherwise, if we have
at least 10 knights,
print('Trojan Rabbit')
Otherwise, if it's
Tuesday, print('Taco Night'),
and if all three of these things
are False, we'll print('Truce?').
Another thing to note is as soon
as one of those ifs or elifs
are true, we'll run
that block of code
and then exit the conditional.
We can combine conditionals
with Boolean operators
and and or, which will come in
handy because King Arthur has
complicated our rules of
engagement a little bit.
He's declared that on
Mondays, we always retreat,
and we can only use the
Trojan Rabbit on Wednesdays
because we have to
rent it out for parties
on the other days of the week.
Let's start out by handling
the new Monday rule.
If num_knights is less than 3,
we retreat, or if it's a Monday
we retreat.
In conditionals, we can
have multiple comparisons
separated by the or operator.
Here, we'll handle
the Trojan Rabbit rule
by checking if we have
at least 10 knights
and the day of the
week is Wednesday.
and and or make it possible
to combine Booleans.
A True and a True
result in a True.
A True and a False
result in a False.
Basically, if there's one
False in an and statement,
the result will always be False.
For or, one value
only has to be True
and this statement
will result in a True.
For example, True or
False results in True.
Here's our program
after we incorporated
King Arthur's request
for the day of the week.
Instead of assigning
hard coded values
to our variables
in our script, we
can ask the user to
input their own values.
input is a built in function
in Python, like print.
It will print out this
statement to the user
and then wait for the
user to enter their answer
and then save that value.
For example, we have
input('Enter the day of the week')
We run the program.
It asks the user for the day
of the week, they enter Monday,
we save that into
the day variable
and then we print it back out:
'You entered: Monday'
Since input comes
in as a string,
if we want the user
to enter a number,
we have to convert their
text input to a number.
We can do this with
the int function.
Now that num_knights
is a number,
we can print it
out to the console
and then check if it's less
than 10 or the day is Monday.
Since neither of those are
True, we don't print('Retreat!')
Let's look at how different
user input changes
the outcome of our program.
Here, if the user enters 2
for the number of knights
and Tuesday for the day of
the week, 'Retreat!' is printed.
If the user enters 12
for the number of knights
and Wednesday for the day,
'Trojan Rabbit' is printed.
We've encountered a
new enemy that has
thrown a wrench in our plans.
If we see a Killer
Bunny, we have
to throw the Holy Hand Grenade.
Otherwise, we'll use our
original rules of engagement.
This kind of
situation will come up
a lot in your
programs, where you'll
need to follow one decision
with a series of decisions.
That's called a
nested conditional.
Here, we check if there
is a Killer Bunny.
If so, we use the
Holy Hand Grenade.
Otherwise, we nest in
our original battle rules
into the else block.
Here, you can see our final
rules of engagement program,
complete with a
nested conditional.
Now it's time for you to
play with some more complex
conditionals in the challenges.
Good luck, and I'll see
you in the wrap-up video.
I feel like I'm like shouting.
I'm a little a
shy about smiling.
I know, it's weird.
Dang it.
Here, we can-- concatenated.
It's a hard word.
Characters where each-- I'm
sorry, I'm like losing my mind.
We use the Holy Hand
Grenade-- grand-enade.
[LAUGHTER]
That was good.
All right.