Welcome back to level
six of Core IOS 7.
In this level, we're going to be
talking about parallax and
motion effects.
But when I say parallax, what
does that actually mean?
Well, in the case of the IOS 7
app, it's a technique to add
depth to an otherwise
flat interface.
As you can see here, we
have a view sitting on
top of another view.
And when we tilt the phone in
various ways, the view moves
so you can see more of
what's underneath.
This effect simulates that one
view is on top of the other
and gives the feeling
of a 3D interface.
As you can see, when there's no
tilt on the horizontal axis
on the phone, the top view
sits right in the center.
Then when the device tilts to
the left, the top view moves a
little to the left.
And when the phone is tilted
to the right, the top view
moves to the right.
The same idea works for
the vertical axis.
When you're looking straight
on, the view is
right in the center.
When you tilt it down a little
bit, the view goes down.
And when you tilt it up,
the view goes up.
To implement this parallax
effect in our IOS 7 apps,
there's a new API called
UIMotionEffects, which is a
set of classes that performs
changes based on the tilt on
the x and y-access, like
we saw earlier.
This is much easier to implement
than just looking at
the raw device motion
updates, which you
could have done before.
But this saves you a couple
hundred lines of code.
So let's jump into some code
and look how we would
implement this parallax effect
on our Login View controller
that we were just looking at.
As you can see here, we're
in the viewDidLoad.
And we're creating a new UI
interpolating motion effect.
To create this object, we're
using the Init With Key Path
type initializer.
And we're passing in the
center.x key path, which is
the property that we're
going to change.
And the type is UI Interpolating
Motion Effect
Type Tilt Along Horizontal Axis,
which means we'll be
working on the horizontal
axis in this effect.
And then finally, we're going
to add this motion effect to
our Login View controller's
view.
Because we set the key path to
center x, the Login View
controller's views center x
property will change when the
device is tilted--
in this case, in the
horizontal axis.
But how much, in this case, does
center x change when the
device is tilted?
Well, to specify that, we have
to set the maximum relative
value and the minimum relative
value on the center x object.
These two properties specify
the range of motion on this
motion effect.
So in this case, the most the
value will change will be 20
points to the right and
20 points to the left.
So we've set our maximum and
minimum relative values on our
motion effect.
But what about all those points
in between when, say,
the device is only
tilted by 25%?
Well, that's where the
interpolating part of the UI
Interpolating Motion Effect
class comes in.
So for example, if the offset
value is 0.25, our relative
value is 20, then the change
in the center x is 5.
Now you don't actually need to
do any of this calculation
yourself, because UI
Interpolating Motion Effect
takes care of that for you.
But it's good to know what's
going on under the hood.
Now that we've implemented the
horizontal tilt effect, we can
go ahead and do the same thing
for the vertical tilt effect.
As you can see here, not
much has changed.
We're still creating
a UI Interpolating
Motion Effect object.
And we are passing in center y
this time to the Init Width
Key Path argument.
And we're using the vertical
axis constant instead of the
horizontal axis one.
We're also setting the same
maximum and minimum relative
values for this motion effect
and then, once again, adding
it to our view.
Now our view has multiple motion
effects, which means it
would be better if we grouped
these motion effects in a UI
Motion Effect group.
To do that, we just need to
create a new instance of UI
Motion Affect group and then set
the center x and center y
objects as that group's
motion effects.
And then instead of adding the
individual effects to the
view, we add the
group instead.
When you have multiple motion
effects on the same view,
you'll want to use a UI Motion
Effect group so those effects
get applied at the same time.
And it's more efficient
that way.
Now we have a working parallax
effect on both the vertical
and horizontal axis.
In addition to creating parallax
effects, UI Motion
Effects can be used to change
any property that is
animatable by core animation on
UIView, such as the frame,
the bounds, the alpha value.
And you can use them to change
any of the views layer
properties, such as border
width, anchor point, bounds,
and even the shadow offset.
For example, we could move the
shadows position as device is
tilted to create this dynamic
lighting effect,
as you can see here.
So let's run through real
quick how we'd actually
accomplish this.
We're inside of a View
Controller's viewDidLoad
method here.
We create the gray block view,
as you can see on screen here.
And then we get access
to its layer.
Now before we animate anything,
we're going to have
to set up the initial state of
the shadow on this block view,
as you can see here.
Notice that we're setting the
initial state of the shadow
offset to 0, 0, meaning that
it's going to be directly
behind the view.
Setting the shadow offset to
0, 0 is important, because
this is the property that we're
going to be animating
with our motion effects
in a minute.
Now that we have our initial
view and shadow set up, we can
go ahead and add our
motion effects.
Now most of this code is going
to look almost exactly like
our previous example.
Notice though that are key
paths have changed.
We're using the layer shadow
offset width key path.
And that works because shadow
offset is a CGSize struct.
The other thing to note is
that we've inverted the
maximum and minimum
relative values.
That way the shadow will move
how you would expect it to.
So there's a lot of repeated
code here.
For example, what if we wanted
to use this shadow effect on
another view?
We wouldn't want to have to
type all this out again.
So how might we go about
refactoring this?
One way to clean up this code
is to implement a new custom
subclass of UI Motion Effect.
And all we have to do in that
subclass is implement the key
paths and relative values for
Viewer Offset method.
So we create a new class called
Shadow Motion Effect.
In the implementation of the Key
Path's method, we need to
return an NS dictionary.
This dictionary is going to
define which properties change
and by how much.
To calculate how much the shadow
offset's width and
height should change,
we use the Viewer
Offset Object [? Path ?]
In.
Since we're no longer using the
UI Interpolating Motion
Effect class, we have to
multiply our viewer offset
values by the min and max
relative values, which in this
case is 50, but could be
whatever you felt was
appropriate.
So that's all the set
up we need for
our new custom subclass.
Now we can use it in our
implementation, just like this.
You can use this new custom
subclass in UI Motion Effect
groups, just like any
other motion effect.
What if we wanted to build
something a little more
complex and interesting, like
this mock Safari tab view
here, where we're rotating
these views in 3D space.
How do we do that?
Well, we'd have to dive
in a little bit more
into the Views layer.
Every UIView has a backing
the layer, which is
an instance of CALayer.
Now CALayer handles things like
rendering and layout and
animation, while UIView handles
user interaction.
CALayer will also give you
access to features that UIView
doesn't have, such as shadows
that we just saw, rounded
corners, colored borders.
And most relevant to this
example, it gives us access to
3D transforms and positioning.
So let's jump into the code to
create a really simple example
of this 3D rotation motion
effect using the layer's 3D
transforms.
So here we're setting up our
initial state in viewDidLoad.
And we're just creating a single
view and adding that to
our view hierarchy.
So first, we get access to the
Block View Layers transform.
Then we're going to rotate the
transform by 45 degrees around
the x-axis by calling the CA
Transform 3D Rotate function.
And finally, we'll apply that
transform to the layer.
As you can see here, it looks
like something has gone wrong.
Our gray box here just looks
like it got a little shorter
instead of looking like
it's in 3D space.
And that's because it's
missing perspective.
So how do we add that back in?
To set a 3D perspective on this
transform, we have to set
the m34 property.
We do that by dividing negative
1 by some number.
In this case, we're dividing
it by 500.
This number specifies the
distance between the imaginary
camera and the screen
endpoints.
You can play around with this
number to see how it affects
the display and to find out
which value works best.
By setting that m34 property,
our gray box now looks like
it's been rotated in 3D space,
as you can see here.
That work we just did was to
set the rotation manually.
But now we want to create a
vertical motion effect to have
the view rotate as the
device is tilted.
To do that, we create new
interpolating motion effect,
and we set the key path
to layer transform.
We create new default transform
using the CA
Transform 3D Identity
constant.
And then we use that new
transform to create new
minimum and maximum rotated
transforms that we're going to
use on our maximum and minimum
relative values.
One thing to note is that we
have to wrap those transforms
in an NS value before we set
them on the maximum or minimum
relative value properties.
Then all we have to do
is add that motion
effect to the view.
Now you can see that our view is
rotating in response to the
device's motion.
But it's rotating around the
center point of view when we
want it to rotate around the top
of the view, like it does
in the Safari Tab view.
And to fix that, we have
to update the View
Layers anchor point.
So let's see how changing the
anchor point of a layer
effects rotation.
By default, the anchor point is
in the center of the view,
or 0.5 by 0.5.
And when we rotate that view
by 45 degrees, it rotates
around that point.
Now, if we update the anchor
point to, say, 0, 0, which is
in the top left of the layer,
when we rotate by 45 degrees,
it now rotates in
a different way.
So for this example, since we
want to rotate around the top,
we can just set the point to 0.5
and 0, which, as you can
see, will rotate around
the top center.
So back in the code, we just
set our anchor point on the
layer to a new CG
point of 0.5, 0.
One thing to note though is that
you're going to want to
set the view's frame after you
set the anchor point, because
the anchor point will move the
bounds of the view, and it'll
be out of position.
Now you can see that when we
tilt the device, the view is
rotating in 3D space around
the top of its view.
Now it's time for you to
practice motion effects and
parallax in the challenges.
Good luck.