Welcome back.
In this section, we're going to
be looking at the new iOS 7
UI view snapshotting API.
The new snapshotting API is
really just a fast way to
flatten an entire view hierarchy
into a single
rendered view.
And that view is really useful
when you're pairing it with
things like animated and
interactive transitions.
The code to create this snapshot
is pretty simple.
We just pass the Snapshot View
After Screen Updates
method to some view.
And we store the result inside
of a new UI View Object.
Now there is one argument to
this method that's a boolean,
indicating whether or not
snapshot view is going to
contain recent changes
made to self.view.
So let's take a look
at what that means.
In this demo app, when we tap
one of these buttons, the top
square is assigned a
random color, and
a snapshot is taken.
If we pass in No to the snapshot
method, then the
color is applied after the
snapshot is taken, meaning
that the two boxes will never
have the same color in them.
If we pass Yes into the snapshot
method, then the
snapshot is taken after the
color is applied, thus, the
two squares will have the
same color in them.
So the previous example
showed that
snapshots are really fast.
And that makes them great to
use in custom animated
transitions, because it allows
you to animate a single
snapshotted view instead of
an entire view hierarchy.
And that's going to result in
a much higher frame rate
during animations.
Let's look at that a
little bit closer.
For this login view controller
that we've been animating in
previous examples, this is what
the view hierarchy might
look like if we were to
not use snapshotting.
So you can see, we've got at
least 20 different views in
here that have to be moved. l
And frames have to be changed
every time an animation
happens.
If instead, we were able to use
a UI View snapshot instead
of the full UI View hierarchy,
we could reduce that down to
one single view.
We covered animated transitions
in great detail in
level three of this course.
But we're going to review some
of the more relevant set-up
pieces to what we're
doing right now.
First, inside of our Animate
Transition method, we need to
insert the modal view into the
transition view's hierarchy.
Next, we need to set the
starting position of our modal
view, which, in this case, is
our login view controller,
represented here by toVC.
Then we'll animate the modal
view in the position using UI
View Animations or
UI Kit Dynamics.
And finally, we'll complete
the transition once the
animations have finished.
So to start updating this
transition to take advantage
of the new snapshotting APIs,
we first want to create a
snapshot view from toVC.view.
And we definitely want to make
sure and take the snapshot
after the screen updates, or
the snapshot will be blank,
because it's part of that
animated transition.
Then we'll update the snapshot
view's frame to be equal to
the toVC.view's frame.
Then in the UI View Animation
block, instead of animating
the toVC.view's frame, we
animate the snapshot views
frame into place.
And finally, in the completion
block, we need to swap the
snapshot view for the actual
toVC.view before we complete
the transition.
We need to do this because the
snapshot view was just a
temporary copy we made to make
our transition go faster.
And ultimately, we
want the actual
toVC.view to be in place.
And now it's your turn to get
those frame rates up with UI
View snapshotting in
the challenges.
Have fun.
[BEEP]
Push a new navigation--
And rotated around an access--
Why did I even try?
[BEEP]
Look at how we can
fix this problem.
Did I get it?
Yeah.
[BEEP]