Welcome to Level 8 of Core iOS7.
In this level, we'll be
looking at the improvements
that iOS7 brings to networking
and multitasking APIs.
In iOS7, there's new APIs
for background uploads
and downloads, background
updates like background fetch,
silent push notifications,
and a brand new networking
API called NSURL session that
replaces NSURL connection.
First, let's talk
about the things
that the new NSURL session
updated architecture brings.
First, you can now initiate
background downloads
and uploads over standard
HTTP connections.
This is when your app
closes, it can actually
still finish downloads
after it closes.
Next, there's advanced support
for pausable and resumable
requests.
So while a user
is using your app,
they can decide
to stop a download
once it's already started.
You can now isolate
caching cookies
and other types of
credentials to an app where
before these were all global.
And finally, it enables you
to build private browsing HTTP
sessions into your
own applications.
Previously, this
was just available
in the Safari application.
So we need to look at how we can
transition from the old NSURL
connection API to the
new NSURL session API.
In iOS6, the way that
this worked was you
had NSURL, NSURL request,
and NSURL cache classes.
And you would combine them
with an NSURL connection
class and its various
methods and delegate
methods to make requests
and retrieve responses.
In iOS7, those URL methods
are the same basic classes,
but the NSURL
connection API has been
replaced with the NSURL session
class and various helper
and delegate classes, like NSURL
session data task, download
task, upload task, and
session configuration.
There's several different ways
to create a session object,
depending on the type of
session that you need.
If you need a session that
mimics the way that NSURL
connection worked, you can just
pass the shared session message
to the NSURL session class.
Most of the time
though, you'll want
to declare a configuration
profile first.
And to do that, you can
just create an NSURL session
configuration object
and then create
a session using the session
with configuration initializer.
To create a session that's going
to support background downloads
and uploads, you'll again create
a URL session configuration
and you'll pass it a unique key
using the background session
configuration message.
And you can even modify
that session configuration
to do things like allow
cellular access or not.
Which would allow you to
limit cellular downloads
for data inside of your app.
We built a sample app to
use in this section called
Searchagrams.
Searchagrams is powered
by the Instagram API.
And every time we make a
request for a search term,
we get a standard JSON response.
Our JSON response contains
an array of images
that we'll use to display data
inside of our application.
If we were to make this request
using the NSURL connection API,
it might look
something like this.
One of the screens in our app
is the photos view controller
which returns a
list of photos based
on a search term
that's been entered.
Every time this photos
view controller loads,
the refresh photos method fires.
And if we were to use the old
NSURL connection approach,
it might look
something like this.
The problem with
this approach is
there's no way to handle
any kind of authentication
challenges, any redirects, or
even cancel the request if you
want to cancel it after
it's been started.
So is iOS7, we replaced
the NSURL connection
calls with their NSURL
session equivalents.
Notice that all of the NSURL
and NSURL request set up
is exactly the same.
But now we create a
session configuration,
turn on the session, and
then pass the data task
with request completion handler
message to that session.
There's a little more
we have to do here
to get this working properly.
The completion handler, which
fires whenever the request is
complete, is not guaranteed
to run on the main thread
when you're using
an NSURL session.
So we need to force that code
in the completion handler
to run on the main thread.
Remember that any UI update
has to run on the main thread.
So we can force it to run there
by using an NS operation queue
and calling our table
view reload data method
inside of that block.
Now all this code
is determining what
happens when the session
finishes running.
But we're missing
an important step.
We haven't actually
started the session yet.
There are many different
ways to create a task
but just creating a task
does not make the request.
We have to first resume
the task to start.
And here you see the
request working properly.
We're able to click on a
tag and see a response that
contains different users,
time stamps, and eventually
photos posted by those users.
But obviously, you
can see that we're not
displaying those photos yet.
So we need to write
another request
to actually grab those
images from the server.
Since this is a table
view, these images
will be loaded in the
table view cell for row
at index path method.
And here you can
see what that would
look like if we were using
the old NSURL connection API.
Again, we'll replace all
that NSURL connection
code with a session
configuration,
create our session object,
start a session data task,
and then in the
completion handler,
instead of reloading
the table, we'll
update the cells image
view on the main thread,
remembering to pass the resume
message to the task object
so the request starts.
This will actually load
the images just fine,
but there's another
problem that's
a little bit harder to diagnose
and it's a performance problem.
Because the cell for
row at index path method
runs over and over
again, we're actually
creating a new session
object for every cell
that we create multiple times.
And we just want
one session object
that each one of
these cells can use.
To fix this, inside of our
photos view controller header,
we'll declare an
NSURL session property
and then we'll create
the session inside a view
did load instead of the
cell creation method.
This way we'll only
ever have one session.
Then back in the cell for
row at index path method,
we'll replace all
our local references
to that NSURL session with our
self.image session property.
And here's our app working.
If we tap on a tag and we
scroll through the table view,
each of the images for
that table view load.
But what if we were to
hit the Back button,
and then tap on
the same tag again?
It seems like all
these images should
be cached so we don't have
to download them again.
But if we inspect
the HTTP traffic,
you can see that these images
are being requested again
when we go back to the
same table view controller.
To fix this, we can modify
the URL cache property inside
of our NSURL session
configuration object.
And by default, every
request is stored
in the same global cache.
But we don't want that.
We want to create
a separate cache
for just our image requests.
And you can see here, if we
were to dig into the cache
database, which is
an SQLite3 database,
we can see all of the requests
that were cached inside.
Again, this is the
global NSURL cache.
To create a custom cache, we'll
update our URL cache object
using the init with memory
capacity, disk capacity, disk
path initializer.
Now the memory capacity
and disk capacity here,
we're just making
large enough to make
sure we can store
all of our requests.
And the disk path
is really important.
That's going to be the
name of our custom cache
that's not global anymore.
I also want to mention that
there are different caching
policies for
different situations.
But in this case
the default policy
will be the one that we use.
Here you can see that if
we reset our global cache
inside of the simulator, and
then reload the application,
all of our images load without
making new requests which
you would see in the console on
the right side of the screen.
This means that our custom cache
is set up and working properly.
Creating caches for
certain types of data
is really useful, especially
when you have multiple session
requests for different
types of data.
Here we're using a
custom images cache only
for situations where we're
requesting image data directly.
Other requests inside
of our application,
like those for a search term,
still happen on the main cache.
Properly caching requests,
even in a best case scenario,
is always a good idea, but also
testing under the worst case
scenario can help
you uncover bugs
that you might not normally see.
To simulate that worst case
scenario for network requests,
Apple provides a tool called
Network Link Conditioner
that you can download
from the dev site.
When you open up that DMG,
there's a network link
conditioner .prefpane file
that you can just drag and drop
into your system
preferences window.
Then you can turn the
network link conditioner on
and change your profile
to simulate everything
from really bad edge
network to super fast WiFi.
Now your app will respond
accordingly inside
of the simulator.
Here's one bug that
only becomes apparent
when the network
performance is really bad.
You can see here that
we loaded up a tag,
and we're scrolling
through these images.
And we're waiting
for all of our images
to download and something
really weird's happening.
After the images
have been downloaded,
they seem to just
randomly change.
What's happening is that cells
from the top of the table view
are actually being
reused when we scroll
to the bottom of the table view
before any image requests have
finished.
So to fix this, we need
to make sure to cancel
a request every time
the cell is reused.
Back in our original code in
the cell for row at index path
method, you can see
that we're not currently
associating a task with a cell.
So to fix this, we can create
a UI table view cell subclass
that we're calling MyPhotoCell
and move the task object
to that subclass.
And we're not showing you all
the code inside of that custom
subclass because you've done
this kind of thing before.
There's just a property that's
of type NSURL session data
task inside of that subclass.
The most important
thing this lets us do
is to check if the cell has
a task currently running
and then cancel that task if
the cell is trying to be reused.
Now when we run the app and
we scroll in the table view,
we can see that our
images still aren't
loading in the way
we'd expect them to.
This is because our
completion handler
gets called every single
time that request happens.
But it's not currently
taking into account
what happens if a request got
canceled right in the middle.
It's still trying
to load an image,
and then it doesn't
have one to load.
This completion
handler is being called
when the request completes and
when the request is canceled.
But right now, no
matter what happens,
we're trying to create
an image with it.
To fix this, we can
first check if there's
an error inside the
completion handler.
And if there is, that means
the task was canceled.
And if it wasn't
canceled, then we
can continue loading the image.
Finally, here you can
see our app working.
There's still one
more little tweak
we can make to our code to
make this a little bit more
efficient.
Right now, we're only
canceling requests
if a cell is trying
to be reused.
But what if we start
loading a bunch of images
and then immediately
hit the Back button?
We should probably cancel
all of our requests
when we hit the Back button too.
This is really easy to
do with NSURL sessions.
You need to pass the
invalidate and cancel message
to your session.
And that's going to wipe
out any active requests.
You can do this either in
dealloc method for photos view
controller.
You can also
invalidate a session
and allow the tasks
to finish if you
know you aren't going to be
using this session again.
And now it's time
for you to practice
using NSURL session
in the challenges.
Good luck.