Welcome back.
In the last section, we
used NSURL session methods
to initiate a video download.
But we still haven't
solved the problem
of allowing that download to
continue in the background
after the app has been closed.
First, let's look
conceptually at how
background downloads work.
We create an NSURL
session configuration,
just like we did
before, except this time
we'll give it a special
identifier so that we can know
that it's our
background session.
Then we initiate a
request with that session.
This is actually no
different than when
we made a foreground request.
The request code
is exactly the same
for foreground and
background downloads.
At that point, the NSURL session
background Daemon actually
processes the request
and periodically it
reports the progress
of the download.
If, at this point,
the app were to exit,
the background
Daemon would still
continue to download your
data until you either
open the app again or
the download finishes.
And at that point, the
app will be reloaded,
the NSURL session, background
session, will be reconnected,
and the completion delegate
method will be called.
So here's the code
we have currently
in our video view
controller before modifying
it to work with
background downloads.
If you were to look through
the Apple documentation
on NSURL session
configuration, you'd
see a method called background
session configuration.
This method accepts a string
as a unique identifier
in order to set up a
background session.
Here we're calling
ours MySession.
So we need to take
extra steps to make sure
that only one of
these is ever created,
and the easiest way
for us to do that is
to use the Dispatch
Once function.
By creating a static
NSURL session object
and using the Dispatch
Once function,
we can make sure that only one
background session is created.
Now that your
session's created, you
can go ahead and make
requests just like you
did when you were making
foreground requests.
But let's say that
the app closes
in the middle of your download.
Well there's a
method to override
in the app delegate called
application handle events
for background URL
session completion handler
that runs whenever background
downloads have finished
and the app is closed.
Inside of this method, you need
to recreate your background
session using the same
identifier and configuration
and delegate.
So that's easy enough.
We can just copy in our
NSURL session configuration
and session object, but we have
a little bit of an issue here.
If we set our delegate to self
inside of the app delegate,
we're saying that the app
delegate serves as our session
delegate which it does not.
Video view controller
was our session delegate.
So we need to figure out a
way to have the same delegate
class accessible from both the
app delegate and video view
controller.
Here's another way to visualize
the problem we're having.
If we go into video
view controller
and start a background
download session,
our self.download
session object
is created like we'd expect,
and the delegate for our session
is our video view controller.
If we were to then navigate away
from our video view controller
and open up another video and
try to start that download,
because our self.download
session only gets created once,
the same download
session will be used
but the delegate will still
point to the first video view
controller not the new video
view controller that we want.
So the quickest
solution is going
to be to remove the delegate
protocol from the video view
controller and
instead put it inside
of another class that will
sit in between the video view
controller and the session.
We're going to call that
class, video downloader.
And it will adopt the
NSURL session protocol
instead of the video
view controller.
Since this video
downloader class
will act as our shared
session manager,
we'll take that dispatch
once code and move it
from the video view controller
into the video downloader
in a method called shared.
This is a class
method that we can
call anytime we want
to return an instance
of the video downloader.
Using dispatch
once will make sure
that every time we call
this shared method, we'll
get the same video
downloader object making sure
that we're using
the same session.
We'll also take our NSURL
session configuration and NSURL
session object
creation and move it
inside to the video downloader
so it can all be in one place.
Notice that when we create
the NSURL session object,
we're setting the delegate to
self and self, in this case,
is the video downloader class.
And that's going to solve
our problem of needing
to have the delegate
in two places at once.
Now that we have the video
downloader initializer set up
properly, we need to make
a slight modification
to video view controller to
use that video downloader.
So the code we have right
now is sending the download
task with URL
message to the self.download
session object.
Instead we want to
send that method
to the video downloader
shared object.
That means that we
actually need to define
this method in the
video downloader.
And the implementation of this
method in video downloader
can be as simple as just
returning the result of sending
the download task with
URL method to the session.
Back in our video
view controller,
we also need to add some
notification observers that
are going to be
listening for when
the video downloader completes
certain parts of the request.
Here we've created one
observer that we'll
call the update progress method
whenever the download progress
notification is received
and another that we'll
call the finished download
method whenever the download
completion notification
is received.
Video downloader will
broadcast these notifications
and that will let video
view controller know
to take certain steps.
So let's look at where to
add these notifications
inside a video downloader.
We'll start with the method that
tracks progress of a download.
Before, we were updating the
progress indicator directly
in this method.
But since the progress indicator
is now in video view controller
and the delegate method
is in video downloader,
we can instead just track
that progress the same way
we did before and then post it
as a notification with a user
info dictionary.
This will allow the
observer to read the data
inside of that
dictionary, so it knows
how much progress has been made.
If this is the first time
you've heard of the user info
dictionary, it's kind of
an oddly named parameter.
It actually has nothing to
do with the user of your app,
and it's probably more aptly
named developer extra info.
It's just a way for you to
take some extra bits of info
that you want to pass
along with the notification
and attach them to the
notification that's
being posted.
With the progress
notification out of the way,
we can now tackle the
download finish notification.
Here we'll just
create a reference
to the spot in our app where we
want this download to be saved.
And then call our copy
item at path to path method
to copy it from
the temp location
to its final
location on our app.
Then we'll create another
user info dictionary.
This time it will contain the
URL of our downloaded video.
And then we'll pass that along
with the download completion
posted notification.
So we have the
notifications being
posted from the video
downloader and we
have them being observed in
the video view controller.
So let's look at those methods
that the observer calls.
First, in update
progress, we want
to update that progress
indicator using information
in the notifications
user info dictionary.
So we can do that on the
main queue like this.
Then when our finished
download method gets called,
we'll again use that
URL parameter that's
part of our user
info dictionary then
we'll check if that name's
equal to the name of the video
that we're currently displaying
in the video view controller.
If it is, then we'll turn off
the download progress indicator,
we'll hide the progress
bar and instead
show a check mark to show
that the download is finished.
Finally, if our
download is completed,
we know that we no longer need
our notification listeners
for progress or completion.
So we'll remove those from
the notification center.
We've now successfully moved
all of our NSURL session
and delegate information into
the video downloader class.
We've also modified our
video view controller
to make requests from that
video downloader class instead.
So only one part remains.
We need to modify
the app delegate
so that it will properly respond
to requests that are started
and stopped from the
video downloader.
To set this up, we'll start
by declaring a block property
on the app delegate.
Now remember that any time
you declare block property,
you need to use the
copy keyword instead of
the weak or strong keyword.
Next, inside of our
application handle
events for background
URL session completion
handler method, we'll store
that completion handler
inside of this new block
property that we created.
Once we have it stored, we'll
initialize a video downloader
with the shared message.
That's going to create the
video downloader object
and it's going to reconnect
the session to the background
Daemon even if the user
hasn't opened the app.
So now that we have that
completion handler stored
as a property, we can
implement the URL session,
did finish events
for background URL
session delegate method,
inside of the video downloader.
We'll start by getting a
reference to our app delegate,
and then we'll check if that
property has been set.
If it has, we'll execute the
completion handler which
will update the app snapshot,
letting the background service
know that we've
handled the request.
And then we'll set
that property back
to nil so that it's ready
for the next request that
comes through.
Finally, we can see everything
all working together.
We open our app and navigate
to a specific video page
and start downloading our video.
We can see that our
progress gets updated.
And the video appears inside
of our app as downloaded.
If we then switch to
another video, download
that video but then close
the app before the video
finishes downloading,
the background download
will still finish and
when we reload our app,
the video still shows as
being already downloaded.
And now it's time
for you to practice
using background downloads
in the challenges.