Welcome back.
So when we finished the last
section, we started a download,
and then we put our app
into the background.
And then we finished
the download
and opened up that
app again, but our app
forgot where it was.
It didn't open back up into
the Video View Controller.
Instead, it jumped right back
to the Tag List View Controller.
So by implementing some
simple State Restoration,
we'll make sure that our app
always returns to the point
that it left off when it
was put into the background.
State Restoration has
been around since iOS 6,
but it's especially
important now
that background
downloading is a feature.
So there's four steps in order
to save and restore your UI.
The first step is
to opt in to State
Restoration in your AppDelegate.
The second step is to
move initialization code
to
application-willFinishLaunchingWithOptions
instead of
application-didFinishLaunchingWithOptions.
The third step is to assign
restoration identifiers
to different view controllers.
And then finally,
the fourth step
is to assign restoration
classes to view controllers that
need to have extra
information restored.
If you want to go into great
detail about this topic,
you should check out What's New
in State Restoration session
from WWDC 2013.
So let's get started.
Step one is really easy.
All we need to do is implement
these two methods inside
of our AppDelegate, and
return yes from both of them.
And that tells the app that we
want to use State Restoration.
Next, we'll take the
code that's usually
in
application-didFinishLaunchingWithOptions
and we'll put it in
application-willFinishLaunchingWithOptions.
That's because the did Finish
Launching method actually
runs after all of the
State Restoration methods.
So it'll be too late at that
point for State Restoration
to work.
The will method runs before
State Restoration starts,
so that's where we want to
initialize our root view
controller.
So inside of that method, we'll
set the restoration identifier
for our Windows
root view controller
equal to some string.
Here, we're using
RootViewController.
The actual string you use
isn't as important as the fact
that these strings
need to be unique.
And setting this
restoration identifier
will let UIKit know
that it's going
to try to save and restore
the state for this controller.
Next, any other view
controllers that you
want to be a part of
this restoration system
need to have their own
restoration identifiers.
And it's probably
best to set those
in those controllers
init methods.
If you're saving and restoring
the state of view controllers
that don't have any
dynamic content in them,
then it's as simple as this.
But any time there's any
kind of dynamic content,
like, let's say a search term
that determines which photos
to display, you're
going to need to take
a few extra steps to include
that inside of your State
Restoration.
Photos View Controller
displays a list of photos
according to a search term.
So here we've created
a new initializer
called initWithSearchTerm.
And then once that
object has been created,
we're setting the
search term property,
updating the title to
show that search term,
setting our photos view
controllers restoration
identifier, and then setting
this extra property called
restoration class equal to our
photos view controller class.
This is a necessary
step any time
you're also updating properties
when a view controller
state is being restored.
And the way that we actually
archive those properties
is by using the
encodeRestorableStateWithCoder
method.
This is a method that
becomes available to you
when you're using
State Restoration.
This works just like the
encodeWithCoder method
that you might have seen
before if you've ever
used the NSCoding protocol.
So inside, we just
need to encode objects
for each one of the
properties that we
want to save using a unique key.
And then these
properties are going
to be archived, along
with the state of the UI
whenever State
Restoration happens.
Next, we'll implement the
viewControllerWithRestorationIdentifierPath
coder method.
And that's sort of equivalent
to the initWithCoder
method in NSCoding.
This method will run inside
of Photos View Controller
every time the app detects that
it's trying to restore state.
And inside, we'll
decode our search term
and use it to re initialize
our Photos View Controller.
You'll need to repeat these
encode and decode steps
for any view controller
that has properties in it.
Now you can see that
when we run our app,
and start a video
being downloaded,
and then exit out of
that app and close it,
the download will finish
in the background.
And then when we
reload our app, it
remembers that we were on
that video's download page
instead of shooting us back
out to the main tag list.
So now it's time for you to try
the final challenges of Core
iOS 7.
Congratulations on
making it this far.
--divided into multiple
different classes, so that--
This cache is she--
ca-sheh-sheh--
--download
progresses-- progress.