Welcome back.
In this level, we'll be talking
about a new framework
that's been added to iOS 7
called UIKit Dynamics.
UIKit dynamics allows you to
add real-world physical
behavior to your views.
Things like springing a
notification view into place,
or transitioning view
controllers and adding a
little bit of bounciness to
the end of the transition.
Even things like making views
look like they're swinging in
on an invisible string is
possible with UIKit dynamics.
And the underlying principle
behind using UIKit dynamics is
that you define a set of
behaviors that decide how to
animate views, as opposed to
applying the animations
directly yourself.
Anytime you want to use UIKit
Dynamics, you first have to
declare a strong property of
type UIDynamicAnimator.
This is really important,
because if it's not a strong
property, none of the animations
will work.
Next, somewhere after your
view has loaded, like in
viewDidLoad, you need to
initialize that dynamic
animator and give it
a reference view.
Now, the reference view is
usually a container view,
while the subviews are the
things that you're are
actually animating.
So here, we'll use self.view,
since it's a container of all
of our subviews.
Finally, once that animator is
set up, all you have to do is
add behaviors to it, and
the animations will
automatically start.
So let's look at a few
of those behaviors.
The first, UIGravityBehavior,
simulates how gravity would
work on Earth.
If you drop your keys, they'll
hit the ground.
Well, if you add gravity to a
view, then that view will drop
as soon as the behavior
is added.
That's usually paired with a
UICollisionBehavior, which
will set boundaries on how
far that drop can happen.
So here you can see that the
purple square starts dropping,
and when it reaches the bottom
edge of self.view, it bounces
and stops, because there's a
collision behavior there.
The UIPushBehavior allows you
to give a view a little push
in any direction with a certain
velocity, so you can
use that to move views in and
out in a straight line.
A UISnapBehavior allows you to
take a view from one point and
move it to another, and
add some effects, like
springiness, to the view when
it comes into place.
A UIAttachmentBehavior allows
you to link one view to
another, so that when one view
moves, the other moves with
it. Or you can even link it up
to an arbitrary point, like
the point generated by a gesture
recognizer, and then
use that to move views
around the screen in
response to the finger.
And finally, there's a generic
behavior class, called
UIDynamicItemBehavior, that
controls things like density,
linear and angular velocity,
elasticity.
So, for example, you can see
that there's a gravity and
collision behavior on the
square with a different
elasticity and angular velocity
that causes it to
turn a little bit as it falls,
and bounce a little bit more
when hits that collision
boundary.
So let's jump back
into the code.
We want to try to create that
gravity simulation where the
square starts in the middle of
the screen, and then falls
down, but then bounces
when it hits the
bottom edge of the view.
So to start, we'll add a
UIGravityBehavior, and we'll
use the initWithItems
initializer, passing in the
item that we want to have
the behavior on.
Here we want our purple square
box view to have this gravity
attached to it, so we
initWithItems self.boxView.
Then we add our behavior to the
animator and the gravity
will begin.
In this case, self.view is
the reference view, and
self.boxView is this item that
we're going to have animate.
Next, we need to set the gravity
direction, and that's
set by using a CG vector, which
we can create with the
CGVectorMake function.
Now, the first number that
you pass to CGVectorMake
determines the x direction of
the gravity, and the second
number determines the y
direction of the gravity.
Let's look at that in a little
bit more detail so we can
understand what those
numbers mean.
If we have a CG vector using the
numbers 0 and 1, then that
means there's going to be no
gravity in the x direction, or
horizontal direction, but there
will be some gravity in
the y direction.
So as you can see, the box will
fall straight down with a
y vector of 1.
If we increase that y direction
vector to 3, then it
falls three times the rate
of speed that it did when
it was set to 1.
So we're really determining the
magnitude of how fast the
view falls.
If we want the gravity to pull
up instead of down, all we
need to do is set the y vector
to a negative number.
Here we're setting it to
negative 1, and that's going
to cause that box to be
pulled towards the
top and not the bottom.
To move the box to the left or
the right, we can set the x
vector and not the y vector.
So here we're seeing that it's
being moved to the right at a
magnitude of 1.
As you might imagine, to move
to the left, we just need to
apply a negative x vector.
And here you can see the
difference between applying a
magnitude of negative 1 and
a magnitude of negative 2.
If you use negative 2, it moves
to the left faster than
negative 1.
So let's take a look
at what adding that
gravity behavior did.
It starts pulling the square
down, but it doesn't stop when
it hits the edge of the
view, it keeps going.
So for that reason, gravity is
usually paired with a UI
collision behavior, so that we
can set boundaries on where
that square can go.
To help visualize the problem,
you can see that before the
gravity is applied, we have our
boxView, and then as the
gravity starts being applied,
it's pulled down.
As motion starts and continues,
the box is pulled
down a little bit farther, but
because there's no collision
boundary, the box moves off
the edge of the screen and
then keeps falling forever.
So to fix this, we'll add a
collision boundary in addition
to our gravity behavior.
If the subview that has the
gravity applied never needs to
leave its container view, we can
use the translatesRefere
nceBoundsIntoBoundary property
and set it to yes, and that's
going to create boundaries for
each of those four walls that
the view encompasses.
Now, as the box moves down,
the edge of self.view is
actually acting as a collision
boundary, and the gravity's
still there, but the boundary
prevents the boxView from
moving any further than the
edge of the screen.
So now it's your turn to have
some fun playing with UIKit
Dynamics in the challenges.