The new behavior that fullscreen
views take on is so
significant that you really
need to ask yourself these
four questions every time you
try to lay out a view in a
view controller.
The first question is, does my
screen show a status bar?
Next, you'll want to consider
whether or not you're also
going to have a navigation bar
at the top of your screen.
Then you'll want to ask, are you
showing a navigation bar
and a tab bar down
at the bottom?
And finally, you'll want to ask,
is my main view a scroll
view, or any other subclass of
scroll view like a table view
or a collection view?
It might not be clear yet why we
need to have the answers to
these questions, so for the
remainder of this level, we're
going to be looking at why these
details are important.
So first, let's talk about how
having a status bar might
influence the way that your
view is laid out in
fullscreen.
If we look at the statistics
view controller here, you can
see that it's really easy to
accidentally position your
labels too close to the status
bar in a way that makes it
hard to read the content
of those labels.
The won and lost labels are
actually getting dangerously
close to the content that's in
the status bar, that content
that shows the carrier and the
Wi-Fi strength, and even the
battery and the time.
I also want to point out that
this is a pretty simple view
hierarchy in this
view controller.
We've just got a main view that
has four subviews, one
for each of the labels that
you see in the view.
So, to understand how to start
solving this problem, let's
again step back and look at
how iOS 6 calculated view
dimensions.
In iOS 6, if we loaded a simple
view with this code,
just adding a view and setting
its background color to green,
it would look something
like this.
The view's height would actually
be calculated as the
screen height minus the
status bar high.
Since the status bar is 20
points hi and we're displaying
this on a 4 inch screen, the
view height is actually going
to be 548 points high.
That's that 20 points at the
top for the status bar, and
then the view sits entirely
below the status bar area.
If we look at the same code
running in iOS 7, you'll
notice that the view's height
is now 568 points high, the
entire available height
of that 4 inch screen.
So what if you actually want
that view 20 points lower than
the status bar area so
you can avoid any of
those content conflicts?
One way to solve this in iOS 7
is to create a content subview
that will be a subview
of your main view.
And instead of adding all of
your other subviews to the
main view, you'll add them to
the content subview instead.
Once we've got that view
hierarchy in place, all we
need to do is figure out a way
to set the content subview
frame to start right below
the status bar frame.
So switching over to code, let's
first create a UIView
property called content
subview.
And then in our load view
method, we'll create that
content subview.
We'll set its background color
to an orange color so we can
see a difference between
the main view and
the contents subview.
And then we'll add the content
subview to the main view.
There's one more thing
that we need to do.
Self dot view's frame gets
automatically set because it's
the main view for this view
controller, get set to that
fullscreen dimension.
So we need to manually set our
content subviews frame.
And we do this in view
will layout subviews.
If you're used to setting your
frames view did load, we
recommended that you switch over
to the view will layout
subviews method.
View will layout subviews
actually gets fired after view
did load, and it will be
apparent in a minute why this
is an important place to
put your layout code.
So here in view will layout
subviews, first we call super.
And then we are setting
the frame of our
self dot content subview.
Here we're setting the origin
of our content subview frame
to 0, 20, which means it will
start 20 points below the top
of the main view.
And we're picking 20 because
that's the height of our
status bar area right now.
And then for the width and
height, we're just setting our
content subview to be the entire
width of the screen and
the entire height of the screen,
minus that 20 points
that we got from calculating
our status bar height.
Now this is actually not a great
approach because the
status bar height area might
not always be 20 points.
Could be a bigger number.
One of the situations that
makes the status bar area
bigger is if we have
a nav bar.
We'll actually be covering
that in the next section.
But for now, just understand
that the status bar area is
not always going to
be a fixed height.
So with that in mind, we're
going to need a way to detect
that height as we lay out all of
our subviews so we can make
sure that we use the
right number.
And iOS 7 introduces a new UI
view controller property
called topLayoutGuide.
TopLayoutGuide will always
contain the height of the
status bar area if you access
it inside of the view will
layout subviews method.
So if there's no status bar
displayed, then top layout
guide dot length is going
to be equal to zero.
If there is a status bar
displaying, then top lab guide
dot length is going
to be equal to 20.
And that's great, because now
we can update our view will
layout subviews method to,
instead of using hard coded
values for the status bar, use
the top layout guide dot
length value so that we'll
will always be able to
dynamically adjust the size of
our view in response to the
status bar.
So if there's no status bar,
let's look at what these frame
numbers are going to be.
The origin dot x is going to be
zero and the origin dot y
is going to be zero also,
because self dot top layout
guide dot length is zero.
The width is going to be 320 and
since the top layout guide
is zero, the height is going to
be the entire height that
we have available in our view.
If we do have a status bar, our
origin dot y is going to
be 20 points and our height is
going to be 568 points for our
full view, minus those 20 points
that come from the top
layout guide dot length, or 548
points, which is almost
full screen but makes sure that
our content subview is
just under the status bar.
So now we've got this in place,
we can go ahead and add
all the rest of our subviews for
this view controller just
like we normally would.
Except now, we're going to be
adding them to the content
subview and not to
self dot view.
And notice here in the screen
shot how the spacing between
the status bar text and the
won and lost labels is now
enough to not cause
any conflict
while reading the text.
In case you're wondering where
we're adding all of the
subviews, we're putting them
inside of the load view
method, which is a good place
to initialize and
add views as subviews.
Here, you can see we're creating
the one label and
we're adding it to the self dot
content subview, which is
again going to be the
view that holds all
the rest of our views.
And then, when it comes time to
lay out the frames of those
subviews, again we'll go
into the view will
layout subviews method.
And I just want to point out
here that we're not using
topLayoutGuide again because we
already use topLayoutGuide
to push down our content
subview.
So any of our subviews of that
are going to be relative to
the content subview, meaning
that we don't need to add any
extra padding, because the
padding is already there.
And now it's time for you to
try laying out views in the
challenges.