Welcome back to Core
iOS 7, level 7.
In this level, we're going to
be talking about some of the
cool new improvements
to Auto Layout.
And the biggest improvement into
Auto Layout in iOS 7 is
the new workflow.
In iOS 6, it was impossible to
have ambiguous layout when you
were using Auto Layout with
Interface Builder--
ambiguous layout being a
situation where you didn't
have enough constraints to fully
describe the layout.
Now this sounds like it
was a good thing.
But in practice, it was actually
very frustrating,
because Interface Builder
would automatically add
missing constraints for you.
And sometimes it would be adding
constraints that you
never expected to be there
in the first place.
So the workflow in iOS 6 was
basically to just have an idea
of what your final interface
should look like and then
start adding constraints and
hope that nothing went wrong
in the meantime.
In iOS 7 and Xcode 5,
this workflow has
been greatly improved.
First, constraints are only
added one at a time.
And in fact, Xcode 5 is never
going to add an explicit
constraint unless
you ask it to.
One trade off of this, of
course, is that you can have
ambiguous layout if you don't
add the right constraints.
But there's a neat new debugging
panel that helps you
solve these problems before
you run your app.
So a quick refresher on how
Xcode is laid out when you're
using Interface Builder.
Here you can see on the left
pane, we still have the
Project Navigator, which lets
us select our class
files or xib files.
Next to that, there's an outline
that shows all of the
different views and sub views
that are inside of an
Interface Builder document.
Next, there's the Editor panel,
where all of your
dragging and dropping of
views takes place.
And even some of your
constraints can be added here.
At the top right is the
Inspector panel, where you're
going to be able to do some fine
tuning and tweaks of your
Interface Builder documents
after you have your initial
constraints in place.
And then at the bottom right is
the Object Library, which
provides a really easy drag and
drop system that allows
you to move views directly onto
the editor and have them
added into your view
hierarchy in your
Interface Builder document.
Let's start looking at this
new workflow in iOS 7.
First, we want to make sure
that the Use Auto Layout
checkbox is checked for any
Interface Builder documents
where we want to have
Auto Layout active.
Remember that you can have
Auto Layout enabled
individually for each xib or
storyboard, which means you
can have one xib file that uses
Auto Layout to determine
the layout and another xib
file where the layout is
determined entirely in code.
It's fine to mix and match.
To start, we'll drag elements
from the Object Library onto
the editor.
Now notice that we're editing
the names inside the
outline view here.
This is important, because it's
going to help us keep
track of all of our different
subviews as we lay them into
the editor.
Then we'll set the properties
for each of the views that
we've added in to our editor.
Here, we're setting the initial
frame using the
Inspector panel.
And we're also setting the
background color of these
squares so that we can see
them against the white
background.
Now that we've got these
elements on the editor with
the right properties, we're
going to want to move them
around and put them in
what we expect to
be their final locations.
Now, if you don't know exactly
where these elements are going
to end up, it's OK.
We're going to be able to
make changes later.
But if you do know your general
layout before you
start, it's going to make the
process a lot easier, because
there will be a lot less
changes down the road.
Now that we've got these first
few steps in place, it's time
to start thinking about
constraints.
The first thing you want to ask
yourself before adding any
constraints is, what would the
frame of this view look like
if we were to write
it in code?
In this case, our purple squares
frame would look
something like this.
Our origin would be 20 points
from the left, 50 points from
the top, and 40 points wide
and 40 points high.
So our job is to figure out what
constraints we have to
apply to this purple square in
order to generate that frame
using the Auto Layout system.
There are multiple ways that
you can add constraints to
reach the same goal.
So we'll just look at
a few of those now.
Starting with the exposition,
we'll apply a Leading Space to
Container constraint between the
view and it's superview.
This is going to give us 20
points of spacing between the
edge of that superview's wall
and the edge of the purple
square, thus giving us the
effect of setting our frame 20
points from the start
of the superview.
When our x-position constraint
is in place, it's time to move
on to our y-position
constraint.
And we'll use a similar approach
that we used before.
Here, we'll use a Top Space to
Container constraint, which is
going to constrain the top space
between the superview's
edge and the purple
square's edge.
Finally, we'll need to add width
and height constraints
to determine how wide and
tall the square is.
So we'll add width and height
constraints directly
here to this view.
Now, you're always going to need
to represent the x, y,
width, and height constraints
for every single view inside
of your Interface Builder
document.
But there's different ways
to go about this.
You don't always have to set
them directly on the left
edge, top edge, and width
and height explicitly.
One example of this is setting
the x and y position using
center constraints.
So if we add a Center
Horizontally in Container
constraint to the purple square,
it's going to make
sure that that square
sits right in the
middle of its superview.
Likewise, if we set the Center
Vertically in Container
constraint on the purple square,
it's going to make
sure that that purple square is
always right in the middle
vertically of that superview.
So this is another way that we
can set x and y position
without setting an explicit
number from
the left or the top.
Here you can see one way that
we can do this in Xcode.
We can right-click and
drag from the purple
square to the superview.
And when we do, we get
a list of constraint
options that pops up.
And we can choose our
constraints right there.
So here, you can see I'm
adding a leading space
constraint, a top space
constraint, and a width
constraint.
So you probably noticed that as
we were adding constraints,
they were turning orange in the
Interface Builder layout.
Those colors tell us something
about the state of the layout
while we're working.
Orange means ambiguous layout.
Again, we don't have enough
constraints to determine the
entirety of the layout from the
constraints we've added.
In this example, we're
missing a height
constraint on that view.
We've set the x position,
the y position, and
the width of it.
But we haven't set the
height constraint.
The reason the ambiguous layout
is bad for the Auto
Layout system is that it
doesn't have enough
information to determine how
high this view should be.
We don't give it a height
constraint.
It could be the final number
we're expecting, which is to
produce a square.
Or it could stretch it out to be
a really long rectangle and
have a really big height.
Or it could have a really
small height.
Fact of the matter is, if we
don't declare a height
constraint, all of those are
valid outputs, and thus the
layout is ambiguous.
One of the great parts about the
changes in iOS 7 is that
there's now a Debugging panel
for Auto Layout built right
into the Outline View.
If you create a situation by
adding constraints that causes
something like ambiguous layout,
you'll first see this
little orange arrow appear at
the top of the Outline View.
If you click this arrow, you'll
get a full list of all
the problems that have
automatically been detected in
your layout.
Here you can see that on our
purple square the system is
telling us that we need
constraints for height.
And as a result of that, we
have a misplaced view.
Our expected height is 0, but
our actual height in the
Interface Builder
system is 80.
So we need to add another
constraint in
order to fix this.
This Debugging panel is a great
place to check if you've
added constraints but you're
still seeing unexpected
behavior in your layouts.
So if we go back and we add a
height constraint onto this
purple square, then everything
will turn blue.
Blue is what we're hoping for.
If all of your constraints
are blue, then that means
everything's been set
up properly and your
layout is in place.
As you add more and more
constraints in your editor,
your Outline View is going
to get bigger and bigger.
So it's important to remember
where all these constraints
are placed in case you need
to go find them to make a
change later on.
So here you can see that
constraints like width and
height that directly affect the
view that you're working
with appear nested inside of
that view in the Outline View.
Constraints that affect the
position of that view in the
superview appear nested
inside of the
superview in the outline.
This Outline View will get more
and more complex as you
add more constraints into your
layout, so just be careful.
We just looked at how to add
constraints between a view and
a superview, which is great
for getting our
initial layout in place.
Sometimes you'll want to create
constraints between
views that are siblings or
appear closer to each other in
the layout.
In this case, you'll want
to consider applying the
constraints between the two
views directly instead of
involving the superview.
For example, if we have these
two squares, and the purple
square already has constraints
for leading space and top
space, your first instinct
might be to add a leading
space constraint to
the red square.
Instead, you could add a left
constraint between the purple
square and the red square
to give the red
square its x position.
Adding that left constraint will
say, take the left edge
of the red square and line it
up with the left edge of the
purple square.
Similarly, we could use a top
space constraint here to
constrain the top edge of the
red square to the superview.
Or we could add a center y
constraint between the purple
square and the red square to
make sure that the centers of
those two squares always stay
on the same horizontal line.
So you have lots of options when
you're adding constraints
to pin views together.
Then you would just add a
horizontal spacing constraint
between the purple square
and the red square.
And that will be enough to
define the red square's x and
y position.
Here you can see a
demo of all this
working together in Xcode.
We've got our purple square
and our red square.
And to start, we're applying a
center y constraint between
the purple and red.
Then we're applying a horizontal
spacing constraint
between them.
And finally, we'll set the width
and height of the red
square so that all four of those
x y width and height
constraints are represented.
And when we do this, all of
our constraints turn blue,
because we don't have
an ambiguous layout.
And we're good to go.
We're doing good with our
Auto Layout workflow.
We've started out by dragging
a bunch of views onto the
Editor panel.
Then we've added a bunch
of constraints.
But what happens if we decide
to move the position of one
view in the editor after we've
added a constraint?
In iOS 7, there's a different
behavior than
there was in iOS 6.
So if you move a view from
one spot to another after
constraints have been added,
you're going to see this red
dotted outline of where
the view used to be.
This appears whenever you've
moved a view after you've
added a constraint.
This outline appears because
Interface Builder doesn't know
if you meant to move
that view or not.
Here you can see moving that red
square to a new position.
If this was a mistake, and we
want to place it back to where
it should be as defined by the
constraints, then we'll choose
the Update Frames menu option
from the Resolve Auto Layout
Issues tool, which appears at
the bottom of the editor.
If we really do want to move
this view to a new position,
then we'll choose the Update
Constraints option from that
Auto Layout Issues tool.
And that will update those
constraints to put the view in
the new spot.
Here you can see that
the constraints
have now been updated.
But we've got a little
problem.
When you choose Update
Constraints from that Auto
Layout Resolve Issues menu, it
doesn't actually change the
constraint type.
It just changes the value
that's applied to the
constraint.
So this can sometimes lead to
constraints that don't really
make logical sense anymore.
In this example, we've moved our
red square from the right
of the purple square,
down below it.
So you'd expect that there would
be a vertical spacing
constraint and maybe a left
or a leading constraint.
But instead, we've still got
this y position constraint,
now with a negative value,
and a horizontal position
constraint also with
a negative value.
This doesn't really make
any sense anymore.
So we probably want to go
in and delete these two
constraints and then add new
constraints to the purple
square so they make a
lot more sense when
we're debugging later.
This is one of the negative
side effects of using the
Resolve Auto Layout
Issues menu.
Sometimes it can get
you out of a jam.
But a lot of times, it'll just
add constraints in weird
places for you.
So be careful.
So now it's time for you to
practice working with Auto
Layout in the challenges.