Welcome back.
My name's Eric Allam.
And in this level, we're going
to be going over customizing
your view controller
transitions.
Now you're probably already
familiar with view controller
transitions, such as these here
when you're pushing a
controller onto the navigation
stack, or popping it off, or
presenting modal transition
or dismissing it.
These view controller
transitions are pretty common
in almost all iOS apps.
For example, a navigation
controller animated
transitions look like this where
you have a starting view
controller, PathsViewController,
and then
you push another view controller
on top of it,
course view controller.
When you're done on that view
controller, he can push the
Back button, and it'll pop that
view controller off, and
go back to the
PathsViewController.
Another example we just saw
are our modal animated
transitions, and they work
similarly to navigation
transitions where we're
starting with the
PathsViewController, and then
we present the login view
controller to the user.
And then when they're done,
they'll dismiss it, and then
we'll be back at the
PathsViewController.
All of these transitions are
now customizable on iOS 7.
You could do them in iOS
6, but they took
way too much code.
And now in iOS 7, we can
easily create much more
complex transitions, like this
transition here where we're
showing the login view
controller, bounce in, and
it's actually smaller than the
full screen, which you
couldn't do before.
This is a good way to add depth
and context to your app.
Instead of login view controller
taking up the
entire screen, now the
user can see the
PathsViewController underneath
and know where they are.
This also makes your apps stand
out from apps that use
the stock transitions.
In this level, we're going
to be customizing a modal
transition, but the concepts
work equally well for
navigation transitions.
So now let's take a step back,
and look at how stock modal
presentation works.
Here we have our
PathsViewController.
And when the user taps
on the button -
the loginButtonTapped
method is called -
we create the login view
controller, and then we
present it using
presentViewController animated
completion, passing
an animated YES.
So how might we customize
this transition?
Well, we're going to
break it down into
five different steps.
First, we have to specify that
the presentation should occur
using a custom transition.
Next, we're going to adopt the
transitioning delegate.
Then we're going to create an
animated transition class that
will actually control
the transition.
We're going to implement the
transition delete, and then
implement the animation in the
animated transition class.
Now I know that's a lot, but
we're going to be breaking
these down one by one.
So let's get started.
All right, so let's get
into the steps.
Step one, we want to set up
the custom presentation.
The first thing we have
to do is set the
modalPresentationStyle on the
login view controller to
UIModalPresentationCustom.
If we try to run this code as
is, we would see this warning
in the console, basically saying
that we can't set this
property to custom unless we
implement the animation.
So let's do that now.
The next thing we have
to do is set the
transitioningDelegate on the
login view controller.
Now this transitioningDelegate
we're setting to self, which
is the instance of
PathsViewController.
So whatever we assign to the
transitioningDelegate needs to
adopt the UIViewController
TransitioningDelegate
protocol, which in this case
is the PathsViewController.
Before we get too deep into
this, you might want to brush
up on protocols in Objective-C,
because this API
makes heavy use of protocols.
You might want to check out Try
Objective-C Level 5 where
we cover particles, or Apple's
documentation on working with
particles in their
developer docs.
Here you can see that in the
PathsViewController header
file, we have to adopt
the UIViewController
TransitioningDelegate
protocol.
The responsibility of the
transitioningDelegate is to
define which custom transitions
should occur.
For example, our
transitioningDelegate needs to
implement the animationControl
lerForPresentedController,
presentingController,
sourceController method.
This method needs to return a
object that conforms to the
UIViewController
AnimatedTransitioning protocol.
This object will define how the
animation actually works.
Before we implement that
method, in the
PathsViewController, let's
create our animated
transitioning class.
In this case, let's just call
it BouncyTransition.
It inherits from an NSObject,
and conforms to the
UIViewController
AnimatedTransitioning class.
Now in the implementation of
BouncyTransition, we need to
define two methods.
The first method is
transitionDuration.
This method should just return
the number of seconds that
this transition should take.
As you can see here, we're
just returning 1, so this
transition will just
take one second.
The only other method that this
class needs to implement
is the animateTransition
method.
This method is where we do the
animation and the transition,
but we're not going to get into
the details of that now.
First, let's go back
and implement that
transitioningDelegate method.
Now we're actually going
to implement the
transitioningDelegate method.
Back in the PathsViewController,
we're
going to first import
BouncyTransition.h.
And then we're going to
implement the delegate method,
create a BouncyTransition,
and return it.
So let's see how our
transitioning
is working so far.
As you can see here, I'm
pressing the login button, but
nothing is happening.
And that's because we haven't
implemented the animation in
the BouncyTransition
class yet.
So let's go ahead
and do that now.
To implement the animation,
there are four steps.
First, we need to insert the
modal view into the transition
view hierarchy.
Then, we need to set the
starting position
of the modal view.
After that, we animate the modal
view into position using
UIView animations.
And then to finish off, we
need to complete the
transition.
So to be able to add the modal
view into the transition view
hierarchy, we first need to get
access to the view, and we
do that through the transition
context with a method called
viewControllerForKey.
Now there are two keys -
one for the To view controller,
and one for the
From view controller.
In this case, the From
controller is the
PathsViewController, because
that's where we're starting,
and the To view controller is
the login view controller,
because that's where
we're going.
The next thing we need
is the transition
view hierarchy itself.
Now this transition view
hierarchy exists only during
the transition, and can be
accessed again through the
transition context using the
containerView method.
The containerView already
holds the From view
controller's view.
And we just need to
add the To view
controller's view to that.
And we do that just like
any other view.
We call addSubview, and
we pass in the to view
controllers of view.
And now our transition view
hierarchy has both the From
view controller and the To view
controller inside of it.
Now that we have the login view
controller's view inside
the container view, we need to
set its starting position.
This position defines where the
login view starts at the
beginning of the animation.
And in this case, we're going to
want to start at below the
bottom of the screen.
So how do we do that?
To do that, we're first
going to get the
initialFrameFromViewController,
and that's going to give us
the full frame of the
PathsViewController.
From that, we want to access
the height, and
store it in a variable.
And then we just set the To
view's frame to a new CGRect.
Now let's walk through
these one by one.
We're going to set the x
to the fullFrame's x
to keep it at 0.
Then we're going to set the y
position of this frame to the
height of the fullFrame
plus 16 -
that means it's going to start
16 points below the bottom of
that frame.
And then we'll just keep
the same width and
height of that fullFrame.
Now that we've set the starting
position of the login
view controller's view, all we
need to do is animate that
view into position using a
UI View Animation API.
In this case, we're going to use
a new iOS 7 animation API
that will add that springy-ness
to the view.
As you can see here, we've set
the duration of this animation
to be equal to the
transitionDuration.
There's no delay.
We're setting the spring damping
and velocity to be
just some values that we figured
out would work well
for this transition.
We're making the animation
curve ease in and out.
And then we're supplying an
animation block to the
animation's parameter.
And then inside the animation's
block, we want to
specify where the login's view
controller view will finish.
In this case, it's going to
be the fullFrame of the
PathsViewController.
All right, let's see
how we're doing.
Now when we press the button, we
can see that the login view
controller does animate into
place using that Spring API,
but, unfortunately, it looks
like our UI is frozen, and
that's because we forgot to
complete the transition.
Now let's go back to
our animation code.
We need to do one more thing
when the animation completes,
and the perfect place to do that
is to pass a completion
block into this API method.
Inside of that completion block,
we're just going to
call the completeTransition on
the transitionContext, and
pass in YES.
This will complete
the transition.
So as you can see here, now when
we present the login view
controller, our UI
isn't frozen,
but there is one more thing.
Our login view controller's
view is still full screen.
So how do we make it smaller?
Again, let's go back into
our animation code.
The first thing we want to
change is the size of the
starting position of
our login view.
If we want to shrink our login
view controller by 40 points,
we just need to add 20 points
both to the x and y position,
and subtract 40 from the height
and the width, changing
the login view controller's
starting position and size.
We're still setting the final
position of the login view
controllers to the full
size, so we'll
need to fix that next.
And to do that, we're just going
to set the frame to x
and y equal to 20, and then
subtract 40 from both the
width and the height.
So now you can see that our
custom transition works.
When we click on the login
button, our shrunken login
view controller comes up,
bounces around, and settles
into place, and our
UI isn't frozen.
So I know that was a lot to take
in, so we're going to go
through a quick review of those
steps getting our custom
transition to work.
First, we had to specify that
the presentation should use a
custom transition.
Then on our PathsViewController,
we
adopted the
transitioningDelegate.
Next, we created a animated
transition class that controls
the transition.
We implemented the
transitioningDelegate method,
and returned an instance of the
BouncyTransition class.
Then, we went back into the
animated transition class, and
actually implemented the
animation and transition.
We inserted the modal
view into the
transition view hierarchy.
We set the starting position
of the modal view.
We animated the modal view into
its final position using
UI view animation, and then we
completed the transition.
It's time for you to try out
making your own custom
transition in the challenges.
Good luck.