Welcome back.
In this section, we're going
to learn how to use dynamic
behaviors to enhance the display
of a notice view
whenever the "save" button is
tapped in our articles
application.
So before we get too far, let's
set up our plan for how
to make this notification
view snap into place.
So first we'll need a notice
view property so that we can
access that view.
Then, when the "save" button is
tapped, we're going to call
the saveArticle method.
Inside of that method,
we'll initialize and
add our notice view.
We'll set the notice view's
frame to somewhere offscreen
so that it can bounce in.
And finally, we'll use a snap
behavior to hold that view
onto the screen at the
point that we want.
So here we are creating
the notice view.
And we're setting the y position
to start offscreen so
that when we snap it into place,
it looks like it just
magically appears
from the top.
Then we'll create a UI snap
behavior, initializing it with
the item self.noticeView.
And we have an extra part of
this initializer called
snapToPoint that determines
where the final resting place
of this notice view
will be after the
snap behavior is applied.
Now, it's important to note at
this point we're snapping to
is not the top left corner of
where we want to view to be.
It's actually the center
point of where we
want the view to be.
So here we've set it to 160 x,
to be right smack in the
middle of the view, and then 15 y
so that sits nicely right
underneath that navigation
bar.
And here you can see
the result of that.
But right now, it's not very
bouncy when it comes in.
It really just looks like
it sort of slides in.
So there's a property on UI snap
behaviors called damping.
And when we adjust that damping,
we use a number
between 0 and 1.
0 means that it's going
to be really bouncy
when it pulls in.
And 1 means it's not going
to be bouncy at all.
So here, we've set it to 0.3.
It's really a matter of
personal preference.
So you'll likely be playing
with different values for
damping as you put snap
behaviors in your own
applications.
So now when we tap the Save
button, you can see that
notice view slides down into
place and kind of has a little
bit of bounciness to it before
it comes to rest.
So we're still not done because
this notice view never
disappears.
We click the Save button,
and it bounces into
place like we want.
And then it just stays
there forever.
We want the notice view
to go away after the
animation is stopped.
So we need to figure out a way
to programmatically access
when that is.
And the way that we do that is
by adopting the UI dynamic
animator delegate protocol in
our header and then setting
the self.animator's
delegate to self.
That animator delegate protocol
gives us access to a
method that runs whenever
the animation stops.
The flow here is that before the
snap behavior starts, the
notice view is offscreen.
As the snap behavior continues,
you see that the
notice view starts snapping
into place.
And then as soon as the notice
view comes to rest, the
delegate method
dynamicAnimatorDidPause is called.
Inside of this delegate method,
we'll first remove all
existing behaviors from our
animator, which is probably a
good step because our
snap behavior has
finished at this point.
And then we'll remove our notice
view from our main view
so it disappears.
So now you can see that
this works as planned.
We hit the "save" button,
the view pops in,
and then after the animation
stops, it completely
disappears.
But we can use dynamics to
make this a little more
interesting because just
having it immediately
disappear is not so exciting.
So we'll add another behavior
after the snap stops that's
going to push that
view offscreen.
So back in our
dynamicAnimatorDidPause
method, we've removed all of our
behaviors, which at this
point, is just our
snap behavior.
We're creating a UI push
behavior for the
self.noticeView.
And we're using the
instantaneous mode, which
means that it just applies that
push once and then the
animator takes over.
And we need to decide
which direction to
push this view in.
So we do that, just like we did
with gravity, by using a
vector to determine the
direction that the
push should go in.
Here we're pushing things
to the right.
And finally, we add the push
behavior to the animator.
So we do have another
little problem here.
And let's see what's
happening.
So before we push, the
self.noticeView is just
sitting there at the
top of the screen.
And then the push starts, and it
starts moving to the right.
And then it continues moving
further to the right.
And now it's even moving
offscreen.
We don't even see it
anymore, yet the
push is still happening.
And that's because unlike snap,
there's no real default
stop state for a
push behavior.
You just start pushing,
and it just
continues going on forever.
So the way that we can solve
this is by implementing this
block called action that we get
because we're part of the
UIDynamicBehavior class.
Remember that all behaviors
inherit from a UIDynamic
Behavior class.
And inside of that action block,
we can actually get
updates about the status
of our animation.
So let's start by logging out
the frame inside of the action
block so we can see
what's happening
with this push behavior.
So as the Save button is tapped
and the push animation
begins, we can see that the x
position of our notice view is
just increasing into infinity.
Even after it's offscreen, the
number just keeps going bigger
and bigger and bigger.
Our strategy for solving this
problem is to detect if the
current frame of our notice view
no longer appears inside
of the bounds of self.view.
That means that it will
have moved offscreen.
We can use the
CGRectIntersectsRect function,
passing in two rectangles
that we want to compare.
Now, this function will be true
as long as the notice
view is partially onscreen.
Because there'll be some
intersection between self.view
and that notice view's frame.
We want to check when that
function is not true.
So when these two frames are not
overlapping anymore, we'll
remove the push behavior.
And we'll remove the notice view
from the view hierarchy.
And here you can see the result
of first snapping into
place and then pushing
offscreen.
Let's try another approach
that's a little more creative
using UI kit dynamics.
We'll still start by snapping
our view into place.
But then we'll apply a downward
gravity pull.
And we'll even turn the view a
little bit with an angular
velocity so that it appears
to kind of turn
and then fall offscreen.
That's a little more fun than
just pushing it offscreen.
Back in our delegate method,
we'll replace the push
behavior with a downward
gravity behavior.
And then we'll create a UI
DynamicItemBehavior
initializing with the
self.noticeView item.
And remember that UIDynamic
ItemBehavior is this generic
class that allows us to add some
velocity and elasticity
and deal with some
of the physical
properties of the view.
So here we're adding an angular
velocity for the
self.noticeView item.
And that's going to turn the view down slightly as the
gravity is pulling it down.
Now we've got our falling and
turning notice view, just like
we expected, but there's
another problem.
If we hit the Save button
multiple times, it's actually
adding multiple notice views.
And it's freezing them
in motion when we
tap the Save button.
And this is not what we want.
Fortunately, this is
a really easy fix.
Because we're adding
self.noticeView inside of the
save article method, all we need
to do is first check if
self.noticeView is already
a child of self.view.
And if it is, then we want to
remove it from the superview
first and remove all the
behaviors, which will give us
a nice fresh new notice view
when the animation starts.
So if we look at this again, now
we can see that we can tap
the Save button multiple
times.
And every time we tap, even if
it's in the middle of an
animation, it will completely
wipe out that notice view and
give us a brand-new one at the
start animation state.
It's time for you get your
hands dirty with more
animation behaviors
in the challenges.