Welcome back.
Now that you've had some
practice resizing UI labels,
we need to look at some of the
changes that iOS 7 brings to
working with UI text views.
So let's say we have an app,
and in this app we make a
network request for new text.
And we want to update our
text view in our app to
show that new text.
But you can see here that we're
getting more text back,
then will fit inside of
this text views frame.
And because of that, we're
getting scrolling.
If we don't want that scrolling,
we need to figure
out the frame of the text inside
of that text view and
resize the text you accordingly
so it displays all
the text without scrolling.
And the addition of text kit
has really changed the way
that you work with
a UI text view.
In iOS 6, if you wanted to
resize the content of a text
view, to account for both the
width and height of the text
inside of it, you would
use the sizeWithFont
constrainedtoSize lineBreakMode
method.
And that was really all that
you needed to use.
But that method is now
deprecated in iOS 7.
And before we show you which
method is the method to use
now, we need to explain
a little bit about
how text kit works.
So UI text view, is really
just a scroll view, that
displays some text.
But now, before you can get to
that text, there's two other
classes that manage how
the text is laid
out inside of it -
the NSTextContainer, and
the NSLayoutManager.
The text container determines
where text can be laid out,
and gives you the frame
for how that text fits
inside the text view.
So that sounds like a good place
for us to worry about
where to resize things.
The NSLayoutManager sits between
the text container and
the actual text storage.
And fortunately, unless you're
needing to do some really
detailed customization, you
don't ever need to get into
the NSLayoutManager class.
So we're going to
avoid it here.
We'll start by looking at
a sample UI text view.
If we were to ask for the frame
of this text view, we
would get the area that is
represented by this red box,
just a box around all the text
with a little bit of padding
around the edges.
If we did a little bit deeper,
there's a new property now
called textContainerInset .
And by default, it's got an
inset padding of eight points
at the top and eight points
at the bottom of
the edge of the frame.
It doesn't have any default edge
insets on the left or the
right sides.
So we've got a frame, with a
little bit of padding in it,
defined by this text
container inset.
Next, we've got the actual
text container.
Which is the frame of just the
text, and not the frame of the
text view, itself.
Remember that text view is a
scroll view, so there needs to
be a little bit of extra space
in order for that
scrolling behavior
to be active.
Finally the text indent, inside
of the text container,
is defined by the line fragment
padding property.
And the default value for this
property is five points.
So when we're resizing a UI text
view we don't need to
know the frame of the
text view itself,
instead we need to know the
frame of the text container
that is inside of
that text view.
And there's a new method that
we can use to get that frame
pretty easily.
Now after the text views text
has been updated from a
network response,
we'll pass the
ensureLayoutForTextContainer
method to the text to use
layoutManager, passing in the
text container as an argument.
And that's just going to make
sure that the textContainer
has all of its bounds
computed and
it's ready to be measured.
So the next step, we'll pass the
usedRectForTextContainer
method to that layoutManager,
again passing in the text
container as an argument.
And that's going to actually
perform the sizing
calculations, and return
the size of that
text area as a CGRect.
This is going to return the
frame of the text container.
And we can use that when we're
calculating the new width and
height of the text view.
So where do we perform
this sizing?
Well, unlike before, where we've
been resizing everything
in viewWillLayoutSubviews,
you actually need to resize
text views inside of
viewDidLayoutSubviews.
And that's because some of the
math that creates the size
inside of the text container
isn't performed until after
the viewWIllLayoutSubviews
method runs.
So as long as you sized
your text views in
viewDidLayoutSubviews,
or later, then
you should be fine.
So if we build and run this app,
and see it working, we
now see that the text view
is still scrolling.
So what happened here is we
forgot about those texts
container insets, that had that
eight points of padding
at the top and the bottom,
of the text view frame.
So if we go back to our frame
calculations, and add those
top and bottom text container
insets back in, then we should
be good to go.
Now another point to mention
is that we really should be
returning a rounded
number for here.
Because we're working with
text sizes, and we're not
always going to get an integer,
we want to make sure
that we round that up to the
next highest number, to avoid
rounding calculations having the
frame be off by one pixel.
So now when we build and run
this app, even though we're
getting varying lengths of
text coming back from the
network, each time the text view
has resized accordingly,
and there's no scrolling.
It's time for you to resize
some text views in the
challenges.