Welcome back.
In this section,
we'll look at how
to use iOS 7's new
background transfer
APIs to keep
downloads running even
after an app has been closed.
Now, it was possible
to do this in iOS 6
in a very limited capacity.
You would call this
Begin Background
Task with Expiration
Handler method.
And then you would put your
code to download things inside
of that.
But there were some
problems with it.
First off, it didn't allow
your device to go to sleep.
So if you were in the
middle of a transfer
and the device went
into sleep mode,
the transfer would
immediately be canceled.
Related to this, your
app could actually
be terminated in the middle
of a download or an upload--
again, immediately
canceling the request.
And if your app crashed in the
middle of a download or upload,
you'd have to
restart that request
when the app loaded again.
In iOS 7, background transfers
have been greatly improved.
Now downloads and uploads
are not limited by time.
You can start a really long
download in the background.
And it will just continue even
after your app's been closed,
even when you move
into another app.
You can even start these
background transfers
when your app has
already been closed.
Transfers can be
resumed really easily
if there's a network failure.
And the UI can be updated
in the background when
a task completes before
the app has been reloaded.
Just like before,
NSURLSession is the class
that powers all of
this new functionality.
We've modified our
Searchagrams app
to now display both
images and video.
So from inside the
app, we're going
to be able to watch the video.
We're going to be able to
download the video locally
and show a progress bar
while it's downloading.
And we're going to write
code that allows the download
to continue even after
we've closed the app.
We've modified the app
structure a little bit
from the first section.
And now our PhotosViewController
has the ability
to load a VideoViewController
from the Watch Video
and Download Video buttons.
We'll start by creating
an NSURLSession that we're
storing in the Download
Session property
inside of VideoViewController.
We'll even give the
session a description,
calling it Video
Downloader, so we
can make sure to isolate it
from the rest of our sessions
that are already
inside of this app.
The Download Video
method is run every time
the Download Video
button is tapped.
Inside of that method, we're
creating a download URL
from data in our model.
Then we're creating an
NSURLSession download task
object by passing the download
task with URL completion
handler message to our session.
This is the method that's
going to be downloading
the video that we request.
The location object that gets
passed into this completion
handler contains the temporary
location in the iOS file system
where the video has
been downloaded.
So we need to copy
that downloaded video
from the temporary
location to a location
inside of our own app which
is being generated with this
build file path method.
This will permanently save
that video inside of our app
once the request completes.
That's all we need to do
to download that video.
But if we want to show
the download progress,
we need a few extra steps.
The first thing we need to do
is adopt a delegate class inside
of VideoViewController and
then set our download sessions
delegate to that class.
You're probably familiar
with directly assigning
a delegate using the delegate
property of your class.
But with sessions,
you can't do that.
Instead, you need to use the
session with configuration
delegate delegateQueue
method and then
pass in Self for that delegate.
Realistically, most
of the time, you'll
be setting a delegate
on your session.
Delegates enable things
like background downloads
and uploads, authentication,
SSL certificate validation,
uploading data from
a stream, limiting
caching programmatically,
controlling HTTP redirects,
and-- most importantly for us
right now-- getting updates
on download progress.
We need to choose
the proper method
to use from the four protocols
of the session-pocalypse.
Uh, yeah.
So we have NSURLSessionDelegate.
And that's to handle
session level events.
NSURLSessionTaskDelegate,
for events
common to all tasks;
NSURLSessionDateDelegate,
for events common to data and
upload tasks; and finally,
NSURLSessionDownloadDelegate,
for methods
to handle task events that
are related to download tasks.
That sounds like the
one that we want,
since we're trying to check
the progress of a download.
There's three optional methods
inside of this download
delegate are going to
be important to us.
There's one that's called
when the download finishes,
which is going to take the
place of our completion handler.
There's one that's called
as the data is downloading,
which we'll use for progress.
And there's one that's
called if a download
task is resumed
with resume data.
And we'll use that
if a task gets
canceled and we want
to resume it later on.
So back in our
download video method,
that again is called whenever we
tap the Download Video button,
we'll start by implementing
the delegate method that
tracks download progress.
Calculating our
current progress is
as simple as creating
a CGFloat variable
and then dividing the
total bytes written divided
by total bytes
expected to write.
And that's going to give
us the percent completion.
And then we can use
that progress number
to update our progress
indicator, which is stored here
in self.downloadProgress.
Next, we need to refactor our
code to not use the completion
handler, because
that's only going
to run at the very
end of a request.
And instead, we'll use
this delegate method
that runs whenever
the task is completed.
Remember that we have three
different delegate methods.
And so far, we've
handled the first two--
a method for when the
download is finished
and a method for when
the download is currently
in progress.
If we run the app now
and navigate to an image
and click the
Download Video button,
we would expect to see the
progress indicator moving.
But we don't see that.
It just stays blank
and then shows us
that we've finished
the download.
That progress view isn't
updating because we're not
running our UI code on
the main thread here
like we're supposed to.
Since we set our delegateQueue
to nil inside of our session
configuration, there's
a chance that we're not
updating our UI on
the main thread.
And remember, any
time you access the UI
off the main thread,
you have a chance
of either failing silently
or even crashing your app.
So to be safe, we'll wrap
our progress updater inside
of an NSOperationQueue
on the main queue
to make sure that
that UI update always
happens on the main thread.
Now when we navigate to a video
and hit the Download Video
button, you can see
that progress indicator
updating until the
download has completed.
And now it's time for you to
work with the session delegate
methods in the challenges.