Welcome back.
So there's a cool new feature in
iOS 7 called dynamic type.
And you can see a
demo of it here.
What's happening is that, at any
point, a user of your app
can go into their settings
app and adjust the
dynamic text size.
And they're going to expect
when they get back in your
app, that the text is going
to scale, accordingly.
So there's a few pieces that
we need to put together in
order to make this
system work,
and the first is called
text styles.
So text styles are predefined
fonts the can scale, based on
that user setting in
the settings app.
And the idea here is that
we declare semantic font
descriptors that relate to
different sections of text
inside of your app, rather than
explicitly declaring a
font and size for that
font, because that
size is going to change.
Apple provides six descriptors
for us: textile headline,
subheadline, body, caption one,
caption two, and footnote.
Now the pro of this, of course,
is that users are
going to be able to dynamically
adjust this size
to fit their needs.
One of the big cons of this is
that you can't do this with
custom fonts.
You have to use Apple's one
provided system font, in order
to use dynamic type.
Here you can see a screen shot
in mail app that gives you an
idea of what types of
descriptors you might use for
each of these sections.
You can see that we're using a
headline text style for the
sender of the message, a
subheadline for the subject, a
body style for the actual body
of the message, and then a
caption style for the time that
appears, a little bit
smaller, up in the right
corner of the screen.
Now I also want to point out
that you don't have to
completely add text styles to
every font on your screen.
Elements in this shot, like
the navigation item at the
top, or the edit button, or even
the unread count down at
the bottom in the tab bar,
aren't going to need to
necessarily be things that
the user can scale.
So you can apply text styles to
some text, and not others.
The way that we add these text
styles in code is to create a
UIFontDescriptor again,
but this time we use the
preferredFontDes
criptorWithTextStyle method,
and we pass in one of those
six text styles.
Then, we use the
fontWithDescriptor method of
UI font, to create an
actual font object.
And notice here how I'm setting
the size to zero.
Setting the size to zero here,
is letting the app know to use
whatever size the user has set
in their settings app.
If we did set the size here,
then the user would not be
able to modify it.
If we wanted to modify the
example we saw earlier, this
is how our code would update.
We're applying a text style,
instead of a font family name.
We can still actually add some
traits to those text styles,
to turn them bold or italic.
And then we're setting size
zero, again, to indicate that
the user will determine how
big this text should be.
And here's a demo that
app running.
We'll run this code and
look at our app.
And we can see that we
definitely have a font and
trait and size applied.
So now let's go into the
settings app and change that
dynamic type slider, so we
can see the text change.
And we changed it, and the
app didn't change.
So what's happening here is that
we actually need to let
our app know to listen
for a size change.
The size change is happening,
but our app, by itself, isn't
smart enough to know that it
should even be listening for
that change.
So here's what's happening
when the
user makes that change.
First they enter the
settings app.
They change the slider.
Every time the user adjusts
the slider, inside of the
settings app, for dynamic type
size, the notification named
UIContentSizeCat
egoryDidChangeNotification
notification is fired to
any open applications.
So those applications have to
listen for that notification,
and then fire off a method that
makes sure that the text
size gets updated,
accordingly.
So adding the notification
is no different than
we've always done them.
We can just use the
NSNotificationCenter and add
an observer for ourself, define
a method that will get
called whenever this
notification is received, and
pass in the name of the
notification that we're
listening for.
Then when that notification is
received, our app will call
the contentSizeChanged method,
and inside of that
contentSizeChanged method,
we're going to want to
recreate the same font object
that we'd started with.
So we create the font
descriptor, apply our traits,
create the font object with size
zero, and then reapply
that font to our label.
The final step that's
needed inside of the
contentSizeChanged method, is
to pass the setNeedsLayout
method, into self.view.
What that's going to do, is it's
going to re-trigger any
of the layout code that you
have set for your label.
Which is important because as
our label size changes with
bigger size text, we're going to
want the frame of the label
to increase and decrease.
And here's a demo of
this app running.
And you can see now, that as
we change the dynamic type
size, the font sizes in our
app change as well.
And now it's time for you
to add some dynamic
type into your app.
So I guess do a challenge.
Who cares?
[LAUGHTER]
Who wants to learn iOS anyway.
This is like a cakewalk.
You might as well do the welcome
back and everything.
Welcome back and everything.
[LAUGHTER]