In this section, we're going to
be talking about some new
ways that you have to customize
the appearance of
controls in your application.
The first one is called
tint color.
Tint color is an easy way to set
of key color for all the
major UI kit views,
in just one place.
And key colors are very
important in the look and feel
of an iOS 7 app.
So here you can see I've got a
tint color of red set in the
top image, and the button
segmented control, text view
cursor, and progress indicator
all take on this red tint
automatically.
If I were to set my tint color
to blue, you might get the
image that's appearing at the
bottom of the screen.
Another important thing to
note, if you're used to
working with the UI appearance
protocol, tint colors has been
moved out of that in iOS 7.
And you can't set tint color
with UI appearance anymore.
Setting a tint color will save
you a lot of time and energy
when you're coding, because you
said it once in the most
parent view that you can, and
that color will cascade down
to all other child views,
after that point.
So if we set the
window.tintColor property in
the AppDelegate, that's going to
cascade down to all of the
other views that are part
of that window.
The tint color can be changed
for any one of the child views
by just accessing that view's
tint color property, as you
can see here.
Controller1's views now
have a green tint color.
Any kind of bars, like a UI
navigation bar, actually have
a separate tint color system,
and they work a little
bit differently.
First you decide what style
of bar you want to use,
and there's two styles in iOS
7: UIBarStyleDefault and
UIBarStyleBlack.
As you can see, a default bar
has a white background with
black status bar text and
navigation item text, while UI
bar style black is the
inverse of that.
And this provides a blank
canvas for you to apply
future colors to.
So you always have to pick one
of these first, and we'll
apply the colors onto
them after that.
Setting these styles in code
is as simple as setting the
bar style property to one
of those two constants.
So now that we have our base
layer applied for our bar, we
can apply some more vivid
colors to it.
And there's two places
that we can do that.
The first is in a property
called tintColor, which is a
different tint color than
the one that you
apply to your view.
So there's two different tint
colors happening here.
One of them is happening
for your bar.
for your view.
And the tint color in a bar
actually adjusts the color of
different items that are in
that bar, like the back
button, or if you have an
icon button item in
the top right corner.
There's another tint property called barTintColor, and
that's the one that actually changes the color of the
background of the bar itself.
So here we set the windows tint color to red, the
navigation bar's tint color to green, and the navigation
bar's barTintColor to blue, and this is what we get.
We get a blue bar with a green highlight, just for the items
in the nav bar, and a red highlight for the items that
are part of the main view.
Another place where the tint
color of a bar comes into play
is when you work with tab bar
items that have images.
And there's a different way
that iOS 7 renders some of
these images that we
need to look at.
So for example, we have
this bar image -
ios_icon.png.
And if we load that image,
we need to now also set a
rendering mode for it.
The first rendering mode,
UIimageRendering
ModeAlwaysTemplate, is going to
take that iOS icon and fill
it in with whatever our tint
color was for our bar.
If we don't want that to happen,
and we instead want to
show the original image, we'll
want to set the rendering mode
to UIimageRendering
ModeAlwaysOriginal, and then
that's going to insert that
image for the bar icon with
no tint color applied.
You might have noticed earlier
when we looked at our Senator
Showdown Sample app, the UI
buttons that were on the
showdown view controller had
a blue tint to them.
So, we would need to make that
view's tint color purple, so
our button text matches the
overall purple theme that we
have in this view controller.
You'll notice that our bar tint
color is already purple,
because we've got these little
purple filled in template
icons for the showdown, history,
and statistics tabs.
So because of the sort of global
nature of applying tint
color, we can add this tint
color in two places.
The first places in
our AppDelegate.
We can add it using
self.window.tintColor, and set
our color to purple there.
Or inside of this specific view
controller, showdown view
controller, we can just
set the tint color
property of the view.
And either of those approaches
will still get us the purple
button at the end.
There's another great feature that's
been added to Xcode 5 with the
release of iOS 7, and that's
called "Asset Catalogs."
So you're probably used to
something like this in your
project navigator, a whole lot
of .h and .m files, and then
lots of different images
at different
places inside of there.
And it can sometimes get hard to
read and get really jumbled
up, because you need different
images for different purposes
and different device
resolutions, like the iPhone
3GS and iPhone 4 have different
resolutions, so
they'll need different
image sizes.
The different iPads have some
different resolutions.
And you'll end up with folders
just full of different images,
with different names.
And it can get complicated to
keep them all organized.
So the Asset Catalog is a way
to organize all of those
images into easy to
use image sets.
You'll notice when you create a
new project in Xcode 5, that
you automatically have a new
file called "images.xcassets."
And clicking on that assets
file will give you a more
organized list of all the
image assets that you've
brought into your project.
Images get imported and stored
directly in the asset catalog,
so you don't need to still
import them using the old add
files approach that you
did in the project
navigator in iOS 6.
So once you have some images
imported into the asset
catalog, accessing them in
your code is as easy as
referencing the name
of the image set.
So here I've got an image set
named 415-weightlighter.
And it's a set of icons at both
1x and 2x resolution.
If I want to access that in a
view controller in my code
base, I just need to access an
image named 415-weightlifter.
Referencing an image from an
image st is great, because
it's automatically going to pick
the right image for you,
depending on which device is
running the app at that time.
Now another thing I want to
point out is that these images
are no longer part of your
normal project folder, instead
they're part of this
xcassets structure.
So it should be safe to delete
any of the old images in your
main project folder, after
you've successfully added them
to the asset catalog.
And the last thing I want to
point out about the asset
catalog is it makes it really
easy to target exactly the
devices that you're going to
need to support in your app.
So you can just right click on
any image set, and choose the
types of devices that
you want to support.
And when you do that, you'll get
indicators for different
images for you running on the
iPad, running on the iPhone,
running on a Mac app, or
universal images that are set
up to run the best they can
on all of those devices.
So now it's time for you work with
the asset catalog and
customize the appearance of your
app in the challenges.
What it - the way it worked
when we put it as yes.
[INAUDIBLE].
Bleh, bleh, bleh.
Ugh.