Welcome back.
In continuing the theme of
adding depth using the new iOS
7 APIs, is in this section we're
going to look at how we
can add blur to views to
give a sense of depth.
You can see examples of
this all over the
standard iOS 7 controls.
Things like the frosted blur
affect in Control Center and
Notification Center, where you
can see the view that's
underneath it shining through
a little bit.
And even a slight blur that's
applied to the views
underneath, whenever a UI
alert view pops up.
So there are two main
types of blurs that
we'll be working with.
The first, static blurs,
don't change after the
blur has been applied.
And we're going to be using a
category that Apple actually
provides to us on UI image
to make that blur.
And the second, dynamic blurs,
actually update the blur
effect as the view underneath
moves, like we see in Control
Center and Notification View.
So in this simple example, you
can see that we've got a UI
view that's floating above
a UI web view.
And as we go through and click
the pre-defined buttons in the
toolbar that we have set up for
light, extra light, dark,
and tint color, you can see that
the simple static blur
effect is applied to that
floating UI view.
Let's start to recreate
this in code.
There are going to be
three basic steps to
create a static blur.
The first is that we need to
take a snapshot image of the
view underneath--
in this case, a UI web view--
using a method called
drawViewHierarch
yInRect:afterScreenUpdates.
Next, we'll add that UI image
ImageEffects category that
Apple gives us to our project.
And finally, we'll apply that
image effect to the snapshot
image and set the placeholder
image view that's floating
above the web view.
We've configured our sample
app to call the light blur
method whenever that light
button is tapped in the
toolbar of our sample app.
And we want this light blur
method to apply the blur to
that floating UI view.
So first, we'll create an image
context using the size
of the button view's frame.
This will give us the correct
area that we'll be applying to
that UI view.
Next, we'll call the
drawViewHierarchyInRect after
screen updates method
on the self.web.
And we'll pass in
self.buttonview.bounds as the
rect that we're trying
to draw into.
Next, we'll pull an actual UI
image out of that context now
that we've taken the
screen shot.
And finally, we'll end
of the image context.
And if we look at what that new
UI image we created looks
like, we can see that we've
got a little bit
of a problem here.
The overall frame is correct,
but the stuff inside of it
looks like it's all
shrunk down.
Looks like we didn't take
the correct screen shot.
What we really want is a
screen shot that looks
something like this, that's a
representative smaller piece
of that UI web view, rather than
the entire web view just
scrunched up into
a smaller frame.
So to fix this, we first need
to convert the bounds of the
button into the web view's
coordinate space.
And we can do this by using
the convert rect to view
method, passing in the button
view's bounds as the rect we
want to convert and the self.web
view as the view's
coordinate system that we
want to convert to.
So now we've converted that
coordinate system, we'll want
to store the result of this
a CG point variable.
Here, we're calling it
button in web view.
And then we can take that CG
point and use it to offset the
bounds of the web view, using
the CG rect offset function.
This is going to give us the
appropriate sub rect inside of
the web view that we want to
actually take a screen shot of
so that we're not taking
a screen shot of
the entire web view.
So now we'll use the
drawHierarchyInRect after
screen update methods to take
that screen shot again.
Then, we finish up by grabbing a
UI image out of that context
and ending the context.
And you can see now that we've
got an appropriately-sized
image that we're going to use
inside of our UI view.
We've got our screen shot.
But the whole point of even
taking this screen shot was
that we wanted to apply a blur
effect to it and re-add it
back into our view hierarchy.
So to do that, we'll need that
UI ImageEffects category that
Apple provides to us that
I mentioned earlier.
We've re-hosted that UI image
effects category on Github so
you can download it easily.
And once you've downloaded an
expanded that zip file, you'll
add these two UI image
plus ImageEffects
files to your project.
And then you'll import that UI
ImageEffects header into
whatever class you want
to apply the blur to.
In this case, it's our class
called RootViewController.
The UI ImageEffects category
gives us access to a couple
methods that blur in
different ways.
And here, we'll use the method
apply light effect to give us
the light blur that
we're looking for.
So after we create this new bg
image from our image context,
we'll go and find our self.blur
view, which is that
floating smaller view on
top of the web view.
And we'll set the image property
of that equal to the
image return by applying
the light effect
to our new bg image.
And that's going to give
us the resulting blur
image you see below.
ApplyLightEffect is just one of
the options you have when
you use this category.
There's also
applyExtraLightEffect, which
applies the blur and then makes
it a little bit lighter.
ApplyDarkEffect, which
darkens it.
And applyTinyEffectWithColor,
which is going to try to find
the tint color that you have set
for that view and apply a
little bit of a tint adjustment
to whatever is blurred.
Our blur is definitely
working.
But what happens if we try to
scroll the content underneath
it, scroll this web
view up and down?
You can see that it looks
like it's just
setting the initial blur.
And that it's not updating
that blur as we move the
content underneath it,
which is obviously
not an ideal situation.
We want the blur to update
as the content changes.
So let's look at
how to do that.
There's probably a couple
different ways
to pull this off.
But one of the easiest ways
right now is to do a little
bit of a hack by creating a UI
toolbar and borrowing the CA
layer property of that UI
toolbar to apply a blur to it.
This will work great, because a
UI toolbar actually already
has that blurring effect.
And it will update live without
us having to write any
custom code.
So in root view controller's
viewDidLoad method, we were
already creating our
button view.
And now we'll also create
a UI toolbar using our
entire views frame.
And we'll set the bar style to
UI bar style default so that
we get that default translucency
and blurring
effect inside the bar.
And then, we'll insert the
toolbars layer into the button
view layer's hierarchy, making
sure that we're putting it at
the very bottom.
And that's going to make sure
that our button view now has
this transparent blurred
background, and that blurred
background updates automatically
as the content
underneath it changes,
like this.
There are other ways that using
this insert sub layer
method can help us
out on iOS 7.
One example is when we're
dealing with bar tint colors.
So let's say we're setting the
bar tint color to this
orange-ish, brownish
kind of color here.
When we actually set the tint
color, if we look at the
resulting screen, you can see
that it's obviously not the
same color.
It's a little bit desaturated
because of that transparent
blur on the nav bar.
So to fix this and make that
color a lot stronger in the
nav bar and a lot closer to the
color that we're hoping
for, we can use a similar
approach that we used in the
previous example.
And instead of creating
a UI toolbar, we can
just create a UI view.
We need to set our UI view's
frame equal to the frame of
the nav bar.
We'll make sure that you can't
interact with that view, so it
doesn't interfere with any of
the interaction that's already
enabled on the nav bar.
And we'll set the alpha and the
background color to the
colors that we want.
Then in our navigation bar,
we'll insert the strong color
views layer as a sub layer.
It's very important, if
we do this, we have to
insert it at index 1.
Index 1 is the only
place where this
trick is going to work.
So you can see that the
navigation bar's bar tint
color is a lot closer to
the original color
we were hoping for.
But we've got another problem.
Whenever we push a new view
controller onto the navigation
stack, the layer is actually
appearing over the navigation
items instead of
underneath it.
And that's making them look
a little bit transparent.
So let's look at how we
can fix this problem.
To fix this, we need to reapply
that insert sub layer
method after the transition
is finished.
And we can do this by adopting
the UI navigation controller
delegate, setting our nav
controller's delegate to self,
and then overriding the
navigation controller
didShowViewController
animated method.
This method will fire whatever
that transition from one view
controller to another
finishes.
Inside of that delegate method,
we'll remove strong
color views layer.
And then will re-insert it
into the navigation bar.
And here you can see the result
of that working, and
the navigation items no longer
being obscured by that layer.
Now it's time for you to work
with blurs in the challenges.