Welcome back.
Now, we left off in the last
section with a cool custom
presentation animation,
as you can see here.
Now when the user taps the Sign
In button, we're going to
dismiss that view controller.
Now it looks like everything
went all right, but if you
were in the console you'd see
this warning, because if you
have a custom presentation,
your dismissal
also has to be custom.
In this section, we're going
to walk you through how to
create that custom dismissal
transition, and we're even
going to use some of the new
key frame APIs in iOS 7.
As you can see here, when we hit
Sign In, our view goes up
a bit and then will shoot down
to the bottom of the screen.
So in a plain modal dismissal,
for example, when the user
taps on this Sign In button
here, it would sign them and
dismiss the view controller,
we would have
something like this.
All we'd have to do is call
dismissViewControllerAnimated,
completion, and pass in YES.
Obviously, there's a little bit
more work to do to create
a custom dismissal.
First, we need to adopt the
transitioning delegate, then
we need to create the animation
transition class for
the dismissal, next we would
implement the dismissal
transition delegate method, and
then we would implement
the key frame animation in the
animated transition class.
These steps might
look familiar.
In fact, a lot of what we're
going to do to create a custom
dismissal transition is pretty
much the exact same thing as
the custom presentation
with just a couple
little things different.
Remember, we already adopted
the transitioning delegate
protocol on our past view
controller in the last section.
And so we don't actually
need to do that again.
What we'll need to do is
implement the animation
controller for Dismiss
Controller method that's a
part of the transitioning
delegate protocol.
Notice how both objects that
get returned from these
methods have to adopt the UI
View Controller animated
transitioning protocol.
Before we can implement this
dismissal method, we'll have
to create the animated
transition class for the
custom transition.
Just like in the last section
when we created the custom
presentation, we're going to
create a plain object here
that conforms to the UI View
Controller animated
transitioning protocol.
We're going to give it the name
TwoStepTransition to
differentiate it from the
BouncyTransition we created in
the last section.
Again, we're going to need to
implement two methods, the
transition duration method and
the animate transition method.
Notice that while we're
returning one second from the
transition duration method, it
doesn't have to be the same as
our presentation animation we
created in the last section.
It can be anything you want.
So back in our Paths View
Controller we can implement
the dismissal method now and
just return a new instance of
the TwoStep Transition class.
Now when we jump back into our
animate transition method on
our TwoStep Transition class,
you'll notice that even though
our code looks the same, the
to and the from view
controllers have flipped.
As you can see, the To view
controller now refers to the
paths view controller, and the
From controller refers to the
login view controller.
That's because we're going from
the login view controller
back to the paths
view controller.
Another difference here is
that both our To and From
views are already in the
container view, so we don't
need to add any views before
we do the animation.
So we can jump right
into the key frame.
Before we start animating, we're
going to need the frame
of the login view controller,
and we're going to get that by
calling the
initialFrameForViewController
on the transition context.
Next we're going to start the
animation by using the new key
frame animation API.
Our first step will be moving
that login view off the top of
the screen.
The next step of the key frame,
we'll just move the
view off the bottom of the
screen and rotate it a bit.
Now, there's one little error
in this code where we're
trying to change a variable
inside of a block -
that presented frame variable.
To fix this, all we need to do
is add a under under block
declaration before
the presented
frame variable is defined.
And that means we'll be able to
modify that variable inside
of a block.
Now it's your turn to implement
a custom dismissal
transition using some key frames
in the challenges.
Next.
Dit, dit, dit.
Actions we just ran over -
The presentation - bleh
And it bounces and I'm dumb.