Welcome back to Core iOS 7.
In this level, we're going to
be going over interactive
transitions.
Now, what is an interactive
transition?
The easiest place to see an
example of one of these
transitions is in a navigation
controller stack.
By default, you can pan from
the left side, as you see
here, and go back to the
last controller.
You can also see an interactive
transition in, for
example, the control center,
where you can pan up from the
bottom to bring it up, and also
pan down to dismiss the
control center.
In addition to being able to
tap the Sign In button to
dismiss the view controller, we
also want to let the user
interact with the view
controller to dismiss it.
Interactive transitions are
great, because they take
advantage of powerful gesture
recognizers that you might
already be familiar with in
iOS, but they're also very
easy to do in iOS 7.
This would have been much, much
harder to do in iOS 6.
It also allows the user to feel
more in control of the
experience, basically allowing
them to control the
transition.
Now at a high level, an
interactive transition is made
up of two parts.
The first part is what we
built last level in the
animated transition.
Now this doesn't
change at all.
Now the second part is the
user's interaction.
For example, a pan gesture where
they start from the top
and pan down to the bottom.
So you can think of this
like a movie you'd
watch on your computer.
The animated transition is
the movie, and goes from
beginning to end.
The interactive transition is
like the scrubber, allowing
you to scrub through the movie
to any point that you'd like.
So what do we want
to do in our app?
Basically, we want to allow the
user to dismiss the log in
view controller by
panning their
finger from top to bottom.
But we also want to make sure
that the two step transition
we built last level
still works by
tapping the sign in button.
There are three phases to an
interactive transition that
we're going to have
to implement.
The first one is starting
and setting up.
The second one is to update
as an interaction
changes over time.
And the last one is to finish
or cancel the interactive
transition.
In our starting and setting up
phase, we need to do three
different things.
First, we need to install the
gesture recognizer when the
modal finishes presenting.
When that gesture begins, when
the user starts panning their
finger, we need to actually
dismiss the view controller
and start the whole
transition.
Next, we need to implement the
interactive transition
delegate method to return a
interactive transition object.
This should look familiar.
We're back in the
PathsViewController inside of
the login button tap method,
where we're displaying the
login view controller -
presenting it, actually -
and we need to install the
gesture recognizer when this
presentation is done
so we can start
listening for the gesture.
We can do that by passing in
a completion block to the
presentViewController animated
completion method.
Inside of this block, we're
going to create a new
UIPanGestureRecognizer, we're
going to add a target of self
with the action being the
handleGesture method, and
we're going to add that gesture
recognizer to the
login view controller's view so
we're only detecting that
gesture inside of that view.
Now that we've installed our
gesture recognizer, we need to
implement the handleGesture
method on the
PathsViewController.
This method is going to be
called many times over the
life of this gesture.
Each time this method is called,
we're going to want to
switch on the gesture's state,
which can be any
one of these constants.
If we want to start the
dismissal, for example, when
the gesture begins, we would
add the code to the
UIGestureRecognizerStateBegan
block.
When we call dismiss, this
is going to kick off the
transition.
But how do we make sure that
it becomes an interactive
transition instead of just a
normal animated transition?
To do that, we need to implement
the interactionContr
ollerForDismissal delegate
method on PathsViewController.
Returning from that method is an
object that should conform
to the UIViewController
interactive
transitioning protocol.
In our animated transitions from
the last level, we had to
create our own classes, like
balancing transition, or
two-step transition to actually
implement those
transitions.
But for the interactive
transition, we can use a class
provided by UIKit called
UIPercentDrivenI
nteractiveTransition, and this
class implements the
interactive transitioning
protocol.
For example, we can use it
like this, where we just
create a transition object, then
with that object, we can
update the interactive
transition to a certain
scrubber position. We can
finish the interactive
transition, or we could cancel
the interactive transition.
And we're using each of these
methods to learn how to drive
the interactive transition.
The first step, obviously, is to
just return an instance of
this class from the
interactionContr
ollerForDismissal delegate
method in our
PathsViewController, like so.
Now that we have our interactive
transition set up,
let's move on to phase two.
In phase two, we need to
calculate a number between 0
and 1 based on how the gesture
changes, and update the
interactive transition.
So what would that look like?
Basically what we want to do is,
as the user's finger moves
down the screen, we want
to continuously call
updateInteractiveTransition,
passing in a value between 0
and 1 based on that position;
and we're going to look
at how to calculate
that value in a minute.
The number we pass into
updateInteractiveTransition
sets the timing of the
animated transition.
For example, if we passed in
0.0, the animation would be at
its starting position.
If we passed in 0.5, or
50%, the animation
would be halfway through.
So if we want to call
updateInteractiveTransition
continuously as a gesture
changes, we're going to want
to go back into the
handleGesture method and open
up the
UIGestureRecognizerStateChanged
case and add the
code in there.
There are two things
here we need to do.
One is to figure out what
number to pass into
updateInteractiveTransition.
The other is, how do we access
the transition object that we
created in the
InteractiveTransition delegate?
To fix that last problem,
we'll go back in the
PathsViewController header and
add a property for that
PercentDrivenInt
eractiveTransition, and we'll
just call it something like
myInteractiveDismissal.
Then, in our PathsViewController
dismissal
delegate method, we'll
set that property
and then return it.
Now, back in our handleGesture
method, which again is defined
on PathsViewController, we'll
have access to that property,
and be able to call
updateInteractiveTransition on it.
But we still have that one
problem left where what number
do we pass into that method?
And we'll figure that out now.
If we access the
gesture.view.superview, this
will return us the transition
context container view.
And if we pass that view into
the translation and new
method, it'll give us the
CGPoint that we're calling
translation.
Now we're going to use that y
position on that CGPoint and
divide it by the height
of the views frame.
That will give us the
percentTransitioned, which
we'll pass into the update
interactive transition method.
Let's get a better idea of what
that means by visualizing
the percentTransition
calculation that we just made.
Here we have the view hierarchy,
and the user has
panned their finger down the
screen a certain length.
Now, that orange bar is going to
signify the translation.y.
We're going to divide that by
the height of the view, which
corresponds to the green bar.
Now that will give us
the result of the
percentTransitioned.
So in this example, it looks
like we're about 25 to 30%
transitioned.
So that wraps up phase two.
Now we're moving on to phase
three, where we have to finish
or cancel the transition.
Back in the handleGesture
method, when the user, in the
middle of the interactive
transition, lifts their
finger, we have to decide
whether we want the view to
continue animating off the screen,
or finishing, or to
animate back into place,
which is canceling.
Our interactive dismissal
object has a
percent complete property.
This will return the last
value we pass to
updateInteractiveTransition, and
we can use that value to
decide whether we want to
finish or cancel the
transition.
In this case, we're going to
finish the transition if it's
past 25%, otherwise we're
going to cancel the
transition.
We also want to make sure we
implement the case where the
gesture is canceled.
Now, this can happen if the
gesture is, let's say,
disabled somewhere
else in the code.
In that case, we're always going
to want to cancel the
interactive transition.
Now get into the challenges
and create your first
interactive transition.