In this section, we're going
to look at how we can apply
Auto Layout to working with some
of the topics we covered
in level two--
namely UI Text Views and the
new Dynamic Type system
that's in IOS 7.
Auto Layout is perfect for
working with variable-height
text views and Dynamic Type.
You'll recall from level two
that variable-height text
fields come into play whenever
you have data coming over from
a network request and you don't
know how much you'll
have after the request
is complete.
So your text view might contain
a little bit of text.
It might contain
a lot of text.
We'll be able to use Auto Layout
in a creative way in
order to size the UI Text
View accordingly.
We're going to set up these
constraints in Senator Detail
View controller.
This view controller comes into
play after one of the
senator [? shaoyun ?] games
has been complete.
And when we click one of the
history items from the History
View controller, the Detail View
controller pops up and
gives us information in the form
of a picture and a text
view for whichever senator
was involved in that
round of the game.
So to get started with this
layout in Interface Builder,
we'll want to first make sure
that everything is inside of a
UIScrollView.
Remember from the last section
that if we wait until after
we've added all the constraints
to embed things in
the Scroll View, those
constraints will go away, and
we'll have to do double
the work.
So here we'll start with
a UIScrollView.
And we'll set the top, leading,
center horizontally,
and center vertically
constraints in order to make
sure that scroll view takes up
as much space as it needs.
Next, we'll drag in the toolbar
and segmented control,
the label for the senator's
name, any the UIImageView for
the senator's picture.
And we'll add some constraints
that position
each of these views.
Then we'll grab our text view,
represented here by the pink
square, and give it the
remaining available space
underneath the UIImageView and
the bottom of the Scroll View
with a little bit of room
on the edge for padding.
Then we'll add the Leading,
Trailing, and Center X to
Container constraints in order
to give that little bit of
padding on the left and the
right side and give it the
exposition by centering it
inside of the Scroll View.
Then we'll need to set a fixed
height for the text view.
This is really important.
And it's not obvious, because
if our text view is variable
height, it doesn't seem like
we'd be setting a fixed height
inside of it.
But we'll fix that
in just a second.
Finally, we'll add a bottom
constraint to the text view
and repeat our trick from the
previous section, where we set
the constant to zero, thus
allowing the scroll view's
content size to expand
to be as big or small
as it needs to be.
To be able to change that height
constraint after we've
added it in Interface Builder,
we need to jump into a little
bit of code.
So in Senator Detail VC's
header, we'll add two
properties.
The first one will be a weak
property that's an IB Outlet
for the text view.
And the next property will also
be weak and an IB Outlet,
but this time it'll be for
NS Layout Constraint.
And we'll call this constraint
Text View Height.
You'll remember that once we've
declared a property with
the IB Outlet designation, that
means we can create an
outlet in the outline view
between the file's owner and
the constraint itself.
And you see here that
we're choosing the
name Text View Height.
So now we've created a link
between our Text View Height
property in code and the Text
View Height constraint in
Interface Builder, which is
going to allow us to change
that constraint in code and
have Auto Layout update
accordingly.
Since we're working with
constraints and Auto Layout,
instead of using view will
layout subviews or view did
load to set our frames, we'll
instead use the updated view
constraints method that's part
of any UI view controller.
Inside of that method, we'll
call super update view
constraints.
And then we'll set the text view
heights constant equal to
this new method that
we've defined
called Text View Height.
If we look at the code inside
of Text View Height, you'll
notice that it's the same code
that we used in level two.
We're passing the insure layout
for text container
method to the text view.
And then we're capturing the
usedRect for text container,
which gives us a CGRect that
contains the full bounds of
our text container.
And finally, we're returning the
height of that Rect plus
the insets at the top and the
bottom of the text container.
This is the same set of code we
used in level two in order
to size our text views.
Here, we've just wrapped it a
nice convenience method that
allows us to pass in a text
view and get the ultimate
height of that text container
as a return value so that in
Update View Constraints, the
constant is always going to be
set to the ultimate height
of that text view.
So now, if we watch this working
inside of the Senator
Detail View Controller, you
can see that scrolling is
working pretty well.
We can switch between the two
different tabs in the toolbar.
And the text view height and
scroll height update
accordingly.
But if we try to rotate the
device, we'll see that
something's gone wrong.
Looks like that that text
view height is not being
successfully set.
And it's resulting in some
strange behavior
with the text view.
Fortunately, the fix for
this is really easy.
All we need to do is implement
the Will Animate Rotation to
Interface Orientation Duration
method inside of Senator
Detail View Controller.
And then we just need to call
Set Needs Update Constraints
on the self.view object.
This is going to re-trigger the
update view constraints
method, which is going to
recalculate the height of the
text view and reapply that
height into the height
constraint.
So here you can see
that scrolling and
rotation are now working.
So that covers working
with the text view.
But what about dynamic type?
Well, we've looked at the
dynamic type code
before in level two.
And you'll recall that it looks
something like this.
We have a method called content
size changed that gets
called in response to a
notification that the system
posts whenever the user
changes the text size.
And then inside of that method,
we do something like
reapplying a text style.
We reset the font for that
particular text view using
size zero so that it knows
to use the automatically
calculated system size.
And then again, all we need to
do in here is pass the Set
Needs Update Constraints
method to self.view.
And then that will re-trigger
update view constraints again.
And then the text will
be size accordingly.
And the scroll view will
be the right height.
And everything will
rotate properly.
So here you can see the result
of the dynamic height
adjustment and dynamic type
working together beautifully.
Now it's time for you to work
with some text views in the
challenges.
Good luck.
You'll--
[CLEARS THROAT]
Ah.
You'll--
[BEEP]
Ta--
[SIGHS]
Tata.
[LAUGHTER]
[BEEP]
While we're--
wow we're?
[LAUGHTER]
[BEEP]