Hi, and welcome to Core iOS 7.
I'm John Friskics.
And in this course, we're going
to be talking about some
of the exciting new advancements
that the iOS 7
SDK brings and how to work with
all these new tools, as
you build your apps for this
new operating system.
In this level, we're going to
be talking about some of the
important changes to the way
that views are laid out, in a
view hierarchy.
So, let's get started.
To help us understand how this
has changed from iOS 6, we've
created a sample app called
Senator Showdown using iOS 6.
And we're going to show you
how some of the elements
inside of that app change
as we transition
it over to iOS 7.
In the first half of this app
you can see that in iOS 6 the
view used to sit below
the status bar,
but in iOS 7 the view actually
slides under the status bar.
This is going to be a common
pattern in the way that views
are displayed in iOS 7.
You also see that in the iOS 6
version, our buttons have a
rounded rectangle border.
And in iOS 7, those borders
don't exist anymore.
They're actually gone
from the system.
Finally, you'll notice that in
iOS 6, we've got a purple tab
bar with some tab
bar items on it.
But in iOS 7, that bottom tab
bar is actually translucent,
and the purple that we're seeing
is the purple seeping
in from the view below it.
Now in our history view
controller, in iOS 6, you can
see that the status bar was
separate from the nav bar.
While in iOS 7, they're
actually connected
into one big bar.
That's going to be important.
The tint color that's been added
in iOS 6, to make the
top and bottom bars purple,
is not showing in iOS 7.
And finally the tab bar image
has a detail selection state
that is inverting the color from
the normal color to this
sort of blue highlight.
While in iOS 7, the tint color
is actually being applied to
the tab bar icon, turning
it purple.
Looking at this detailed view
controller, you can see that
many of the UI kit elements
actually have different
default styles.
And even things like fonts
and font attributes are
slightly different between iOS
6 and iOS 7, even if we're
using the same font
on both systems.
Here you'll notice one of the
biggest differences between
views in iOS 6 and 7.
In iOS 6, this view is taking
up only as much space as is
available underneath the status
bar and the tab bar.
But over and iOS 7, that
view is actually
taking up the full screen.
Views in iOS 7 naturally try to
fill up the entire screen.
If we look at this in a little
more detail, we can see that
the status bar on iOS 6
was 20 points high.
And the space between the first
label on here, the won
and lost labels, and that status
bar, is 40 points.
But if we look at the same
view in iOS 7, while the
status bar content still is 20
point high, that content does
not influence the top
of the layout.
And you see that the space
between the won and lost
labels, and the very
top of the screen,
is now that 40 pixels.
Thus, it's not influenced
by the status bar.
You have two options for
how you can display the
status bar in iOS 7.
You can either display it as a
black text on a transparent
background, or white text on
a transparent background.
And you can set that by
overriding the method
preferred status bar style
in your view controller.
The default is to have black
text on a transparent
background, but if you want to
be white text, then you can
override the preferred status
bar style method, inside of
your view controller, and return
the UI status bar style
light content constant.
If you decide that you don't
want the status bar showing in
one of your view controllers,
you can override the preferred
status bar hidden method,
and return yes.
And then when you load that view
controller, the status
bar will disappear.
Now remember that hiding the
status bar won't affect your
layout dimensions at all,
because it's not used in the
calculation of frames anymore.
And now it's time for you to
work on some challenges.