So let's see how our interactive
transition is
looking at this point.
As you can see, when the user
starts panning their finger,
it looks like we might still
be using that Two Step
keyframe animation
from level three.
And that's not right,
obviously.
We need to fix that.
The problem is, as you remember,
the interactive
transition just drives the
animated transition.
And as you can see here, we're
still using the Two Step
transition in our paths
view controller.
To fix this, we need a different
animated transition
when dismissal is interactive.
So let's create a new animated
transition object just for
when the transition
is interactive.
We can name it something like
SimpleAnimatedDismissal.
We make sure it adopts the UI
view controller animated
transitioning protocol.
And then, in the implementation,
we return a
duration, even though it's
really not going to be used.
And of course, we have
to implement our
animateTransition method.
Now, this is stuff we've covered
before, especially in
the last level.
One important thing that is
different here is that we're
going to pass in the curve
linear option to
the animation API.
If you don't pass in the curve
linear option and instead,
say, you use a ease in/out, the
view won't stay under the
user's finger, leading to
a loss of interaction.
To be able to track whether
the current dismissal's
interactive, we're going to add
a Boolean property to our
paths view controller and
call it Interactive.
Then, in our handleGesture begin
state case, we're going
to set the interactive to Yes.
Now in our animation controller
for dismiss
controller method, we can use
that interactive property to
return the simple animated
dismissal object when
interactive is yes.
And otherwise, if interactive
is no, we're going to still
return the Two Step
transition object.
Now let's see if that
fixed our problem.
As you can see here, as the
user starts panning their
finger down the screen, the
view follows their finger,
just like we wanted.
And then when they let go, when
they're past 25%, the
transition will finish.
But what happens if they don't
drag down far enough and the
transition cancels?
The canceled transition worked,
but unfortunately, it
still removed the view
from the hierarchy.
And that's not what we want.
What's happening here is that
when you pass yes to complete
transition, you're telling the
transition context that the
transition finished.
And that's not what happened.
Since interactive transitions
can be canceled, we have to
make sure we are passing in the
right argument to complete
transition.
We can easily do that by asking
the transition context
whether or not it
was canceled.
In our simple animated
dismissal, all we had to do is
update our code like so.
So now when the interactive
transition is canceled, as you
can see, the view stays in the
hierarchy just like we wanted.
Unfortunately, our keyframe
animated transition has
stopped working.
To see why this is happening,
if we go back to our
interaction controller for
dismissal method, you can see
that we're always returning
an object.
This means that we're always
going to use an interactive
transition when we're
dismissing, which
isn't what we want.
What we need to do is return nil
from this method when we
just want a plain animated
transition.
We can do that pretty easily
by using the interactive
Boolean property.
All we have to do is only return
that object when we're
in the interactive transition.
If we're not, just return nil.
You might be wondering, why are
we worried about animated
transitions inside a method
called interactionController
ForDismissal?
And that's because even on a
regular animated transition,
the transition system is going
to call this method.
And we need to tell it not to
use interactive transition for
that animated transition.
One last thing we have to do
before we go is we need to
reset the interactive
Boolean to know when
our dismissal finishes.
That way, next time a dismissal
happens, we're not
accidentally using interactive
when we
really just want animated.
So that's pretty easy to do.
All we had to do is add a
completion block to that call
and set interactive to nil.
Now let's take a look at our
finished interactive
transition.
As you can see, we can now
dismiss our view controller
using an interactive
transition.
And when we open the view back
up, we can also still dismiss
it using our keyframe
animation.
There's a couple more things you
can do to really add some
polished to your interactive
transitions.
The first one would be to look
at the velocity of the gesture
instead of just the position
of the gesture.
That way, you can allow the user
to throw the modal down,
and it won't cancel
unexpectedly.
Another thing you could
do is to subclass the
UIPercentDrivenI
nteractiveTransition class and
combine it with that animated
transition used during
interactive.
That will clean up some
of your code.
Another good idea would be to
create a separate transition
delegate class, instead of
overloading the presenting
view controller like we were
doing in our paths view
controller earlier.
But we'll leave that
for another day.
For now, get into the challenges
and create your
first interactive transition.
[BEEP]
"Guess-ture?"
No, gesture.
"Jesh."
Gesture.
[BEEP]
[MUMBLING]
Ow.
Cramp.
[BEEP]
One ping.
Ping?
[LAUGHTER]
[BEEP]