In this section, we're going to
be talking about how having
top and bottom bars affect the
layout of your main view.
So, you can see here that this
is not just a simple status
bar anymore.
It's got a navigation
bar attached to it.
And that navigation bar takes
up additional space near the
top of the screen.
So, let's look at how this
is different from iOS 6.
In iOS 6 your status bar was
a fixed 20 points high.
And the navigation bar, unless
you subclassed it to make it
custom, by default was
44 points high.
Which meant that your view
sitting underneath it would be
504 points high if you viewed
it on four inch screen.
That's the screen height minus
the status bar height minus
the nav bar height, to get
the size of self.view.
In iOS 7 the status bar and nav
bar height are actually
connected in 164 point bar.
And conveniently, the height
of that bar is available in
topLayoutGuide.length.
Remember that views in iOS
7 are full screen,
so self.view is actually sitting
underneath the nav
bar, at full height.
Back in our previous example,
if we were to have a
navigation bar and status
bar, it would look
something like this.
We can see that the top layout
guide.length is now 64, which
we'll use for the origin.y.
And the height is going to be
504, because that's going to
be the main view height minus
the topLayoutGuide.length.
So, what this comes down to is,
if you're already laying out
views with topLayoutGuide in
your layout subviews method,
then adding a nav
bar just works.
The will automatically be
re-sized to fit underneath
that new nav bar, when
it's available.
Now if you're main view or
content subview is a scroll
view, then there's a few more
things that you're going to
need to understand.
So, I've set up a
situation here.
Here we have a scroll view
that's the content subview.
The scroll view's height is
the entire height of the
screen, which makes sense.
We'll be able to see
it underneath
those translucent bars.
We've got a UI label that is a
subview of our scroll view.
And the labels origin
y is zero.
So, it seems like the label
should be partially hidden
underneath this nav
bar, doesn't it.
If our origin y is zero and
our scroll view is full
height, shouldn't that label
start at the height of the
scroll view, which is underneath
the nav bars.
But that's not actually
happening.
So, why is this not hidden?
Well, if we look at this another
way and we kind of
give it a 3D angle, we can see
that there's definitely some
padding that's being added to
the top of this scroll view.
Our scroll view is the orange
section, and the label is the
blue section, and those little
transparent rectangles that
are all layered on top of each
other, are the nav bar.
So, you could see that the
label's definitely not
touching the very top of
the orange scroll view.
It's pushed down a little bit.
So that padding is actually
added for you automatically,
whenever self.view or the
immediate content subview of
self.view, is a UI
scroll view.
And the padding amount,
conveniently, is equal to
topLayoutGuide.length.
So, there's a new property in
iOS 7 called "automatically
Adjusts Scroll View Insets."
And by default that property
is set to yes, and that's
what's enabling this magic
padding to appear.
If we were to set the
automaticallyAdjustsScrollViewInSets
property to no, this
is the code we would add
in order to recreate the
behavior when the property was
yes, updating the content inset
and content offset of
our content subview.
So, let's take a look at these
lines of code, and really
think about what
they're doing.
The first line, where we're
adjusting the content inset,
means that we're adding 64
points of padding to the very
top of the scrollable area
of our scroll view.
Adding this padding will push
our content down a little bit
too far, so we have to offset
that with our content offset
property, by moving
that content back
up again by 64 points.
So now let's talk about what
happens when you have a nav
bar and a tab bar in your view
controller, which is a pretty
common situation.
That tab bar is 49
points high.
And back in iOS 6, again, your
self.view property would
automatically adjust its size
to the available space, not
including the bars.
So our self.view height would be
the screen height minus the
status bar on the top, minus
the nav bar underneath it,
minus the tab bar height
at the bottom.
So that you would fit right
inside of there.
On iOS 7 that tab bar is still
49 points high, but just like
with the top bars, the
view doesn't resize
itself to fit inside.
It stays full screen.
So sometimes we'll also need a
way to calculate the size of
the bottom bar.
So just like before, we've got
a property called "bottom
layout guide."
And if we look at the top length
of that, it will equal
49 points, when a tab
bar is present.
If our view is a scroll view,
then the insets are going to
be automatically adjusted again
for us, although this
time they'll also be adjusted
at the bottom by 49 points.
Again, the default value is to
let the view controller handle
all of these numbers for you,
but we're just showing you
what's going on under the
hood, in case you run
into any problems.
What's nice about this set
up is that when we start
scrolling, we can actually see
our content underneath the
translucent nav bar and
translucent tab bar, and that
wouldn't happen in iOS 6.
So the previous example talked
about what to do if we have a
scroll view,
but if we just have a
plain UI view, it's
a little bit simpler.
All we need to do is go back to
our content subviews frame
in viewWillLayoutSubviews,
and also subtract the
bottomLayoutGuide.legnth from
our height calculation.
And that's going to make sure
that our UI view sits snug, in
between that top nav bar
and bottom tab bar.
So remember those four questions
that we asked
ourselves earlier
in the level.
Well, if you answer yes to any
one of the first three, then
you're probably going to want to
consider using the new top
layout guide property and bottom
layout guide property,
to control how those views
are positioned.
If your main view is a scroll
view though, or a subview of a
scroll view, then you're going
to want to consider letting
the automaticallyAdjustsScrollViewInsets
property do
some of that positioning work
for you, so your content is
still visible underneath
those bars.
And now it's time for you to
work on some challenges.