Welcome back.
In this level, we'll be looking
at how to use UIKit
Dynamics with animated
transitions.
Remember that any place where
you traditionally have a UI
view block-based animation is a
candidate for being replaced
with UIKit Dynamics.
So consider this example.
In our articles app, we've added
a Settings button to the
articles list view.
When you tap that Settings
button, it drops down a
settings view that allows us
to change the mode from day
mode to night mode with
a simple switch.
And when we hide that settings
view, settings view slides
back up and goes away.
And the view is updated
accordingly.
Now, you may have noticed that
as that settings view was
dropping, there was a slight
bounce in the animation as it
hit the bottom edge
of the view.
That's because this actually has
a gravity behavior applied
to the animated transition so we
can see that bounce effect.
So let's look at how we
would build this.
To start, we'll do a really
quick overview of how an
animated transition is set up.
We covered this in great
detail in level three.
So first, we have a method
called showSettings that gets
called whenever that
Settings button is
tapped in the toolbar.
Then we create a settings view
controller and set the modal
presentation style and
transitioning delegate.
And finally, we call the
present view controller
method, which starts the
presentation happening.
Inside of the completion block
for that presentation, we need
to register some kind of gesture
that we'll be using on
the settings view controller.
In this case, since we're
dismissing it with a simple
button, we'll just use
a simple tap gesture.
We're presenting and dismissing
a modal view
controller.
So we need to override these two
methods that are part of
our transitioning delegate.
And just like we talked about
in level three, we've got a
DropBounce for the presentation
animation and
DismissGravity for the
dismissal animation.
So as you'll recall, the
animated transition class for
the present animation
usually starts out
something like this.
We capture our From and
To view controllers.
We grab the start frame from
our From view controller.
And we use it to help set the
start frame for our To view
controller so we can set the
beginning position before that
settings controller is
visible onscreen.
And then finally, we add the
To view controller to our
transitionContext
containerView.
And that was that big
containerView that held both
the start and end position.
And after that, we would add a
UI view-based animation to
move that To view down onto
the screen, maybe add some
keyframes to make it move around
and bounce around a
little bit.
And overall, we would end up
with 100 or 150 lines of code
when we were done, of all the
different states of our
different animation.
So this is a great
candidate for
replacing with UIKit Dynamics.
And we'll be able to drastically
reduce the amount
of lines of code that
we have to write.
To start, we'll again add a UI
dynamic animator property
that's strong to our
DropBounce header.
And then inside of our
DropBounce implementation,
we'll alloc Init that
dynamic animator.
But this time, instead of
using self.view as our
reference view, we'll use
our transition context
containerView.
And let's look at why that is.
When we're dealing with a single
view, self.view is
usually the highest superview
that's displayed onscreen.
But when we add a transition
into the mix, the From view
and the To view are actually
just children of this bigger
view, called containerView.
So when we want to try to add
a reference for all of our
animations, we can't be sure
that the dimensions of the
From view or the To view
will stay the same.
But we can be sure that the
containerView's frame will
always be the same.
Back in our DropBounce
animation, we'll Alloc Init a
gravity behavior, applying the
gravity to the To view
controller that's going
to be moving from
the top of the screen.
We'll set up the direction
to pull the To view down.
And then we'll add that behavior
to the animator.
As expected, when we tap the
Settings button, down comes
the To view controller,
and there it goes.
Yeah ... it's not stopping and
bouncing when it hits the
bottom of the view.
So we need to also add a
collision behavior so that it
knows to not try to keep
falling down forever.
Before, we used the entire
dimensions of the screen as
our collision boundaries.
But here, we really only want
to have one of those
boundaries block the gravity.
And that's the very bottom
of the containerView.
So if we add a boundary to
just the bottom of the
containerView, we
should be fine.
Again, we create a UI
collision behavior.
And we apply it to
the toVC.view.
Then we can call this method
addBoundaryWithIdentifier
fromPoint, toPoint.
And give that boundary a
name in case we need to
reference it later.
And then we're basically drawing
a line for where we
want that boundary to extend,
from the very bottom left
corner of our container to the
very bottom right corner of
our container.
And this is going to allow that
view to drop with gravity
and only bounce when it hits
that bottom edge boundary that
we just created.
Now the Settings button drops
the view, and it bounces when
it hits that boundary.
But we forgot to complete
the transition.
Remember that whenever you're
finishing an animation in an
animated transition, you have
to call the complete
transition method.
Otherwise, you won't be able
to interact with the view
anymore, which is what
we're seeing here.
So again, we need a way
to determine when
the animation stops.
And then we'll want
to complete the
transition after it stops.
So inside of our DropBounce
class, we'll implement the
dynamic animator delegate, just
like we did before when
we needed to do this.
And we'll also add a property
to store the transition
context because we'll need a way
to access that transition
context inside of the
delegate method.
Inside of our animate transition
method, we'll
capture the transition
context first thing
inside of our property.
We'll set our delegate
to self.
And then in our
dynamicAnimatorDidPause
method, we'll call the complete
transition method,
which formally completes the
transition as soon as the
animation stops.
Now you can see that once our
animation completes, we're
able to interact with the
controls that are in the
settings view, which is just
what we want to happen.
When it comes to dismissing the
settings view, we'll do a
lot of the same steps.
Since we used dynamics to
present the settings view, it
would only make sense
that we use dynamics
to make it go away.
So let's use a gravity behavior,
this time applied in
a negative y direction to shoot
the view back up once we
hit the Hide Settings button.
Just like we did in DropBounce,
in DismissGravity,
we'll Alloc Init the animator
object using the containerView
again as the reference view,
and we'll add a gravity
behavior.
This time, we'll add it
to the From view.
Since if the settings view is
already onscreen, it will now
be the From view controller.
And the list view that we're
trying to go to will be the To
view controller.
And here, we'll use a vector
that's negative 12, which
means that the settings view is
going to move up when this
behavior is added.
And finally, when that settings
view moves completely
offscreen, we need to remove all
the animation behaviors.
And we need to complete
the transition.
So to do this, we'll
add an action block
to the gravity behavior.
And again, we'll check if
the transition context
containerView frame is not
intersecting at all with the
From view frame.
And if they're not intersecting
at all, we'll
remove the behaviors and
complete the transition.
Here we can see the final
working version of this
animated transition.
The settings view drops from the
top of the screen, bounces
a little bit when it hits that
collision boundary, and then
flips itself back up really
quick whenever the "Hide
Settings" button is tapped.
And now it's time for you to
use UIKit Dynamics in an
animated transition
in the challenges.
Good luck.
[BEEP]
- different times, and
trying to [MUMBLING].
[LAUGHTER]
[BEEP]
- to enhance a common thing.
Hm, common thing [LAUGHS].
[BEEP]