Welcome back.
In this level, we're going to
be talking about the changes
to working with fonts,
and working with text
layout in iOS 7.
So the way that you would create
a font and iOS 6, is
you would just call the font
with name size method, on a UI
Font class.
And that would return to you a
UI Font object, that you could
apply to your labels
and text views.
Now, Apple saw a problem with
that, in that file names don't
always follow a consistent
format.
For example, you can see some
different bold font names, and
bold italic font names.
So it's hard to know exactly
what the name of the font is
going to be, before you
have to use it.
So in iOS 7, they're taking
a new approach called "font
descriptors."
And the idea here is that you
describe the kind of font that
you want, with a certain set of
attributes and traits that
relate to that font, and you'll
get a UI Font object
out of that.
So here, I've created a
UIFontDescriptor, using the
fontDescriptorWithFontAttributes
method, and I
passed it a dictionary
containing
UIFontDescriptorFamilyAttribute
key, with a value
of Helvetica Neue.
That gives me just the
base Helvetica font.
Then, if I want that font to
also be italic, I can take
that base font, and I can apply
a font descriptor with
symbolic trait of
UIFontDescriptor trait italic.
That's going to take that
base font, and modify it
to now be in italic.
And then finally when I'm
creating my UIFont object
that I'll use with my labels,
I call the fontWithDescriptor
size method,
and I pass it that font
descriptor that was created.
And the end result is I'll
have a UI font, using the
italic version of Helvetica
Neue that's 18 point size.
So you can see with this code,
we're creating a UI label.
Then we're creating a bold font,
and we're applying that
font to the label.
So it's fairly common in iOS
apps to need to change the
contents of a label, after
they've been initially set.
Say new data comes in from
a network request.
Well when we do that, we also
need to adjust the size of the
label, not just the
text inside of it.
In iOS 6, the method that you
used to size the label was
called "size with font."
And that method is actually
deprecated in iOS 7.
Instead of sizeWithFont,
we can use the sizeWithAttributes
method.
And we'll pass in the
dictionary of
attributes for that font.
The two attributes we're using
here are the font name itself,
which we can access with the
NS Font attribute name key,
and the trait that we've applied
to font, which in this
case was a bold font.
So we passed the
UIFontDescriptorTraitsAttribute
key the value,
UIFontDescriptorTraitBold.
And now the size that's returned
by this method will
be the appropriate size for the
new content that was added
to our label.
Once we have that size, we use
it to resize the frame of the
label, accordingly.
The properties that determine
how our text is laid out can
come from both font attributes,
like name,
family, face, and size,
but they can also come
from attributes in an
NSAttributedString, like
paragraph style and spacing,
kerning and ligatures, whether
the text is underlined or has
a strikethrough.
Since both of these sets of
attributes affect the way that
text is laid out, we need to
consider which attributes are
applied to the text we're
trying to resize.
Here's an example of a label
that has its attributed text
property set, rather than
just its text property,
which means we're using an
attributed string, instead of
an NS string.
We're adding some attributes
to that attributed string,
like letterpress effect, making
the color gray, and
setting the kerning over the
entire length of the string.
So that means when we go to
resize this string, we need to
take into consideration not only
the font and any traits
applied to it, but also any
of the attributes from the
attributed string text that
might affect the layout of the
text inside of the label.
In this case, the kerning will
most definitely affect the
spacing and layout
of the text.
So we need to add it to the
size with attributes
dictionary.
Now we know that that's a lot of
new information in a very
short amount of time.
So we want you to try some
challenges where you're going
to be resizing labels with
various attributes.
And then we'll come back
and learn some more.