Welcome back.
In this level, we're going to
take the Senator Showdown app
that we used in level one and
we're going to reimplement
some of the layout using
Auto Layout.
We've already completed the
initial steps of dragging in
each of the views--
in this case, all UI labels.
We've set their initial
properties, like their frame
and their text color.
And we've arranged them all
around the general location
that we want them to be.
If we run the app that contains
this layout, it's
going to look something
like this.
Obviously, we've got a little
bit of work to do before this
is working perfectly.
So we need to add constraints to
position each one of these
views in the right spot and to
make sure that these labels
don't get truncated.
Before we add any constraints,
we'll want to make sure that
our outline view is
easily readable.
Because there's lots of views,
there's going to be lots of
constraints.
So the more descriptive we can
make our names and the shorter
we can make those descriptions,
the easier it's
going to be to read those
constraints once
they've been added.
So something like this where
we're repeating the word
"label" a lot is going to get
really confusing when we see
it listed multiple times.
Instead, we'll rename each of
our views to more concise
names, and we'll order them in
the outline from top down.
So now, when we're looking at
the order of our views in the
outline, it mimics the order
that those views
appear in the editor.
There's two different
ways to add
constraints in this layout.
The first one is right clicking
and dragging between
views in the Editor panel.
The pro is that this is visual
and it's easy to understand
the constraints that
you're applying.
But the con is that it's very
easy to accidentally click and
drag onto the wrong view or
one of its super views.
And if you do this, you're going
to end up adding the
wrong constraint.
The second approach is to right
click and drag directly
between views in the outline.
And the pro of this is that you
don't need to worry about
creating constraints between the
wrong views because you're
directly adding them from
one to the other.
But it becomes much harder to
visualize exactly how these
constraints work together
in the layout.
Once you get used to both of
these approaches, it's not
uncommon to mix and match and go
back and forth while you're
working on a layout.
Here, I'll add constraints
directly into the editor.
But you'll notice that, as I
add a top constraint and a
leading space constraint, that
the constraints turn blue
without having to add a
width and a height.
And that's kind of strange.
We said before that we always
need to have an X, Y, width,
and height constraint
in order for the
constraints to turn blue.
So why do we only need to
declare X and Y here?
Well, some views have something
called an intrinsic
content size that determines
their width and height at run
time based on their font
and text properties.
So things like UI labels, UI
buttons, and even UI image
views that have an image inside
of them in Interface
Builder all define an intrinsic
content size,
meaning their width and height
is predetermined.
In fact, you don't want to set
width and height constraints
on views that have an intrinsic
content size,
because they'll automatically
be calculated for you
when the app runs.
Since these are all UI labels,
we're only going to need to
add X and Y positions for
each of these views.
We'll start by adding a
constraint between the Won and
Lost labels using the horizontal
spacing and
baseline constraints.
Then we'll connect up the Won
and Lost number place holders
using vertical spacing and
center X so that W and L stay
centered on the Won and Lost.
We'll connect up the percent
sign to the W using vertical
spacing and to the super view
using center horizontally so
it stays in the middle of the
view, and then connect up the
rest of these views at the
bottom, mainly using vertical
spacing and either left or right
positioning, just to
keep them aligned with
each other and fixed
inside of this grid.
When we're all finished, these
constraints turn blue.
And again, that's a sign that
we've done something right.
Now, if we run this in the
simulator, we can see that our
layout looks a lot better
than it did
before in portrait mode.
If we rotate the device into
landscape mode, we've got a
few problems.
First everything's pushed over
to the left a little bit.
And we probably want all of
that to be in the center.
And since landscape doesn't have
as much vertical space,
now we need to put all of this
inside of a scroll view so
that we can scroll and see
all of the content.
Let's tackle the first problem
that some of the
views are not centered.
If we look at all of our
constraints, we've got a
leading space constraint
on the Won label.
This constraint is actually
saying to always position the
Won label that amount of points
from the left edge.
And that's why it's pulling it
over to the left when we
rotate the screen.
If we delete the leading
constraint and replace it with
a center horizontally in
container constraint, then
we're going to be able to center
everything inside of
the superview.
Notice that when we do this,
the center constraint is
actually offset by 59 points.
And this is because the Won
label doesn't appear directly
in the center of the layout.
It's offset over to the left
by a little bit, but it's
still anchored to that center.
Now, when we re-run this in
the simulator and view in
landscape mode, everything
is centered.
But we still have the problem
of not being able to see all
the content because we
need to embed all of
this in a scroll view.
Now, there's some good
and bad news here.
The good news is that Xcode
provides a menu option to
directly create a scroll view
for a set of views.
So we'll start by highlighting
all the views that we want to
put in the scroll view and then
choose Editor, Embed in
Scroll View.
And when we choose that, all of
those views will get placed
directly inside of
a scroll view.
The bad news is that all of the
constraints have now been
reset because our superview
has changed.
So we'll need to go through the
process of re-adding all
of these constraints.
In addition, we need to add
constraints for the scroll
view itself so that
it sits correctly
inside of the main view.
Adding constraints for the
scroll view is pretty easy,
though, because we need it to
always take up the entire
available space.
So we can do that by adding a
top space, leading space,
center horizontally, and center
vertically constraint.
And then that scroll view will
always take up the entire
available space of the view
in either portrait
or landscape mode.
We've gone through the process
of adding all those
constraints back, so we don't
have to show it again here.
But you'll notice that that
orange arrow is now appearing
when we add those constraints.
And if we click on it to see
the debugging inspector,
you'll see that we have a new
error called Scrollable
Content Size Ambiguity for both
the height and the width.
We're getting this error,
because we need to set the
content size for our
scroll view.
Now, unfortunately, there's no
option in the Inspector panel
in Interface Builder to just
set a content size.
But we can use Auto
Layout to set it.
To do this, you'll want to find
the view in the scroll
view that is closest to
the bottom and right
of the scroll view.
In this case, our Party label
is both the closest to the
right edge and the bottom
of the screen.
Next, we'll add trailing and
bottom constraints to that
Party label.
And finally, in the editor,
we'll double click each of
those constraints and reset the
constant to be equal to 0.
Here, you can see setting the
trailing constraint constant
to 0 and the bottom constraint
constant to 0.
This is a little bit of
Auto Layout magic.
Setting those constants to 0
let's Auto Layout know to use
the minimum amount of space
needed for the content size of
the scroll view.
And here, you can see that as we
switch between portrait and
landscape, we're able to scroll
and see all of the
available content in
our layout now.
There's another great new
feature in iOS 7 that you can
activate by navigating to the
very top left of your outline
view and choosing
Preview and then
highlighting the xib file.
Now, if you hold Shift and
Option at the same time and
click on that file, you'll get
this little display inspector.
If you double tap on the right
panel, it'll actually open up
a second preview window
inside of the editor.
If you then click on the Apply
Landscape Orientation button
at the bottom right, you'll be
able to get a live preview of
both the portrait mode and the
landscape mode while you're
editing and changing
your constraints.
This is a great new feature,
because it means that you
don't always have to keep
re-running the app in the
simulator and flipping the
orientation manually in order
to see the changes that you're
making to your Auto Layout
constraints.
Now, it's time for you to work
with Auto Layout and scroll
views in the challenges.
Good luck.