[SINGING] With a viewbox or port,
you have nothing to lose.
Draw yourself in any shape
or vector you choose.
From circles to rects,
polygons to ellipses.
Groups will connect,
then transform and
rotate these.
Soon you'll see
where you can be,
creating scalable
graphics with glee.
Just You, Me & SGV!
Welcome back.
This is level two
in You, Me, and SGV.
In this section,
we'll be covering
a new element, circles.
In the last level, we
created our X59 retina screen
in icon form.
So for the Schmuffle's
sake, let's
go ahead and build the Schmuffle
phone in icon form two.
We'll start off by including
the phone in an image tag.
Say image, source, phone,
underscore, icon.svg.
We'll then open that file,
and inside our SVG tag
that has all of
those pre things,
of the XML namespace and the
version number, all of those
are already in there.
Inside that, we'll
create a rect tag.
We'll give our rectangle
a height of 100
and a width of 70.
We'll also give it a fill of
white and a stroke of red.
The red color is in
hexadecimal form,
whereas white is
using the keyword.
Both are accepted
inside these SVG tags.
When we pull up
our browser, you'll
see that our white
rectangle does in fact,
now have a red stroke.
It's kind of thin though.
We can adjust this by
saying stroke-width,
and give it a larger one, so 10.
Now, when we refresh,
it's thicker.
But something is happening on
our top and left of our icon,
something weird.
What's happening here?
Well, first, I'm going to draw
a blue line around our viewport
so we can visualize it.
I'll put a dot at
0,0, the top left.
If we zoom in, we'll
see that our viewport
outline is centered along
the rectangle stroke.
And half of it is being
cut off, it's not seen.
This is easily adjusted by
just moving our icon away
from the viewport's edge.
We can give our rect an x
of five and a y of five.
And when we reload
it in the browser,
you'll see that our full 10
pixel stroke is surrounding
the white rectangle now.
So what do we have left?
Well, we need to
go ahead and round
those corners on the
rectangle and add
the circle in the bottom.
We'll start off by
drawing the circle.
Conveniently enough, this
is with a circle tag.
So below the rect,
we'll say circle.
And we need to give it a
center point for its x and y.
So we'll say cx
of 40, cy of 105.
So it's at the bottom and
middle of our phone icon.
We also need to
give it a radius.
So r of three, so the circle
knows how large to be.
If we look in the browser, we'll
see that we have our circle.
It's the right size, and
it's in the right position,
but it's the wrong color.
We can change that,
simply, with a fill
of white inside the circle tag.
Now all we need are the rounded
corners for our phone icon
to be complete.
Before we can create
those rounded corners,
though, we need to
know about ellipses.
We can create an ellipse
with an ellipse tag.
We give it the same cx and
cy for the center points,
like we did with the circle.
However, unlike a
circle, an ellipse
has two different radiuses.
It's not perfectly round.
You specify those with rx
10, we'll say, and ry of 25.
That would create an
ellipse like this one.
Now to use the ellipse
knowledge to round
the corners of our rectangle.
Inside the rect tab, we'll
use the rx and ry attributes
to create an invisible
ellipse that will
be used round the corners.
We can use that same
rx of 10, ry of 25,
and you'll see that we
get a rectangle that's got
slightly wonky rounded edges.
For our example, we want
evenly rounded edges.
So if we use an rx
of 5 and an ry 5
to create the ellipse shape,
or, in this case, a circle,
we'll get these
rounded edges that we
want to create our icon.
Because the rx and ry that
we're using are the same,
we can simply say
rx of 5, and it will
use that same value for ry.
Yay!
Congratulations!
We've made the
Schmuffle phone icon.
So far, we've used the
image tag to include any SVG
that we wanted on our site.
With this image tag, you're
able to rotate, scale, animate,
on an offscreen,
the SVG as a whole.
However, if you wanted to go
ahead and animate a part of it,
like the icon button,
for instance, and only
the icon button, you
wouldn't be able to do this.
You have no way to select the
inner elements of the SVG.
What if we wanted to change the
color of the SVG background?
Again, no.
You don't have access
to this with CSS
because you're using the
image tag to include your SVG.
So how can we do some
cool things with styling
or animating to our SVGs?
There's another
more powerful way,
instead of using an image
tag, to include SVGs.
So instead of having
your image tag,
take the SVG code
from inside the file,
and put it inline your HTML.
Inline will give us access
to the inner elements
so that we can iterate on
styles, or even animate,
with CSS.
So, here, we've
selected the circle,
and we've added
a grow key frame.
If we go ahead and
check that out,
you'll see, now, that our icon
looks exactly how it did when
we were with the image tag.
But, now, the
circle is animating
or growing larger and smaller.
Don't worry, if you're not
familiar with animating in CSS,
go ahead and give
circles a spin,
and I'll see you back
in the next section.