[SINGING] With a viewbox or port
you have nothing to lose.
Draw yourself in any shape
or vector you choose.
From circles to rects,
polygons to ellipses,
groups will connect, then
transform and rotate these.
Soon you'll see
where you can be,
creating scalable
graphics with glee.
Just you, me, and SVG.
You're watching
"You, Me, and SVG."
This is level three, where
we will be covering groups.
As a little refresher,
here's where
we left off with our badge
in the index.html file.
Our badge is still looking
a little plain, however, so
how could we add some more
detail or pizzazz to our badge,
with perhaps some groups
of triangles here or there?
How could we do this?
We'd start off by
drawing and positioning
three of the triangles.
We'd give them points so
that we'd have one on top
and two on bottom.
We'd give them the fill
of the greenish blue color
and a stroke of one pixel.
If we go ahead of the polygon
is inside of our index.html
and open up our
browser, we'll see
that we do have the
group of three triangles,
but it's not a
part of the badge.
So how are we going to move
this over and down so that it's
a part of our beautiful badge.
We could add 45 pixels
to each x element and 67
to each y in order to
get all of the triangles
to move over and down and
be a part of the badge.
This is getting a bit
tedious, and there
has to be a better way though.
Well, this is where
groups come to the rescue.
We can add a g tag, or
group, around the polygons.
And by doing so, we
can now transform them.
We can move them over
and down as a whole.
We'll use a transform
attribute inside the g tag.
This will allow us to do
things like translate,
or scale and rotate, to
the group as a whole.
So inside the g tag, we'll
say transform, translate,
and we'll give it
the 45, 67, that it
needs to move for its x and y.
Remember, translate is
kind of a weird word.
So if you're ever wondering,
what was translate again?
It's just to move.
Translate to move.
We'll load the badge
back up in the browser.
And we'll see now that
the group of polygons
is inside the badge,
as we expected.
Effectively, by
grouping these polygons,
we've given them a new
0,0, a new origin point.
And then when we
transform translate,
we're moving that origin
point over by 45 and 67.
For the next group
of triangles we
can simply copy paste
that group of polygons
that we used before.
We do need to change the
translation, however.
It needs to be 198 from the
left edge, and 67 from the top.
So we'll say, transform
translate 198, 67.
If you load the badge
up, you'll see now
that we have those two
groups of triangles.
For a third one, we
do it all over again.
Copy paste that group,
and, this time, we'll
give it a translation
so that it's
at the bottom
center of the badge.
Notice that we said
121.5 for the x.
SVG coordinates
can use decimals.
A lot of these styles
are duplicated, however.
And this is something that
group takes care of yet again.
We can give each group a
class of triangle group.
Then, inside our
style sheet, we'll
call out the class
of triangle group
and give each of these polygons
a stroke width of one pixel.
Remember before, when we
gave the blueish-green fill
to all polygons?
We actually don't
have to say that again
inside the triangle group.
They'll still
inherit that style.
Groups have allowed us to
translate, or to move, elements
as a whole on the page.
And they've also allowed
us to clean up our styles.
Groups are the best.
Why don't you go give them
a try in the challenges,
and I'll see you back
in the next section.