[SINGING] With a viewbox
or port you have nothing to lose.
Draw yourself in any shape
or vector you choose.
From circles to rects,
polygons to ellipses,
groups will connect,
then transform and rotate these.
Soon you'll see where
you can be, creating
scalable graphics with glee.
Just you, me, and SVG.
You're watching You, Me, & SVG.
This is Level 4, Section 1.
In this section we'll
be covering paths.
So far we've been writing the
points to any of our elements
in our SVG out by hand.
But in real life
you're not going
to be coming up with these
coordinates by yourself.
You're going to be
using a program that
will export them out for you.
So for example, in this
Mac app called Sketch,
we went ahead and
drew a check asset.
If we wanted to export
this asset as an SVG,
we'd select it, go down
to the bottom right,
and hit the Export
button, SVG, and then we
would save it as check.SVG.
If we wanted to look
under the covers,
however, inside this SVG
file we would see some things
that we're familiar with like
the SVG or the group tag,
but also some things that are
a little weird like this really
long and scary path.
What's going on here?
Paths are very powerful
for creating complex SVGs.
However, they're better suited
for creation by software
than by humans.
So we'll show you the basics
on what paths are doing.
Don't worry about memorizing
it or needing to be
able to do it by hand, however.
This is just so that
you can go grok SVG
code when you see it or you're
handed it by other developers.
What would a triangle--
that polygon element
that we used in our badge--
look like as a path?
Well, here's the polygon
with the points as we drew it
and a path of this polygon
would look like this.
The M specifies, this
is the start of my path.
The L is where the points are
specified that the path will
connect to create a shape.
And the Z is to signify
the end of the path.
As you'll see, both polygons
look exactly the same.
Using a path is just a
different way to draw it.
M, L, and Z are
all path commands
used to draw straight lines.
You can draw not straight,
like curvy lines for instance,
with things like C. C denotes
that we're using a cubic Bézier
curve in our path.
So as you can see here, we
still have in M, the move to,
but we have a C now
that's going to give
the x and y of the
first handle, the x
and y of the second
handle, and the x
and y of the second point.
Anthony Dugois built an app
that's called SVG Path Builder.
This app allows you to
play around with paths
so as you move the paths, you
can see the coordinates change.
It's really great to
wrap your head around all
of these different
coordinates and how they
change when your path changes.
So definitely check it
out if you're interested.
Similarly, the cubic Bézier, we
can create a quadratic Bézier
using Q in the path.
We're not going to get into
the nitty gritty of it.
But this is what a Q
path would look like.
There's also an
elliptical arc curve.
This one has a leading A. This
is by far the most complicated
path of them all.
Don't worry, as we said before.
You don't need to memorize
how to draw these paths out
by hand.
You just need to be able to
grok them for the future.
Paths, just like any
other SVG element,
can be styled or animated.
You can add styles like fill,
stroke, stroke-width, inline
or put them in a style sheet
and call that path element out.
There's some other attributes
besides stroke and stroke-width
that apply to a path.
You have stroke-linecap,--
which is the shape of the end
of the line--
stroke-dasharray,--
which is the length of
dashes-- and stroke-dashoffset,
which would be the space between
or how far offset the dashes
are.
Why don't you have fun
practicing with paths
and understanding them
a little bit more.
And I'll see you back in the
final section for You, Me,
and SVG.
.