You're watching You, Me and SVG.
This is level four,
section two, and we'll
be talking about symbols.
So far we've been creating
icons and assets in isolation.
But most of the
time you're going
to include them on a web page
with a bunch of other HTML
elements going on.
Here you can see we're
using this phone icon twice.
One time up in the header,
and the second time
below the paragraph.
This is what it would
look like inside the HTML.
You've got your body tag,
you've got your SVG up
at the top, the header,
and then a paragraph,
and your second SVG.
If you need to use icons or
elements in multiple places,
there is something
magical called symbol.
Symbol is what people
use, very commonly,
to wrap around icons, and
reuse them over and over again.
To define a symbol that we can
use multiple times on a page,
the first step is to
make the symbol tag.
We give it an ID of phone,
and inside the symbol tag
is all of the code that's used
to draw that phone, or icon.
Since we're just defining
an icon for later use,
we don't actually want
to see it up here.
So inside our style
sheet, we'll call out
the defined-icon, which
is a class on our SVG,
and we'll give it
a display of none.
Throughout the course,
we refactored our styles
from inline into
the style sheet.
So the same with
this phone icon.
The styles are coming from
inside our style sheet.
So now.
to use the symbol
that we defined above,
we'll create a new SVG.
We'll give it things like
the name space and version
that it needs.
And then we'll also
give it a viewbox.
This viewbox goes on the
second SVG, the SVG that's
actually displaying the icon.
Inside this SVG, we'll use
something called the use tag.
The use tag takes an
xlink href attribute.
That attribute points to
whatever icon or element
needs to be pulled in.
So in this case, it's
pointing to the ID of phone.
This is really important.
You can't point to a class,
you have to point to an ID.
Just like we gave the
browser a heads up that hey,
we need to use a
different type of XML,
when we use the XML namespace.
Now we need to give it
a heads up that we're
going to use an xlink.
So on the SVG that
has the used tag,
we're going to say
xmlns colon xlink,
and give it a link
to those docs.
The use tags xlink points
to a named anchor--
the ID of phone, in our case.
This can also be an outside
source, like a file.
However, IE 10 and below don't
support that just a heads up.
As we did in the last
level, let's go ahead
and give this phone icon, that
were reusing multiple times,
a responsive width and height.
We've already given the
viewbox the static 80 by 110.
Now inside the stylesheet, we'll
call out the displayed icon,
and give it a height of
auto and a width of 30%.
So in real life, if we opened
up the site inside our editor,
we would see an index that
has all of these elements.
With the SVG defined at
the top, and then below,
we're using the
element multiple times.
We also have our
styles for the top
displayed-icon, the defined-icon,
and the displayed-icon
here.
That are making the
top icon smaller
than the bottom larger icon.
You can style them
differently with use,
and it cleans up your
code quite a bit.
Now for my personal favorite
part, accessibility.
SVG has two elements that make
accessibility possible, title
and description.
So inside our SVG, we can give
it a title of schmuffle phone
icon.
We can also give a
description like,
a phone with a large red
border with rounded corners,
so on and so forth.
Now to most people,
these two tags
don't really mean that much.
But to a blind person, now
when they're on your site,
they can see or imagine
in their head based
on the description and
the title that you just
provided for your asset.
Let's go ahead and
look and listen in
on what a screen reader would
do for our small example site.
SVG symbols, Schmuffle
Phone, Schmuffle Phone Specs.
Easy to use yet
schmuffle phone icon.
A phone with a large red
border with rounded corners.
A white screen, and
a white round button
centered below the screen.
It has been so much fun doing
this SVG course with you.
I hope you rock those
last few challenges,
where you go over
symbol, and also
a little bit of accessibility.
For the future, and beyond.
Gregg!
Pav-- Out of the room.
Styled or animated.