Welcome to level three, section
three, in You, Me, & SVG!
In this section,
we'll be covering
how to responsibly create
icons or assets in SVG.
I'll have to admit, the
assets and icons that we've
created thus far are
looking really good,
no matter what screen
size they're on.
However, they're
still not responsive
based on the screen size.
And what do I mean by this?
Well, take our
badge for example.
If we go and load
it in the browser
and change the browser's width,
the badge stays the same.
It doesn't change.
Wouldn't it be great if our
SVG's width was a percentage,
and it changed as the
browser's width changed.
In order to create responsive
icons or assets in SVG,
we need to revisit
our coordinate system.
Back in level one, when
we first created SVGs,
we set a height and width.
That height and width
is the viewport.
This is the base
coordinate system
that anything inside
our SVG lives within.
As we saw with groups,
it's possible to have
nested coordinate systems
inside this viewport.
Well, for our
responsive asset, we
want to create another
coordinate system, called
the viewBox.
We'll copy our viewport values,
those static 268 by 268,
and we'll put them
on the viewBox.
These two coordinate
systems are overlapping.
Their 0,0's are on
top of each other.
In our graph, they're not,
because that would be insane.
But in real life,
they're overlapping.
The second step is to give
our viewport responsive values
for the height and width.
So here, you can see that
we gave our height of auto
and our width of 50%.
Now when we resize
our screen, you'll
see that the badge is
growing or shrinking
based on the screen's width.
Now let's actually
do this in our code.
Inside the SVG, we'll
take that 268 by 268
for the height and width,
and we'll move that
into the viewBox attribute.
Now, viewBox takes
four things total,
and the second two are
the width and height
that we just set, 268 by 268.
The first two are the
origin, the x and y.
And as we said, we want
ours to match up and be 0,0.
So we'll just say 0,0.
Now all we need to do is
set those responsive values
for our viewport inside the CSS.
We'll say SVG, give it a height
of auto and a width of 50%.
And as you can see, we're
getting the responsive growing
and shrinking badge with our
screen size as it changes.
Go practice using the
new coordinate system
called viewBox to create some
responsive icons or assets,
and I'll see you back
in the final level.
[LAUGHING]
Why don't you go practice them.
I don't know.
[INAUDIBLE]
Level three.
[LAUGHING]
Just read the slide, ma'am.
OK.