Welcome back.
This is You, Me, and SVG,
level three, section two.
In this section we're talking
about transforms a little bit
more.
In the last section
we used transform
to translate or to move
things around on the page.
But as we mentioned, you can
also rotate or scale things
with the transform attribute.
Let's see if we can
modify our badge
by rotating the top
two triangle groups
and scaling the bottom one.
To rotate this top
left group of polygons,
we'll use transform's
rotate property.
Right next to translate,
we'll say rotate.
And rotate takes three values.
The first is the
degrees to rotate.
And the second are the x
and y to rotate around.
If you just specify the
first value of the degrees
the x and y will
default to 0,0.
However, in our example, we want
to rotate around the center,
so 12.5 12.5.
As you would imagine,
rotating the second group
is just as easy.
We'll say rotate, but
instead of 10 we'll
say negative 10 degrees.
We'll also give it the center
x and y to rotate around.
Static rotations like
this will use numbers
between 360 and negative 360.
For our last group, in
order to shrink it down,
make it smaller, we're going to
use transforms scale property.
Next to translate
will say scale,
and scale takes one value.
And this is a modifier
that your scaling with.
So if I said scale 1, nothing
would change about the group.
They would stay
exactly the same.
If I say scale 2, they
would be twice the size.
So on and so forth.
So in order to get the
desired effect of a smaller
bottom group, we're
going to say scale 0.6.
When we load it up now you'll
see that it is scaling,
however it looks a bit
off center, just a smidge.
This is because the group
is scaling from 0,0.
If you remember, with
most things, not text,
but with most things,
that 0,0 is the top left.
So when the triangle group
scales from the top left
it probably looks
like it's moving over
to the left a little bit.
The only way that
you can adjust this
is by chaining on
another translation.
For this example, we need to go
ahead and translate it 8 by 8.
For other examples
based on your scaling
those numbers will be different.
Our triangle groups are
now rotating and scaling
as expected, and
we're looking good.
You've learned not
only how to translate,
but how to rotate and
scale with transform.
Go practice that
in the challenges
and I'll see you back for
this levels last section.