[SINGING] With a viewbox or port,
you have nothing to lose.
Draw yourself in any shape
or vector you choose.
From circles to rects,
polygons to ellipses.
Groups will connect,
then transform and rotate these.
Soon you'll see
where you can be.
Creating scalable
graphics with glee.
Just You, Me & SVG!
Welcome, my name is
Alyssa Nicholl
and you're watching
You, Me and SVG!
In this course, we're going to
cover some things like--what
are SVGs?
When should you use an
SVG over a raster image?
How do you build SVGs?
And how to use SVG
elements together
to create things like
icons or other images?
Prereqs for this course do
include a working knowledge
of HTML and CSS.
Welcome to level one.
In this level, we'll be building
our first SVG image together.
As you can tell by
the name of our course
we're in a Seussical land
called Schmuffle Land
and the Schmuffles are super
excited to release their all
new X59 Retina Screen.
This screen has an insane
resolution of 90,000 pixels
by 60,000 pixels.
However, when you
pull up the old icon
that the Schmuffles
are used to using,
you can see that they're
super blurry when you zoom in.
It's kind of gross.
It's probably
blurry because it's
a raster image,
dot JPEG or J-P-G.
Raster images don't work
for every screen size.
So in order to future
proof your assets,
you need to use SVG--that's
scalable vector graphics.
Scalable vector
graphics will work
on things like the old Schmuffle
phone, the new X59 Retina
Screen, and anything else
our Schmuffles can dream of.
How do we build SVGs though?
Well our first step is to
get it in the application
or showing up on screen somehow.
A common way that people do this
is by including it just like
any other file type--inside
of an image tag.
Here you can see
we have an image
tag inside our
index.html, and we're
using source with our
first dot SVG inside it.
How do we create
this SVG though?
Well open up our first dot
SVG, get into that file,
and we can start by
using the SVG tag.
This should look
super similar to HTML
tags that you have
used in the past.
This is because they
both come from XML.
They're both types of XML.
Next up we'll set the height
and width on the SVG tag.
We'll give it a height of
300 and a width of 400.
This is actually setting the
viewport, the canvas or window
that our SVG asset's
going to sit inside of.
Now we need to let
the browser know
that we're going to use
something else other than HTML.
We're going to use SVG.
So we give it an XML name-space
attribute--XMLNS and then give
it this HTTP, W3 line.
We also need to specify the
version that we're using.
We're going to use the
latest which is 1.1.
These lines are kind
of long and scary.
You don't need to memorize them.
Just know that we're letting
the browser know, hey,
inside these SVG tags we're
going to draw some SVG.
If we open up the SVG file
in our chrome browser,
you'll see that we have
absolutely nothing there.
Woo, but this isn't quite true.
In Chrome you have the option
to right click with your mouse,
scroll down to Inspect
Element, and this will bring up
the Chrome Dev Tools.
Lots of browsers have them.
You might have to get to
them in a different way.
Once we're in the Dev
Tools, you can see there
that we have an SVG element.
That's the tag that
we just created.
When we hover over
it, Chrome Dev Tool
shows you the height and
width of the element.
Even though, there's no color
or any elements inside of it,
you can still see how much space
that invisible element takes
up.
Now we're actually
ready to draw something.
So let's build our
X59 Retina Screen.
It's a little complex though.
Let's start off with a
simpler icon version of it.
Inside our SVG tag now, we'll
go ahead and use a rect element
that stands for rectangle.
Kind of semantic, woo.
We'll give it a height
of 80 and a width of 100.
If you go ahead and pull up
our Chrome browser again,
you'll see that we do, in fact,
have a black rectangle that's
80 by 100.
For the second step
of our X59 icon,
we'll need to create
another rectangle.
However, this one needs to
have a white background.
So below our first one we'll
say rect, height of 50,
and width of 80, and we'll
give it a fill of white.
If we open our
browser, we'll see
that we do, in fact, have
our white rectangle sitting
on top of our black rectangle.
How do we move it over though?
It's on the top left corner.
We want it to be centered
inside of the black rectangle.
Before we move it,
we need to understand
why this is happening.
This is because we're inside
our viewport coordinate system.
This is the default
coordinate system
that we created with
the height and width.
Right now both rectangles
are drawn at 0,0.
That's the top left.
There's also the top right,
400,0, bottom left 0,300,
and bottom right 400,300.
This is the coordinate
system that all our elements
are going to work within.
So in order to move that
white rectangle over,
we need to simply specify
a different x and y.
We'll give it an x
of 10 and a y of 10.
If you refresh the
browser, now you
can see that the white
rectangle's anchor point
is at 10,10, instead of 0,0
like the black rectangles.
We did it.
We're going to create one
last rectangle to finish off
our icon.
Below this one we'll say rect
and give it a height of 10
and a width of 40.
An x of 30 and a y of 90.
When you load the icon now
you'll see that we did it.
We have this simplified version
of our X59 Retina Screen.
There's one last
bit of clean up that
needs to be done before
we can ship this icon off
into the world.
We should really
modify our viewport
to be the exact height
and width of the icon.
So in the SVG we'll change
it to height, 100, width,100.
And when you hover over the
SVG element inside Dev Tools,
like we did earlier, you'll see
now that our SVG is 100 by 100.
Snugging up to the
exact size of the icon.
Great job!
Go have fun practicing
building your first SVG
using some rect
elements, and I'll
see you back in the next level.
So in order to future proof.
Get rect!