Welcome back to the
second section of level 2.
Remember that badge that
we showed back in level 1?
Well, in order to create
an asset like this in SVG,
we would need to know a few
more shapes like text, polygon,
and line in order
to build something
as fancy as this badge.
To get started, inside our
HTML, because we're not
using the image
tag anymore, we'll
go ahead and start our SVG tag.
We'll give it a height
and width of 268.
We'll also specify the version
and the XML namespace here.
Now we're ready to build
the circle element.
Inside the SVG,
we'll say circle.
We'll give it a radius,
a center x and y point.
And if you'll notice with
our badge, it has no fill.
So we'll say fill of none.
We'll give it this green
hexadecimal stroke.
And a stroke width
of seven pixels.
So far, we've only
done our styles inline,
inside the tags themselves.
However, there is another way.
With our link tag, we can
include a CSS stylesheet
and go ahead and move the
fill, stroke, and stroke width
into our CSS.
It's really important to note
that when you do styles inside
of an SVG tag, unit identifiers
like pixels, percentages, EMS,
those aren't required at all.
But when you move them into
CSS, they are required.
So as you'll see,
7 changed to 7px.
Just keep that in
mind for future use.
If you'll notice though,
our radius, cx and cy,
are all inside of our tag still.
This is because anything
that sets a coordinate
should stay inline.
Very important.
We have our circle.
So we're ready to
go ahead and build
the line that's below the
triangle in the badge.
So inside our SVG tag, below the
circle, we can use a line tag.
To draw a line, you need to
specify 2 x and y points.
One for the start
of the line and one
for the end of the line.
For our example, we'll have
an x1 of 47, y1 of 198,
an x2 of 221, and a y2 of 198.
So it's a straight line.
Inside our stylesheet,
we'll call out the line tag.
We'll give it a stroke
of black and a stroke
width of five pixels.
Now when we load it up, we
have our circle and our line.
We're getting there.
Next step though, we'll need
to add some text and a polygon
to our badge.
Next step, we'll
use the text element
to add SVG to our badge.
We'll say text,
give it an x and y
so it's centered on
our screen, and the SVG
in the middle of the opening
and closing text tags.
Inside our stylesheet, we'll
say text font-size 60 pixels.
If we load the badge
up in the browser,
you'll see that we do have
the SVG text in the badge.
However, it's not centered.
What is going on here?
Well, unlike everything
else that we've
learned so far in SVG, the
default anchor point for text
is in the bottom left.
This can simply
be adjusted though
by saying text-anchor
middle inside your CSS.
Refresh and you'll
see now that the text
is centered as expected.
Our text could use some
sprucing up, however.
So inside the stylesheet,
we'll say
font-family 'FilmotypeMajor'.
Stroke of black, stroke-width
of three pixels, and a fill
of this white cream color.
This font family isn't one
that all browsers will have
by default. So we'll probably
want to use @font-face when we
put this into production.
We have a course,
Front-end Formations,
that covers @font-face in detail.
So head on over there if
you have any questions.
If we look at our
index.html as a whole now,
you'll see that the
circle, line, and text all
have coordinate
setting attributes
that are still inline.
Again, it's so important that
I'm reiterating it twice.
Please leave any coordinate
setting attributes
inline and not in your CSS.
We're so close to being done.
We have one last shape we
need to add for our badge
to be complete, and
that's the polygon.
Inside our HTML, below
all the other elements,
we can say polygon.
And a polygon, unlike
the other elements,
takes multiple points.
So we'll say points.
And we'll give it three
different sets of points.
This is for the starting,
the top, and the endpoint
that make up the triangle.
Inside our stylesheet,
we'll go ahead and give it
a blue-green fill, a black
stroke, and a stroke-width
of two pixels.
This is what the triangle look
like with these styles applied.
When we load our entire
badge in the browser,
however, we'll see that
something not so awesome
is happening.
The triangle is smack
right on top of the text.
We can't see our
SVG text anymore.
This is because just
like HTML elements,
SVG elements stack on top
of each other in the order
that they were specified.
Super simple fix.
Put the polygon line
above the text line
so that your polygon
is drawn in first
and then your text is
drawn on top of it.
Now when we refresh,
we have the badge
that we set out to create using
not only circle, but text,
polygon, and line as well.
Go have fun practicing
all these new elements
that you just learned.
And I'll see you back
in the next level.
--work on that line.
Ugh.
Our text be ugly, though.
So let's get it some style.
Sheet will say--
Is it?
OK.
Whoops.