So in section 1, we
covered property binding
and class binding.
And then we covered
event binding.
Both of these are a
one-way binding-- one
in that direction,
one in that direction.
But how might we bind
in both directions?
Like when we have
a form field and we
want to keep it in sync
between the data we
have over in the JavaScript
and the value in the HTML?
First off, let's
add an input field
in between the
plus and the minus.
And we should be able
to adjust the quantity
either by typing
a number in here
or by pushing plus or minus.
How do we make that work?
Well given what
we know so far, we
could start by using
property binding.
So we could bind to
the value and bind
that to the carPart.quantity.
What would happen in this case?
Let's see.
So we increment using
plus and decrement.
But now, when we set the
value by typing in 10--
well it didn't remember that 10.
That's not good.
So we've only bound
in one direction.
We could then use
event binding to listen
for input on our event box.
So here we could listen
for the input event.
And when it happens,
we're just going
to write some code here in-line.
We'll set carPart.quantity
equal to $event.target.value.
Now let's see what happens.
We can change the quantity
using the input field.
And it remembers.
Sweet-- information
is flowing two ways.
But there's another
way to do this.
This is where ngModel comes in.
It allows us to have one
command to do two-way binding.
You can see this ngModel command
uses both square brackets
and parentheses to signify
that we have two-way binding.
And we just specify
the component property
that we want to bind on.
And as you can see,
it works just like it
did on the previous slide.
This syntax has a funny name.
Sometimes it's called
banana in a box.
Can you see why,
with the parentheses
and the square brackets?
It's important to know that
when we use the ngModel syntax,
we can only set it equal
to a data-bound property.
So because of that, we'll use
it mostly for form fields.
Here are two different
component properties
like user age and first name.
Those would be great.
But if we try to set
this equal to a component
method, for example,
it's going to error out.
It won't work at all.
In this level, we learned
that the ngModel syntax
allows us to specify a
component property which
will use two-way binding.
We also learned
that two-way binding
means that if the component
property is modified
inside the component
or inside our web page,
it will stay in sync.
Have some fun with
the challenges
with that banana in a box.
[BEEP BEEP]
Box, balked, bok,
[CHICKEN NOISE].
[BEEP BEEP]
--binding.
Whereas where-- whereas where?
Whereas where?
[BEEP BEEP]
Ready-- blah.
We'll do it again.
[BEEP BEEP]
I don't always like banana.
But when I do, I
put it in a box.