Welcome back-- and now it's
time to use the internet.
What could possibly go wrong?
So up until now, we've
been using mock data.
How might we reach out to the
internet for our car parts?
Well our car parts currently
asked our service for data.
So it's really
inside the service
that we want to fetch
the appropriate data
from the internet and return
that back onto our template.
Before we get into
it, it's important
that you understand how Angular
loads first in our browser
and then loads data.
So when our browser first
tries to access our website,
it sends back HTML CSS.
It loads up Angular.
And then when it's
done loading, it'll
go back and fetch API
data like car parts.
And then our server
sends back JSON,
which then loads into our page.
Let's go through the steps
needed to make this happen.
First, we need to create a
JSON file with car parts data.
We'll call it car-parts.json.
Then we'll ensure our
application includes
the libraries it needs
to do HTTP calls.
Then we'll tell our injector
about the HTTP provider.
Then we'll inject the HTTP
dependency into our service
and make the get request.
And lastly, we'll
listen for data
returned by this request
inside our car parts component.
The first step is easy.
We just brought over our mock
data into our car-parts.json
file.
But I've wrapped our
array in an object
to make it feel a little more
realistic in that data object.
So we'll have to keep that in
mind-- that to get to the data,
we need to go through
that data keyword.
Next we need to make sure we're
including the right libraries.
The HTTP library
provides the get method
we'll need to call
out to the internet.
And the RxJS library
stands for Reactive Ex
and provides an advanced
tooling for our HTTP calls.
If you use the five
minute quick start-- well
it's already including
these libraries.
You don't need to
worry about it.
Step three is we need
to register a provider
to our dependency injector.
And we'll do that
inside app component.
Well import the HTTP providers
from our Angular library.
And then inside providers,
we'll specify a second provider.
Now we'll be able to inject
the library when we need it.
Time to inject it and use it
to call out to the internet.
So first, we need to import our
HTTP library as well as a part
of the Reactive Ex library.
We just need a map in this case.
Then we'll create a
constructor so we can
inject HTTP as a dependency.
We can do this because our
service class is injectable.
If we weren't using the
injectable decorator,
then our service class couldn't
have additional dependencies.
Now inside the car parts method,
we'll write a bunch of code.
And there's a lot going on here.
So I'm going to split it
out into multiple pieces.
And we'll go through
it step by step.
First, calling the get
method and fetching our JSON
file-- you might expect
this to return a promise.
But it actually
returns an observable.
Observables give us
additional functionality
on our HTTP calls, one of
which is to treat the return
value like an array.
Which leads us to
the map method.
We call the map method.
And then we're saying
for the data returned,
do this to the response.
And we're using the fat arrow.
We call JSON on the response
to parse the string into JSON.
And the array we want, remember,
is under that data keyword.
So we call .data.
Lastly, we tell our
TypeScript compiler
to treat what gets returned
like an array of CarParts.
Back in our car
parts component file,
we need to change some code
because our service now
returns an observable object.
And we need to
subscribe to that stream
and tell our component what
to do when that data arrives.
So we'll write "subscribe."
And when our carParts
arrive, we'll
set this.carParts-- our
local carParts array-- equal
to the data that we receive.
If we called this up in our
browser, we would see nothing.
It would break.
And it would give
us this error--
cannot read property
length of undefined.
And it comes down to
this line of code.
this.carParts--
well, is undefined.
And underneath the covers,
it's trying to call that
length on it.
Hmm.
Well remember that
graph I showed you
at the beginning
of this section.
Angular loads and then
it evaluates the code.
But we haven't called
out to get our data yet.
So it's calling
this.carParts.length,
but this.carParts is
currently undefined.
So we need to make
sure that this.carParts
is an array before we
try to use this for loop.
One way to solve this problem
is to use the arrays "is array"
function to make sure
this.carParts is an array
before we try to loop over it.
Now if we jump back
into our browser,
we can see that we can now
increment and decrement
our different car parts all
loaded across the internet.
Before we move onto challenges,
I've got a few last thoughts.
First of all, we didn't put any
error handling in this code.
And if you're actually
calling across the internet
to a data API,
you're going to want
to code in error handling to
make sure you fail gracefully
when that API doesn't work.
Also, since we isolated our
network calls as a service,
we could easily write
a RacingDataServiceMock
and inject it when we're
testing or developing offline.
Lastly, observables
are really cool.
And they're worth learning about
if you do lots of HTTP calls.
So what did we learn
in this section?
Well, Angular apps
usually load data
using service classes after
the application is initialized
and running.
We can use the HTTP library
through dependency injection
to make internet calls.
And our HTTP calls return an
observable, not a promise,
which behaves more
like an array.
So why don't you get your
hands dirty in the challenges.
And I will see you
in the outro video.
[BEEP BEEP]
Still kind of sucks.
No.
So this is--
[BEEP BEEP]
Wow, if I read that,
I wouldn't understand.
[BEEP BEEP]
I'll just try to
put it in my words.
Cool.
These are your own words.
Oh--
[BEEP BEEP]
That's one way to do it.
That's hilarious.
Did you just [INAUDIBLE]?
All right, I like it.
I like it.
[BEEP BEEP]