Welcome back.
In section 2 we'll
be talking all
about component HTML and CSS.
So back inside of our
component we put HTML here,
but how might we tie
CSS into our component?
Turns out we can add a
styles array to our metadata.
So here in our HTML
template, first,
let's add some new CSS classes.
And then here you'll
see we specified styles.
Sent an array.
Notice the back tick and
then we have a couple styles.
If you load up our
web page we could see
the styles are getting applied.
Our description is smaller
and the price is bold.
If we look at the HTML
source for this code,
we'd see something
really interesting.
First of all, in
the HTML, you'll
see that a custom
attribute is getting added
by angular ngcontent-dcy-2.
And then, inside of our CSS you
would see that that same custom
attribute is getting
added to our CSS source
effectively scoping our
CSS to our template.
Kind of like properties are
scoped, it's scoping our CSS.
So technically, if I
had a description class
in one component and
a description class
in another component, they
wouldn't clash with each other
because they're getting scoped.
Mind blown, right?
Because the component
property is scoped
and also the CSS is getting
scoped all to the directive.
PWOO!
I don't know, I thought
that was pretty cool
when I was learning Angular 2.
It's time to split things
out into more files.
And if you're like me, you're
probably looking at this code
and going, what is
your HTML and CSS doing
inside of my JavaScript?
We need to split this
out into multiple files.
So let's create a
car-parts.component.html where
our HTML will live.
And our car-parts.component.css
where our CSS will live.
So back in our component
let's split out this code.
And as you can see here, we have
our car-parts.component.html
and our car-parts.component.css.
Then inside of our
car-parts component
itself, we need to tell
it about these files.
So we write
templateUrl and specify
where I can find this file.
And also we write styleUrls--
this is still an array--
and specify our CSS file.
Even though our CSS is
now in a separate file,
it still gets scoped
to this component.
So what did we learn?
Well, our CSS can be included
inside of our template just
like our HTML.
Our CSS automatically gets
scoped to our component.
PWOO!
And also, our HTML and
CSS can get split out
into their own files to
keep things more organized.
Now as you can see, this is
what our architecture currently
looks like.
And, oh, it's time for you.
Do some challenges.
We'll be back in section 3.