[SINGING] Put your pedal to
the metal and burn up the road.
Start the race and
load Angular 2 code.
A class decorator can
help you in this moment.
Tune your engine with a
template and component.
Use data binding to
drift through the turns.
With import and export
separate your concerns.
Inject your service
with your racing crew
while Accelerating
Through Angular 2.
You're watching Accelerating
Through Angular2.
I'm Gregg Pollack, and
this is level 5,
where we'll be talking
about services and HTTP.
Let's take a second look at how
we're importing our mock data.
Now, we're loading our CarParts
by importing our mock file,
but this actually isn't the best
solution for working with data.
This isn't the best
because we need
to import mocks in every
file that needs this data.
And if the way we access
this data changes,
we'd have to change
it everywhere.
Also, it's not easy to switch
between real and mock data.
And this sort of data
loading is actually
best left to service classes.
Services are used to organize
and share code across our app,
and they're usually where we
create our data access methods.
So in car parts
component, we're going
to ask our service for data.
We'll create a service called
racing data service dot ts.
And that file will be
in charge of fetching
the appropriate data,
which in this case,
will come from our mocks file.
Let's start out by creating
the simplest service,
and then we'll learn
something called
dependency injection that'll
make it even more powerful.
So here's our new
racing data service.
Inside there, we will import
our CarParts from our mocks,
we'll create the class
racing data service,
and inside of it,
it'll have one method
called getCarParts that'll
simply return the CarParts.
Then to use this
service, we'll import it.
And inside our ngOnInIt,
we'll create a new variable
called racing data service that
has a new instance of racing
data service.
And we'll set this dot car
parts equal to the return
value of getCarParts.
So this is great.
We've decoupled our data layer.
But there's still
some stuff that sucks
about this implementation.
Classes using this
service must know
how to create a
racing data service,
and if that ever changes, we
have to change it everywhere.
And we'll be creating a
new racing data service
every time we need to
fetch CarParts, which you know,
is going to use up more memory.
And it'll be harder to
switch between a mock service
and a real one later on.
This is where dependency
injection comes in.
When you run an
Angular 2 application,
it creates a
dependency injector.
An injector is in
charge of knowing
how to create and send things.
So here's an example
of how it works.
If the CarParts components
needs that racing data service,
it's going to ask the
dependency injector, hey,
could I have
RacingDataService?
The dependency injector
might say, oh yeah,
I know how to do that.
So it goes and creates a
new RacingDataService
and delivers that to CarParts.
The injector knows
how to inject,
which means create and
send our dependencies,
or the classes
that we depend on.
One benefit of this is that
if the injector already
created a service, you can have
it resend the same service.
So let's say we have
a car cart component.
And it also wants the
RacingDataService.
It could ask the
dependency injector.
And the injector knows
hey, I already created one,
here it is.
But how does the
dependency injector
know what it can inject?
Well, we have to tell it by
registering providers with it.
So here, our
dependency injector has
three things it
can provide that it
knows how to create and send.
In order to make this work
with our RacingDataService,
there's three steps
we need to follow.
First, we need to add
the injectable decorator
to RacingDataService.
Then, we need to let our
injector know about the service
by naming it as a provider.
And then third, inject the
dependency into our car parts
component.
Step one.
We need to turn our
service into something
that can be safely used by
our dependency injector.
We do this by first importing
the injectable decorator
from Angular.
And then we simply
use it at injectable.
And don't forget
the parentheses.
Next, we let our injector
know about the service.
And we want all of
our subcomponents
to have access to
RacingDataService.
So we'll register it as a
provider at the top level.
Specifically, an app component.
So here in app
component, we're going
to import RacingDataService.
And then we'll specify
it as a provider
using the provider's metadata.
Notice it's an array, so you
could have multiple providers.
Now, subcomponents can ask
for or inject the RacingData
Service when they need it.
And an instance of
RacingDataService
will either be
delivered if it exists.
Otherwise, it'll be
created and then delivered.
Next we need to
inject the dependency.
So in our car parts
component, we'll
import RacingDataService.
And then, we're going
to declare a constructor
for this component.
It's going to have a private
RacingDataService of type
RacingDataService.
That private keyword
will cause TypeScript
to automatically define a
component property based
on that parameter.
So under the hood, the
generated JavaScript
looks something like this where
it declares this dot racing
service equals racing service.
Setting the parameter
type is what
identifies that the
RacingDataService is what will be
injected into this component.
Last thing I want
to mention that we
don't need to add
RacingDataService as a provider
because it's a subcomponent.
Now we just need
to use the service.
So back inside
our ngOnInIt, we
can set this dot
carParts equal to
this dot racing service
dot get car parts.
Now our app is more
scalable and testable.
It's scalable because
our dependencies aren't
strongly tied to our classes.
And it's testable because it
would be easy to mock services
out when we want to
test the component.
Now if we jump back into
our app, still works.
But this time, it's
using a service.
And our code feels cleaner.
So what did we learn
in this level?
We learned that services are
used to organize and share code
across our app.
They're usually where we
create our data access methods.
We use dependency injection
to create and send services
to classes that need them.
We give our dependency
injector providers
so it knows what classes it
can create and send to us.
And we ask for dependencies
by specifying them
in our class constructor.
Dependency injection is not
an easy concept to grasp,
but hopefully this gives you
a small basis to start from.
And maybe practice
in the challenges.
I'll see you in
the next section.