Welcome back.
This is section 3
where we'll be creating
a model and a mocks file.
We're coding in TypeScript
and TypeScript gives us
the ability to be more object
oriented with our data.
So let's create a model for
our data, which will basically
be a class.
We'll create car-parts.ts, and
inside of it we'll export class
CarPart, and specify each of our
properties and what type they
are.
This is TypeScript and it
will allow our compiler
to ensure that we are using
the data properly, using
the right names for the
properties when we're setting
and getting the values.
So how do we use this new model?
Well, let's dive back into
our carParts component.
Inside here we need to
import our new model
and then we'll use a
TypeScript code to tell it
that this array of
objects, it should treat
like an array of carParts.
So now when we go to transpile
our TypeScript into JavaScript,
if we accidentally wrote
carPart.title instead
of carPart.name, our compiler
would throw an error.
It would say, hey, there's
no title in carPart.
Nothing else needs to
change in our code.
Even in our template we're
accessing the values,
just like we're supposed to be.
And in our browser
everything works.
Eventually, we want to call
out to a web service or API
to get this carPart data
and we have all this mock data
inside of our component.
We need to move this out
and create a mocks.ts file.
Inside this mocks.ts
file, we need
to import our carPart
model and we'll
create a constant of
all capital CARPARTS.
Notice, we're using
const instead of let.
This is an ES2015 feature
which doesn't allow
CARPARTS to be reassigned.
We're exporting
this constant, which
means we need to import it
into our carParts component,
like you see here.
Next, we need to initialize
our carParts array inside
of our carParts component.
And you might think
the best place
to do this would be
inside a constructor,
but this is better off
inside our ngOnInit method.
The ngOnInit method is
invoked after the component is
constructed, and
is the best place
to initialize property values.
It also makes this
easier to test.
And their application
still works.
We didn't add any
new functionality,
but our code now is a lot
easier to maintain and scale.
Let's take a look back
through our architecture
and see how our files are
being included and used.
Our index loads
our main.ts file,
which imports and bootstraps
our first component, which
is app.component.
This loads our header
and our subcomponent,
car-parts.component.ts.
If we dive into
that file, we'll see
that our carPart model
is getting imported
and our carPart mocks
are getting imported.
Lastly, it's including
our HTML and CSS files.
So what we'd learn
in this level?
Well, TypeScript can use
classes to model our data.
TypeScript also helps us
specify class property types,
which help our compiler ensure
that we're writing good code.
Lastly, it's a good practice
to keep your mock data
separate from your model
and your components,
in its own file.
Why don't you go into
the challenges and I'll
see you in the next level.
Now we've sare-- sareprecated?
Different parts of
our application.
I don't like this take.
It's awful.
That's how that works.
Three separate files --