Welcome back-- in
the last section,
we talked about property
binding and class binding that
are binding in this
direction, from the JavaScript
to the HTML.
In this level, we'll be
talking about event binding.
That's where we're listening
for events-- like a mouse click
or hover or key
press-- and we're
sending that event from the
HTML into our JavaScript
to do something about it.
Let's look at where we should
be at the end of this section.
We want to be able to
increment the quantity
of any particular
CarPart with the plus,
and we want to
decrement it as well.
How could we do this?
First we need to add a quantity
property to our CarPart.
So we'll add it to the model.
And then we'll go into our
mocks and start our quantities
all at zero.
Now in our CarParts
component, let's start out
by defining the method
we want to call.
And we'll do the simplest thing.
If the upQuantity
method is called,
let's simply show an
alert so we know it works.
Then in order to capture
an event from our template,
we need to wrap the
name of the event we
want to listen to in
parentheses and then specify
the method we want to call.
So in the code,
we write "click,"
surround that by
parentheses, and then set
that equal to the method we
want to call-- in this case,
upQuantity.
Using parentheses like
this around an event
is a special Angular syntax.
Now if we go into the web
page, we press the plus button.
And we can see that
an alert pops up.
Now let's use that
carPart.quantity we
have on each CarPart.
First, inside of our
CarPartsComponent template,
we will print out
carPart.quantity to the screen
so we can keep
track of the value.
We also need to send
in the current car part
into our method so
we know which one
to increment the quantity on.
And then inside our
upQuantity method,
we'll receive that CarPart
and increment the quantity.
Now on our page, we can
increment the quantity.
But uh-oh-- looks like we
can increase the quantity
beyond what we have in stock.
That's probably not good.
So let's get back
into our method
and see if we can fix that.
All we need to do here
is add a conditional.
If carPart.quantity is less
than what we have in stock,
only then increment
the quantity.
Now if we jump back
into our browser,
we can see that we can
increment only up to the number
that we have in stock.
Nice.
If we even go down
to zero-- well
we can increment
padded seats at all
because we don't
have any in stock.
Which is the behavior we want.
Now let's add our
decrease button which
is pretty self-explanatory.
Well listen for the click event.
And if we hear it, call
the down quantity method.
Then inside of our
CarPartsComponent,
we will receive that carPart.
And if the
carPart.quantity is not
equal to zero-- because we
don't want negative numbers--
we'll decrease the
carPart.quantity.
So now we can see that we
can increment and decrement
the carPart.quantity.
Any standard DOM
event can be listened
for by wrapping
it in parentheses
and removing the "on" at
the beginning of the word
like you see here.
Sometimes, though, you may need
additional event information
like what key is pressed or
when the mouse is on the screen.
And this is what the
Angular event object is for.
So here you can see we
have a key down event.
And we're sending $event--
that's the Angular event
object-- into the method.
We receive that in
the show key method,
and then we're just alerting
the key code to the screen.
And then for the
mouseover event,
we might want to send
that into a method
if we wanted to have access to
where exactly the mouse was
on the screen for the
x and y-coordinate.
Lastly, it's worth
mentioning that we could also
call event.preventDefault
to prevent
a clicked link
from being followed
or a form from being submitted.
So what did we learn
in this section?
We learned that we can use event
binding to listen to any DOM
event and call a component
method when it gets triggered.
We learned that to
listen to any event,
we remove the "on"
in front of the word,
wrap it in parentheses,
and specify a component
method we want to call.
Also, if we need to
access the event object,
we can pass it into our
component method with $event.
Why don't you give it a
try in the challenges?
And I'll see you in
the next section.