[SINGING] Put your pedal to
the metal and burn up the road.
Start the race and
load Angular 2 code.
A class decorator can
help you in this moment.
Tune your engine with a
template and component.
Use data binding to
drift through the turns.
With import and export
separate your concerns.
Inject your service
with your racing crew
while Accelerating
Through Angular 2.
You're watching Accelerating
Through Angular.
I'm Gregg Pollack, and this
is level 4, where we will
be learning about data binding.
And in the first section,
property and class binding.
In the first few levels, we've
worked with really simple HTML
and CSS.
But we just received a
template from our designer
which has pure HTML
and CSS that we
can integrate into our
design so it looks nice.
It's going to look
something like this.
So we need to bring in this
HTML and CSS to our app.
OK, let's do that.
We'll take the styles and
we'll put them in two places.
First, we'll put the base
styles in a style.css file,
which is in a new CSS
directory we've created.
And the rest that are
specific to car parts
will be put in the car
parts component.css file.
The HTML, on the other hand,
goes in three different places.
It will go in the index.html,
for the base HTML,
then in the app
component for our header,
and then finally the
rest in our car parts
component for our
car parts list.
So here's what our
app now looks like.
But wouldn't it be nice
to have images in there?
Well, let's work towards
getting the images in there.
But first, we need to talk
about the different ways
that data can flow
in an Angular app.
First, it can flow from
our JavaScript code
or our component into our
HTML, or our template,
like we've been doing with
properties and components.
It can also flow from
HTML back to JavaScript,
like click events or
hover or key presses.
Or it can go both ways,
like with a text box,
which needs to stay in
sync between the HTML
and the JavaScript.
And I'm saying JavaScript here
because our TypeScript compiles
into JavaScript.
In our application
thus far, we've
been sending lots of
data from our component
to our template
using interpolation,
as you can see here.
And this is the same code.
But remember, we integrated
that design from our designer
so it looks a little different.
Take a look.
Now, how would we add an image
tag with a dynamic image?
First things first, we'll add
an image property to our model.
Then, inside of our mocks,
we'll add image data.
And our designer
happened to send over
some images for
each of our parts.
We'll stash those inside
a new images folder.
To add the image or template,
we can use interpolation,
like you see here.
And this would work just fine.
However, there is an
alternative syntax
we can use when we want to set
DOM element property values.
This is property binding.
Property binding allows us
to glue component properties
to DOM element properties.
And check it out.
All we have to do here is
add those square brackets.
No curly braces needed.
Source equals car part image.
The square brackets tell
Angular to set this DOM element
property to our
component property.
And if the component
property changes,
go ahead and update this.
And if we check in our
browser, we can see,
sweet, now we have images.
We can use this
technique to bind
to any DOM element property.
So how might you
think we bind these?
All we need to do to these
is add brackets and specify
a component property.
So if the user isn't an admin,
maybe we want to hide a div,
we might want to
disable the button,
or set the appropriate image
description as the alt text.
Next, we have another
piece of functionality
we want to add to our page.
Our designer gave
us a featured class
that we can add
to our list items.
And we'll give it that nice,
lighter gradient border.
So how would we add that
functionality to sometimes add
that featured class?
First, let's add the ability for
our car parts to be featured.
We'll add it as a
property to our model.
Then inside of our mocks,
we'll set some data.
So right now,
product 2 is featured
and the others are not.
Next, we need to conditionally
add a class if that property is
true or false.
We do this using class
property binding.
We specify class.featured
equals carPart.featured.
The behavior here is if
carPart.featured is true,
then the class is added.
And if it's false, then
the class is removed.
And now in our
browser, we can see
that carPart number 2 has
that class and is highlighted.
And if we look at
the source, we can
see that the element and the
class are properly scoped.
You might be tempted to bind
directly to the class element
property and you
can do that, but it
will overwrite all classes
when that value changes.
So remember, you just do class
dot and the name of the class
you want to add or remove.
And that's how it works.
And it's worth mentioning
that class names with dashes
also work fine.
So what did we learn
in this section?
Well, property binding allows
us to bind component properties
to DOM element properties.
Any update to the
component property value
will update the DOM
property, but not vice versa.
That's why it's called
one-way binding.
And class binding
allows us to specify
a CSS class to add
to a DOM element
if a component property is true.
Why don't you try some property
and class binding and I'll
see you in the next section.