[SINGING] Put your pedal to
the metal and burn up the road.
Start the race and load
Angular 2 code.
A class decorator can
help you in this moment.
Tune your engine with the
template and component.
Use data binding to
drift through the turns.
With import and export
separate your concerns.
Inject a service with your
racing crew while Accelerating
Through Angular 2.
You're watching Accelerating
Welcome back.
In this level, we'll
start out by talking
about structural directives.
A directive within Angular is
how we add dynamic behavior
to our HTML.
And you already know one.
A component is a kind of
directive with a template.
In this section,
we'll be learning
about structural directives.
And we'll define them in a bit.
There's also
attribute directives,
which we won't be
covering in this course.
Let's jump back into
our code and think
about what would happen if we
had more than one car part.
How would we print
that into the template?
First, we're going to
change our single car
part into an array
of car part objects.
Sweet.
Now, how would we loop through
each of these in the template?
In the template, we're going
to create an unordered list.
And inside of our
list item, we'll
specify ngFor let
carPart of carParts.
Let's step through this.
ngFor is a structural directive.
And as you might
imagine, it gives us
for syntax functionality.
carPart is a local
variable, and carParts
is the array we want
to loop through.
The loop, as you might
imagine, is run three times,
one for each carPart.
And here is the
result in our browser.
A structural
directive, like ngFor,
alters our layout
by adding, removing,
or replacing HTML elements.
Jumping back over
to our code, we
want to add some
additional functionality.
When there are zero carParts
for a particular carPart,
instead of displaying
zero in stock,
we want to display out of stock.
We can do this using another
structural directive called
ngIf.
It allows us to
evaluate conditionals.
So we'll code out ngIf
carPart.inStock greater than zero.
And we'll add a new
paragraph that has ngIf car
Part.instock equal to zero.
And if either of these
conditionals is true,
the paragraph will get
displayed on the page.
Otherwise, it won't.
And if we look at our
browser, everything still
works as it should.
I want you to code
some ngFors and ngIfs.
But before you do,
what did we learn?
We learned a
directive in Angular
is how we add dynamic
behavior to HTML.
We learned that a component
directive has a template.
And we learned that a structural
directive alters layout
by adding, removing, or
replacing HTML elements.
And we learned two of
those, ngFor and ngIf,
which you should go
code in the challenges.