[SINGING] Put your pedal to
the metal and burn up the road.
Start the race and load
angular 2 code.
A class decorator can
help you in this moment.
Tune your engine with the
template and component.
Use data binding to
drift through the turns.
With import and export
separate your concerns.
Inject your service
with your racing crew
while Accelerating
through Angular 2.
You're watching Accelerating
Through Angular 2.
I am Gregg Pollack.
And in this section, we'll
be splitting out our code
into multiple files to
get things more organized.
We've been developing Angular
2 all in one file, main.ts.
And obviously, it's
not going to scale.
So we're going to split this
into three different files.
First, our main
ts is going to be
just for bootstrapping
our app and loading
our first component.
Then our app component.ts
file is where
we'll have our page header.
And then finally, we'll have
a car parts.component.ts
that will have our
list of car parts.
After this, we will have
two separate components.
So let's jump back
into our main ts.
And you'll notice
around here I'm
using a lot of dot
dot dots, which
means that code is still there.
It's just hiding because
I couldn't fit it
all on one slide.
So just know that
it's still there.
So we'll take some of this
code out and into a new file
called app.component.ts.
Does this work?
No, it doesn't work.
It's actually broken.
We're bootstrapping
our app component,
but inside our main.ts
it doesn't have access
to our app component.
So how do we get
access to a class
from another file in Angular?
First step is to export the
class that we want to import.
In this case, our app component.
Then inside main.ts we'll
import app component
from the file app component.
Notice here we use
dot slash to specify
it's in the same directory.
And we don't have to
write .ts at the end.
Also worth noting the names
here have to be the same.
We're exporting app component
so that's what we write inside
of our import statement.
App component.
All right.
We're halfway there.
If we look in our browser we
see that everything is still
working just fine.
But we need to create
that second component.
Let's jump into that.
Here we are back in
our app component.
And we need to take that car
part list and split it out.
So here we have our new
file car parts.component.ts.
Inside of it we need to
import the component function.
Then we need to use the
component decorator.
We're going to specify
a new selector.
This one called car parts.
Then we'll write
out our template
surrounding our HTML
with back ticks.
And then we'll declare our
car parts component class,
remembering to export it.
Great.
But now we need to tell
our app.component.ts file
about this new component class.
And there's three
things we need to do.
First, we need to
import our new component
into our app component file.
We need to use this new
selector, car parts.
Thirdly, we need to tell our
app component to explicitly use
the car part component.
Let's do this.
So first, we'll include
our new component
using a new import line.
Then inside the template
we'll use our new selector.
And then if we
look in our browser
we'll see that it
is not working.
There is nothing between
the car parts tag.
And that's because we haven't
done the third step yet.
Angular doesn't know yet
to look for our car parts
selector inside this template.
We need to tell
our app component
that we're using the car parts
component in the template.
And to do that, we'll
add a piece of metadata.
We'll specify directives,
and inside array
send in car parts component.
This is where we list
all the directives
we use in the template.
And remember, a component
is a type of directive.
We look in our browser.
Yay, it works!
So now we've separated our
concerns into three files.
And our application
feels more scalable.
We've also created our
first reusable component.
And components are
meant to be re-used
if we can in different
parts of our application.
Remember, Angular
2 applications use
a component-based architecture.
Components make up the
different parts of our app.
This isn't the app
that we're building.
But it could look like this.
Our app looks a little
bit more like this
where we have our app component
and our car part component.
So what did we learn?
Well, in our main
ts that's usually
where we just import our first
component and bootstrap it.
In order to import
a class we must make
sure to use the export keyword.
We use the directives metadata
to list the directives
that our component uses.
And components are the building
blocks of our application.
Here is what our
architecture currently
looks like with our index file.
And we have our three files.
Main, app, and car parts.
Why don't you do
some challenges.
And I'll see you in
the next section.