Welcome back.
In this section,
we'll be talking
about pipes and methods.
We use pipes in angular
to format screen data.
So it takes data input and
transforms it into data output.
How might we use one to
write out our car part
names in all capital letters?
Well, here, down in
our code, all we do
is we write pipe uppercase.
And if we look in
our browser, we'll
see that all of our titles
are now in upper case.
The pipe works similar
to the Linux pipe,
if you're familiar with it,
where it just takes an input,
transforms it to
a desired output.
Let's add some data
to our car parts,
which we'll have to format
properly onto our page,
like price.
Here you can see we added
price to our car parts array.
How might we use the
angular documentation
to look up the
right pipe to use?
Well, we go to the
documentation page.
We would click on API reference.
Then, we could just type in the
word pipe into the search box
here, which would show us
a list of all the pipes we
have available to us.
We want to use currency pipe.
And here, on this
page, we could read
all about how to use
it in our template.
To format our currency,
we use the ISO currency
code, like USD for US
dollars or EUR for euros.
So we need to provide that
as a parameter to our pipe.
We do that like this,
by just using a colon,
EUR, like you see here for euro.
If we look in our
browser, we'll see
that it's printing out
EUR 4.99, EUR 9.99, which
isn't quite what we wanted.
We wanted to use the
actual euro symbol.
If we look back in
the documentation,
we'd see we just need to add
another parameter to do this,
which is a boolean of true.
So if we specify colon true,
then look back in our browser,
we can see it's now using
the proper euro symbol.
There's a bunch of
additional pipes you can use,
like lowercase, date,
number, decimal, replace,
slice, and the last one, json is
great for debugging because you
can take any object,
pipe it to json,
and it will print out
nicely into your browser
so you can take a
look at your data.
You can also create
your own custom pipes.
Jumping back into our template.
How might we display the
total number of car parts
in stock at the top of the page?
First off, let's add
our HTML template code.
It's going to look
something like this.
There are total car parts,
total parts in stock.
Notice there, in between
the curly braces,
I'm calling a method
total car parts,
which I haven't defined yet.
Let's go ahead and do that.
First, let's do
the simplest thing
and just create a class
method that returns 10.
So here, down in
our app component,
we'll define total car parts
and just say return 10.
If we look inside
our browser, we
can see there are 10
total parts in stock.
Notice, inside a
TypeScript class,
we don't use the word function
to declare a class method,
just like we didn't use
let to declare properties.
This is ES2015 functionality
enabled by TypeScript.
Now let's really
get total car parts.
First, we'll declare a sum
local variable called let.
Set it to zero.
Then we'll use a for loop, much
like we used in our template,
iterating through each car part.
And we'll add the in stock
number to our sum.
Lastly, we'll return that value.
Now, if we jump back
into our browser,
we can see it shows us there
are nine total parts in stock.
So in this section,
we learned about pipes
to transform our
template output.
And we learned how to create and
use methods in our component.
And our application architecture
looks something like this.
We just have an
index and a main.ts.
And then over the next couple
levels, that will grow.
So why don't you jump
into the challenges
and practice using pipe and
creating a class method?
There is a bonus section
attached to this section.
Remember this code here?
Well, some of you probably saw
that and were thinking, hey,
I know quicker ways, shorter
ways in JavaScript to do this.
And so if we wanted
to simplify this code,
we could do something
like this using reduce.
So notice here, this goes
through each car part.
And that zero parameter at
the end says start at zero.
Then add it all
up and return it.
Since we're using
TypeScript, we could
simplify this one step
further and use the fat arrow
from ES2015.
This would also work fine.
I'm going to keep the
original code personally
because it is a
little more readable.
OK.
Now, you can go
do the challenges.
Really.
Really, it's the end.
Go.
[BEEPING]
Alters are laid out.
Laid out?
[BEEPING]
Jumping back into-- oh.
And we omit the
blah, the, the, the.
[BEEPING]
I also want to notice the door.