[SINGING] Put your pedal to
the metal and burn up the road.
Start the race and
load Angular 2 code.
A class decorator can
help you in this moment.
Tune your engine with a
template and component.
Use data binding to
drift through the turns.
With import and export
separate your concerns.
Inject your service
with your racing crew
while Accelerating
Through Angular 2.
You're watching Accelerating
I'm Gregg Pollack, and
in our first section
we're going to be creating
our first component.
In case you're not
familiar, Angular
is a framework for
dynamic web applications.
It's a way to organize your
HTML, CSS and JavaScript
so you can ship it over
into somebody's browser.
So it's sent over
from your server,
but you're still going to need
some sort of server application
that might be Rails or
Django or PHP, which
loads not just your Angular
app but any other data that you
need to load into it later.
Angular was released in
2011, and it's mainly
maintained by Google with
the help of the open source
community.
By the end of the course
we'll be building together
this Ultra Racing app that
shows us all of the car parts
we have in stock and allows
us to select how many we want.
In the challenges you're going
to be building the Ultra Racing
Schedule, which allows you to
enter races and cancel races
based on how much
money you have.
Just to give you a quick
overview of what we're
covering in this
course, in level one
we will be creating
our first component.
Level two, structural
directives, pipes and methods.
Level three, we will
organize our code
and create a model
and mock our data.
Level 4, we'll do some
really fun data binding.
And level 5, we'll
build our own service,
figure out dependency
injection and then
use HTTP to call
over the internet
to fetch some data from an API.
And of course
between all of these
you'll be doing
challenges and building
that app I just showed you.
You don't need any prior
experience with Angular
to take this course.
However, you do need basic
JavaScript experience.
And if you don't, go check
out our JavaScript Road Trip
courses.
You'll also need
basic HTML and CSS.
We have courses for that.
And optionally, I recommend
you take our ES2015 Shape
of JavaScript to Come course.
Because we're going to be
using some cutting edge
features of JavaScript in
this course with ES2015.
What is the difference between
Angular 1 and Angular 2?
Well first and
foremost Angular 2
is a lot speedier in a
bunch of different ways.
Also with Angular 2
we use components,
which are much simpler
than controllers and scope
from Angular 1.
Also directives are simpler.
It's easier to create
custom directives.
There's also this great
intuitive data binding,
which we'll get into in level 4
where we link data into our web
page and vice versa.
Also services are
now just a class
and there's a bunch
of other things
I'm not going to get into.
A lot of improvements.
I really want to show
you some Angular 2 code.
But before we get there, we need
to decide what language we're
going to be coding in.
We could use plain
old JavaScript,
but browsers aren't up to the
latest version of JavaScript
and there's a couple different
ways we can get access
to these newest features.
One is by using
Babel, which allows
you to code in the newest
versions of JavaScript
and then it does
something called
transpiling into JavaScript
that is compatible with all
of our browsers.
However, we could
also use TypeScript.
Typescript is a
superset of JavaScript,
which means it has all those
new cutting edge features
plus a bunch of
additional features.
Typescript also
transpiles into JavaScript
to be compatible with
all of our browsers.
In this course we'll be
programming TypeScript.
Don't freak out!
It's actually really cool.
TypeScript is Microsoft's
extension of JavaScript,
which allows use of
all ES2015 features
and adds powerful type checking
and object-oriented features.
In fact, the Angular
2 source code
itself is programmed
in TypeScript.
So in this course, instead of
seeing JavaScript files like
main.js you see here, we'll be
using TypeScript files which
end in .ts If you want to
learn more about TypeScript,
definitely check out
TypeScriptlang.org.
Since our browsers don't know
how to read TypeScript out
of the box, we need to
translate it or transpile it
into JavaScript and there's
two ways we can do this.
The first way is we can send
our TypeScript into the browser
and leave it to the browser to
transpile it into JavaScript.
The second way is
we can take care
of transpiling to JavaScript
before we ship to the browser.
This usually happens when
we build or deploy our code.
So I just made a commit.
I build the code.
It transpiles my TypeScript
into JavaScript, sends that up
to the server, which then
gets served into the browser.
This method is going to
load your website faster,
so it will be what you
want to do in production.
Time to start coding,
and we're going
to start with our index.html
with just some basic HTML code.
Now inside the
header tag here is
where you're going to load all
of your Angular 2 libraries.
But I'm not going to
show you how to do it.
There's actually a
few ways to do it.
When you're ready
to start developing,
we suggest you go over and
follow the 5-minute QuickStart
Guide on the official
Angular 2 homepage.
Inside the body of our HTML,
we're going to put a body tag
and use our first custom
element called my app.
This is where Angular 2
application will load,
and it's worth noting that
this my app custom tag could
be anything, even racing app.
Until our app gets loaded in
the browser, if we load this up
we're just going
to see loading app.
If you followed that
five minute tutorial,
you probably are using
SystemJS to load Angular 2
and inside this
script tag you have
something that looks like this.
This bit of code
is going to look
for a main.ts file, which
is where we're going
to put our application's code.
This bit of code also makes sure
that error messages are printed
out to the browser console.
Time to write our
first TypeScript file
and the first
thing we need to do
is import some Angular
2 library modules.
First we have import
bootstrap and then
we have import component.
What's happening here?
Well, import is
an ES2015 feature
used to import functions,
objects or primitives.
And here we're importing
the bootstrap function
and the component function.
Bootstrap is a function used
to instantiate an Angular 2
application, which we'll be
doing at the end of our file.
And for your
information this has
nothing to do with
Twitter Bootstrap,
the front-end framework.
Then component is
a function we'll
use to create our
first component, which
are the basic building blocks
of Angular 2 applications.
The component basically
controls the part of our screen
and throughout
this tutorial we'll
be using this symbol you see
here to represent components.
I mentioned that
component is a function.
It's actually a
decorator function.
A decorator function
adds additional behavior
to our class from
outside our class.
It's a bit of code we declare
immediately before the class.
So here's our class
app component and right
before that is where we're going
to write our decorator code.
And it's that decorator that
turns our plain old JavaScript
class into a component.
You'll notice here we're
using our component
symbol in two pieces.
The bottom piece for our
class, and the top piece
for our decorator.
Let's code out our component.
It looks something like this.
We write add component.
Inside there there's an object
with selector, my app, template
and some HTML.
The app component syntax is
used to apply our component
decorator to our class.
You might not have seen
this before because it's
a TypeScript feature.
Then we specify the selector.
This is the CSS selector
for the HTML element
where we want the
component to load.
And if we look back
at our index HTML,
we can see this corresponds
to the custom tag we created.
Then the template
is where we put
the content we want to
load inside our selector.
The configuration lines
inside the decorator
are sometimes referred
to as metadata.
Next we just need to
send in our component
into the bootstrap function
that we imported to instantiate
our Angular 2 application.
If we load that up in the
browser, we see Ultra Racing.
And in case you're
curious, if we
look at the source we can see
that Ultra Racing was indeed
inserted in between
our custom tag, my app.
Components are the
building blocks
of our Angular 2 application.
And they nest very well
inside of each other.
An app might look
something like this
where you have one big
component, and the header
component, maybe a sidebar
component and little list
components.
And each component can have
its own class file, HTML file
and CSS file.
So we have our first component,
but it's not dynamic at all.
Let's start thinking about
how to send data around.
So if we have a property
inside of our component
let's create a title
property, which
has the value Ultra Racing.
Notice here inside a TypeScript
class, we don't use the var
or let keywords to
declare class properties.
Though, in TypeScript you still
use var or let but, you know, in methods.
So the question
we're asking now is
how do we put this
class property
inside of our template?
To print properties we use
something called interpolation.
See those curly braces?
Inside there we can specify
a component property
we want to print to the screen.
So now if we load
up the browser,
we can see that it
prints out Ultra Racing.
But what if we have an object
we want to print to the screen?
Here you can see
our car part object
with different keys and values.
To do this we simply use
more interpolation and access
carPart.name
carPart.description,
carPart.inStock
like you see here.
Now you'll notice our
single quotes disappear.
This is because this time
we need to use back ticks.
Using back ticks allows us to
have template strings, which
allow us to be multi-line.
This is another ES2015
feature enabled by TypeScript.
So now if we load
up our page, we
can see it prints
out our object.
It's almost time for you to
create your first component.
But first, what did we learn?
Angular is a framework for
dynamic web applications.
We're coding Angular
using TypeScript, which
transpiles into JavaScript.
Components are the
basic building blocks
of any Angular application.
And we use custom
tags or selectors
to show where we
want our component
to load inside of our HTML.
Lastly, our component
decorator is
what turns our plain TypeScript
class into a component.
Now it's time for you to
start coding some Angular 2.
And I'll see you
in the next level.
So what?
So.
Gets better every time.
FYI, this has nothing to do.
F Y, F Y I. This is
how it gets done.