[SINGING] When your page load is slow
and your code is off track,
it is fun for a fact to try using React.
To keep your app clarity,
component modularity
When your data changes,
use state to update the pages
To load it quickly all along,
it is the virtual DOM
Send your data all around,
using props to call it down.
It's time to act, keep your app intact
Powering Up With React
Hi!  I'm Sergio Cruz and you're
watching Powering Up With React.
In this first level we're going to jump right in
and learn how we can write our first React component.
But before we do that, you might be wondering
what is React?
We all heard it was good at some point,
but what makes it useful?
React is a JavaScript library for
building user interfaces.
Some people use it as the V in MVC.
React was built to solve one problem:
building large applications with data
that changes over time.
React was originally conceived
at Facebook and heavily used
and battle-tested
on products like the Facebook website
and also Instagram.
These applications contain complex UIs,
and React was built to simplify some of
the process behind developing these apps.
After using React internally for a while
Facebook got around to open-sourcing it
and now it's used by many
major players in our industry.
Before we start diving deep into
React, here are some prereqs.
You need to know JavaScript.
Be sure to check out the JavaScript
fundamentals course here at CodeSchool.
We'll be using ES2015 syntax throughout this course.
More specifically the class syntax,
arrow functions and the spread operator.
If you're not familiar with those,
check out our course on ES2015.
In this course we'll learn what makes React great,
which includes how to write React components,
rendering data to the page, how to pass data
from one component to another,
how react handles events, capture user
input, talk to remote servers.
Now that we know what React is and
what we'll be learning in this course
let's start exploring how to build things in React.
To do that, we need to start
thinking in terms of components.
Let me show you what that means.
When using React, we solve problems using
something called component based architecture.
We create components, and if a component gets too complex
we break it into smaller, simpler components.
Let's look at a social media feed
and try to visually identify some
components we might end up creating.
The first component is what
brings everything together.
We'll call it StoryBox.
This'll be our root component.
The second component we'll create is StoryForm.
This component will contain
a form that will allow users
to add new stories to our feed.
And the third component we'll create is called Story.
This component is responsible for
holding information about each
individual story in our feed.
Notice that we're reusing the
Story component over and over again
but with different data each time.
Pretty cool, right?
We have been using the term component a lot.
But what is a component in React?
Components work similarly to JavaScript functions.
They ultimately generate
what becomes our HTML code.
Let's look at this simple component.
When the render method
is called on it, it returns Output #1
with some some markup in it saying
good morning, and the current time, 10:45am.
Later on, we'll call this same component's render method again
and then we'll generate what we see in Output #2.
Some some markup saying good morning,
and the time, which is now 10:55am.
Now just because the component produced a brand new output
it doesn't mean the whole DOM has changed.
That's where the virutal DOM comes in.
The virtual DOM is an
in-memory representation of the real DOM
generated by React components
before any changes are made to the page.
It's a step that happens between the render function
being called and the displaying of elements on the screen.
A component's render method returns some markup,
but it's not the final HTML yet.
It's the in-memory representation
of what will become real elements.
This is Step 1.
Then that output will be
transformed into real HTML,
which is what gets displayed in the browser,
as we can see in Step 2.
You may be wondering, why go through
the extra step of generating a virtual DOM?
Well, this is what allows React to be fast.
It does this by means of virtual DOM diffing.
Diffing allows React to minimize
changes to the DOM as a result from user actions,
therefore increasing browser performance.
So back to our original component example.
The first time the render method is called
it'll return some markup with two paragraphs.
Good morning and 10:45am
The second time the render method is called
it will return the same markup but with one difference:
the new time is now 10:55am.
Because we have a virtual DOM
diffing mechanism in place
the only part of the DOM that gets
updated is the paragraph with the current time
making the browser DOM work as least as possible,
since it's known for being slow.
Now that we understand how the virtual DOM works,
let's start building our first React application.
What we want out of this application is very simple.
We just want to
print the words Story Box on the screen.
So, let's see what writing
this React component will look like.
Components in React are JavaScript classes
that extend from the React.Component base class.
Let's break it down a bit.
First we declare a class called StoryBox
and make it extend React.Component.
Every component in React needs to include a render function.
This is a must have for every component we write.
Our render function will return some markup.
You're probably wondering why
we don't have to put quotes around this markup.
And that's because of something called JSX.
It basically allows us to inlude HTML in our JavaScript.
But it has some enhancements.
We'll talk about that in the next section.
Now that we have a component written,
we need to put the result into a web page.
We will use the React DOM object
to render components to our HTML page
as it reads output from a supplied
React component and adds it to the DOM.
We'll call ReactDOM.render
and that method takes two arguments.
The first is the StoryBox component,
again with no quotes.
The second argument of the
render function is a target container
where the component will be rendered to.
In this case an HTML element with the story-app id.
Every time we create a React component we use it
by writing an element named after its class.
In this example when we invoke StoryBox
we are referencing a variable using JSX syntax.
So the case here is very important
so it matches the variable,
which is the class name in scope.
Now let's start writing the HTML code for our page.
The target element in the
ReactDOM.render method is called story-app,
so let's make sure our page
contains a div with that id associated to it.
Once our div is in place we can start including
some script tags to get React to work.
Let's go ahead and include the source code for
React, React DOM, Babel and our components file.
React and React DOM will take care
of rendering our components for us.
Babel will help our web page
understand ES2015 code as well as JSX.
Let's take a look at our
project folder here on the left.
We have an index.html file, components.js, which is where
all of our components will live, and the vendor files.
And when we run index.html, we will see the
Story Box text being displayed on our web page.
Let's take a step back, and review how
our React application comes together
It all starts with index.html.
When opened the browser will download
the dependencies that come with it
causing the React library
and our components to be loaded.
Then the React DOM renderer
will render our StoryBox component.
It will take in a virtual representation
of the DOM that is returned from the StoryBox render method
and then turns that into real DOM elements.
Consequently, the Story Box message
gets displayed on the screen.
I know that might sound like it's a lot,
but let's do a quick recap on what makes React awesome.
It was built to solve one problem:
building large applications with
data that changes over time.
In React, we write apps in terms of components.
We use JavaScript classes
when declaring React components.
Components must extend the React.Component class
and must contain a render method.
Finally, we call the ReactDOM.render function
to render components to a web page.
We've reached the end of the section.  Head over
to the challenges and I'll see you here in our next section.