Welcome back.
In this section,
we'll learn more
about JSX, the markup that
lives in our JavaScript code.
The first thing you
need to know about it
is that it's not a string.
When writing JSX code, elements
that start with the lowercase
are rendered as normal
HTML elements, like the div
we wrote up here.
And elements in
upper camel case are
rendered as React components,
like the StoryBox down here.
JSX is just another way
of writing JavaScript
with a transpile step.
JSX stands for JavaScript XML.
Let's take a look at how
the browser reads JSX code
once it's transpiled.
As we can see in the
return method of StoryBox,
our div becomes simple function
calls to React.createElement,
including arguments
describing what
our markup should look like.
If we look below where we refer
to the StoryBox component,
it's the same thing:
another function call
to React.createElement,
but this time
passing the StoryBox variable.
This might take a
little getting used to,
but it will feel
natural in no time.
We've seen that JSX
looks similar to HTML,
but gets strings formed
into JavaScript code.
Now let's look at how we can
expand our StoryBox component.
Here we have an h3
and a paragraph tag.
See how we can easily
define HTML elements?
Notice that our paragraph tag
has an HTML class associated
to it, and also notice that
we used the keyword className
instead of class.
The reason for that
is because class
is a reserved word
in JavaScript,
so JSX adopted a new way
of expressing HTML classes.
And we have seen this before.
This JSX code is
transpiled to JavaScript
that looks like this.
Let's take a look at
how the flow works when
transforming JSX into HTML.
In our components,
we write JSX code.
But remember, browsers don't
understand JSX natively,
but they do
understand JavaScript,
which is what all JSX
code gets transformed to.
Then that JavaScript is
rendered by the browser,
which ultimately becomes HTML.
As you can see,
we write JSX which
React transforms into
JavaScript, which
then generates the DOM tree.
We don't have to worry
about managing the DOM.
React does that for us.
Let's take a look
at this example
and see how we can display
the current time using
JavaScript inside of JSX.
Since JSX ultimately
becomes JavaScript,
we can easily mix the two.
This allows us to accomplish
some really neat things.
Let's display the current time
in our StoryBox component.
The first thing we
need to do is create
a new variable called now and
give it a new Date object.
Then we use that variable
to display the time
in our component within JSX.
Notice that any
code that is written
within curly braces in
JSX gets interpreted
as literal JavaScript.
Finally, as we
can see, we're now
displaying the current
time in our browser.
Pretty straightforward, right?
Let's look at another example.
This time we will display
a list of elements
using JSX in JavaScript's
native map function.
So we create a variable
called topicsList
and we'll give it an array of
strings with HTML, JavaScript,
and React.
Then we use the map
function to create
a new array of JSX elements.
The result is equivalent to
declaring the list of elements
one by one, except
we're combining
the power of JSX and JavaScript
to make this process dynamic.
Finally, we get to see
our StoryBox component
displaying the current time
and our new array of interests.
And this wraps up
our first level,
but let's do a
quick recap on JSX.
JSX stands for JavaScript XML.
JSX markup looks
similar to HTML,
but ultimately gets transpiled
to JavaScript function calls.
React will know how
to render to the page.
Code written within curly
braces are interpreted
as literal JavaScript.
It is common to map
arrays to JSX elements.
Now head over to the challenges,
and I'll see you here
for level 2.
Ha ha.  That was perfect.
Do that again. Ha ha ha ...
Inherit from the React-- I
don't know how to say the word
"inherit."
Inherit.
That inherit-- That inherit--
I was totally thinking
of "in-hair-it."