[SINGING] When your page load is slow
and your code is off track,
it is fun for a fact to try using React.
To keep your app clarity,
component modularity
When your data changes,
use state to update the pages
To load it quickly all along,
it is the virtual DOM
Send your data all around,
using props to call it down.
It's time to act, keep your app intact
Powering Up With React
Welcome back to level two.
In this section, we will
be learning about props
and components communication.
Throughout the rest
of this course,
we will be building a
commenting engine app.
It can be placed immediately
after a blog post, picture,
or even a video allowing users
to interact with each other.
Let's structure our app
in terms of components.
It's a bit simpler this time.
We'll have two
components this time.
CommentBox as a root component
and Comment as a component that
gets used with different data.
Let's start writing
these components.
Every time we write
a new component,
there's a pattern
we must follow.
First, we need to
declare a class.
Then we'll make
that class extend
the React.Component class.
As stated before,
our component's class
need to have a render function.
That returns some JSX code.
Now that we're familiar
with this pattern, let's
start converting an HTML mock
up into a React component.
Here's an existing HTML mock up.
Our job is to convert this
markup into React components.
By looking at the
HTML code, we can
start to identify which parts
will be what components.
The outer code is what
holds it all together.
So it will become the
CommentBox component,
which is the root component.
Next, we will isolate individual
comments into a component.
So we can reuse it later.
Notice that our div CSS
classes have the same name
as our components.
This is a good
practice when writing
mockups but not a requirement.
Now let's see what converting
the HTML code to React
will look like.
We'll start with writing
the common component.
The Comment component
renders the markup
for each individual comment.
We start by declaring our
component's class called
Comment.
And its render
function will return
JSX code that matches
the HTML code we've
seen before for each comment.
With one exception, however.
The class attribute
becomes className in JSX.
Now that our
component is created,
we can use it with the self
closing JSX tag, like this.
Next, we're going to
write the CommentBox
component, following the
same steps we've seen before.
We'll create a class called
CommentBox and make it extend,
React.Component.
Then we'll declare
the render method,
we'll make it return
some JSX code.
This time though, we get to use
the Comment component we just
created.
Pretty cool, right?
There's a little problem here.
All our comments look the same.
Let's see how we can fix that.
Just like JavaScript
functions, React components
are able to receive arguments.
And these arguments are
called props in React.
And they look just
like HTML attributes.
Let's send arguments to
the Comment components
by adding two props,
author and body.
Now that we're
passing props, let's
see how we can read them from
inside the Comment component.
To read props that were
passed to the component,
we'll use the this.props object.
The first usage
this.props is for author.
We'll display the author data
in the first paragraph tag.
Then we'll read this.props.body
in the next paragraph over.
And when we run the
code again, we'll
see that the comments
no longer look the same.
Here's a review on
passing and reading props.
Let's look at them side by side.
On the left, we invoke
a component giving it
two props, author and body.
Again, they look just
like HTML attributes.
On the right, we read those
props using this.props.author
and this.props.body
Hopefully this is
a bit clearer now.
We learned quite a few
things in the section.
Here's a quick recap.
We learned how to convert HTML
markups to React components.
We created two components,
CommentBox and Comments.
We learned how to pass arguments
to components using props.
And we also learned
that props
look just like HTML attributes.
This is it for this section.
Head over to the
challenges and I'll
see you here in a little bit.