Welcome back.
In this section, we're going
to learn about dynamic props.
As you can see here, we're
passing hard coded strings
as props for author and body.
But what if we wanted to
traverse an array of objects
in the real world
where we hardly ever deal
with hard coded values?
Instead, we'll usually
deal with dynamic objects
that are loaded from an
AJAX request, for example.
Let's start exploring on what
that flow would look like.
Typically, when we consume
data from API servers,
we've returned an
array of objects,
kind of what we see here.
Here, we have a commentList
array with two objects.
These objects have the ID,
author, and body properties.
Given this array, let's see how
we can use this data structure
from inside our app.
To use this in our
code, we'll start
by declaring a new method
called _getComments.
We're using a convention
that uses an underscore
in the beginning of
the name of our method
so we can easily
distinguish custom-written
methods from the methods
that React uses natively.
The _getComments method will
return an array of JSX elements
that is generated dynamically.
To do that, we use the
JavaScript map function
and return a common
element for each object
in the commentList array.
Next, let's pass dynamic
props through these comment
components.
The callback to map
takes an argument
which represents each element
from the calling object.
To pass variables
as props, we can
take advantage of a JSX
syntax we have already seen
in this course, curly braces.
Here's a word of wisdom.
In JSX-land, anything that's
written within two curly braces
is interpreted as
literal JavaScript,
including variables.
This makes our job
really simple here.
Let's see how we can go about
passing two props to comment,
author and body, dynamically.
So within curly braces,
we can call comment.author
and comment.body.
Now, one last thing
we need to do.
Since our comments
are dynamic, we
need to pass a special
type of prop called key.
This prop helps React keep
track of which element is which
in the loop.
It's a good practice to pass
a unique id as the component's
key.
We're done writing _getComments.
So let's go back to the render
function and use this method.
Here in render, we'll create
a new variable called comments
and store the result
of _getComments in it.
Since the return value of
_getComments is an array,
we'll get to call its
length property to find out
how many comments are
available in our title,
making that dynamic.
Then a little
further down, we'll
just use the comments variable
to display the comments.
JSX knows how to render an array
of JSX elements automatically.
So all we need to do is
place the variable there.
When we run the code,
we'll see our values
from the array are being
displayed on the screen.
The next problem we're
facing is that we're always
using plural case no matter
how many comments are returned.
As you can see here,
this causes the grammar
to be incorrect if the
_getComments method returns
one single comment,
or even zero comments.
Let's fix this.
To fix this issue, we'll write a
method called _getCommentsTitle.
This method takes one argument
as input, commentCount,
a variable that contains
the number of comments
we're displaying.
If there are zero comments,
we return a message
that reads, 'No comments yet'.
If there is one comment,
we return a message
that reads, '1 comment'.
And finally, if there is
more than one comment,
we will return that number
followed by the 'comments' word.
Pretty standard, right?
Now, we can call
the method we just
created by passing it
the length of comments.
Hopefully, this
fixed our problems.
Let's check it out.
When we run our
code again, we can
see that our grammar is
correct for all three cases.
When there are no comments,
one comment, or more than one
comment.
And we did it.
Our problems were solved.
Let's do a quick recap
on what we just learned.
In this section, we learned
how to pass dynamic props
as variables.
We also learned how to
map an array of objects
to an array of JSX elements
for display purposes.
We also used JavaScript
to handle the plural case
on our components' title.
That's it for this level.
Go practice some props
in the challenges,
and I'll see you back
here in just a little bit.
[BEEP]
--reached the end. Ha ha ha.
I can't speak today.
[BEEP]
--tag like we see over here.
Did I do that?
OK.
Let me redo it then.
Because that was weird.
No.
We're keeping it. Ha ha ha.
[BEEP]
Closing tag like
we see over here.
Ha ha ha
[BEEP]
--here in our next section.
Is that OK?
[BEEP]