[SINGING] When your page load
is slow, when your code is off
track, it is time,
for a fact, to try
using React to keep your app
clarity, component modularity.
When your data changes you
state to update the pages.
To load it quickly all along.
It is the virtual DOM
Send your data all around using
pops to call it down.
It's time to act.
Keep your app intact.
Powering up with React.
Welcome back.
I'm Sergio Cruz,
and you're watching
Powering Up with React.
In this level, we'll learn
about component state.
Let's write a new
feature for our app.
We want to add a button that
when clicked will show or hide
our list of comments.
To do that, we added a
button to the screen,
allowing the toggle
action to happen.
The comments start our
hidden and the button text
reads "show comments."
Then when the button is clicked,
the comments are displayed
and the button text
becomes "hide comments."
But how can we toggle the
comments and the button text
based on button click?
There are two main ways
to solve this problem.
The first is direct
DOM manipulation,
which is how we do things
using jQuery or Backbone.
The second is indirect
DOM manipulation,
which is how we solve
this problem using React.
Let's take a look at
a couple of examples.
With direct DOM manipulation,
we access the DOM APIs
directly using JavaScript as a
response from browser events.
If we take a look at this
example using jQuery,
we have event listeners that
execute certain actions when
they are clicked,
causing the comment list
element to show or hide.
With indirect DOM
manipulation, we
don't modify the DOM directly.
Instead, we modify a component
state object in response
to user events, and let React
handle updates to the DOM.
Let's take a look at this
code example that uses React.
The display logic is wrapped
into an IF statement that
takes care of either displaying
or hiding the list of comments.
Let's see how that
looks in practice.
The state is a
JavaScript object that
lives inside each component.
We can access it
using this.state.
In our render function,
we'll add an IF statement
that will display
the list of comments
if this.state.showComments
is a truthy value.
Next we'll need to
move the comments
variable into the IF statement.
Let's see what that looks like.
To move the comments
into the conditional,
we use a new variable
called commentNodes and only
assign the div to it if
this.state.showComments
has a truthy value.
Then we use that same
variable within our JSX code.
If showComments is true,
it'll contain the div.
Otherwise, it just
won't display anything.
Pretty straightforward, right?
Because we want to start
with our comments hidden,
the initial value of show
comments must be false.
To do that, we must declare
a class constructor.
And here's a heads up.
Any time we declare
a constructor,
super must be the
first thing called.
Here we're setting the
initial state of showComments
to false, which is
our desired behavior.
We know how to set
an initial state,
but how can we change
the state as a response
to a user's action?
One way not to do
it is by assigning
to the component state
directly this will not work.
Don't do it.
The correct way to
update a component state
is to call setState.
In this example,
we're calling setState
passing an object setting
showComments to true.
This will update the
showComments property
and re-render the component.
Calling setState will only
replace the properties that
were passed as an argument and
not replace the entire state
object.
There are few actions that
can cause our state to change,
and they're usually from
interactions made with our app.
Here are a few examples--
button clicks, link clicks,
form submissions, and AJAX
requests, just to name a few.
Anything that has
an impact on our UI
can potentially
cause a state change.
With that in mind, let's move
on to the next feature variety,
responding to button clicks.
Let's write a
function that toggles
the visibility of our comments.
First thing we'll do is
add a button to the screen
within an onClick
handler that calls
a method called handleClick.
The handleClick
method takes care
of switching the visibility
of comments to true or false.
This button click has an
immediate impact on the US
since it's calling setState.
The handleClick
method takes care
of switching the visibility
of comments to true or false.
It does that by calling
the setState method
and passing an object, changing
the value of show comments.
If it was true, it's
now going to be false.
And if it was false, it's
now going to be true.
The last thing we want to
do is switch the button text
based on state.
Initially, the button text
will be "show comments."
But if comments are
already being displayed,
we will switch the button
text to read "hide comments"
instead.
Then we can simply display that
variable within our JSX code.
Let's see our app working.
When we click the
Show Comments button,
the comments are displayed
and the text of the button
switches to "Hide
Comments" instead.
When we click the button
again, the comments disappear
and the text of the button
switch back to "Show Comments."
Pretty cool, right?
We covered a lot
in this section,
so here's a quick
recap on state.
The state is a vital
part of React apps.
It's what makes our
UIs interactive.
State represents data
that changes over time.
We declare an initial state
in the components constructor.
We update state by
calling this.setState.
In calling setState, we'll cause
our component to re-render.
This is it for this level.
Go take some
challenges on state,
and I'll see you back
here for our next level.
Render will component and
the component will re-render.
We'll replace the whole--