[SINGING] When your page load is slow and your code is off
track, it is time for a
fact to try using React.
To keep your app clarity,
component modularity,
when your data changes you state
to update the pages, to load it
quickly all along, it is
the virtual DOM,
send your data all around
using props to call it down,
it's time to act keep
your app in tact,
Powering Up With React.
Hi.
I'm Sergio Cruz.
And you're watching
Powering Up With React.
In this level, we'll learn
about synthetic events.
Let's add a new
feature to our app.
Let's allow users
to add new comments.
We're going to have to write a
brand new component for this.
We'll call it CommentForm.
And when we're done, this is
what it's going to look like.
How can we go about building
this form using React?
CommentForm will be a child
of the comment box component,
and it will be placed at the
top above the list of comments.
To code a new
component, we'll start
by declaring a new JavaScript
class called CommentForm,
and make it extent
react.component.
From there, we'll
declare the render method
that returns the JSX mark
up that our form will use.
Right now or from is static.
To make it listen
to user events,
we'll add the onSubmit handler.
And we'll make it trigger
the handleSubmit method.
Since the handleSubmit
method will
be run in a different context,
other than CommentForm,
we need to call bind this.
Otherwise, this will not work.
Let's declare the
handleSubmit method.
And it will receive an event
object as its argument.
And we will call
events.preventDefault to make
sure the page doesn't reload
when the form is submitted.
We're not done yet.
We need a way to access
our input and text
area from our submit handler.
To access these fields, we'll
use something called refs.
Refs allow us to
reference the fields
from anywhere in the class
after the component has
been rendered.
Here's what they look like.
I know, this syntax
can be a little
scary with the arrow function
and the class variable
assignment.
Let's expand this code
and see what it's really
doing behind the scenes.
We are passing a
function that gets
called with the
element as an argument.
In this case, we
called it input.
Once our function
receives this input,
it will assign it to a property
so we can have access to it
anywhere within the class scope.
Of course, since we're
using the this keyword,
we need to bind this function
to the CommentForm class.
That's where the arrow
function comes in handy.
That's the long version
of our code above.
Not bad, right?
One more note.
You might be wondering
who caused this function?
And the answer is React does.
React caused dysfunction when
it renders our component.
Now we have a way of
accessing those methods
from the handleSubmit method.
We assigned the author
and body elements
populated from refs in
JSX to local variables.
Since these are
elements, we need
to call the dot value property
to have access to their values.
Lastly, we call
addComment method.
Notice we call this
method from props,
which means it was passed as
an argument to CommentForm.
We haven't done this
yet, but this method
will be passed to CommentForm
from its parent comment box.
This is a pattern we
use a lot in React
to pass functions from parent
components to child components.
So let's talk about
that for a second.
Our comments data live in our
parent component comment box.
However, data for a new
comment is being input
in the CommentForm component.
So we need a way to propagate
data from the CommentForm
over to the CommentBox.
While this may
sound complicated,
JavaScript actually makes it
quite simple, due to the fact
that we can pass functions
around as an argument.
So let's go back to the
CommentBox for a second.
Now in CommentBox,
the first thing we do
is declare the
addComment method.
This is the method that will
be called from our CommentForm
component.
Now in our render method, let's
include CommentForm, and give
it a prop called addComment.
So remember, functions
in JavaScript
are first class citizens.
So we can pass them
around as arguments.
That's exactly what
we're going to do
with the addComment function.
Passing it as an argument
to addComment prop,
and binding it to the
CommentBox component.
Now from inside the
addComment method,
we will build a new
object called comment,
using the author and
body arguments that
are passed to it.
We'll also generate an
idea on the client side,
based on how many items are
in the comment state array.
Then, we'll call
setState and use
the concat a JavaScript
function to add a new comment
at the end of the array.
We chose to use concat
instead of push,
because calm cat returns a new
reference to the array instead
of mutating the existing array.
This helps React remain fast by
detecting the change to happen
in the array early on.
But this comments array
doesn't exist in the state yet.
So let's create it.
So far, we've been defining
a new array every time
the getComments method is
called like we see over here
with the commentList array, but
in order to dynamically update
the component, we need
to move those comments
into the component state.
To do that, let's
move this array over
to the initial state
code in our constructor.
From inside the
constructor, we add
a new property to the
initial state object
called comments, and
assign our existing
comments to this property.
Now they're part of
the component state.
Back to the
getComments method, we
can now read from
this.state.comments
and create components
by looping over
each one of the
elements in the array
by using the map function.
The return statement
remains the same.
We're invoking a common
component each time,
giving it an author, a
body, and a key prop.
Let's see a demo of
our app working now.
We'll type our name here,
so Morgan McCircuit,
and our comment as
a great picture.
Then we'll click
the Post Comment
button, which will cause
the form to get submitted.
Behind the scenes,
the new comment gets
added to the comment state,
causing the new comment
to get displayed below the form.
Pretty cool, Right
One more note about
event handling in React.
In order to ensure that events
have consistent properties
across different
browsers, React wraps
the browser's native events into
what it calls synthetic events.
What this means is that we
can consistently handle events
within React, and it will handle
all of the different browser
behaviors seamlessly.
Let's look at the Submit event.
Let's pretend for a second that
all browsers treated the Submit
event differently.
So Chrome might call
it Event Submit.
Firefox might call it
Submit Event, and so on.
This is just a
hypothetical example.
But if it was true,
React would know
how to handle each
browser's event accordingly.
Well, we as developers have
a consistent synthetic event
in React called onSubmit.
React does that with
a long list of events.
Be sure to check out this link
right here for the full list.
Let's review what we just
learned about React's Event
System.
We use React's Event
System to capture
user input, including form
submissions and button clicks.
Refs allow us to reference
DOM elements in our code
after the component
has been rendered.
Parent components can
pass functions as props
to child components to
allow two-way communication.
Synthetic events are a
cross-browser wrapper
around the browser's
native event system.
This is it for level four.
It's your turn to
take some challenges,
and I'll see you here
for our final level.
[BEEP] [BEEP]
Whoa.
There's like an echo
in the room though.
I didn't like my face
while I was doing that.
Pretty cool, right?
You say that a lot.
I know I do.
I hate it.
[BEEP] [BEEP]