[SINGING] When your page load is slow and your code is
off track, it is time for
a fact to try using React,
to keep your app clarity,
component modularity,
when your data changes you state
to update the pages, to load it
quickly all along, it
is the virtual dom
send your data all around
using pops to call it down,
It's time to act keep your app
in tact Powering Up With React.
Hi.
I'm Sergio Cruz,
and you're watching
Powering Up With React.
In this section we'll learn how
to talk to remote servers using
React's Lifecycle Methods.
In the previous level, we
moved over our comments
to be part of the
component state.
However they're
still hard coded.
In the real world we might
want to pull those comments
from an API.
The first step to integrating
our apps with an API
is to make sure these
comments are dynamic.
The first step to doing that
is to set the initial state
of comments as an
empty array so it
can be later populated
with data that
comes from a remote server.
In order to make Ajax requests,
we'll be using jQuery.
We can download jQuery
from their website
and include it as a dependency
to our index.html file.
If you're not too familiar
with making Ajax requests
with jQuery, it's
highly recommended
that you check out the
course jQuery Return
Flight here on Code School.
Now that jQuery is
available, we'll
write a new method called
fetch comments that will take
care of making Ajax requests.
This method will
make a GET request
to slash API slash comments
every time it's called.
When the Ajax
request is complete,
we'll call setState with
the new array of comments
that we received
from the server.
We used an arrow
function here to make
sure our success callback is
bound to the comment box class.
Another method for making
Ajax requests is written.
Where should we call it from?
We might be tempted
to call fetch comments
from the render function.
But since fetch
comments calls setState
when the request
is complete, that
will calls in the
synchronous infinite loop.
Bad idea.
We need to find a way
to call fetch comments
before the render
method is called.
And to do that, I'd
like to introduce to you
React's lifecycle methods.
Lifecycle methods in
React are functions
that get called while the
component is being rendered
for the first time or
when it's about to be
removed from the DOM.
In this course we will focus
on three lifecycle methods.
Let's go through a React
components lifecycle.
The first lifecycle method to
be called is componentWillMount.
And it is called before
the component is rendered.
Then the render
method is called,
and the component gets rendered.
When the component
is done rendering,
the componentDidMount
method gets called.
And the last lifecycle
method to be called
is componentWillUnmount,
which is
when the component is about
to be removed from the DOM.
There are other lifecycle
methods in React.
But in this course, we'll
be focusing on these three.
Check out the URL
for the full list.
By the way, mounting
here means being
rendered for the first time.
And as you can
imagine, unmounting
means getting
removed from the DOM.
Back to our comment
box, we will use
componentWillMount to call
the fetch comments method.
Remember, since the
component Will Mount
method is called before
the component is rendered,
this will be the
perfect place to have
our Ajax request get started.
Another component made its
first Ajax request, how can we
go about getting updates?
One way is to periodically
make the same API
request, checking if there
are new comments available.
This process is
known as polling.
Where should we start
the polling process
in our component?
Since the component Did
Mount method is called
after the component
is rendered, this
will be the perfect place to
start our polling process.
In componentDidMount,
we will use
setInterval to make sure fetch
comment is called every five
seconds.
Calling effects comments and
re-rendering the component
every five seconds
may sound expensive,
but let me show
you why it's not.
React optimizes the
rendering process
by only updating the DOM
when changes are detected
on the resulting markup.
If you're anything
like me, you're
probably concerned about the
performance of our component.
If you recall from
our first level,
React uses something
called the virtual DOM,
and will only apply changes
to the DOM when needed.
So even though we call
setState, which
causes the render
function to get called,
the browser DOM is only touched
when actual changes were made.
Let's go through the steps.
When the component is
loaded for the first time,
we'll see the No Comments
Yet message on the screen.
Then we finally get a
response from the server,
causing our component to
re-render with five comments.
Then we make sure their
Ajax cause that contains
the same five comments.
And since there were no changes,
the DOM is never touched.
Finally, when we make our
third call to the server,
we receive six comments
instead of five.
So React intelligently applies
the changes to the DOM.
There is one more
concern we need
to address with our component.
It may have some memory leaks.
Let's look at this example.
Page transitions in a
single page app environment
will cause comment box
to keep adding timers.
For example, when we
first load a video page
with our comment box component,
it will create a timer.
Then if we transition
to another page,
say a blog article, which
also has a comment box
component, that will
create a second timer
with the first
timer still running.
Then, if we keep transitioning
to other pages that also have
the comment box
component, new timers
will keep getting added to
the equation unnecessarily.
Ultimately, this will
lead up to a memory leak,
causing our component to
grow because of this leak.
Let's see how we can fix this.
We need to make
sure each component
we write is responsible
for removing
any timers we may have added.
We will remove the timer
from the comment box
component in the
componentWillUnmount lifecycle
method.
To do that, we'll
start the return value
from the setInterval call
into a property called timer.
Then, when the component
is about to be removed
from the DOM, causing
componentWillUnmount to be
called, we will
call clearInterval,
passing at the
interval ID, which
is what is stored in
the timer property.
Another component is
removing the timer.
We can see that in
page transitions,
we only have one
timer at a time.
Here's a review of how
we used lifecycle methods
in our application.
First, componentWillMount is
called, then render is called
and a comment box is mounted.
Then our component waits
for the API response.
And when it's received, setState
gets called causing render
to be called again.
Then componentDidMount
gets called, causing
this dot fetch comments to
be triggered at every five
seconds.
Lastly, componentWillUnmount
is called
when the component is about
to be removed from the DOM
and clears the
fetchComments timeout.
Whoo!
This was a lot.
But here's a quick review
on lifecycle methods.
There are functions
in React that
get called during certain phases
that components go through.
ComponentWillMount is
called before the component
is rendered.
ComponentDidMount is
called after the component
is rendered.
And lastly, componentWillUnmount
is called immediately
before the component is
removed from the DOM.
And don't forget to check out
React's official documentation
to learn about all the other
React lifecycle methods there
are.
This is it for this section.
Go take some challenges
on lifecycle methods,
and I'll see you here for the
last section of Powering Up
With React.