Welcome back.
In this section, we'll learn
how to add and delete comments
from a remote server.
Currently in our app
we have delete button
next to each comment, but
it doesn't do anything.
Let's add some
functionality to them.
To start, we'll add a
new method to comment
box called deleteComment.
deleteComment will receive a
comment object as an argument.
Then we will make an
AJAX request to delete
the comment using jQuery.
We'll pass an object with two
properties to the AJAX method.
The first indicates
that jQuery will have
to make a delete HTTP request.
The second is the URL.
For that we use a string
template from ES2015
to interpolate the common
ID as part of the path.
But we'll not wait
for the API request
to be completed before we
update the component state.
We will give our users
an immediate feedback.
This is also known as
optimistic updates.
In our code, we create a
new array called comments
by copying the
elements of the state.
We do that by using
the spread operator
and wrapping the
statement in brackets.
Then we use indexOf to find
the index of the comment that
is about to be deleted and
assign it to a variable called
comment index.
Next we'll remove the
comment from the comments
array using the splice method.
Lastly, we call setState
with our new comments array,
causing the UI to
update immediately
with the new array of comments.
Now that the delete method
comment is in place,
how can we use it?
We'll go back to the
getComments method.
Delete events are fired
from the common component.
Since the event handler
is defined in the parent
CommentBox, we will
pass the method
as a prop called onDelete
delete to comment.
We still need to bind
the deleteComment method
to our current
context, CommentBox
so when the method is called
from the comment component,
it will know which class
the this keyword refers to.
Now we're looking at
the comment component.
Let's add an event listener
to the delete link.
We start by declaring a new
method called handleDelete.
Within it, we call
events.preventDefault to make
sure the page
doesn't get reloaded
when the link is clicked.
Then we call
this.props.onDelete,
passing the current
comment as an argument.
Next, we add an onClick
prop to our button,
making it call the handleDelete
method every time it's clicked.
Now everything works
as desired, right?
Well, yes but we'd like
to add one more feature.
It is a good UX practice
to ask for a confirmation
before performing a destructive
action like deleting a comment.
So let's go ahead and
add an IF statement,
and only call
this.props.onDelete
if the user confirms the action.
Confirm is a native
JavaScript function
that displays a modal
dialogue with a message
and two buttons-- OK and cancel.
If a user clicks OK, the
comment will be deleted.
Otherwise, the comment
will remain in place.
And our deleting comments
feature is complete.
Great job.
Let's look at the last
feature our app is
missing-- persisting new
comments in a remote server.
When new comments
are added, let's
make an AJAX request
to persist them.
Currently, addComment
has two problems.
The first is that it's
generating a new comments
ID on the client
side when it should
come from the server side.
The second is that it's not
making the AJAX request at all.
Let's address these problems.
We'll start by creating a simple
object with author and body,
and assigning it to a
variable called comment.
Then we'll use jQuery to make
a post request to the server,
sending the new comment object.
When the request is
successfully completed,
we will update the state
with the new array containing
the new comment that
was just created.
Since the new comment is
being returned from the API,
its ID was generated
on the server side.
Therefore, we addressed
both our problems.
We have now used something that
React calls one-way control
flow more than once.
Let's see what it looks like.
In React, control flows
from higher-level components
down to child components,
forcing changes
to happen reactively.
This helps the apps we
write stay modular and fast.
We use one-way data
flow, for example,
when passing the
deleteComment method
declared in the comments box
down to its child, the comments
component, and also when we
pass addComment to comment form.
In other words, data is
only passed down from parent
to child components
through props,
like we did when we mapped over
the comments in comment box
and created comment
components, passing
it an author and body as props.
However, when a child component
would like to send data back
to its parent, it does so
by receiving a call back
also as a prop, and
calling it accordingly.
Component communication can
be a bit tricky in React.
Here's a review on the
two most important things
we learned in this section.
Parent components can send
data to child components
using props.
Child components can accept
callback functions as props
to communicate back
with parent components.
We have reached the
end of our course.
Go take the last few
challenges, and I'll see you
back here in our wrap up video.
Except that my face was weird.
It was like this.
None of you saw it,
but it was awful.
Performance of our component
We will make-- aw, come on.
Great job.
Don't fall back, dude.
Everything works
as desired, right?
Well, not quite.