Welcome back.
You're watching Try Ember.
This is level 2,
section 2, where
I'm going to introduce routes.
In the last section, we
added link-to helpers
to the templates that
allowed our users
to navigate between pages.
But the templates, otherwise,
were largely very static.
And that's not very
interesting, to just have
hard-coded hello messages.
You can see where we're going
is to have more interesting
dynamic data, like
on the receipt
page we're going to eventually
build, where we show
the item title, quantity, cost.
We need to go about adding some
dynamic data to those templates
now.
So how do we do that?
So when a request comes
into the application,
that request hits the router.
The router determines
what it is you're doing
and where you're doing it.
It actually doesn't know
anything or care anything
about the templates being used.
On the other hand, the
template is rendering HTML
once it's called.
But there's nothing
actually telling
the template what data to render
because the router doesn't
actually talk directly
to the template.
There's something in between
there that does that job.
Just as before, when we saw
that Ember was automatically
generating that
index template for us
when we didn't define
it, here, Ember
is actually
automatically generating
another concept for
us, as well, that
sits between the router
and the templates.
And this is where the third
major concept comes in,
in Ember, called routes.
Routes are responsible for
collecting and organizing
data, as well as
handing that data off
to templates to be rendered.
So the router talks to routes,
and routes talk to templates.
And as I very briefly
mentioned, Ember
has been auto-generating
some of these things for us.
So you remember, in
the router we defined
an endpoint called orders.
We didn't actually
define a template
called orders in the router.
What we did was define a route
But because we didn't
actually create
a route in the application,
Ember just used
the auto-generated default.
And that default's job
is to just render a template
that has a matching name.
So when in the router, we said
we have a route called orders,
ultimately, that
auto-generated route
just rendered the
orders template for us.
Normally, when we're going
to add a new endpoint
to our application,
this is where
we're going to start,
which is by adding
a new route to the application.
To do that, we're
going to type ember
generate route and
the route name.
So in our case with
orders, we would say
ember generate route orders.
That blueprint that runs is
going to generate a new route
file for us, it's going to
generate a basic template,
and it's also going to
automatically inject
that route definition
for us into the router,
if we haven't already.
And that route definition
that Ember CLI injects
should look familiar since this
is what we were just doing.
The routes for the application
are defined in the app routes
directory.
And the file name of each
route matches the name
that we gave it.
So in this case, when we
generated the orders route,
you can see that it created
a file in app routes
called orders.js.
Opening that file,
you can see that it
extends from Ember.Route.
By extending Ember.Route,
we can easily
customize how it behaves for
this one particular route
without affecting any other
route in the application.
Currently, I haven't done
anything special to this route,
so it's still equivalent to
that default route behavior.
One way to customize
the route is
by adding a model
function or hook.
In that function, I
could return anything
that I want to make
available to the template.
So for now, I'll
just return a string.
And you can see that when my
model hook returns a string,
I can then go over
to the template
and reference that string as
the model in the Handlebars
expression.
Using model here is
an Ember convention.
Model represents the
primary piece of data
that the route
represents and makes
available to its templates.
So we see that the route's model
function can return a string.
That model function
could return anything.
So in this case, we
could return an object.
That object is still referenced
as model in the template,
and its properties are
referenced using dot notation.
So model.id, model.name.
And here's what it looks
like when it gets rendered.
Or the model hook
could return an array.
How would we deal with that?
Well, in the template,
we could use something
like the each helper.
The each helper is an iterator.
It's called using each,
collection name, as, and what
you want to call each instance.
So in the template,
you can see that I've
defined each model as order.
Remember, model is
that collection.
This block is going
to iterate once
for each item in the collection.
So within that block,
I'm going to go ahead
and just render out each
order's ID and name.
And here's what it
would look like.
Routes have several
other customization hooks
available to them, but
by far, the most common
is the model hook.
With multiple orders
in the system,
it would be nice to be able
to navigate somebody directly
to the receipt for
a single order.
But how would we do that?
Where would we link them to?
How do we tell the
router or the route
that we want to view
order 1 or order 2?
So we need a way for the browser
to tell the application that it
wants to see the receipt
for order number 1.
That request needs to
go down to the router.
The router, in turn,
needs to talk to a route
to say, hey route, load
the data for order number 1
and hand that off
to your template.
The route then needs to
say, OK, order template,
here's the data for order 1.
How do we go about
doing all of that?
So the first step is
to create a new state
in our application
that represents
viewing a receipt
for a single order,
and ideally, it should
view it by order number.
To map the new endpoint or
state in the application,
we need to head
back to the router.
In the router map
section, we'll create
a new route called order.
This will represent the
receipt for a single order.
We'll give it a
path of /orders/.
And here we're going to do
:order_id That :order_id is
called a dynamic segment.
It instructs the router that
it will match anything that's
at that location in the URL.
So that could be
the order number.
Now that we've defined
that new route,
let me show you a little bit
more about how that works.
When a request comes in to
view the receipt for order 1,
for example, the browser is
going to try to go to /order/1.
The router is going
to see that URL,
and it's going to
try to interpret it.
It's going to compare it
against all of its known routes.
So first, it's going to compare
it against that orders route
that we defined a
little while back.
It's not going to
match because it's got
that extra portion at the end.
So it's going to fall down
to the next route, which
is the order route.
In this case, it's going
to match because the orders
portion matches, and the dynamic
segment matches any value.
So in this case, it's going
to match the number 1.
The router is then
going to say, hey,
I've got dynamic values here.
Let me go ahead
and capture those.
So it's going to grab the 1 and
map it to an order_id variable
and put that into a hash.
That hash is then
going to get sent over
to the route to tell it which
order the user requested.
So now that the router
has this order_id 1 hash,
it needs to get that
data over to the route
so that it can use it.
How does it do that?
Well, it turns out
that model hook
that we showed you earlier
takes optional parameters.
And that first parameter
to it is something
that's often called params.
It's whatever dynamic
data the router
has found that's handing
down to the route.
Once that data is
in your route, you
can do pretty much whatever
you want to do with it.
So in this case, I've
re-created the data
that we had earlier
from the orders route,
and I'm using that passed-in
params data to filter
that data down to one object.
Here I'm using the
Ember-provided findBy function
to just say, Ember,
take this collection
and find the first matching
item that has a matching value.
Next, we need an order
template so that we can render
that data back to the user.
In this case, I have a fairly
straightforward template here
that just renders the model
ID and name back to the user.
When I head over to the
browser, I can change the URL
to /order/1, and you can see
that I get order 1's data
on the screen.
So now that we have a
place to send the user,
let's head back over
to that order listing
and go ahead and
hook up that link-to.
To do that, we're going to
take the link-to helper,
and we're going to pass
it an additional argument.
So we're going to say, link-to
"order"-- that's "order"
singular, which is the
receipt we just created.
And we're going to pass it an
additional parameter, which
is the order object.
That order object is
going to get handed over
to the template as its model,
so it knows exactly what
to render on the page.
And now, if we take a
look at the rendered HTML
from this list, you'll see
that the link-to helper was
smart enough to go ahead
and grab the ID for each
of the objects given to it and
stick it in the dynamic segment
portion.
So we have links to
orders 1 and orders 2.
So adding that
link-to works great.
Clicking on a link to
see an orders receipt
shows the order details,
which is exactly what we want.
The part we don't
want, however, is
what the design calls for
that list to stay on the page
as we navigate.
So how do we go about keeping
that list from disappearing?
Currently, in the
router, our application
has what we would call a
very flat route hierarchy.
All of the routes
defined are siblings.
They're equivalent
to each other.
What that means is that,
when the browser requests
each one of these
states or routes,
they end up kind of
replacing each other.
So if somebody goes
to the root route,
they'll see the index template
get rendered into the outlet.
When they go to orders,
they'll see the orders template
get rendered into the outlet,
replacing the index template.
And the same is true
for the receipt.
And this last behavior, where
the order template replaced
the orders template,
is what we don't
want because that's where
we lost the orders listing.
So let's fix that now.
We can solve this by using
something called nested routes.
Using nested routes
allows multiple templates
to be displayed on the
page simultaneously.
To create a nested route,
I'll add a function argument
to the orders route mapping then
move the order route mapping
into it.
This makes the
order route a child
of the orders parent route.
Notice that, among other changes
the we'll see in a second,
this automatically
inherits the parent's path,
so I no longer need to define
the /orders part of the path
on the order route.
Now, how does this
affect navigation?
With the nested routes
in place, when the user
requests the root
path, or just slash,
they'll still see the
index, route, and template.
This time, though, when
we navigate to /orders,
the rendered orders template
replaces the index template
in the outlet.
And it's important to note
here that, now orders is
a parent route, its
template has its own outlet.
And in this outlet, a
new orders index template
is rendered there, as well.
Index templates are always
created for parent routes.
They're like the
index HTML in Ember.
Whenever you navigate
straight to a parent,
it's the index that
gets displayed.
And finally, when clicking on
an order to go to /order/1,
the orders template remains
in the applications outlet,
but now, the order details
are rendered into the orders
outlet, replacing orders index.
So we now have a layer of
templates being rendered,
and that listing from the orders
template remains on the page.
With these nesting changes
applied to the router,
we need to make some
additional changes
to the rest of the application
to make the nesting work.
First, we need to go back
to the orders template
and change our link-to.
Previously, we were
linking to order.
Because order was at the top of
the router, it was just order.
Now that's it's a
child of orders,
we need to change that reference
to say, "orders.order."
That represents
that order is now
a child of the orders route.
And while we're
here, we also need
to make sure that we add that
outlet to the orders template,
just like we needed in
the application template.
Because the orders
template is a parent,
it now needs its
own outlet, too.
And finally, we need to update
the file system to match
our new nested hierarchy.
So inside of app
templates and app routes,
we need to create a new
orders subdirectory.
That orders subdirectory is
going to now contain the order
template and order route.
With all of those
changes in place,
we can now go back to the
application in the browser.
And we can see that when
a user clicks on a link
to view an order receipt, the
listing remains on the page
and the order details
are also displayed.
Now, I know that nested routes
seem a little complicated,
and it might take a few minutes
for that to kind of settle in.
But at this point, you know
about routes, the router,
and templates.
So it's time for you to get
back to your application
and update it with some
changes in the challenges.
And I'll see you
back in level 3.