[SINGING] It's time
to build an app,
to a framework I will go.
Ambitious apps are easy
when Ember runs the show.
Templates, Routes, and
Models; it's a client MVC.
Best practices from all around;
come Try Ember with me.
You're watching Try Ember.
This is level 4,
where we're going
to make our applications more
interactive using actions.
At this point, you know about
the router, routes, models,
and templates.
We've built a pretty darn
good brochure application.
That is to say, the
user can click through
and see a whole lot of things.
But so far, they can't do
anything in the application.
So we need to go
about fixing that.
We're going to do that by
implementing the order form.
On the order form,
the user needs
to be able to enter their
name, enter quantities
for products they
want to purchase,
and click a button to
submit their order.
And we'll start this process
by creating a new, empty order
record.
To have the user submit a
new order to our system,
we need to have a new
empty order object for them
to work with.
To do that, I'm going
to go back to the store.
And in the store, we're
going to create a new order
function that returns that
empty order that they're
going to work with.
So in that function,
we are going
to order.create to create
our new empty order record.
We're going to go ahead and
give it items that are also
empty line item objects.
And we're going to
give it one line item
for each product in the system.
So there's a few
things going on here.
You can see that I'm using
the JavaScript map function.
And what that will do is for
each product in the products
array, it will create and return
a new line item record for us,
assigning itself to the
line item as its product.
There's also that arrow function
expression, or fat arrow.
This is another ES 2015 feature.
It's used here as a shorthand
for function product.
Because we want the order
form to be at slash orders,
we need to customize and
create the orders.index route.
This route was
implicitly created for us
when we nested the
orders routes earlier.
Once it's created, we're
going to customize it
by adding the model hook,
retrieving the store,
and using the store's new
order function that we just created.
Now we need to update
the orders index
template to use that model
that we just created.
So first, we're going
to update the form
to iterate over each
of the orders line
items to present each
product data to the user.
You can see we're printing
out each product title.
Next, we need to bind
all of these input fields
somewhere in the model
as well as do something
to the Submit button so we
know when the user wants
to submit the order.
Binding the input fields
is very straightforward.
Ember provides an
input handlebars helper
that we can use.
To use it, we replace
the square brackets
from the HTML input
element with curly braces
to turn them into
handle bars expressions.
And then we add a new
value property to it
that binds to the property
that we want it to update.
So in this case, we'll bind the
order name to the model name,
because model is that order, and
we'll bind each item's quantity
to an item quantity.
It's important to note
that I didn't put quotes
around the value properties.
If I had put quotes around
it, it would pass a string.
But instead of a string, I want
to pass the property itself.
If we jump back over
into the browser,
you can see that the form
is pretty much working.
We've got product
details showing up.
We've got all the
input fields hooked up.
The only thing we
have left to do here
is fix that Submit button.
So to hook that
Submit button up,
we need a way to listen for
that submit event coming
from the form in that button.
To do that in Ember, we use
something called Actions.
In Ember, Actions let
you map DOM events
to application-specific
domain functions.
For example, clicking on a
Read More link might expand
an article contents, or
typing in a search box
might create some
auto-complete functionality.
But for this application,
submitting that order form
means creating a new order.
So how can we use an
action to handle that?
It's important to remember
that in HTML, a form can
be submitted in a lot
of different ways.
It could be clicking a button.
It could be hitting
Enter on an input field,
or it could be called
from JavaScript.
So we need a mechanism
to capture all of those.
So to define our action, we need
to define an action expression.
So inside of our template,
we'll make an action expression.
The first parameter is
the name of the action
we want to trigger, and
then there's an on property
that you can define that tells
it on what event to watch for.
So to capture the form
submission using an action,
we're going to go
to the template.
We're going to change
the form HTML element.
We're going to add the
action expression to it.
We'll call this
action Create Order.
We'll pass the
model as a parameter
so we know which object
we're working with later.
And then we'll tell the action
to listen for the forms submit
event-- so on submit.
By default, actions prevent
the browser default activity,
which is sometimes referred
to as prevent default.
So in this case, it
will keep the form
from submitting
to the web server.
Now that we're triggering
a Create Order action,
we need to define that
create order function
somewhere so that Ember
knows what to do with it.
And to do that, we're going
to go back to the route.
In this case, because we're
working in the Orders Index
route, we're going to go
into that route to define it.
To define an action handler,
inside of the route,
we're going to create
an Actions block.
Inside of that
block, we're going
to create a new function
called Create Order, which
matches the name of
the action that we
defined in the template.
In this case, because
we're passing the model
through as a
parameter, we're going
to go ahead and add that
parameter to the function.
So going back to
the web browser,
I can fill out the order form
and hit that Submit button.
And when I submit, I'll see
the name appear on the screen.
And that's great.
It works.
But that's not exactly
what we want to do.
Instead, we want to
create that order
and show somebody the receipt.
So let's do that now.
To do that, I'm going to head
back over to the Orders Index
route, and I'm going to
replace the alert functionality
that we had before in
the action handler.
First, I'm going to take
the order that we're given,
and I'm going to hand it over
to the store using a new Save
Order function that we'll
create in just a second.
And then I'm going
to instruct Ember
that I want the
user to transition
from this route to another
using this.transitionTo the name
of the route.
In this case, I want
it to transition
to orders.order,
which is the receipt,
and I'll pass the order
to it as the model
that I want it to show.
This is very similar to the
link to functionality that you
learned from the templates.
So what am I going to do to
save the order in the store?
Back in the store, I'm going
to create the save order
function that takes the
order as a parameter.
And inside of that
function, I'm just
going to pretend that I'm
going to talk to a server,
and I'm just going to
set an ID on that order,
just like a server would
if it had saved it.
After that I'm going to add
it to the orders array that's
already inside of the
store using push object.
Ember's push object is just
like JavaScript's push,
except that it also
has the ability
to alert the rest of the
system that items have changed.
Now, back in the browser,
when I fill out the form,
you can see that I'm taken
to the Orders Receipt page.
And all the way
down at the bottom,
you can see that the new order
is added to the existing order
list.
And the last little
bit that we need
to implement on the
order form is that plus
10 quantity button.
The design gives campers
the ability to bulk order,
if you will.
So how do we go
about doing that?
To do that, we're going
to need another action.
In this case, I'm going to
put an action on the button
directly, because I want it to
trigger when the person clicks
on the button.
I'll trigger and add to
item quantity action.
I'll hand it the item that
I want it to increment,
and I'll hand it an
increment amount.
In this case, I want
it to go up by 10.
You'll notice here that I
did not specify the On Click
trigger, and that's because
click is the default
trigger for an action.
And lastly, I'm passing
two arguments to the action
here, just to make the
action more reusable--
the item and the
amount to increment--
so that in the future, if
we want to increment by five
or three or two, we
just do it right here.
Finally, to implement
that action handler,
I just go back
over to the route.
I add a new handler, called
Add Item to Quantity,
where I accept the line item
and amount to increment.
And then, in one
line, I can just
say line item, increment
property, quantity, amount.
Increment property is
a function provided
by Ember that simply increments
an object's property--
by default, 1, in this case,
the amount that I'm giving it,
or 10.
With the bulk ordering in place,
we can head back to our browser
and open up the form.
In the form, we can
fill out everything--
the name, the quantities.
We can type those
quantities in, or we
could click the
Bulk Order button,
and we can submit the form.
When we submit the
form, we get taken
to the receipt page, where we
see all of the correct values
represented.
So now it's time for you to
make your application more
interactive.
Head on over to the challenges
and implement some actions,
and I'll see you
back in level 5.
.