[SINGING] It's time
to build an app,
to a framework I will go.
Ambitious apps are easy
when Ember runs the show.
Templates, Routes, and
Models; it's a client MVC.
Best practices from all around;
come try Ember with me.
You're watching Try Ember.
This is Level 2,
Section 1, where
we're going to focus on
templates and the router.
In the last level, we create
a new Ember application
using Ember New.
And we saw that heading
that said, Welcome to Ember.
Let's look at what we
need to do to start
customizing that header now.
To start, I'll open the app,
templates, application.hbs
file.
And here, we run into our first
Ember concept, the template.
A template is what
instructs Ember
what HTML to render to your
end user for each page.
This is called the application
template because of the file
name, application.hbs.
And all Ember applications
have an application template.
Ember uses the Handlebars
templating library,
which is why you see that .hbs
file extension for Handlebars.
These Handlebars
templates look like HTML,
but later on, we'll learn how
to insert dynamic data into them
using something called
Handlebars expressions.
You've probably noticed
that icon up there.
You know, it kind of looks
like bicycle handlebars?
Well, that icon is going
to represent our templates.
And you're going to see that a
few more times in this course.
Inside of the
application template,
you'll notice the
welcome message
at the top which
is just hard coded HTML.
So I'm going to go ahead
and change that now.
And you'll notice that
when I changed the title
and save the file, the browser
automatically reloads and I
see my change immediately.
And that's because,
if you recall,
I mentioned that Ember
CLI has live reloading,
so whenever a file
changes, we're
going to automatically
see that update.
In the application template,
you probably also noticed
the curly brace wrapped outlet.
Those curly braces, or mustaches
is as they're sometimes called,
are Handlebars expressions.
Handlebars expressions indicate
the dynamic data points
or logic points or places
that can change inside
of our template.
In this case, the
outlet expression
tells Ember where other
templates can actually
be injected into our application
template to be rendered.
What this means
is later on when I
have other templates
in our application,
those templates are going to
get rendered into the outlet
and then displayed to our
user in the outlet location.
Here you can see what
the final rendered
HTML might look like where
the user template is rendering
in place of the outlet.
Then later, when
the user navigates
to a new place in our
application, maybe one that
uses a post template
for example,
that user template will
get replaced with the post
templates content.
So Ember applications
have many templates
and they can be layered.
And, because the
application template
is the outermost
template and it's always
rendered on the page, often
the application template
is where your
headers, footers,
and any other common
content will end up.
Remember, it's
important to always
have that outlet expression
in your application template.
Because without it,
Ember won't know
where to display your templates
and nothing will get displayed.
So back in the app
we've been working on,
you can see in the
application template
that we have a hard coded
header that we added earlier.
And that outlet is there.
And it's been there
the whole time.
But in the rendered
HTML, there's
really nothing on the page.
So what's happening
with that outlet?
What's going in there?
Well, it turns out that
because we didn't define one,
Ember is injecting an
auto-generated index
template into that outlet.
And it just so happens that the
auto-generated templates are
just empty by default. So when
you look at the rendered HTML,
there's nothing to see.
And now, if we manually
create an app templates
index.hbs or index template
because of the file name,
Ember will detect that we
now have an index template
and it will use that instead
of the auto-generated empty
template.
And here you can see, if
the index template just
says Hello from Index, it
shows up in the web browser.
Now let's make another template.
How about an orders template?
So I'll create a new file
called app/templates/orders.hbs
and give it some content.
But now we've kind of
run into a problem.
How do we show the
user the content?
That landing page worked
because Ember always
has that application template
and the index template.
Ember does not always
have an orders template.
So we need to go about telling
Ember about this endpoint
so that we can render
it for the end user.
In order to tell Ember
about our new endpoint,
we need to work in
something called the router.
The router is the second and
arguably most important concept
in Ember.
The router's job is to manage
the application's state.
It keeps track of
what somebody is doing
and where somebody is at, in
your application at all times.
So for the application
that we're building
together, that could be is
the person viewing the menu?
Are they creating an order?
Are they viewing a receipt?
And it does that by
mapping that state
or what they're
doing into the URL.
We configure or modify the
router by opening the app,
router.js file.
In it, you'll see
something like this.
And this section we're going
to focus pretty much all
of our effort on is
that router.map section.
That is where we're going
to define all the endpoints
in the application.
So how do we configure
the router map section
to tell Ember about
the order's end point?
To do that, inside
of the map, we're
going to say, this.route
and give it a name.
So in this case, orders.
And then we're going
to tell it where
it goes to with path/orders.
That's going to tell the router
that we have a new endpoint
called orders at /orders.
And what that says is, I should
see the orders template when I
navigate to /orders.
So if I call up the browser, you
can see navigating to /orders
now shows us the
orders template.
You may think we should
also update the router
map with an index definition.
You know, something
that says, I want
to see the index template when
I navigate to the root path.
But actually, Ember already does
that for you under the hood.
So you don't need to have
that in there at all.
And in fact, Ember actually
has even another convention
that we can use here.
And that is, if the
name of the endpoint
matches the path that
we want to map it to,
we could actually
omit the path as well
and Ember will go ahead
and infer that path based
on the name.
So we can remove, in
this case path orders
and it's still equivalent.
Earlier I said that
it's the router's job
to keep track of the
state of your application
and what your users doing,
and map it to the URL.
But as you just saw, when we
change the URL to /orders,
we actually changed the
state of our application.
So the router actually
goes both ways.
It updates the URL.
And the URL updates it.
So it keeps things in sync.
So now that we've told Ember
and the router about our orders
endpoint, how do we link
somebody from the landing page
to the orders endpoint, because
it's unlikely people are going
to type /orders in the URL.
So the first thing
you might think
is that you could go into
the index template and just
hard code an anchor
tag, a standard ahref.
And that would work.
When somebody
clicked on the link,
they would go to
the orders endpoint.
The downside is, it
would perform a full page
refresh which kind of negates
most of the value of using
a client side framework.
So to avoid that
full page refresh,
instead in the
index template, we
could use the link-to helper.
The link-to helper works very
similarly to an anchor tag.
It takes at least
one parameter, which
is the name of the
endpoint to link to.
So in this case, orders.
We will link to orders.
Here we've added a
pound sign at the start
of the expression which tells
Handlebars that we're using
a block form of the helper.
That lets us put content
inside of the link,
just like a standard anchor tag.
Then we'll close
the block around
with a forward slash and the
name of the helper, link-to.
Think of it a lot like
a standard HTML tag.
And now, with a link-to in
place, clicking that orders
link avoids the
full page refresh
and Ember takes over
to just re-render
the page purely on the client.
If we look at the rendered
HTML from that link-to helper,
you'll see that it's pretty much
just the standard anchor tag.
But, what's special about it
is, because we use the helper,
Ember now knows about it and
it's watching for those clicks.
It's going to
intercept those clicks.
And rather than having the
browser perform the navigation,
it's instead going to
navigate the router
and re-render the
page automatically
on the client side for us, which
will be significantly faster.
But what if we want to customize
that rendered anchor tag?
Maybe we need a custom
class because that's
what design calls for.
To do that, we just add an
additional property to the link
to helper in this case,
we could say class equals
and whatever class
want to give it.
The link-to helper will
pass that class through down
to the rendered anchor tag.
So you can largely
think of link-to
as a traditional anchor tag.
Most of the attributes
you give to it
will pass through down
to the render tag.
And if you don't provide
an ID, for example,
you can see Ember is actually
going to generate one for you.
What if we need to customize
that tag even more?
Let's say the design
called for a button instead
of an anchor tag.
The link-to helper allows us
to pass a tag name property
through that indicates
which type of HTML element
to render when it
generates its element.
So if I write tag
name, div, Ember
will generate a div for me
instead of an anchor tag.
And even though it's
generating a div in this case,
Embers still knows to
watch for clicks on it
and still performs
the navigation for me.
Ember ships with
several Handlebars
helpers already available to us.
Those include the link-to
that you just saw.
They also include
things like form helpers
for text areas or input fields.
They could include
logging for debugging.
And even conditional
statements like if and unless,
to optionally render content.
So with a link-to
helper in the template,
you noticed that clicking on
the link shows the new page.
You probably also noticed that
it updates the browser's URL
and maybe you're wondering why?
Why would it go through the
effort updating the browser's
URL when all of it's
done on the client side?
There's actually two really
good reasons for this.
First, Ember uses the URL
to keep track of the state
and what you're doing.
That's what we call
the application state.
You may remember me saying that
when I introduced the router.
But second, because
it's using the URL,
that automatically
gives you all the power
and benefit of web browsers.
That means you can
create bookmarks.
You can share URLs
with your friends,
or most importantly, you
can use your back button.
At this point, our Ember
application has two states.
We've got index and
we've got orders.
Index, at the root path,
is where we're ultimately
going to show the
menu to the user
when they want to
purchase something.
And orders is going to be where
we have the order form for them
to create their order.
And now you've also
seen that there's
two ways to change the
state of the application.
First, by changing the URL
directly, typing in the URL
and hitting Enter.
Or by clicking a link and having
Ember do the navigation for us.
I know that was a lot.
But the good news
is, it's time for you
to start customizing
your app too.
So head on over and
do some challenges
and I'll see you in Section 2.