[SINGING] It's time
to build an app,
to a framework I will go.
Ambitious apps are easy
when Ember runs the show.
Templates, Routes, and
Models; it's a client MVC.
Best practices from all around;
come try Ember with me.
You're watching Try Ember.
This is level 5,
section 1, where we'll
introduce computed properties.
The app that we've built
together now displays the menu,
takes an order, and shows the
order receipt to the user.
There's still a
couple pieces left
to implement on that order receipt.
Specifically, we need
the line item cost,
we need the total order cost,
and we need the line item
percentage.
So let's go about
doing that now.
Before we start adding new
functionality to the receipt,
there's something bothering
me about the existing receipt.
And that is if you look
at these properties,
you'll see that we're
accessing the product
title and the product price
through the line item.
I'm not a big fan of that.
That breaks something
called the Law
of the Demeter,
which is you really
are only supposed to talk
to your immediate friends.
But what we want is to just
be able to show the line item
price and the line item
title, like you see here.
So how would we make that work?
So to make this work, I'm
going to show you something
called computed properties.
So back in the line
item model, we're
going to add a new
property called Title.
That property is going to be
an Ember computed function.
Ember computed takes
a couple parameters.
First, it takes a list
of dependent properties.
Those are properties in
which we want to be alerted
if their value changes
so that we can recompute
our local property value.
And lastly, it takes
an anonymous function.
That function returns
whatever value
you want to set as
your property value.
So in this case, I
want the product title
to be my line items title, so
I just return product.title.
The way that this works is
if the product's title ever
changes, Ember
will know about it.
These dependent
values will alert it,
and the computed
function will run again
to update the value
of our local property.
Just like you saw in the
route and in the models,
computed properties are accessed
using get property name.
Because there are so many
common cases when properties
are going to get
computed, Ember provides
a list of about 30
different computed property
macros in the framework itself.
You can get a list of a
couple of them over here,
like alias, collect, empty,
equal, sort, and sum.
In this case, the title
property that we just defined
is very similar to
Ember's alias macro.
We can use the alias macro,
just like you see here.
Just like we saw with title,
a line item's unit price
is just an alias to
the product price.
So I can create a unit
price property here
that is an Ember-computed
alias of the product's price.
It's important to note here
that the product's price
property does not have to have
the same name as the unit price
that we have locally.
Now that we have the alias
properties on the line item
model, we can just head
back over to the template
and update it to use the
new title and unit price.
Now let's implement
that line item cost.
The line item cost is
just a multiplication
of the line item's quantity
times the line item's unit
price.
So you can see here that
1 times $10 each is $10.
1 times $5 each is 5, or 0
for the flashlights is $0.
Now to make that
work, we're going
to head back over
to Line Item model
and add a new price property.
That price property
is going to be
another Ember-computed property.
In this case, it's going to be
dependent on two values, which
are the unit price
and the quantity.
It's going to implemented
as a function that
multiplies the quantity
times the unit price.
You may notice that I'm
wrapping the quantity
property with a parseInt call.
Because when we get
the value from a form,
it comes to us as a string.
And since we're
doing multiplication,
we need it to be a number.
So I'm forcing it to be
a number with parseInt.
And for the sake
of being explicit,
I have a base 10
indicator there that
instructs JavaScript
to force that string
to be a base 10 number.
With that in place, we can
head back over the template
and use that new
line item price.
And you can see here in
the browser that it works.
For a tent where we had 1
at $10 each, that costs $10.
And for the sleeping bag where
we had 1 at $5, that costs $5.
So that still leaves
two things outstanding.
One, we need to calculate
the line item cost
percentage, and two, we need to
still calculate the total order
price.
To calculate the
total order price,
it's just the sum of
each line item price.
So with the example
that we have here,
you can see that
the tent was $10.
The sleeping bag added $5, so
that's a total of $15 so far.
And then the flashlight
and first aid kit
both add $0, so that's
15 plus 0 is 15.
So the total order price,
in this case, is $15.
To implement this total order
price, it'll take two steps.
So let's head back over to the
order model to get it done.
The first step is
that we're going
to add an Item Prices property.
This is going to be
a collection of all
of the prices of the
line items in the order.
To implement that, we're going
to use Ember-computed's map
by macro.
The map by macro
takes two arguments,
which is the name of
the collection to use
and the name of the
property to map.
In this case, items is
the collection and price
is the property.
So if we get the item price's
property from the order,
you can see that it returns an
array of prices from each line
item-- so 10, 5, 0, 0.
And the second step
that we need to complete
is to sum those prices.
For that, we're going to use
Ember-computed's sum macro.
So we'll create a new
property called Price.
We'll use the
Ember-computed sum,
and we'll give it the
name of the property
that we want it to sum--
in this case, item prices.
The macro will go
ahead and take each
of those numbers in the array
and add them together for us.
So when I call
order.getprice, you
can see that we get the
expected number of 15.
And what's really cool about
using any of these computed
properties or macros is that
if any of these properties
change from anywhere in the
system, all of the rendering
gets updated immediately,
and everything knows about it
right away.
The order price is now in place.
And looking at the
browser, you can
see that we get the
value we expect.
That's awesome.
Now it's time for you to go
and do some computed property
challenges.
I'll see you in the next and
final section when you're done.
.