Welcome back.
You're watching Try Ember.
And this is Level
5, Section 2, where
I'm going to introduce
you to components.
The last piece of
functionality that we
need to implement
in the application
is that line item percentage.
The line item
percentage is calculated
by dividing the line item
cost by the total order cost.
So you can see here that the
sleeping bag that cost $5.00
represented 1/2 of the
total order cost, or 50%.
5 divided by 10 is 50%.
And to make things just a
little bit more interesting,
the design team wants
that value to be bold
if it's at or above 50%.
Looking at the cost
percentage, there's
a few things to consider here.
First, the presentation of it
changes based on its value.
Second, nowhere
else in the system
do we currently use that
line item percentage.
It's just local to the
template or presentation.
And finally, it
would be really nice,
if when a user clicks
on that percentage,
they could see the
formula that calculated it.
So that's kind of like
action or interaction.
For all of these
reasons, it's a good idea
to use a component here.
Components represent
a reusable way
to package up templates,
action handling, and behavior
through the rest
of your application.
Components are best
used for creating
common pieces of
an application that
are used over and over again,
like custom buttons or input
fields or other
presentation or actions.
And as time goes on,
components are only
becoming more and
more central to Ember.
So they're really
important to know.
In fact, encapsulating
presentation and behavior
into HTML elements
is so important
that the W3C is working on a
new standard for it, called
custom elements.
And you might be surprised
to learn that you are already
using components when you
used link-to and input.
Ember CLI provides a
generator for creating
components, which is run with
ember generate component,
and the component name.
In this case, I'm going to
create a component called
item percentage, since that's
what it's going to be doing.
As you can see,
it's going to create
a couple of files for us, an app
components item percentage js.
And that's the definition
of the component.
And it will go ahead and
create the components template
in app templates components.
Opening up the item
percentage component,
you can see that it's pretty
straightforward, just like we
saw with services,
except this time it
extends from Ember component.
It's important to note
that components must
have a hyphen in their name.
It separates them from
standard HTML element names.
And it's required to conform
to the custom elements spec.
As I mentioned
earlier, components
have their own
properties and behaviors.
So since this line item
percentage really only applies
this component, I'm going
to go into the component
and define it as
a local property.
To do that, I'm going to
create a percentage property
within the component.
And I'm going to define it
using an Ember computed.
These two properties, item
price and order price,
will be given to the component
through the template when
we use it.
Just like a standard
percentage, it's
calculated by dividing the
item price by the order price
and multiplying it by 100.
And now to display that
calculated percentage,
we'll update the
components template.
To do that, I'll open the
app templates components item
percentage handlebars file.
In there, I'll define the
percentage within a span.
Now that we have the component
and its template defined,
we need to hook it
up to the receipt.
So over in the orders
dot order template,
we're going to add in
item percentage handlebars
expression here.
That's the same name
as the component
that we defined earlier.
We're also going to pass it in
item price and in order price
property, because
remember, the percentage
is based on those
two properties.
So this is how it gets them.
So looking at the Receipt
page now in the browser,
you can see that we get the
expected percentage displayed,
although it is still un-styled.
So let's go about
changing that now.
Back in the item
percentage component,
I'll add another property
called isImportant.
I'll again make it use an
Ember computed macro, which
in this case is gte, or
greater than or equal to.
So I'll say Ember computed
gte of percentage 50.
So isImportant will be true
if the percentage value
is equal to or greater than 50.
Then in the components
template, I'm
going to add a new style
attribute to the span.
And inside of it, I'm going
to say, if this is important,
then we're going to add an
important class to the span.
And to see that in
action, here it is.
In the case of the sleeping
bag is 50% or more of the cost,
you can see the
50% there is bold.
The 0, 20, 30 percents are not.
The last bit we have
here is how do we
show the formula that was
involved in calculating that
to the user?
To do that we'll,
again, use an action.
Components handle actions,
just like routes do.
So over in our component,
I'll make an actions block.
And inside of that block, I'll
define a toggle details action
handler.
For that, I'll have it toggle
a local property, called
show details.
This uses Ember's toggle
property function, which
is a bit like a light switch.
So whenever this
function is called,
it will just swap
that property value
from false to true
or true to false.
Now, to use that action
handler that we just defined,
we're going to head back over
to the components template
and add an action
expression to the span
that we defined earlier.
It will trigger
that toggle details
function that we just created.
I'm not defining
an on trigger here,
because it's going to
use the default on click.
And lastly, I can use
a conditional inside
of the template to change out
what's rendered on the page
depending on the value
of that toggled property.
So here, you can see I
have if show details.
So if show details
is enabled, I'm
going to show the function
of the item price divided
by the order price.
Otherwise, if it's
not enabled, I'm
going to just display the
percentage like we were before.
Finally, to see
everything in action,
we can take a browser
over to the landing page,
where we see the menu displayed.
We see all the products in
the system and their prices.
We can go to the order form.
We can fill out the order
name and product quantities.
We can click on the bulk order
buttons to see that increase.
We can place the order and
get taken to the receipt page.
On the receipt page,
you can see that we
show all of the
expected numbers,
the prices, the percentages.
And when we click on
those percentages,
you can see the
formula displayed.
Great job.
We're done with
this application.
Now it's time for you
to go to the challenges,
show me that you
know what you need
to know about components.
And I'll see you
again in the wrap-up.