[SINGING] It's time
to build an app,
to a framework I will go.
Ambitious apps are easy
when Ember runs the show.
Templates, Routes, and
Models, it's a client MVC.
Best practices from all around;
come try Ember with me.
Welcome to Try Ember.
I'm Nathaniel Bibler.
In this first level, I'm going
to introduce you to Ember.
I'm going to show you
what it's used for.
I'm going to show
you who uses it.
I'm going to show you
some apps that we're
going to build together
with it, and then I'm
going to show you how to
get it installed and get up
and running.
To get up and
running with Ember,
it's important that you
know HTML and JavaScript.
If you're not super
comfortable JavaScript,
you can go to something
like Try JavaScript
on JavaScript.com or Code
School's JavaScript Road Trip.
It's not as important
that you know back
end software, like
Ruby or Python,
or even database systems,
like MySQL or PostgreSQL.
And finally, while you will
need to have Node.js installed
and running, you don't need
a whole lot of experience
with it, and we'll
actually show you
where to go for instructions
on how to install that.
With that out of the
way, what is Ember?
Ember is an open
source MVC framework
for creating ambitious
web applications.
And I know that
sounds like a lot,
and I'll break it
down just a minute.
But first, let's
see who's using it.
The most immediate and
obvious answer is Discourse.
Discourse is an open source
and very popular forum system.
In fact, both Code
School's and Ember's forum
are powered by Discourse.
Ember has also moved beyond just
powering open source systems
to now powering
small businesses,
like Dollar Shave Club.
Or maybe that one's
too small for you.
So how about Sony?
Ember powers PlayStation Now.
Even Apple is using Ember.
In fact, Ember came out
of an Apple project called
SproutCore, and Apple now uses
Ember to power its help guides.
And then there's also
Apple Music Store
that's now powered by Ember.
And finally, if those two
are large enough for you,
we've also got NASA.gov.
Now back to Ember and MVC.
You've probably heard of
Model View Controller, or MVC
architectures, before.
Most server side frameworks
and even client side frameworks
follow these patterns
to varying degrees.
At a high level, your user will
interact with a controller.
That controller will in turn
manipulate data on a model.
That model's data
will change and update
a presentation or view layer,
which your user will finally
see.
The separation of
responsibilities
makes it easier to maintain
and work with the code
as well as distribute that code
to larger teams and everybody
work together at the same time.
Now, what about
that ambitious part?
Well, in traditional
web applications,
whenever a user interacts
with your website,
they might click on a
link or submit a form.
That data gets transmitted
back to the server.
The server then verifies it
and works with it and renders
some new output, which then
ships back over to the client.
That whole process takes
quite a bit of time,
especially on the network side.
To combat some of
those inefficiencies
and make your application
feel more responsive,
the web is actually
well into a shift
of putting more of that
responsibility onto the client.
So where before, the server
was doing a lot of these things
and there was a network
request involved,
those responsibilities, like
validation and rendering,
are shifting onto the client
and cutting out that network
request almost entirely.
Whereas some frameworks only
focus on one or two things,
Ember's philosophy is to be
a lot more all encompassing.
So Ember packages up all of your
build tools and best practices
and standards into
one place that
benefits from the
knowledge of everybody.
And that even extends to having
Ember core team members working
on web standards with a W3C.
Ember's ambitious goal is
to capture all the best
practices in the community,
framework and non-framework,
and boil them down into
straightforward, common
convention that all of us can
use, Ember developers or not.
In this course, we're both
going to work on apps.
I'm going to walk you through
building a camp supply
store for the Woodland
Wanderer Whatchamacallits.
There, the campers
can view a menu.
They can place an order,
and they can get a receipt.
And you are going to make
sure the critters are
learning what they need by
building a camper polling
system.
In it, campers can
create polling questions,
answer those poll questions,
and view the poll results.
Now that you know what Ember
is, let's get it installed.
The official way to create
an Ember application
is by using something
called Ember CLI.
Ember CLI is a Node.js
package, so it's
going to be installed
through Node's NPM.
Just in case you don't already
have Node.js or the NPM Package
Manager installed,
you should check out
Nodejs.org for setup and
installation instructions
in your environment.
There are downloadable
installers
available for Windows,
Mac OS, Linux, and more.
Once Node and NPM are
installed, Ember CLI
is installed by typing
NPM install-g Ember CLI.
Ember CLI is the name
of the NPM package,
and that -g install
Ember CLI globally.
What that does is it
makes the executable
that it installs available
to every user on your system.
Once Ember CLI installs, it
will install an Ember executable
on your system.
You can see here that
when I run Ember version,
it tells me the current
version of Ember CLI installed.
It's important to note here
that it's an Ember executable,
not Ember-CLI, which I know
is a little bit confusing.
But we are going to be
using this executable
throughout this course, so it's
important to know about it.
The Ember Command Line
Interface, or CLI,
is where you're going to be
spending a lot of your time
if you're building
an Ember application.
Ember CLI provides a ton
of features and support,
helpers, and generators
for doing everyday tasks.
At any time, you
can run Ember Help
to get an idea of what
commands are available
or Ember Help and a
command name for details
about a single command.
So let's get started
by creating an Ember
application using Ember CLI.
To do that, we'll type
Ember new project name.
And that will instruct
Ember CLI to run a blueprint
to generate a whole directory
for us for the project.
Here you can see when we type
Ember New Woodland-- Woodland
because that's the
name of our project--
Ember CLI creates a bunch
of new files and directories
to get us going.
Once the project is created,
we can change directories
into our project
directory was created,
and we can type Ember serve.
What that does is it starts
up a development server that
has live reloading
functionality, which
means whenever we change
any file in the application,
it automatically reloads
our browsers for us.
And now we can open a browser,
go to local host 4200,
and see a welcome
to Ember message.
With that, we've
got Ember installed.
Now, I know that you're eager
to start your development.
But first, we need
to make sure that you
know what you need to know and
get your own project started.
So head on over and
do the challenges,
and I'll see you
in the next level.