[SINGING] It's time
to build an app,
to a framework I will go.
Ambitious apps are easy
when Ember runs the show.
Templates, Routes, and
Models; it's a client MVC.
Best practices from all
around; come try Ember with me.
You're watching Try Ember.
This is Level 3,
where we'll learn
about models and services.
In the last level, we
showed how to provide data
from routes to templates.
You might have noticed
that in the model hooks,
we started repeating ourselves
with a lot of the data that
was being returned.
So let's go about
trying to centralize
and organize that before we
start working with that data
little bit more.
To centralize our
data, we're going
to create something
called a service.
An Ember Service is
a long-living object
that can be accessed
throughout your application.
A long-living object is
sometimes called a singleton.
These objects are good
for things like managing
third-party resources
or logging systems
or even holding data in a
data repository, which is
how we're going to use it now.
To create our service,
we're going to, again,
rely on Ember CLI's generators.
You type ember generate service
and the name of the service
you want to generate.
So in our case, we're
going to generate
a service called the store.
And the blueprint
creates for us a new file
in App Services,
called store.js,
which we'll jump to now.
And if we jump into
the store file,
there's nothing too
surprising here.
The only difference
from something
we might have seen
earlier is that we
are extending from something
called ember.service.
But otherwise there's
not a whole lot going on.
Now that we have this
empty store service.
Let's start moving our data out
of the routes into that store.
So I'm going to create a new
get orders function inside
of the store that's going
to return the data we
have from the orders route.
After that I need to go
back to the orders routes
and update the route
to use the store.
To do that, I need to
reference the store.
So here we'll add a store
property to the route.
And we'll inject a new
service, called store.
So Ember is going to locate
that store service for us
and make it available as a
store property in the route.
Now that the store
is available, I'll
update the model to use it.
Inside of the model
hook, I'll create
a new variable, called store.
In this case, I've
defined it as a const.
This is an ES 2015 feature
the just throws a JavaScript
error if that variable changes.
I'll assign it to
be this.get store.
That grabs the property
of store and assigns it
to the store variable.
And then from the
model hook, I'll
just return store.get
orders, which
is the function that we
created just a minute ago.
And here, because the service
name matches the property name,
we can just leave off the
service name from the call.
And Ember will infer it
from the property name.
Now, because the store service
has all of our order data
in it, we can update the
order route to use it as well.
To do that, I'll
create a new function
in the store, called
get order by ID,
where I'll pass it in ID.
Inside of that function,
I'll take the same order data
we already have in the store.
And I'll just move the find
by functionality over into it.
Then back in the order
route, I can just
update it to inject the store
and call our new function.
And with the store
now complete, you
can see those changes didn't
actually change anything
about the application.
Our application still functions
exactly as it did before.
But our data is all
now in one place.
Now that we have a place
for our data in the store,
let's look back at our
application to see exactly what
data we're working with.
First, we have products.
Products have titles, prices,
descriptions, and images.
Then there are orders.
Orders have a name
and a collection
of items being ordered.
And then those line
items each have
an associated product and a
quantity of that product being
ordered.
Now that we've identified the
three types of objects being
used in this
application, let's look
at how we can use Ember
to formalize them.
This is where Ember
models come in.
Ember models represent
the underlying data
in your application that
is sometimes persistent.
Models are defined
in app models.
Since we have a
product model, we'll
go ahead and create an
app models product.js file
to define it.
Inside of that file, we will
extend from Ember Object
for this course.
It's here that we can
define properties, methods,
or other behaviors that we
might find useful for products
in this application.
But why extend from Ember Object?
Ember Object is the base
for just about everything
inside of Ember.
And there are three main
reasons for extending
from Ember Object.
First, it creates a
common interface for us
for creating and
destroying objects.
Second, Ember Object
provides life cycle events
and hooks that other parts of
the system can watch out for.
And third, it provides
some property observation
functionality so that
the rest of the system
can know when properties
change on these objects.
For example, this
observation functionality
is used so that Ember can
update the templates when
data changes.
Now that we've created our
product model, let's go ahead
and play around a little
bit with Ember models
just to kind of get
a feel for them.
So you'll create a new instance
of a model, called a record,
by using a create method.
You can optionally pass
properties into the record,
like you see here.
Properties are read from a
record using the get function.
And properties are changed on a
record using the set function.
The get and set functions,
while a little bit verbose, let
the rest of the
Ember application
know when those properties
are being changed or read.
For now, the line
item in order models
will be identical to the product
model, which is to say, empty.
That'll change as
the course goes on.
But at least this gives us three
different objects to work with.
So with these models in place.
We need to go back
to the service
and start using them within it.
How do we do that?
First, we'll need to import
these model definitions
into the service.
We can do that using
the Import statement.
One way to import them is
by using relative paths.
So from a store service
located in App Services,
I can traverse up a directory
to App with dot dot.
And then I can go into
the models line item
product or order.
And that works.
But if the store ever
changes file location,
those imports will break.
Better than relative paths,
I can use absolute or project
paths.
To use absolute paths, I
start with the app name
and the Import statement.
The app name what I
defined when I Ember new'd
the project, in
this case, woodland.
After the project
name, I can import
the rest of the file path
directly with woodland models
line item.
And it references
the line item model.
With our application models
now available within the store,
let's go about using them now.
To do that, I'll
create a private array
of product records.
I'll fill it with
records whose data
matches those from the
design mockups you've seen.
I called it a private
array, because it's not
directly available to
the rest of the system.
So to make it available
to the rest of the system,
I'll need to add a new
function to the service
that people can call.
So I'll create a get
products function that
just returns this array.
And following the
same pattern, I
can update the
store to also have
an array of pre-defined
orders, just
so we have data in the system.
Orders have an ID and name,
but they also have a
collection of line items.
So here, you can see
I'm creating a handful
of line items for each order.
And now that order's
array is in place,
I can go back to the functions
that we defined earlier,
like get orders, and
have it use them.
Now that the application has
some of our mockup data in it,
it's time to go ahead and
move the rest of the design
over as well.
To do that, I'll
go ahead and grab
some of the snippets of
the HTML from the design
and apply it straight
to our templates.
I'll then grab all of the images
that our design team provided
to us and put them into
public assets images.
This directory doesn't
exist by default.
So I've gone ahead and
created that for you.
And finally, I can just
copy the style sheets
that our designers
provided into the app CSS
file, located in app styles.
That style sheet is already
included in the rendered index
HTML page.
So you can see that
our models are now
being rendered onto the page.
And our design is being applied.
It's time for you to do the
same in your application.
So head on over
to the challenges.
And I'll see you when
you get back in Level 4.