[SINGING] Your online
application's starting to fail.
It's crawling on the network
just as fast as a snail.
We need evented programming
starting from the top.
Better write some code so
the world doesn't stop.
With a non-blocking model,
we will be just fine.
Built on Google
Chrome's V8 runtime.
And all you need to do is
write some JavaScript code,
and use the Real
Time Web with Node.
You're watching Real
And this is level
five, where we're
going to be going over express.
As you saw with Node,
it's a very low level,
which means you're
probably going
to want to build a web framework
if you're building a big web
application or better yet,
use somebody else's web
framework, which sits on top
of Node to build a big web app.
Express is a Sinatra
inspired web development
framework for Node.
Sinatra, in case
you're not familiar,
is a simple web development
framework for Ruby.
And it takes some
inspiration from that.
It gives you stuff
like easy route URLS
for callbacks, middleware,
an environment based
configuration, redirection
helpers, and file uploads.
So it gives you a
lot of codes you're
going to need out of the box
to start building websites.
In this level, we're going to
go over some of the basics.
To start building
our express app,
the first thing we got to
do is require the library.
If you don't yet
have it installed,
you can run npm install express.
And we're going to do --save.
What that's going
to do is not only
install the module in
our Node modules folder,
but also add it to
our dependencies
file, our package.json.
Next, we'll create an
instance of express
by invoking the
express function.
Then we can start
defining endpoints.
Here we're going to define an
endpoint at the root route,
so if someone does
a get request,
it's going to call this
callback we're sending in.
Here we'll call the
response.sendfile,
which will read in a file from
our file system and send it
back with the response.
Lastly, will tell to
listen on port 8080.
Now if we run this code and we
call up our browser, local host
port 8080, we'll see that
the index.html got loaded.
Now let's take a look at
a more complex example.
We want to create
an endpoint where I
can send in a Twitter username.
And it will call out to Twitter,
get the latest 10 Tweets,
and then display those
back for our user.
So to do that, first we're
going to need the request
module and the URL module.
Then we'll create a NuGet
endpoint, which takes
in the tweets and the username.
Notice the colon there.
That means we have
a dynamic user name.
Then we have our callback,
with a request and response.
Inside there, we'll
grab the username out
of the request parameters,
req.params.username.
So if that's Gregg
or Eric, it's going
to store that in the
username variable.
Then we have a bunch
of different options
we're going to specify from
the protocol to the host,
to the path name, to the query.
And lastly, we'll call
our request with our URL.
The response will get returned
back from that function call.
And we'll pipe the response back
in to the response that goes
back to our user's browser.
Before I show you this code
in action, there's one caveat.
And that is, if you
try this code as is,
it wouldn't quite work.
That's because of
the Twitter API.
It's changed since we
wrote this code so that you
have to authenticate
even when you want
to pull a user's Twitter
Stream and get the data back
in JSON format.
So keep that in mind.
You'll have to add
a little more code
if you really want to do this.
Ok, let's check
this out in action.
First thing we need to do
is start up our Node server.
So there we go.
Now if we want to go
ahead and hit that URL,
we're going to use curl
to go to local host 8080
and then give our
tweets/eallam-- because that's
the name of the Twitter user.
We want to get
the JSON feedback.
And there it is.
And it's not that pretty.
Luckily, I know another NPM
module called pretty JSON
we can install
globally, and that
will give us a little
executable so we
can pipe the output into
that executable, pretty JSON.
And now we have pretty JSON
with all the information
from that user's Twitter stream.
Instead of simply
piping the JSON through,
let's figure out how we
might take that JSON data
and put it into our web
browser using some templates.
First thing we need to do is
install a templating library.
For this example,
we'll use ejs, which
stands for embedded JavaScript.
We'll install it
with npm install ejs.
By default, it will
look for templates
under the views directory.
Here we are back
in our application.
Now instead of using
pipe, we're going
to call request and
give it a callback,
so that we can have access to
the error, response, and body.
The first thing we
want to do is parse
the JSON, which we got
back in the response body.
We'll set that equal
to the Tweets variable.
Next, we need to
define what data
is going to go
into our template,
so we can render out the Tweets.
We do this by setting the locals
property on our Express response.
Here we'll pass in the array
of Tweets and the username.
And lastly, we'll
tell our response
which template to render out.
In this case, tweets.ejs, which
stands for embedded JavaScript.
If we open up this
template, we'll
see that we have some HTML.
And in there, we have <%=
and then, we've got name.
And then, we end it with the %>.
That's telling our
Node app to render
that variable inside our HTML.
Then we'll get a
list of the Tweets.
You'll notice here we're
using <% percentage.
And since Tweets
is an array, we'll
do tweets.forEach and
send in a function
to invoke on each of the Tweets.
Inside of there, we can
simply use a list item
and then call
tweet.text because we
know each Tweet is
an object, which
has a text key, which contains
the contents of a Tweet.
Then we simply need
to end our forEach function.
If you're coming
from Ruby on Rails,
this probably looks
really familiar
if you're not coming
from Rails, it might not.
So again, we use <%= if we want
the value that gets returned
from the expression we put
inside of there to get printed
out into the page.
So in our case, name, we want
to print that out to the page.
But if we just want
to run some code,
in this case just
iterate through an array,
we just use <%.
So the result of going
through that forEach
won't get printed out the page.
But every time we loop
through that, it's going
to print out another list item.
Now if we jump into our
console, we'll run our Node app.
If we jump over
into our browser,
we'll go to
localhost slash codeschool this time.
And we've got all the
Tweets from Code School.
So there's some of
the basics of Express.
Of course, there's
a lot more to it.
If you want to start building
big web apps, you can.
But why don't you jump
into the challenges
and practice some
of those basics?
And I'll see you
in the next level.