[SINGING] Your
online application's
starting to fail.
It's crawling on the network
just as fast as a snail.
We need evented programming
starting from the top.
Better write some code so
the world doesn't stop.
With a non-blocking model,
we will be just fine.
Built on Google
Chrome's V8 runtime.
And all you need to do is
write some JavaScript code
and use the Real
Time Web with Node.
You're watching Real
And you've made it to
the final level, level 7,
where we're going to be
talking about persisting data.
So back in our chat app, if we
say, hello, anyone out there?
[LAUGING]
And then somebody else joins,
connects to the server--
it's, of course, Spider.
Who else would it be?
They're not going to see any
of our previous messages.
But that's typically not
how chat applications--
how you want them to work.
So let's figure out how we might
persist these messages as they
come in so that
new people who join
see the previous
couple messages.
You'll notice,
here's our old code.
We're on join.
We're setting the nickname.
We're broadcasting
who joined the chat.
And then, on messages,
when a new message
comes in on the server side,
we emit it to everybody else.
And we also emit it back to us.
So let's jump in here.
What we might do to
store the messages
is create a messages
array on the server side
where we're going to
put all the messages.
Then we'll create a
store messages function.
This function takes
the name of the person
who sent the message,
and what they sent,
and then we'll simply push
onto the messages array
an object with the name and
the data, which is the message.
Then, if our messages is
greater than 10 in length,
we'll go ahead and shift one
off, shift the first one off,
so there will only ever
be 10 previous messages.
Then, down below, in
the messages listener,
after we get done
emitting the messages,
let's store that message
that we just received.
We're storing all the
messages as they get received.
But we need to go back
into the join listener
so that, when a
new client joins,
we iterate through
each of the messages,
like you see here, and emit to
that client that just joined,
all the messages, so it'll
display them onto their screen.
So if we jump back
into our browser,
and we type a couple messages,
and we connect a new client,
we can see that all the messages
are there, waiting for us.
Now let's exit our server,
and restart it, and go back
into our browser.
As you can see, now that
we've restarted our server,
our messages array
got blanked out.
And our messages
aren't there anymore.
So we need to think about how
we could persist those messages,
even if our server restarts.
One way to solve this problem is
to use a database of some sort.
Luckily, node works great
with all sorts of databases,
from Mongo, to Couch, to
Postgres, Memcached, Riak,
Redis, they all
play well with Node.
And they all have
non-blocking drivers.
Lots of times, in
other languages
that use these databases,
you'll find they
have drivers that are blocking.
That means, when you go
to submit a SQL request,
well, your process kind
of just hangs there.
It can't process anything
else while it's waiting
for the database to return.
Kind of crazy.
Well, Node, of
course, everything
we write is non-blocking.
So that means you
could have two queries.
And they both submit
queries to the databases.
And you're process can
do other stuff while it's
waiting for these two queries
to come back, and then
call the callbacks,
and then do more stuff.
Pretty neat.
So let's jump in to redis.
And luckily, Redis has all
sorts of data structures
that we can store
inside of its database,
from strings, to hashes, to
lists, to sets, to sorted sets.
We're going to be using
strings, lists, and sets.
Now, Redis has a
great home page.
It makes it really
easy to start playing
with the different components
and different data structures.
So if we go into the
documentation here,
the different commands, and
we look under strings, we
can see that we can use GET.
We can even start playing with
it right here in the browser.
So we can say something like,
SET, new key, to set a value.
We'll set the value dog.
And then, if we GET new
key, we're getting back dog.
So the new keys is our key.
And then dog was our value.
Now, let's jump into lists.
We're going to be using
the LPUSH list command.
We can check out the syntax.
And then we can start pushing
things onto a new list.
So let's give that a try.
We'll push onto
our new list dog.
our new list cat.
And then we'll use
the lLRANGE command
to get back the values out
of it, from 0 to negative 1,
giving us all the
values in the list.
To connect our Node
application with Redis,
we're going to be using
the Node Redis library.
This is where you could
find it on GitHub.
To install it, we call
just npm install redis,
dash dash save, so
that we can install it
and add it to our package.json.
Then, inside of our code,
we simply require redis.
Then we can create
a redis client
by calling redis.createClient.
Then we can start issuing
commands to the database.
We can call set message1,
hello, this is dog,
set message2, hello,
no this is spider.
So we're setting the
keys and the values.
To get the messages out of the
database, we simply call get.
And we send in a callback.
This goes with that
non-blocking thing.
We're going to get this
out of the database.
But while it's fetching it, we
can go off and do other stuff.
And then, when the value
comes back from the database,
it will invoke this
callback function
and log it out to the console.
If you want to store a
list in the Redis database,
we could create a message
and lpush, left push,
onto the messages list
this current message,
and then specify
a callback here.
This callback is optional.
But it sends back, in the reply
variable here, the list length,
in case you need it.
If we add another
string to messages,
we can see here that it
returns the length of 2.
Instead of logging out
the length of the array
to the screen, we're going
to use the LTRIM function.
The LTRIM function,
in this case,
we're going to send in 0 and 1.
It's going to keep the first
two strings in the array
and remove the rest.
If we wanted to retrieve
the values from the list,
we can use lrange, remember
we saw that before,
sending in 0 to negative
1, which will return
all the elements in the list.
Now if we log them
out to the console,
here's what we would get.
If we jump back into our
old code, you can see,
here's our store
message function.
And we need to rewrite
this to use Redis.
First we need to create
our Redis client.
And then, inside of
our store function,
we need to take the name and
the data that we send in,
put them into an object, and
then call JSON.stringify, which
will turn that
object into a string
we can easily store in Redis.
Then we'll call lpush, send
that in as the message,
and then call ltrim so
it'll keep the newest
10 items in the array.
Here's our old join
listener, where
we're iterating through all the
messages when somebody joins
and printing it
out to the screen.
We'll modify this
code to use Redis,
first fetching all of the
list items with lrange,
then it will
reverse the messages
so they are emitted
in the correct order.
Then we'll iterate
through each message that
gets returned in that list,
first parsing the string that
gets returned into a JSON
object, and then, finally,
emitting that to the client.
Here we are back in our browser.
We say, hello,
everyone, it's me.
Now, if we connect
another client,
and they type in
their name, we'll
see it properly loads
our list from Redis
and broadcasts it
into our browser.
If we exit our server
and restart it,
if we open up a new client,
give it a new nickname,
and we can see it's properly
loaded all the old messages
from Redis, even though
we restarted our server.
There's one more thing we need
to do to create this chatter
application, and that's to
show a list of who is currently
in the room, who is connected.
We're going to do
that using a set.
Sets are lists of unique data.
You can't have duplicates.
And to store a set
in Redis, we're
going to call sadd
and then specify
the set name, in this case,
names, and then the value
we want to send into the set--
in this case, dog, and then
Spider, and then Gregg.
To remove an item, we
simply call srem for a move
and send in the set name and
the value we want to remove.
Then, to list out all
the members of a set,
we call smembers, sending
in the name of the set,
in this case, names.
And then we'll
specify what to do
when the set gets
returned, in this case,
log it out to the console.
Now we need to jump
back into our join event
listener on our server.
When somebody joins, the
first thing we need to do
is, we're going to emit
the add chatter event.
We're going to broadcast
it to all of our clients,
so we can add that chatter.
Then we need to add this
chatter to our Redis set.
We're going to call
the set chatters.
Now, back in our client, we
need to define the add chatter
listener.
And this will invoke a
callback that receives
the name of this new chatter.
And here, we'll simply
build a new jQuery element
with a new chatters name
and then append that
to the chatters element.
So we add this new
chatter when they join.
And we let everyone
know about it.
But what if there is already
chatters in the chat room?
What if there's already
users in our set?
We need to check for that.
So we'll use our redis client
to list out all of the people
in our set, well, all the names,
and then, on that callback,
we'll iterate through
each of the names.
And then, on our client,
which just connected,
we'll emit add chatter
and send in each name.
Last thing we need to do
is remove a chatter when
they're WebSocket disconnects.
So we'll say, on the
disconnect event,
get their current nickname,
broadcast the remove chatter
event to all of
our other clients,
and then remove them
from our Redis set.
Then, on the client
side, we need
to listen for that
remove chatter event,
and when that gets called,
we'll simply use some jQuery
to remove it from the list.
So now, if we jump
back into our browser,
we can send in a message.
You'll notice Dog is
already connected.
We'll start up a new client.
And look, we can see
that both Spider and Dog
are connected users.
Let's even connect
another client.
So here, we'll connect Greg.
And we can see that all
three people are in the room.
And everybody can
see who is chatting.
All right, we have a
chatter application.
It's a real time web
node application.
And now it's time for
you to get into some
of those last challenges.
And I'll see you
in the outro video.
Good luck.