[SINGING] Your online
application's starting to fail.
It's crawling on the network
just as fast as a snail.
We need evented programming
starting from the top,
better write some code so
the world doesn't stop.
With a non-blocking model,
we will be just fine,
built on Google
Chrome's V8 runtime.
And all you need to do is
write some JavaScript code
and use the Real
Time Web with Node.
You're watching Real
This is Level 4,
where we're going
to be talking about modules.
So in previous
levels, we brought
in modules from other libraries
so we could use their code.
Remember we used the
HTTP library and the fs
or file system library.
But how does require
return these libraries?
How does it find these files?
And how might we
create our own modules
so we can share code between
different applications?
Let's create a
really simple module.
We'll call it custom_hello.js,
it has its own file.
Inside there, we'll define a
function, which simply logs out
to the console, "hello!"
In order to expose this
method-- make it public--
we need to write
module.exports equals hello.
Then inside of our
application file,
we can write var hello
equals require custom_hello.
Notice we have to do that dot
slash-- I'll explain why later.
Then we just write hello to
call a method and it will work.
Now let's write another
module and we'll
define it in a different way.
We'll write a goodbye module.
Notice we'll just
do exports.goodbye,
explicitly setting goodbye
as a public method.
Then inside our app.js
we can require the module
and simply call gb.goodbye.
Notice in our first
module, we can only
set one object equal
to module.exports,
that's going to be the only
public method in this module.
Whereas with goodbye, we could
set multiple methods as public.
Lastly, if we wanted
to, we could simply
call the goodbye
method in one line
by requiring it and then
calling that goodbye method.
Let's create another module.
This time with three
functions foo, bar, and baz.
You can see them
visually represented.
Now we want two of
these methods to be
accessible from
outside the module.
Foo, so we do exports
foo equals foo.
And bar, so we do
exports bar equals bar.
Now inside our application,
to call these functions
we require the module
and then we can simply
call myMod.foo and myMod.bar.
baz on the other hand
is a private function,
which is only available
from within the module.
Let's write some code
to do an HTTP request
and then we'll refactor
it into a module.
So here you can see, we
require the HTTP module.
The message we'll send
into the request is,
"Here's looking at you, kid."
We'll have a couple
of options that we'll
need to set for the request--
the host, the port, the path,
and the method.
To initialize a request
we'll call HTTP request,
we'll send in our
options then we'll
pass in a callback function,
which will be executed
when the response returns.
Inside of this function, we'll
listen to the data event.
And we'll specify that
when data gets received,
we'll simply log it
out to the console.
Now to write data
to the request,
we're going to call
request.write message.
We only want to
write one message
so we need to tell the
request that it's finished
by writing request.end.
Let's encapsulate
this functionality
so we can reuse it by first
wrapping it in a function.
So in this function, we're going
to send in the message, which
is going to create the request.
Then we can just invoke it by
writing makeRequest "Here's
looking at you, kid."
Let's shrink this code.
And now we're going
to encapsulate
this functionality
inside of a module.
We'll call it make_Request.js.
Remember, to expose
this function,
we need to write module.exports
equals makeRequest.
Then inside of our application,
we can require the module
and simply make requests.
So now let's jump into
how exactly require
looks for modules.
Remember, some of the
modules we're using
don't have that dot slash,
so what's going on there?
When we require a module using
dot slash it's going to look
in the same directory as our
application for a file with
that name make_request.js.
If we did dot dot slash-- well,
it would look up a directory.
If we specified an
absolute path-- well,
it would look in that
directory as well.
Now inside our app, if
we just do make_request
and we don't specify
any sort of directory
that it might be
in-- well, it's going
to search inside of a
node modules directory
inside of our current app.
If it doesn't find
it there-- well,
it's going to go looking
for a node modules directory
in our home directory.
And it'll look inside slash
home slash node modules.
And lastly, it'll
look at the root path.
Notice here, it's
going up one directory
at a time looking
for that module.
Now you might be
wondering do you really
put individual files inside
these node module directories?
That might get sloppy after a
while, and you would be right.
Most of the time when you look
inside a node modules folder,
you're going to see directories.
Each directory is a package,
which represents a module.
How do we find out about
packages for application?
And where do they come from?
Well, they come from NPM.
If you're familiar with CPAN
for Perl or Ruby Gems for Ruby,
well NPM is where we find
packages and modules for Node.
It comes with Node.
Basically, it's this
little command line
tool just like Ruby Gems.
It has a big module
repository, that's
where you'll be able to
search for useful shared
open-source libraries.
There's also really good
dependency management built-in.
So if you have a package and
it depends on other packages,
well it's going to
go and fetch those
when you install that package.
It's also easy to
publish your own modules.
So you can publish
your own open-source
and allow people
to reuse your code.
npmjs.org is the website,
if you want to check it out.
In our application, we
need the request package.
In order to install it, we can
simply run NPM install request,
like you see there.
This is going to
install the request
package underneath our
application's node modules
directory.
So it's going to create a
directory called request
and put all the files
inside that package,
inside that directory.
Then when we
require this module,
it's going to go look inside
our node modules directory,
find the package,
and include it.
Some modules, you might
want to install globally
instead of just underneath
your application.
For example, here we're
installing the coffee script
module globally with
a dash g option.
Coffee script comes
with an executable.
So we can run coffee
and then specify a file
that we want to translate
into JavaScript.
One thing to note here is that
a globally installed module
can't be required from
inside your application
like you see here.
It wouldn't work.
In order to do
that, we still need
to install coffee script--
in this case, locally
to our application and
then we can require it.
So the next time you find
yourself coding and thinking,
maybe somebody already
wrote this code.
You might want to head
over to the NPM registry,
you can search on there for
existing shared libraries.
You could also go to
GitHub and search there.
Or even on the NPM
command line, if you
think you might
know the name, you
can do NPM search and then type
in the name you think it is
or what it does.
And you might get lucky
and find a shared library.
It's a best practice
that when you're
creating a node project that
you create a package.json file.
Inside here, you can
specify a lot of options.
Here, we're going to specify
the name of the app, the version
of the app-- but the
most important part here
is we're specifying
the dependencies,
the modules that our
application needs to run.
Here you can see our application
requires the connect module.
And we're also specifying
the version number
that our application
needs to run.
Once we specify
the dependencies,
we may want to check that we
have all of them installed.
We can do that by
running NPM install.
This is going to look inside
our package.json file,
and if there's any
dependencies we
don't have in our
node modules directory
it's going to go fetch
them and in this case,
install the connect module.
If you start working on
somebody else's Node project,
it's not going to
have a node modules
directory coming with it--
with all the dependencies.
So you're going to
need to remember
to run NPM install so it'll
go fetch the dependencies
and create that node
modules directory.
Another thing worth
noting is if you
looked inside that connect
folder that was just created,
you would see another
package.json file.
And that might have
more dependencies
that the connect
module depends on.
So when you run NPM
install, it's actually
going to go and not only
fetch your application's
dependencies, but
it's going to go
fetch those modules
dependencies as well.
For example, connect
might go and fetch
the qs library, mime library,
and formidable library
and install that in its
own node modules directory.
Before we get into
the challenges,
we need to make sure
everybody understands
semantic versioning.
This is what NPM uses to
version all of their modules.
So in our library we were
acquiring connect 1.8.7.
That 1 represents a major
version of that module.
The 8 is a minor version.
And the 7 is a patch version.
What's the difference?
Well, a patch version
doesn't change
the API-- doesn't
change the names
of the functions you may call.
A minor version probably won't--
it's a little safer to assume
it's not.
And then a major version,
you can assume will.
If you're developing
a new app, you
might want to make sure
you're using the most
recent technologies.
So in your
package.json you could
write something like this--
connect and then tilde 1.
What that's going to
do is go and fetch
the most recent version
in between 1.0.0
but less than 2.0.0.
Now this of course, is going
to be a little dangerous
because there might be minor
versions that break things.
But if you're
starting an app, you
might be able to
live on the edge.
A little less dangerous,
you can specify tilde 1.8.
This would make sure the version
is greater or equal to 1.8.0,
but less than 1.9.0.
The safest way to
keep up-to-date
with the most recent
patch level would
be to specify tilde 1.8.7,
specifying the patch number.
In this case, it'll look for
versions greater than 1.8.7
but less than 1.9.0.
For more information
on semantic versioning,
check out semver.org.
And with that, it's time
for you to practice using
some modules in the challenges.