[SINGING] Your
online application's
starting to fail.
It's crawling on the network
just as fast as a snail.
We need evented programming
starting from the top.
Better write some code so
the world doesn't stop.
With a non-blocking model,
we will be just fine.
Built on Google
Chrome's V8 runtime.
And all you need to do is
write some JavaScript code,
and use the Real
Time Web with Node.
You're watching Real
Time Web with node.
And this is level 6,
where we're going to be
taking a look at Socket.IO.
Obviously, this is
called Real Time.
Node is really good
at real time apps.
So let's start building
a real time app.
We're going to be building a
chat application in the browser
using WebSockets.
Traditionally, a browser's
request and response cycle
looks something like this, where
the browser sends a request
to the server,
waits around for it
to get back, and then,
whatever, whenever it gets back,
it then renders onto the page.
These days, modern
browsers have WebSockets.
WebSockets allow us to
create a connection with each
of our clients to the server.
Over this connection,
we can send and receive
data from the server back
and forth in real time.
However, we can't rely
on every browser working
with WebSockets, so we
need to use a library,
or a module, that has
intelligent fallbacks in case
the WebSocket doesn't work.
In this case, we're going to
be using the Socket.IO library.
Let's install Socket.IO.
We'll just do npm install
Socket.IO dash dash save,
so it will install it and also
add it to our package.json.
And inside of our
application, we'll
require the express module.
We'll initialize an
express application.
Then we'll create an HTTP server
and have it dispatch requests
to express.
Also we'll require
the Socket.IO module
and also allow it
to use the HTTP
server to listen for requests.
So now, Socket.IO and express
are sharing the same HTTP
server.
We'll then need to
listen for connection
events inside Socket.IO.
And, when a client
connects, we're
simply going to log out client
connected to the console.
Full server index.html
file, using the send file
function we've seen earlier.
And lastly, we'll have our
server listen on port 8080.
Now in the HTML that we're going
to be sending through express,
we need to include the
Socket.IO library--
this will get loaded in
our client's browsers--
and connect to our
Socket.IO server.
Let's add one more thing
to our connection event.
Here, we're going to call client
emit messages, hello world.
So this is emitting
the messages event
on our client, which, in
this case, is our browser.
And we're going to send
the object, hello world.
Then, inside of
our browser, we're
going to listen for
that messages event.
When it gets called,
we'll call alert.
And then we'll have
an alert with the data
that it received, looking
up the hello property, which
has a value of world.
So let's run our code.
First, we'll start
up our Node server.
Then, if we jump into our
browser, go to the right port,
it will connect
using Socket.IO,
send a message back
into our browser,
and we'll get an alert pop up.
We even get the log
message that a client
successfully connected.
And every time we refresh,
it's going to reconnect.
So our browser is
listening for messages.
But we're going to want to
send messages from our browser
when somebody types
something into the chat room
back to our server.
So we also want our server to
listen for the messages event
and, when it does, we'll log
it out to our console, for now.
We then need to write
some JavaScript code that
will run inside the browser
so that, when somebody submits
new code into the chat
room-- in this case,
we're going to just
use some jQuery.
We'll hook onto the
chat form Submit button.
So when somebody
hit Submit, we'll
grab the message out of
the chat input text field,
grab the value from there,
set that equal to the message
variable.
Then we'll emit that
messages event on the server,
by calling socket.emit messages
and simply send in the message
that they typed into
that form field.
Now we'll start up
our Node server again.
And if we go into our
browser, reconnect.
Now, if we jump back into
our browser, type in,
hello, this is dog-- and
we can see that hello, this
is dog, got printed out
back on the console,
and we can go back and forth.
And it works pretty well.
So we know how to send messages
from the server to the client,
and the client to the server.
But this is a chat room.
So we're going to be
having multiple clients
connecting to our server.
And we're going to
need to broadcast
somebody's text that they send
to the chat room to everybody.
Luckily, Socket.IO has
a broadcast property.
And when you call emit on
that broadcast property
with messages, it's
going to send them
to all the other
connected sockets--
in this case, all the other
clients in the chat room.
So now, back on our server, when
our server receives the message
event, this time
around, it's going
to call client.broadcast.emit
messages, data.
That's going to
broadcast the message
to all the other clients
aside from this one that
sent the message.
Back on the client
side, we're going
to revise the messages listener.
In this case, when we
get a messages event,
we simply want to insert
the message onto the screen.
I'm not going to show you
that insert message function,
but you can imagine it
just uses some jQuery
to insert that text
onto the screen.
So let's run our server
again, go to local host, 8080.
We're going to actually
call up another browser
and go to the same port.
So we have two
clients connected.
So now, when we
type in a message,
we say, hello, this is dog.
We can see that it broadcasted
it to the other client.
Then we can say, hello,
no this is Spider.
And we can see that it
broadcast that message
to our other client and also
logged it out to the console.
But you might notice,
we have no idea
who's saying what
on this chat server.
We probably need
some user names.
So how might we implement that?
Well, maybe what we'll
do, on the server side,
is we'll create a join event.
When somebody calls
join, we'll assume
they're going to send
in a name, a variable,
and then we'll set a value on
the client-- client.nickname
equals name.
Setting values this way means
that the value is available,
both on the server
and the client.
Then, back in our client,
when we connect to the server,
we're going to print
out a little status
so we know that we're connected,
then we'll prompt the user,
call that simple
JavaScript function prompt,
what is your nickname,
then we'll take that value
and emit the join event,
sending in the nickname back
to the server.
Now, back in our server, we need
to change our messages listener
so that, before we
broadcast the message,
we get the nickname
of the client
and then, once we've retrieved
the nickname, we'll have a call
back here which
will then broadcast
our message with our username.
Lastly, if you're
in a chat room,
you still get to see
what you type in.
So why don't we just go ahead
and emit the chat message
on the current client,
you know, the one that
invoked the message event, so
that, when we type in some code
and hit Return, we'll see what
we typed back in the browser.
Let's go ahead and
try out this new code.
One browser will go.
It should prompt us
for our username.
This one's Dog.
Let's start up another browser.
And this person's
nickname is Spider.
And we can see, Dog
joined the chat.
Spider joined the chat.
Now, if we type in a message,
it shows us who's typing what.
Can you feel the Real Time?
With Socket.IO, I bet you can.
You know, like communication
going back and forth.
Have some fun with
the challenges.
I'll see you in the next level.