You're watching
Discover Drive, and this
is level four, where
we're going to be
talking about uploading files.
Our application,
Pictures of Pugs,
is using Google Drive
as user storage.
We need to be able to do things
like upload new images, list
images, search images,
download images,
share them, share them
with specific people,
organize pictures
within folders,
get notified when
an image is changed,
and one other top
secret feature that I'll
let you know about
when we get there.
So first off, let's talk about
uploading files from our app
to the user's Google Drive.
To do this, we're
always going to want
to use Multipart Upload.
And as you might know, a
Multipart Upload has two parts.
It has the file, which
contains the document, image,
or whatever, and
it has metadata,
which includes the
title, description,
or other information
about the file.
Our first step is
to load the file
by creating a new UploadIO
object, passing in the path
to the file, as you see here.
Next, since this is
a multipart upload,
we can define some metadata
to accompany our file.
Here you can see we're
defining a title of "Pug"
and a description of, "This
is one photogenic pug."
A full list of
metadata properties
can be found on the Google
website at this link.
Next, we're actually going
to execute the request, which
is going to make a call
out to Google Drive.
It looks a little
something like this.
Now let's go through
this line by line.
First up, all the API calls
we're going to be doing
are going to be made by
calling execute on the client
that we authenticated earlier.
The first option we need to
specify is the API method.
Which method do we want
to call on the Drive API?
Remember that Drive
object we created earlier
that contains all
the API definitions?
Well, here we want to
call drive.files.insert
because we want
to upload a file.
Next up is the
body_object option,
and this is where we
specify our metadata.
In the media
option, that's where
we specify the file
object we created earlier.
And lastly, some
Drive API methods
have some optional or
acquired parameters
that you can pass in here.
In our parameters,
we can specify
that we want to perform
a multipart upload.
Once we run this
line of code, it's
going to call the
Drive API, which
will return some JSON data,
which looks like this.
You'll notice that it
contains all the metadata
for the file we just uploaded.
And it can be accessed in
the result.data object.
The most important piece
of data that gets returned
is the ID of this file.
We're going to need to store
this in our application
so we can reference
this file later.
Here's how we would get the
ID and store it in a variable.
Uploads can fail
sometimes, especially when
you're dealing with large files.
This is why we can use the
resumable upload type instead
of multipart, which will
allow us to continue uploads
where they left
off if they fail.
It's a good practice that if
you have a file less than five
megabytes, you
can use multipart.
But if it's bigger
than five megabytes,
you definitely want to
use a resumable upload.
To do this, all we
have to do is specify
the uploadType resumable inside
the parameters of our upload
call.
We can use this to check to
see if the upload is resumable,
meaning that the upload is
neither complete nor expired,
and we can resume
it and try again.
To resume it, it's
pretty simple.
We just do another
client.execute call,
sending in the
result.resumable_upload object.
Of course there's no
guarantee that it's
going to work the second time
when we resume the upload.
So one way to deal
with this would
be to just put it
in a While loop.
So while the upload
is resumable,
keep on uploading the file.
Of course if it's
a big file, you
wouldn't want your user
to be waiting on you.
So if this code was invoked
by somebody clicking
on a button on a web
page, for example,
you might want to load
this as a background task
in Ruby, maybe using
something like delayed job,
so that the client doesn't
hang, and the upload
happens in the background.
There's another small
problem with our code,
and that is if we
have a While loop,
and we're trying over
and over and over again.
If our error is
recurring quickly,
well, that means we're hitting
the server over and over
and over again, maybe
100 times a second,
to try to do the upload.
And this is a sure way
to hit our usage quota
and to overload our server.
So how might we get around this?
One way to solve this
problem is by using
something called
Exponential Backoff.
This involves waiting an
exponentially increasing amount
of time before
retrying the upload.
I know it sounds confusing,
but bear with me.
So we make one API call.
If it fails, we wait one second.
We try again.
If it fails again,
we wait two seconds.
we wait four seconds.
And then eight seconds.
And then it increases that time.
So that way, if it's
definitely going to fail,
it's going to wait a longer
and longer amount of time
before retrying.
You can read more about
Exponential Backoff
at this link in the slide.
Here's what Exponential Backoff
might look like in Ruby.
So here we've changed
our While loop to a
For loop, which is going to
retry after one, two, four,
eight, and 16 seconds,
finally just exiting out
if it's still unable to connect.
After the loop
finishes, we still
need to know if the file upload
succeeded, if it expired,
or if it tried five
times and failed.
We can do this by checking to
see if the resumable upload is
complete, and we might want
to show the user a success
message.
Finally, if neither of
these conditions are true,
that means the upload
failed to complete.
Otherwise, we must have tried
to do the upload five times,
and it still didn't
succeed, and we
should let the user know that.
Now it's time for you
to start making some API
calls with Google Drive.
See you in the next level.