You're watching
Discover Drive, and this
is level two, where we're going
to be talking about the Google
Picker.
When it comes to handling file
uploads in your application,
the process might look
something like this.
You give an upload form to the
client, they submit a file,
you receive that file
in your application,
and then you might
do something with it.
It's usually a good practice
to take the files that you
get and put them into a content
delivery network, or CDN.
Or we also sometimes call
that a cloud service.
So at this point you might
save it in the cloud,
then you get a URL back
from that cloud service,
which you store,
so your application
knows where that file is.
The Google Picker allows
you to skip the step where
your application
receives the file,
and go straight from the
upload form into the cloud.
It's then going to return
a URL from the cloud back
into your application,
so you know
where to access that file from.
And the URL might look
something like this.
The Google Picker
is a modal window,
which will pop up inside
your web application
and allow the user to
upload or select a file.
You might note here that if
the user isn't authenticated
with a Google account
at this point,
it will prompt them to log in.
In this window, you can
simply drag a folder into it,
or select a file
from your computer,
and it will automatically
be uploaded to Google Drive,
the modal will close and
notify your application
of the URL where this
file can be located.
The Google Picker uploads files
directly into a user's Drive.
This means it's not taking
up space on our server,
it's not using any
of our bandwidth,
and we don't have
to write any code
to parse the file
that's being uploaded.
Lastly, it also
looks a lot nicer
than the standard
file upload form.
You might have
noticed that there's
two links on the navigation
bar in this window-- Upload
and Google Docs.
When they click on this,
it will then show the user
a list of all the files
inside their Google Drive.
They can select one to send
into our web application.
Our application will
then get notified
as to where it can
find this file.
In order to use
the Google Picker,
we first need to learn about
the Google Developers Console.
Inside the console,
we're first going
to create a new API project,
enable the Google Picker API,
create a new OAuth client
ID, developer API key,
then inside of our application
we can include the Google API
loader script,
authorize the user,
and then render the Picker.
We're going to do
that all in one page.
To get to the Developers Console,
you can click on this link
that you'll find in the
slides, or you probably
can Google "Google
Developers Console".
And you'll need to create a
new project once you get there.
Once you create
the project, you'll
want to go into the sidebar,
select APIs and auth, then
select APIs.
And here you'll see
this screen with a bunch
of on and off buttons.
You'll want to enable
the Google Picker API.
Then also under APIs
and auth, you'll
want to look for Credentials,
and click CREATE NEW CLIENT ID.
Here you'll want to make sure to
select Web application and also
input your authorized
JavaScript origins, which
is going to be the
domain of your website.
This page will now
show our client ID,
which we may want to copy
and paste into a file for use
later.
Now we want to go
into Credentials
and click CREATE NEW KEY
and choose Browser key.
We'll then be prompted
to enter our site's URL.
And then this will
generate for us
a new API key, which
we'll need inside
of our browser application.
Now let's jump back into our
web page and load up the Picker.
We've got to do a bunch of
authorization to get there,
but don't worry, we'll take
you through it step by step.
First, we're going to load
the Google API loader script.
It looks something like this.
Now we need to
specify, on load, what
method to call when the API
loader script is ready for use.
We'll declare that in a minute.
Inside the onApiLoad
method, this
is where we specify what Google
API libraries we want to load.
In this case, we first want
to load the Auth library.
We need it to call
a method when it's
done loading the Auth library
called onAuthApiLoad.
Also here, we want to
load the Picker library.
Now inside the
callback method, we
need to authorize
our application
to get access to
the user's Drive.
This call requires the client ID
that we generated a moment ago.
And the scope
option you see here
tells Google we want
access to the user's Drive.
We'll talk a little more about
different scope options later.
Lastly, we need to
specify a method that
will get called once a
user tries to authenticate.
Whether or not it's
successful, it's
going to call this
callback method.
If we loaded up the
page as we have it,
and the user hasn't
authenticated yet,
we would see this prompt.
As you can see, it's
asking for authorization
for our application to get
access to this user's Drive.
After the user attempts
to authenticate,
it's going to call our
callback method, which
we need to define now.
Here you can see it's
checking for the authResult,
and that it didn't
result in an error.
We're then going to
set our AuthToken
to our authResult.access_token.
And we'll create a new
method, which we'll call now,
called createPicker.
Here in our new
createPicker function,
we're first going to build a
new Picker object, like so.
Then we'll set the authToken.
We'll then set the
DeveloperKey, which
we got from the
Developers Console.
And then call the
Build function.
Lastly, to get it
visible on the screen,
we just call
picker.setVisible(true).
If we ran this code as it is,
this is what we would see.
And it's blank.
What's going on?
Well it turns out we're
missing some views.
Views are pages we
can add to the Picker
to give it additional
functionality.
Without any views, well,
we get a blank page.
Every view we add will get
added to the navigation bar.
And as we click on
it, it will render
that view in the
main content area.
To add a view, we use
the addView function.
And we're simply going to chain
that on to our existing Picker
builder.
Like this.
Here we're adding the
google.picker.DocsUploadView.
A full list of the
different views you can add
can be found at this link
at the bottom of the slide.
So with a single view, we now
get the ability to upload files
into our user's Google Drive.
Just like so.
To add the ability for
our user to select files
from their Google Drive, we're
going to add another view--
the DocsView.
Now our modal has two
different views in it,
and we can select the
DocsView to select files
from our Google Drive.
Why don't you try
the Google Picker?
I'll see you in
the next section.