You're watching
Discover Drive where
we're going to be talking about
downloading and sharing files.
So our application
might have just
fetched a bunch of metadata,
saw a bunch of file IDs,
and now we want to
download a specific file.
How do we do that?
Well, if we don't have the
metadata yet for this file,
we're going to want to fetch it
by doing a files.get request.
In the metadata, we're going
to find a download URL.
Next, we're going to make a
new API call, this time passing
in just the download_URL
as a URI option.
What this is going
to do is return
the binary data for this file.
In this case, pug.jpg.
But having the binary data
doesn't do us any good.
We need to store this in
a file in our file system.
So since this is
Ruby, we're going
to call file.open and just
write it out to the file system.
Why don't you give this
a try in the challenges.