You're watching
Discover Drive, where
we're going to be talking
about authenticating
a user with Drive.
We're about to dive into
the Google Drive API.
And we're going to
build an application
along the way called Pictures
of Pugs, which will allow people
to upload and share
pictures of pugs.
Using the Drive API, we can do
things like upload and download
files, store application
data, manage permissions
across those files,
receive push notifications
if those files change,
and a lot of other things.
So let's dive into it.
To get started with the API,
we need to do a few things.
First, we need to go back
to Google's website.
If we haven't yet, we need
to create a new API project,
enable the Drive API,
register a new application,
and customize the
consent screen.
Then in our
application, we're going
to install the Google
client library,
create a client object, get
authorization from the user,
and then we can make API
calls to the user's Drive.
The first few steps
are all really
so we can get a client ID.
This will allow us to
communicate with Google
to get information
about a user's Drive.
So back into the Google's
Developer Console we go.
You might have already
created a project
based on what we showed
you in the previous level,
so if you have,
well, obviously you
don't need to create a new one.
Inside your project,
you're going
to want to go back
to APIs and auth, APIs,
and here you want to enable
the Drive API and Drive SDK.
Now back on the
Credentials page,
we need to create a new
client ID for our application.
We're creating a
web application,
so we'll select that.
We'll enter in our authorized
JavaScript origin, which
is our domain,
and lastly we need
to specify an
authorized redirect URI.
This is the page
in our application
that Google will
redirect users back
to once they've
authorized with Google.
Once we hit that Create
Client ID button,
we'll be given a client
ID that we can then
use in our application.
Next, we might want to
customize our consent screen.
This is the page
that Google shows
users when they're asked to
authorize our application
to get access to their Drive.
And as you can see
here, we can customize
product name, homepage
URL, and logo.
Now that we have OAuth
and our client ID set up,
we can start diving into
calls to the Google Drive API.
In the previous level,
we took all the steps
we needed to get set up
with a Google Drive API
on the Google website.
Now it's time to get the
Google Drive API set up
on our application,
on the server side.
We're going to be using the
Ruby language with a Ruby client
library to do this.
Now don't worry if Ruby's
not your language of choice,
and you prefer something like
PHP, or Python, or Objective-C,
or even Java.
There are client libraries
for all those languages.
And you can still follow
along through this tutorial.
Just when it comes
time to code, you're
going to want to look up how to
do it in your client library.
The three steps we're
going over in this level
is installing the
proper client library,
creating a client
object, and then getting
authorization from the
user to access their Drive.
We'll then be able to make
API calls to the user's Drive,
but that'll be in
the next level.
To install the Ruby
client library,
we're just going to
manually install the gem
by running gem install
google-api-client.
Or if we're using
Bundler, we can add it
to our Gemfile just doing
gem google-api-client.
Then to require the
API in our application,
we just do require
google/api_client.
To use this client, we simply
create a client object,
like you see here.
This is what we'll be
making our API calls on.
Next up, we'll need the
client ID and client secret
that we got from the Google
website on our previous level.
We'll put them in here,
just like you see,
as well as the
redirect URI, where people
are going to get redirected
after they authorize
with Google.
With these variables
in place, we
can request access to
a user's Drive account.
However, we need to
know what type of access
we're requesting.
We could get create,
edit, and delete access
for just the files that
our application creates.
We can get read-only
access to files.
We can get full access to files.
Or there's a few
other options here.
We need to figure out what
type of authorization scope
to request from Google,
which will give us
different levels of
access to a user's Drive.
If we ask for this
first scope, we're
going to get per-file
access to all the files
that we upload through the API.
If we ask for just
Drive scope access,
we get full access
to the user's files.
And if we ask for
Drive.readonly access,
we get read-only access to
file metadata and file content.
It's a best practice
to only request
the minimum level of
authorization you need,
which in most
cases is just going
to be this top authorization.
You only want to
request full access
when it's absolutely necessary.
A full list of scopes can be
found on the Google website
at this link.
We only care about reading
and modifying files
that our application creates.
You know, our Pictures
of Pugs application.
So we can specify that
authorization scope.
In some cases, you might want to
request multiple authorization
scopes, in which case
you can request them
all up front-- so you don't
have to request them again--
by just using an array,
like you see here.
It'll become obvious
why you might
want to do this
in future levels.
Next, we're going to ask the
client library for the URL
that we're going to deliver to
our user to authenticate access
to their Google Drive account.
If we were using Rails, we
would use a redirect command.
So in a controller, we would
redirect them to this URL,
and they would
see something that
looks like this, asking them
if our application, Pictures
of Pugs, can get access
to their Google Drive.
If the user accepts the
authorization request
on the Google website,
they'll be redirected
to the redirect URI
that we set earlier.
Also, attached to this request
when they get sent back
to our server, it's going to
have an authorization code.
Here you can see
what the URL might
look like with the authorization
code appended to it.
We'll want to set
this authorization
code equal to client.code.
Now that we have this code, we
can call the fetch_access_token
method on our client, which
will make a request to Google,
and get back from it
the access token, which
is what actually grants us
access to the user's Drive.
This also sets
the refresh token,
which we can use later
to request a new access
token when it expires.
That way we don't
need to send the user
to authorize with Google every
time we need a new token.
You can read more about
access and refresh tokens over
on the Google
website at this URL.
If you are building a
Ruby web application,
there are other
libraries that'll
make this authentication
even easier, like OmniAuth.
Now that we've done
the authentication
necessary to make
Drive API calls,
we need to load the
Drive API definitions.
To do that, we call
client.discovered_API,
specify the API we want to
load, as well as the version.
This Drive object we've created
contains all the methods
we can use with the Drive API,
which we'll see in a minute.
You can read more about the
Google API's Discovery Service
at this URL.
So we've installed
the client library,
we created the client
object, and we've
done the authorization we need
to start making API calls.
So we're ready to do it.
And we're going to do
that in the next level.
See you then.