I'm Gregg Pollack, and
you're watching Google Drive.
Before we get into
it, we need to make
sure everybody understands
what Google Drive is.
It's a storage
service that allows
us to organize, back
up, share photos, videos,
or any other file
in Google's cloud.
If you have a Google account
and you go to drive.google.com,
you'll see all the
files that you currently
have stored in Drive.
What's great about
this is you can access
these files from your home,
work, or mobile-- any place
that you have a web browser.
Recently, Google created
some native applications.
So you can install Google
Drive on any of your devices,
and they'll automatically
sync and be up to date,
no matter where you are.
What makes Google Drive
even more powerful
is that they've created a
series of Developer Tools that
allows you to integrate Google
Drive into your application.
The first two Developer Tools
we're going to be looking at
are JavaScript tools.
The first is the
Save to Drive button.
This you would put in
your web application
if you have a file you
want to allow users
to download into
their Google Drive.
In the second level, we'll be
looking at the Google Picker.
This replaces your
traditional Upload File form
with something a
little easier to use.
You're probably already familiar
with some applications that
use the Drive API to
store their files.
Applications like Google
Docs, Sheets, and Slides
all use Google Drive as
their primary storage.
When you create new files
using these applications,
you will see them inside
your Google Drive, which
makes it really easy
to click on them
and open them back up in
the appropriate application.
In the same way,
the Google Drive API
allows you to create
applications and use
Google Drive as the
primary user storage.
The application we're going
to be building together
in this course is
Pictures of Pugs,
you know, to store all
of our pictures of pugs.
And the storage here is going to
be using the Google Drive API.
Once our users interact
with our application,
if later they go to
drive.google.com,
they might see a couple
of the pictures that
were saved from our application.
Levels three
through 11, we'll be
going through lots of
different actions you
can do with the Google Drive
API, from uploading files,
to downloading files,
to updating files,
to getting push
notifications, and even
installing and showcasing
your application.
Let me show you what that means.
When we're inside
Google Drive and we
want to create a new file, we
might hit the Create button.
This asks us what kind of
file we want to create,
whether it's a document,
presentation, spreadsheet,
or something else.
Well, Google Drive API allows
you to install your application
inside someone's drive.
So as you can see here,
I can create a new file
with Pictures of
Pugs, our application.
We can also open existing
files inside Pictures of Pugs
by right-clicking on
it inside Google Drive
and selecting Open
with Pictures of Pugs.
In this first level, we're
going to be looking at the Save
to Drive button.
The Save to Drive button
allows your website visitors
to save files into
their Google Drive.
Whether they need to save an
image, a document, a song,
or something else,
there's simply
going to be a link
on your website
that they're going
to click on, and it
will allow them to
save it to Drive.
Here's a picture of
a pug on our website
that we want to allow
a user to save to Drive.
As you can see here,
I can click Save.
And if I'm signed in, it prompts
me to immediately save it
to My Drive, and
then it lets me know
that it's been copied there.
Later on, I can go
into my Google Drive,
and I'll see that
this picture of a pug
has been successfully
saved there.
Much like the plus-one
social media button,
to use the Save to Drive
button, all we need
is some HTML and JavaScript.
First, you'll need to include
this Google JavaScript library.
Then, we need to create
an HTML element.
In this case, we're
going to use a div, which
has the class g-savetodrive.
This can be any HTML tag,
but it needs to have this class.
Then we need to declare
a couple data attributes,
the first of which is going to
be the URL of the file, where
the file is located.
Next will be what we want to
call this file on Google Drive.
And lastly, we'll
include our website name.
This is going to appear
on the Permission Window
when we ask the user if they
want to save it to the Drive.
And that's all there
really is to it.
From here, you can jump
into the challenges
and try to create
your own Drive button,
or skip to the next video,
or one of the future levels
if there's something specific
you want to learn about.