So that's how you download a
file into your application.
But what if you
wanted to provide
a link that the
user could download
this file from in their browser?
You wouldn't give
them the download URL.
What you would give them, though,
is the data.webContentLink.
However, this URL is only going
to be useful to this user,
because it's inside their
Google Drive account.
If they took this URL and shared
it with someone else-- well,
they would see 403.
It's an error because they
don't have access to this file.
This is where
permissions come in.
And the Google API
gives us the ability
to manage file permissions.
And file permissions
come in three parts.
The role-- basically what a user
can do with the file; type--
what type of user we're
granting access to;
and value-- specifying
an identifier
for that type of user,
such as email address.
The most common roles
you'll encounter
are owner, writer, and reader.
The owner can read, modify,
comment on, and delete.
The writer can read, modify,
and comment on the file.
And the reader obviously
can just read it.
You can read more about roles
at this URL on Google's website.
Using types and
values, we can specify
what user or group of
users gets assigned
to the role we just specified.
If we specify user as
a type, then our value
is going to be a
user's email address.
If we specify a
group, the value is
going to be a group's
email address.
If we specify a
domain, the value
is going to be the
Google Apps domain.
And if we specify
anyone as a type,
then the value
doesn't really matter,
because this link is
going to be public.
You can read more about
types and values here.
Let's create a
permission that gives
a friend of ours, an
individual, access
to read one of our pug images.
So here we'd specify the
role of reader, the type
to user, because this
is an individual.
And the value would be
their email address.
We now need to make an API call
to the permissions.insert API
method, passing in as the body
object the permission object
we just created, and specifying
in the parameters which
file we're setting
permissions on.
The response will simply contain
details about the permission,
letting us know that it
was successfully created.
The user will be automatically
notified via email
that they've been granted
read access to this file.
The email might look
something like this.
The user can open the file by
clicking the link in the email.
Or if they go to
their Google Drive
and click on the Shared
With Me navigation link,
they'll see that this file
was shared with them in Drive.
Now it's time for a few more
challenges on permissions.