Welcome back.
So in the previous level,
we saw how Google Picker
allows us to take file
uploads and bring them
right into a user's
Google Drive.
But once it's there, how does
our application get notified
where that file's
located on their drive.
How does it get that URL?
Well if we look at our
current application,
and we select a file, and
hit that Select button,
well, it's not going to work.
And that's because we
need to specify a callback
function to receive
information about the file that
was selected.
Let's see how to do that.
What we need to do is add
another change function,
the setCallback function.
And then we're going to specify
the pickerCallback function,
which we're going to define now.
This function receives some
data, which contains information
about the file, and the action
that triggered the callback.
The first thing we
might want to do here
is check to see if
the action is picked,
which is triggered when the
user picks or uploads a file.
We can also check to see if the
user hit Cancel, in which case
it will return
the cancel action.
In this data object,
we can access things
about the file, like the
name, description, and URL.
In our case, we're just
going to print out an alert
to the screen with
the URL of the file.
Now you might notice here
that docs is an array.
That's because sometimes
we might allow a user
to select multiple files
inside of our Google Picker.
There are a lot of
other properties
about a file that you
might want to access,
including its content.
And we'll show
you how to do that
using the Drive API
in future levels.
If we ran this code
and selected a file,
you can see here
that an alert pops up
with the URL where we can access
the file we just selected.
If we do want to allow our
user to select multiple files,
we need to enable
that as a feature
by using the enableFeature
method, like you see here,
with MULTISELECT_ENABLED.
We can also disable
features with
the disableFeature function.
And you can find
a list of features
at this URL on the slide.
That's the end of level two.
It's time for you to
complete your Google Picker.
And I'll see you
in the next level.