Welcome back.
In the previous
level, we took a look
at how to upload
files into Drive,
and get back identifiers
for those files.
But how do we then look up
files inside someone's Drive
and get information about them?
This is where metadata comes in.
We can get information like
title, description, mimeType,
links for sharing
and downloading,
from getting the metadata.
To retrieve a
file's metadata, we
need to initiate a files.get
request, as you see here.
We'll need to send
in the file ID
that we received when we
uploaded the file initially.
We'll then get back from the
server all the file's metadata.
This might look familiar.
This is the same data that we
get back when we upload a file.
We can access this
metadata in the response
by calling result.data.
So we can do result.data.title,
and result.data.description.
But what if we want to
list out all the files
that we have access
to in a user's Drive?
To do this, we do a
file.list request.
Don't forget, the
files we have access to
are determined by the
authorization scope
that we initially set.
The response will look
something like this.
Inside of it we'll
see an items array,
which will have all the
files that we have access to.
Each item in this array
isn't the entire file,
it's simply the
metadata for each file
that we have access to.
And we can simply
do a loop if we
want to iterate through
each item that was returned,
and print out the title.
What happens when we have a
lot of files stored on Drive,
and we need to
filter through them?
Well, we can actually
do some search queries
when we do our initial request.
We do this by providing a field
that we want to filter by,
an operator, like
"contains", and a value.
Obviously, this would
return only files
that title contains puppy.
Let's take a look at a few
metadata fields with operators
and value types you
can use with them.
So here you can see title.
The value here is
going to be a string.
And the operators
we can use with it
are either contains or equals.
We can do a full
text search, which
includes title,
description, and for files
containing text content.
So we can see if any of these
contain a certain string.
We can also search by mimeType,
so the type of file it is,
like perhaps a text
file or an image.
And lastly, we can
search by modified date.
A full list of
searchable metadata
can be found at this URL.
To do a search for a
particular list of files,
we simply use the API method
drive.files.list and send
in the queue parameter,
meaning query,
with our field,
operator, and value.
The response is
going to look exactly
like the response from
our files.list call, which
has an array of items
we can iterate through.
But what if we have
multiple search parameters?
Like if we wanted to only find
images with a title of "puppy".
So we can add a new clause
to refine our query results,
using the And operator to
combine multiple clauses.
Here you can see,
we're searching
for title contains puppy, and
mimeType equals image/jpeg.
So we can find cute
little images of puppies.
If we wanted to find
a file that has "puppy"
not only in its title, but
maybe also in its description,
or if it was a text file, in
the contents of the file itself,
we can search on the fullText
field, like you see here.
Time for you to get
some metadata and search
for some files.
See you in the next level.