[SINGING] The time has
come for a .NET quest,
the MVC pattern
ensures your success.
Building with models,
views, and controllers
is better than jousting
with oversized ogres.
You'll be fetching data and
routing requests with C sharp carved
on your family crest.
Rescue your web
apps and let them
be free by writing and
trying .NET MVC,
by writing and
trying .NET MVC.
Welcome to "Try .NET MVC."
My name is Eric Fisher.
In this course, we're going to
learn to make a web application
using a .NET Framework.
In our first level, we're going
to learn about the Model View
Controller structure.
So what is ASP.NET MVC?
It is a framework for
the rapid development
of web applications.
It handles everything
from the UI to the server.
And while being a
Microsoft product,
you'd think it'd
only run in Windows.
It actually can also
run on Linux and OS 10.
So imagine we're
playing a tabletop game,
and we're keeping all of
our stuff on notebook paper.
Now, we've got a lot of
papers to keep track of.
You can't really search through
them in an organized way.
And any time we update or erase
anything, it gets really messy.
To solve that problem, we're
going to make a .NET MVC
application.
This application is
going to allow our users
to add their own
characters, and we'll
provide the full list of
characters back to the user.
Before we write any
code, let's look
at how data moves through
our MVC application.
The user enters a
URL into the browser.
This makes a request.
The controller
takes this request,
accesses the data in the model,
and then passes that model data
on to the view.
The view is then presented
back to the user.
When you create a
new MVC project,
we're going to get a number
of folders to start with.
We'll have a root
folder that will have
the same name as our project.
We'll also have folders
Models, Views, and Controllers
contained in that folder.
These three folders
represent the parts
of MVC-- Models,
Views, Controllers.
We'll be doing most of our
work in these three folders.
You'll notice these
three shield icons
we have next to the folders.
When you see these
icons, you'll know
what part of the application
you're actually working in.
The names of files and folders
are very important in MVC.
As you can see, we have
a HomeController.cs file
in the Controllers folder,
a Home.cs file in the Models
folder, and an Index.cshtml file
in the Home folder in the Views
folder.
Now, you'll notice all
three of these have Home.
Because our Home controller
has the same name as our Home
Directory inside
our Views folder,
these will automatically map up.
At this point, we're going to
create an Index.cshtml file
in our Home folder.
Now, how you actually
create this file is
going to depend on what tool
you're using to make it.
A cs.html file is
a template file.
It allows us to use both HTML
and C#-like code to generate
our pages.
In our Index.cshtml file,
we've entered some raw HTML.
As you see here, this HTML will
present our list of characters.
The problem is, we can't update
this list without directly
updating this file.
Our names need to
be dynamic, but how
are we going to do that?
To update the name dynamically,
we need to do two things.
We need to update our view to
be able to accept incoming data.
We also need to update our
controller to send that data.
We're going to deal
with the view first.
We'll add @model String.
This lets our view know
that we're expecting
a single string for our data.
When you start
mixing HTML and C#,
you're using a built-in
engine called Razor.
To access that string we're
passing into our view,
we're going to use @Model.
Notice though that this @Model
is an uppercase as opposed
to lowercase.
We'll need to pay attention to
the capitalization of @model.
Lowercase @model
defines the data
we're going to
send into our view.
Uppercase @Model gives
us access to the data
we send to our view.
Now that our view is
ready to accept data,
we need to set up our
controller to send data.
We have a Home Controller that
comes when we made our project.
We're going to go look at the
code that's already there.
Looking inside our
Home Controller,
our Home Controller
class is broken up
into three separate parts.
We have the Index, which
is a method, the class,
which is the Home Controller,
and the namespace,
which is the name of our
application, .controllers.
You'll notice our Index method
returns an IAction result.
Any method that returns
an IAction result is also
known as an action method.
IAction result provides
responses usable by browsers.
We're going to go
into our Index method,
and we're going to
create a string, name.
We're going to set this
name string to Hux, which
is one of our character names.
Then we'll pass name
in as a parameter view.
As you can see here, our
Index action is now working.
We're now getting data
from our controller
to our view dynamically.
Now it's your turn to set
up a view and a controller
in the challenges.
Have fun.