Welcome back.
In this section, we're
going to learn about routes.
Routes are how our application
uses the URL to determine what
controller and controller
action it wants to access.
In our last section, the
action we were accessing
would have been Home/Index.
How exactly do our routes
map up with our controllers
and actions?
When you look at our URL--
www.example.com/Home/index--
the first directory you'll
see typically maps up with
the controller.
So in this case, Home would
map up to the Home Controller.
While the second
part, Index, would
typically map up to the
action, in this case, Index.
The controller also maps to
the views in the same manner.
You'll notice our
home controller,
with its index action,
maps up to our home
directory in our Views
folder and our Index
view inside that directory.
In this case,
returning View will
return the view in the Home
folder with the Index action.
Normally, when we
go to a website,
we don't go to
whatever.com/Home/Index.
We would just type
in whatever.com.
You'll notice, when
we access our website,
even if we don't enter
Home/Index, we still get there.
This is because of a concept
known as default routes.
With default routes,
anytime you omit
the controller or the
action from the URL,
it's going to default a
controller and action.
Normally, it will default
these to Home/index.
Why don't you try identifying
some routes in the challenges,
and I'll see you in
the next section.