Welcome back.
In this section,
we're going to learn
how to use models to give
our data some structure.
Where we left off, we were
only showing a character name.
But being that we're making
this for a tabletop game,
we know we're going to
need stats down the road.
So we're going to need more than
a string to accomplish this.
Instead of just
using a string, we're
going to create a model
class Character.cs.
And we're going to
put this character
class inside our Models folder.
When we access our
Character class,
there's already going
to be some code there.
We're going to need to add
a field name to our class.
We can do this by adding
public string Name.
You'll notice our Name
field we've capitalized.
This is because whenever we
have a public field, variable,
or property, we want to do
those in Pascal case, which
means the first
letter is capitalized
and every word within
that name is capitalized.
At this point, we're
going to go back
to our index action,
our home controller,
and we're going to change it
from using a string to using
our Character model.
Before, we were
setting our string
to Hux, which is our
character's name.
Instead, we want to set our
model's Name field to Hux.
We'll then pass our
entire model into our view
instead of just a string.
If we were to run
this now, we would
get an error-- the
type or namespace name
"Character" could not be found.
We're getting this error
because our character
isn't in the same namespace
as our controller.
In .NET, we keep a number
of name spaces to help with
the division of concerns.
For example, each one of our
directories, models, views,
and controllers will be
within their own namespaces.
This is to help prevent
us from accessing
code we don't intend to.
Back in our home
controller, instead
of using just
Character, we're going
to go ahead and
add the namespace
in front of Character.
We get this namespace by looking
at our actual Character class
in our Models folder and
seeing that it's the name
of our application .models.
Because we've changed
the data we're
passing from our
controller to our view,
We also need to go into our
view and change the type of data
it's expecting.
We're going to use the full
namespace for Character here.
At this point, though,
we were using @Model.
Unfortunately, now @Model
corresponds with the character
object and won't
give us the name.
So we're going to change it
@Model.Name to get the Name
field from our character.
At this point, we have
a complete, simple MVC
application.
The browser would make a
request to our controller.
Our controller would
then set the model data
and then pass that
on to the view.
And then our view would
render that data dynamically.
Now it's your turn to
set up your own model
in the challenges.
I'll see you in the next level.
To solve this problem,
we're going to make a--
[BEEPING]
To solve this
problem, we're going--
[BEEPING]
To solve that problem--
that was way too much.
[BEEPING]
To solve that
problem-- problem--
[BEEPING]
To solve that problem--
That was good.
Yeah.
And I even paused, like,
to sanity check it,
which was the problem--
was I pause to sanity--