[SINGING] The time has
come for a .NET quest,
the MVC pattern
ensures your success.
Building with models,
views, and controllers
is better than jousting
with oversized ogres.
You'll be fetching data and
routing requests with C sharp carved
on your family crest.
Rescue your web apps and let them be
free by writing and trying .NET
MVC.
By writing and trying .NET MVC.
Welcome back to Try .NET MVC.
My name is Eric Fisher.
In this level, we're going to
go over getting user input.
In the last level, we set up a
review to use data dynamically.
Unfortunately, we
were still hard coding
that data in the controller.
So we need to set
up our application
to be able to accept user input.
To accomplish this,
we're going to need
to create a form in our view.
We're going to need
to add a Create method
to our controller.
And we'll need to move our
existing logic from our Index
action to our Create action.
We'll start by adding a basic
form to our Index.cshtml view,
as you can see here.
When we add our
Create method, it's
going to look a lot
like our Index method.
The big difference here is we're
going to be accepting a string
parameter.
Now, you'll notice the
name of this parameter
is character name.
You'll also notice that
the input field on our form
is also named character name.
Because the name
of our input field
and the name of our
parameter are the same,
these will automatically map up.
When we hit the submit
button, whatever
we enter into that text
box is automatically
going to be populated
into our parameter.
So let's take that
Create method and move it
into our home controller.
We'll put it right
after our Index method.
Now currently, our Index method
is creating our character,
setting its fields.
And that's really the
purpose of our Create method.
So we're going to go ahead and
take the code from our Index
method and move it down
to our Create method.
And then we'll set our
index back to just returning
a simple view.
We were hard coding our
character's name field,
but let's go ahead
and use that character
name we've been passing
into our parameter instead.
Before, we didn't have to
specify the name of the view
because our actions' name
matched the name of the view
it was returning.
Instead, we're going to specify
the view in our Create method
by adding Index as the
first parameter for our view
we are returning.
This'll have the effect
of returning our index
view with the data when our
Create method is called.
The last thing we're going
to do is go to our view
and tell our form what
action we want to access.
We do this by using what's
called a tag helper.
In this case, we're
going to use asp-action,
and we're going to
set that to Create
to access our Create method.
Because our index view happens
to be in the home folder
and accessing the
home controller,
we wouldn't need to
specify what controller,
because the automatic
mapping would help.
But in the event I needed to
reach into a controller that
didn't automatically
have that mapping,
I could use
asp-controller, and then
specify the controller
I want to access.
At this point, our view is
now able to accept user input
and render that input
in the list below.
Now it's your turn to
create a view that accepts
user input in the challenges.
Have fun.
The structure of an ASP.NET
MVC project-- ah, that's
a terrible way to start it.
[INAUDIBLE]
You could pick it up from--
Applications-- the-- [INAUDIBLE]