[SINGING] The time has
come for a .NET quest,
the MVC pattern
ensures your success.
Building with models,
views, and controllers
is better than jousting
with oversized ogres.
You'll be fetching data and
routing requests with C sharp carved
on your family crest.
Rescue your web apps and
let them be free by writing
and trying .NET MVC-- by
writing and trying .NET MVC.
Welcome back to Try .NET MVC.
My name is Eric Fisher.
In this level, we're going to
work on retaining user data.
At the end of our last level,
we were accepting user input
and we were rendering
that back on the screen.
The problem is every time
you had entered the username
and hit that Add
Character button,
it would wipe out whatever
we had before and just
put the new name down.
It's really not what we want
for actually maintaining
a list of characters.
We need a way to
persist that data.
So we could use arrays
to accomplish this,
but there's a better
option called lists.
See, arrays, while
you can resize them,
it's not very elegant or
easy to do-- versus a list
is just a single line of code.
Generally you'll
want to use arrays
when you have groups of
objects of a fixed size.
When you don't know what
the size is, or the size is
going to change, you probably
should stick to a list.
Back in our index view, we were
accepting our character object,
but now we want to have a
list of character objects.
We can do this by having the
word "list", angle bracket,
our character object,
angle bracket.
This means instead of
sending one character object,
we'll be able to send a
list of character objects.
We were accessing one
character's name field before.
At this point, though, we
have a list of characters.
So we're going to need
to be able to iterate
through the individual
characters to list their names.
So one way we could accomplish
this is with the C# foreach
loop.
The way we can use that
in our cs.html page
is to go @foreach
var item in Model,
then for each item
in our list, this
would allow us to add
another list item.
The @ symbol allows us to use
C# code inside an HTML page.
You may be wondering why
we don't have the @ symbol
in front of our curly braces.
Razor does a really good job
at knowing when we intend
to jumping in and out
of C# very fluidly.
Here you can see the parts of
this code that are C# and HTML.
So the next thing
we need to do is
create a place to actually
store our list of characters.
Now normally you'd want to
use something like a database,
but that's beyond the
scope of this course.
So what we're going
to do is we're
going to use what's known
as a global variable.
Now one thing I am going
to caution you is you do
want to use global
variables sparingly,
as they can cause lots
of problems if misused.
So just like before, when we
create our character model,
we're going to have
some existing code.
So we're going to add a
characters variable of type
list character.
We do want to make sure we have
only one list of characters.
That way every one of our users
doesn't have their own list.
But how would we
accomplish that?
We can ensure we have only
one list of characters
by making our characters
variable static.
What static does is it makes
sure I can only ever have
one instance of an object.
We're also going to have to make
sure that our global variables
class is static as well.
If we were to run this,
we'll get a namespace error
like we did earlier.
In this case, though, it's
unhappy about us having list.
Now, we could put the entire
namespace in front of list
like we did before
with characters.
For the list, that would be
System.Collections.Generic.
And this works, but if we
plan on using multiple lists,
this could get messy
and repetitive.
Instead, we're going
to try using what's
called a using directive.
We do this by adding using
System.Collections.Generic
to the top of our file.
This is a way for us to be
able to access classes outside
of our current namespace
throughout our file.
So now that we have a
place to store our data,
we need to go ahead and set
up being able to actually
set and retrieve that data.
We're going to go into
our character model
and add those methods
after our name field.
The first method we're
going to add to our model
will be a create method.
It's going to be a lot
like the create method we
had in our controller.
It's going to accept a
character name parameter,
create a new character
object, set the name
field of that character
to the parameter,
but instead of returning a
view like in our controller,
we're going to add our character
object to our global variables
characters list.
We can do this by using .Add.
One thing we do need
to be careful about
is making sure our
characters list isn't null.
If we had tried to add a
character and it's null,
we're going to get an error.
The way we can accomplish this
is add a simple conditional
that checks to see if our
characters list is null,
and if it is null,
we will set it
to be a new list of characters.
We're also going to
make this method static.
What a static method
allows us to do
is it allows us to access that
method without instantiating
the class it lives in.
We can call this by using
Models.Character.Create
then passing in the string.
So let's add that to our home
controller's create method.
Since our create
method is static,
we can call it without
instantiating it first.
We're going to make one more
change to our create method,
and that's going to be
returning a redirect to action.
What that's going to do is
instead of returning the view,
it's going to actually take us
to the index action in our home
controller.
We're doing this to help prevent
the user from accidentally
saving the same character
twice by refreshing the page.
Now we have everything we
need to create a new character
in our model and controller.
But we need a way to actually
get that data, to view it.
The way we're going to
accomplish this is we're
going to go back into
our character model
and create a Get All method.
This Get All method
is just going
to return a list of characters
from the global variables
characters list.
Now just like we had
to worry about nulls
in our create method, we've
got to make sure to handle them
in our Get All method as well.
Now our home
controller's index method
becomes as simple
as taking the view
and just passing in our
Models.Character.GetAll method.
So as you can see here, when
we go ahead and type in a name
into our input field, hit
Submit, it'll add to the list.
And if we enter a different
character, hit the Submit
button, it'll add that
name to the list as well.
One thing we can do to
improve our application
is right now every
time we go to access
GlobalVariables.Characters,
we're
having to check it
for null manually.
And while this works, that can
create a lot of duplicate code.
What we're effectively
doing is any time it's null,
we're defaulting it to a
new list of characters.
But we can do this
exact functionality
by changing our characters
list into a property.
The way we can change a field
or a variable into a property
is by adding curly brace, "get",
semicolon, "set", semicolon,
curly brace.
This is what's known
as a get setter.
And now all we have to do to
give our property a default
value is to add equals and then
our new list of characters.
Now in the event our
characters property is null,
it will use this new
list of characters
as the default value.
So when we started
this course, we
set ourselves two
goals to accomplish.
The first goal was to be able
to add characters to a list.
The second goal was to be
able to display that list.
We've accomplished both of
those goals using an ASP.NET MVC
application.
It's your turn to retain user
data in a global variables
class.
I'll see you in
the wrap-up video.
Why don't you
practice identifying
some routes and the challenges?
I'll see you in
the next section.
Why don't you-- [LAUGHTER]
Little too much.
I'm going to need you
to come in on Saturday
and do some challenges.
.