[SINGING]
He's got money in a suitcase
and a map on his phone.
He's got the secret location
of the deadliest drone.
He'll use pins and annotations
to find his destination.
The MapKit framework will help
his world domination.
He'll land at the coordinates
and load up his pack.
The only secret agent who
can blow it off the map.
He's Mr. Higgie.
I'm Jon Friskics and
this is iOS Maps.
We've got a problem, Mr. Higgie
has gone missing, but
with the tools and tricks that
we're going to learn in this
course, we're going to be able
to find his location using the
MapKit framework.
In this course, we're going to
be learning how to link to the
Apple Maps application.
We're going to be learning how
to put a map in our own app,
and then we're going to learn
how to track the user location
of our device, how to add points
on that map, how to
bring in an existing set of
points from the web, and even
calculate the distance between
points on the map so we can
find out which points
are closest to our
device at the time.
To do this, first we'll need to
set up the MapKit framework
and we'll load some points
into the Apple Maps
application which is installed
on every iPhone.
When we first create a new
project in Xcode, our screen
is going to look something
like this.
To add the MapKit framework to
this project, first we're
going to need to look in the
file browser on the left side
of the project window, find our
application target, and
then we'll need to scroll down
and find the Linked Frameworks
and Libraries section
in the middle part
of the project window.
There's a little plus icon at
the bottom left of that window
that we need to tap.
And that's going to bring up a
dialog that asks us to choose
frameworks and libraries
to add.
If we search for the MapKit
framework, and double click it
to add it, when we're done,
our window should look
something like this.
Whenever you add the MapKit
framework, it's a good idea to
also add the core location
framework so you can repeat
the steps I just showed you to
add that framework as well.
So to start out, we have
information about a place,
Envy Labs at this coordinate.
We want to leave our app and
show this place in the Apple
Maps application.
So let's talk about what format
that coordinate is in.
The format of our coordinate
is latitude and longitude.
In case you're not familiar,
latitude and longitude is a
way to find any place
on planet Earth.
The latitude lines on a map
run east and west and the
longitude lines run
north and south.
And the combination of a
latitude and longitude value
is enough to locate any
place on earth.
While Earth is a 3D sphere,
whenever we're looking at a
map of places on Earth on our
phone, it's going to be a 2D
projection.
And there's a couple different
types of projections that you
can use that distort the map
in different ways and show
different parts of the map
in tiny different ways.
One of those projections
is equirectangular.
The very center of this map is
at the latitude and longitude
zero, zero.
And latitude values range from
positive 90 to minus 90, while
the longitude values
range from minus
180 to positive 180.
The combination of any two
latitude and longitude numbers
within that range is going to
locate any point on a map.
The problem with an
equirectangular projection is
that some of the top and bottom
locations on the map
actually get distorted
a little bit.
So Apple Maps uses a different
projection called the Mercator
Projection.
The important thing to know
about the Mercator Projection
is that it doesn't actually go
all the way to positive 90 and
negative 90, it stops around
positive 85 and negative 85.
This is going to be OK because
the only locations that are
above and below those numbers
are in some of the far regions
of the North Pole and
the South Pole.
So most of the locations that
we're going to be trying to
find on planet Earth are going
to fit inside of this Mercator
Projection just fine.
So that coordinate we showed
you a second ago was at
28.5407 latitude and negative
81.3786 longitude and that's
actually the location of the
Envy Labs office if you were
to plot it in a map.
And that's here in
Orlando, Florida.
Now that we understand what
these points mean, let's work
on getting some code inside of
our app that is going to open
this coordinate in the Apple
Maps application.
We've created a view
controller called
MapLoadViewController.
And in the header of that
ViewController, we'll import
the MapKit framework so that we
can use the map code inside
of this ViewController.
We'll also create an array
called map locations that's
going to store any locations
that we want to
display on the map.
And then we'll also create a
method called open in Apple
Maps that we're going to
link up to a button.
And when that button is tapped,
then we're going to be
directed to the Apple
Maps application.
Over in the implementation file
of MapLoadViewController,
we're going to create the
map locations array.
This array right now contains
an NS dictionary that has
three keys, name,
lat, and long.
The value of name is going to be
an NSString, Envy Labs, and
the value of lat and long are
going to be NS numbers.
It's a good idea to start out
with an array, if you think
you're only going to have one
point because it's really easy
to add extra points
later on once you
already have that array.
Next, we'll add a UIButton to
the ViewController that when
tapped, calls the open
in Apple Maps method.
This code should look familiar
because we've taught this in
previous iOS courses here
at Code School.
Before we write all the code
for our open in Apple Maps
method, we're going to need to
talk about what kind of data
Apple Maps is expecting to
receive when this method runs.
So Apple Maps is expecting
an object
that's of type MKMapItem.
And MKMapItem is a container
that holds a couple different
properties inside of it.
So let's examine what those
properties are.
The first property is called
placemark and it's of type
MKPlacemark.
Now that has a lot of properties
of its own.
But the one we're most concerned
with is this
property called location that
is of type CLLocation.
CLLocation, like before, has
some properties of its own.
But the one we're concerned
with is a property called
coordinate that's of type CL
location coordinate 2D.
Now notice how there's
no star next to
CLLocation coordinate 2D.
That's because it's not
actually an object.
It's a C struct.
Since Objective C is built on
a C language, sometimes you
mix and match Objective C
objects and regular C data
types like structs.
So our CLLocation coordinate
2D is not an object.
It's actually just a struct.
And we'll look at how to access
that in a second.
Finally, this struct contains
two values of its own, one
called latitude and one called
longitude that are both of
type double, which is just
a floating point number.
This feels like a lot
of different pieces.
So let's take each one of those
pieces one at a time.
So first, we're going to want
to create those double
versions of latitude
and longitude.
And we can do that by accessing
our map locations
array at position zero using
the lat and long keys, and
then turning those NS numbers
into double numbers by passing
them the double value message.
Next, we'll take those two lat
and long double variables that
we just created and create a
CLLocation coordinate 2D using
the CLLocation coordinate
2D make function.
This function takes a latitude
and longitude number and wraps
them up into a CLLocation
coordinate 2D struct.
Then, we'll create our
MKPlacemark object using the
standard alloc init pattern,
although this time, we'll
actually use a convenience
initializer called init with
coordinate address dictionary
so that we can pass our
CLLocation coordinate 2D struct
into the MKPlacemark
initializer all in one step.
And now that we have a placemark
object, were finally
ready to create an MKMap item
and we can do that using the
alloc init with placemark
convenience initializer,
passing in our new MKPlacemark
object to create the map item.
We can set a few more properties
on this map item
before we send it over
to Apple Maps.
One of those is the name
property, which is going to
show up in the call out bubble
that appears whenever we tap
our pin in Apple Maps.
In addition to name, you can
also set phone number or set
URL to pass some additional
data over to Apple maps.
And the moment you've all been
waiting for, we're finally
going to open this map item in
Apple Maps by passing at the
open in maps with launch
options message.
As you can see here, we're not
passing in any launch options.
Were just opening our map item
in the Apple Maps application.
So you can see that we
tap the button in
MapLoadViewController and the
app switches over to Apple
Maps and shows our MKMap
item on the map.
There are some useful launch
options that you might want to
pass in when you're opening
Apple Maps and they come in
the form of an NS dictionary.
You've got MK launch options map
type key, which allows you
to pass in one of three
different map types, standard,
satellite, or hybrid.
And you actually pass those in
as an NSNumber, either zero,
one, or two.
You can pass in the MAP Center
or the Map Span which is going
to determine how much of
the map area is shown.
You can pass in a Boolean that
will show traffic or turn
traffic detection off.
And you can even launch
directly into driving
directions from your current
location by passing in the MK
launch options directions mode
driving value or MK launch
options directions mode
walking to get walking
directions.
And here you can see the result
of passing in some
launch options.
We're opening the map with a
hybrid map display centered on
our placemark, and
we're turning the
traffic detection on.
So now it's your turn to work
with MK map items in the
challenges.