[SINGING]
He's got money in a suitcase
and a map on his phone.
He's got the secret location
of the deadliest drone.
He'll use pins and annotations
to find his destination.
The mapkit framework
will help his--
World Domination.
[SINGING]
He'll land at the coordinates
and load up his pack, the only
secret agent who can blow
it off the map.
He's Mr. Higgie.
Welcome back.
In this level, we'll be looking
at how to add a map
inside your application so that
you don't have to open up
the Apple Maps app every time
you want to view map data.
The number one reason why you
might want to add a map into
your own application is that
once you redirect to the Apple
Maps application, there's no
easy way to redirect back to
your own app.
The only way to do that is to
close out the Apple Maps app
and then open up
your app again.
And most users are going to find
that really annoying and
inconvenient.
To get this in our own app,
let's first add a view
controller called
MapViewController.
And we'll add an object that's
an MKMapView as a subview in
that view controller.
We've created a view controller
to hold the map
inside of our app, called
MapViewController.
And that MapViewController is
going to have a subview that's
of type MKMapView.
MKMapView is the MapKit class
that adds a map inside of an
application.
Just like before, we need to
add the MapKit framework to
the MapViewController class
in order to access
all the MapKit functions.
We also need to take an
extra step, though.
We need to add a delegate
protocol to this view
controller called
MKMapViewDelegate.
This is a protocol that contains
a bunch of useful
methods for working
with map views.
And finally, we'll
need to create a
property of type MKMapView.
And I'll call this
one mapView.
Next, in our MapViewController
implementation file, we'll
want to create an MKMapView
object using
the alloc init method.
Then we'll set the frame of
that mapView to cover the
entire screen.
We'll remember to set the
delegate of our mapView object
to self, because self is the
class that contains our
delegate protocol.
And finally, we'll add
our mapView as a
subview of the main view.
The result of running that code
as is looks like this.
This is really just a map view
that encompasses most of the
United States.
What if we want to zoom in,
though, and not show the
entire United States at once
and just show one state?
Well, MapKit does not
actually contain
any methods for zooming.
If you've worked with another
map API, like Google Maps,
you're probably used to having
a method that zooms directly.
MapKit does not provide that.
So we have two options.
The first one is to create
a map region using the
MKCoordinateRegion class.
And to do that, we'll need the
center latitude and longitude
point of where we want
our map to display.
And we need a width and a height
of the area that we
want to display on the screen.
The other option is to use
something called an MKMapRect.
And with that option, we're
actually creating a rectangle
with top left, top right, bottom
left, and bottom right
points, and displaying
a map that fits
inside of that rectangle.
Everything that we're going to
need to do in this course,
we're going to be able to
accomplish with regions.
So that's what we're going
to be teaching you.
To set the display area with an
MKCoordinateRegion, we need
a center latitude and
longitude point.
And then we also need
some dimensions.
We need to know the width of
the region we're trying to
display and the height
of the region that
we're trying to display.
Now when we're creating a
region, the dimensions are
what's called best fit, which
means that we might pass in a
region that doesn't perfectly
fit in the dimensions of our
iPhone screen.
And MapKit is automatically
going to try to scale that
region so that it fits
the best that it can
inside of the view.
The code for setting a region
starts out by creating a
CLLocationCoordinate2D
that's the center
coordinate of the map.
Next we'll create variables
for the region width and
region height.
And if we use the
CLLocationDistance class, we
can actually just set those two
numbers that are in meters.
Once we've got a center region
width and region height, we
can pass all of those values
into the MKCoordinateRegi
onMakeWithDistance function.
That function is going to return
an MK Coordinate Region
that we can then send into the
map view using the setRegion
animated message.
Since you can call setRegion
more than one time in a view
controller, setting the animated
to yes means that the
region will animate its
transition as opposed to just
replacing the old region
with the new one.
Here's the result of calling
the setRegion method.
Now, wouldn't it be nice to
know where on this map the
phone that's running
the app is?
You've seen it before.
There's a little blue dot that
pulses on the screen, has a
little animated pulse.
How do we get that
into our app?
Well, it's really easy.
All we need to do is set the
showsUserLocation property of
the mapView object to yes.
And when we do that and re-run
our app, we'll get that will
pop-up the first time that asks
us if we want to share
our location with the app.
And if we say yes, then the blue
dot will appear at our
current location.
I also want to note that the
location tracking will stay on
until you set the
showsUserLocation property
back to no.
This could be important in your
app if you're worried
about battery performance,
because the longer that you
leave location tracking
on, the quicker the
battery will drain.
The iOS Simulator can actually
simulate the location of the
device when you're running
it on your Mac.
And you can do this by going
into the Debug, Location,
Custom Location menu option
and setting a latitude and
longitude for where that little
blue dot will always
appear when you open the app.
This is not something you're
going to have to do in our
challenges.
But if you're using Xcode at
home, this is an important
feature that you'll
want to look into.
Now that we've got the user
location on the map, what if
we wanted to recenter our region
so that it's centered
on the blue dot?
Well, you might try to do
something like this, where
after you set the
showsUserLocation property to
yes, you pass the
setCenterCoordinate animated
message to the mapView.
And for that center coordinate,
you pass in
self.mapView.use
rLocation.location.coordinate.
This is going to be the
coordinate that represents the
location of the blue
dot on the map.
Well, if you ran this code, this
actually wouldn't work,
because the location is not
found immediately when you
turn showsUserLocation on.
Sometimes there's a little delay
from when you set it to
yes to where it actually
finds your location.
So the next thing you might try
would be to use one of the
many delegate methods in the
MKMapView delegate protocol.
There's a delegate
method called
mapView.didUpdateUserLocation
that runs every time a new
location is tracked
for the device.
This is actually going to
cause another problem.
If we open our app and then try
to swipe away from that
blue dot, every time we swipe
it's going to be recentered on
the blue dot immediately.
This is because this method
runs every time a location
update is received, which
can be quite often.
So we'll need another
approach.
One way to fix this is to add
a Boolean property to the
MapViewController called
userLocationUpdated.
Back in our delegate method,
we can check if the user
location has not been
updated yet.
And if it hasn't been updated,
that means that this is the
first time that this method
has been run.
The first time it's run, we can
set the center coordinate
on our user location.
And then we can flip that
Boolean property to yes, which
means that this method will not
get called the second time
that the location
gets updated.
And as you can see now when we
swipe, the center is not
constantly recentered
on that blue dot.
There's a few other map
view properties
that might be useful.
One of them is called MapType,
that allows you to set the map
type to either
MkMapTypeStandard,
MkMapTypeSatellite, or
MkMapTypeHybrid to determine
which type of map displays
in your app.
There's also properties for
turning the zoom and scroll
capabilities on and off.
And if you set these to no,
then you won't be able to
pinch to zoom to change the
region display on the map.
And you won't be able to scroll
between different
locations on the map
with your finger.
This might be useful if you
want to show the user a
location on the map but you're
not intending for them to be
able to find other locations
by flicking and zooming.
Remember that you can always
still do all of this
programmatically, setting
zoomEnabled and scrollEnabled
to no does not mean that you
can't still call setRegion
And it's time again for you to
try some map view challenges.