[SINGING]
He's got money in a suitcase
and a map on his phone.
He's got the secret location
of the deadliest drone.
He'll use pins and annotations
to find his destination.
The MapKit framework
will help his--
World Domination.
[SINGING]
He'll land at the coordinates
and load up his pack, the only
secret agent who can blow
it off the map.
He's Mr. Higgie.
In this next level, we're
going to look at how to
visualize points on a map
using a feature called
annotations.
Annotations are probably one
of the most recognizable
features of a map app.
And they're those little pins
that drop down at different
locations that you can tap and
find out more information
about that location
on the app.
The default annotation in MapKit
is actually this little
red pin icon.
And we'll look at how
to change that to a
custom icon as well.
So to add the ability to show
annotations, we need to create
an annotation model object.
The simplest version of this
is just an NSObject that
adopts the MKAnnotation
protocol.
By adopting that protocol,
we also need to add a
CLLocationCoordinate2D property
named coordinate.
I've created an annotation
model called MyAnnotation
that's a subclass of NSObject.
I imported the MapKit framework
into this annotation
object because, again, we're
going to be using some MK
classes that come from that
MapKit framework.
I adopted the MKAnnotation
protocol.
And I added a property.
The MyAnnotation implementation
file doesn't
actually need to have
any code in it.
Simple annotations will work
fine without declaring any
special implementation.
Back in MapViewController.m,
I'll want to import the
MyAnnotation.h file so that I
can access all of the features
of that class.
And then somewhere in
viewDidLoad, all I need to do
is create a coordinate,
initialize a new annotation
object, set the
annotation.coordinate property
equal to the coordinate I just
created, and then call the
addAnnotation method, passing it
in the annotation variable.
When we run this code, this
is what we'll see.
This is great.
But that annotation is a little
bit close to the edge
of the screen.
Wouldn't it be nice if we
recentered the map region on
that annotation after
it was created?
Doing this is really easy.
All we need to do is pass the
setCenterCoordinate animated
message to the map view again.
Except this time, instead of
using the user location
coordinate, we'll use the
coordinate that's inside of
our annotation.
And then that's going
to recenter the
map on that red pin.
Lots of apps don't use
the default red pin.
And instead, they add their
own image and add it as a
custom annotation view.
So let's look at
how to do that.
First, we need to understand
the structure of how our
controller, model,
and view relate.
Right now, we've got a
MapViewController that asks
for a MyAnnotation object.
And that MyAnnotation object
has a property called
coordinate.
Meanwhile, in the
ViewController, we've got an
MKMapView subview.
And in that MKMapView,
whenever we call the
addAnnotation method, it
actually creates an
MKAnnotationView and adds
the pin to the screen.
Now, that MKAnnotationView has
a property called image.
And if we were to go in and
change the value of that
property, we'll get a custom
image to display.
Now I also want to note that
there's a strange relationship
that happens with MKAnnotation
objects and MKAnnotationViews.
Usually a view doesn't have any
idea about the data that's
going to be displayed in it.
And the data doesn't really know
where it's going to be
shown in a view.
But MKAnnotation is different.
There's actually a small
relationship between an
MKAnnotation object and an
MKAnnotation view, in that the
MKAnnotation view knows
something about which
annotation it's connected to.
And that's going to be helpful
when we're trying
to change the image.
So to start, we've got another
delegate method called mapView
viewForAnnotation.
And this delegate method runs
automatically every time the
addAnnotation method
is called.
And you can see that this
method returns an
MKAnnotationView, which will
be great because we can
customize things inside of this
method and return them as
a new view.
And it even keeps track of
which annotation we're
currently looking at
by passing in an
annotation model object.
There's some boilerplate code
that almost always shows up
inside of this method.
It starts out by creating
MKAnnotationView object using
the dequeueReusableA
nnotationViewWithIdentifier method.
You should recognize
this method from
working with table cells.
And the idea is the same.
We're not recreating a new
MKAnnotationView unless we
absolutely need one.
And instead, we're pulling from
this pool of available
MKAnnotationViews that might
not be in use anymore.
For example, let's say the user
scrolls the map away from
where an annotation
is displayed.
An annotation offscreen is not
necessarily removed from
memory, so the object can
be used to display a new
annotation that's in our
visible map area.
Next, if we don't have any
MKAnnotationViews in that
reuse pool, then we'll create
a brand new MKAnnotationView
using the annotation that
gets passed in.
And we'll give it a reuse
identifier, so that the
dequeue method can access
it later on.
And finally, since this method
returns something, we'll want
to return that MKAnnotationView
so it can be
displayed on the map.
We need to add a new image to
our Xcode project if we're
going to make that available
to our MKAnnotationView.
So I have added an image
here called altPin.png.
Then, back in the delegate
method, all I need to do is
take that view and set the image
property to a UI image
named altPin.png.
And when I run this code again,
now there's a custom
image for each of those
pins on the screen.
But there's another
problem now.
The blue dot is gone.
We've actually replaced
it with our red pin.
So let's look at how to fix
this problem and bring the
blue dot back.
We can do a quick check back in
our delegate method before
we try to display anything.
We can check if our current
annotation has a class of
MKUserLocation.
The blue dot annotation that's
returned by location services
is of type MKUserLocation.
So in other words, we're saying,
if this is the blue
dot, then don't try to set any
custom display and instead
return nil.
Everything else won't
be the blue dot.
And then all the code can
update the red pin
accordingly.
So if we run this again,
we can see that we got
our blue dot back.
It's also very common that
whenever you tap one of those
annotation views, a little
bubble pops up with some
information in it.
That bubble is called
a callout view.
And adding support for callout
views is really easy also.
So first, we need to update
our MyAnnotation object to
have two more properties.
Those properties should
be NSStrings.
And the first property
name should be title.
The second one should
be subtitle.
The names here are important.
Then, back in our
MapViewController, in addition
to setting the annotation's
coordinate property, we're
also going to want to set the
title and subtitle properties.
Since this coordinate was Lake
Eola in Orlando, I set the
title to "Lake Eola." And I
set the subtitle to "Cool
swans," because there's cool
swans in Lake Eola.
And then the last thing we
need to do is back in our
MKAnnotationView delegate
method, we need to set the
canShowCallout property
of our view to yes.
And then when we tap on that
view, the call out bubble
appears with the information
related to that annotation.
So now it's your turn to try
to add some annotation into
your map view in
the challenges.