[SINGING]
He's got money in a suitcase
and a map on his phone.
He's got the secret location
of the deadliest drone.
He'll use pins and annotations
to find his destination.
The Map Kit framework will help
his world domination.
He'll land at the coordinates
and load up his pack.
The only secret agent who
can blow it off the map.
He's Mr. Higgie.
In this level, we're going
to learn how to work with
multiple annotations at one
time, and we're also going to
look at where that annotation
data might be coming from.
Creating a variable to hold
multiple annotations is as
simple as using an NSArray to
store multiple dictionaries.
In this NSArray, we've got three
dictionaries, one for
Lake Eola, one for
Lake Lawsona, and
one for Lake Lucerne.
Since we need to create more
than one annotation at one
time, a convenient way to do
this is to use an enumerator.
So here, I'm enumerating through
each NSDictionary in
the array in a variable called
Location, and then I'm
creating a coordinate,
initializing an annotation,
and then setting the properties
of that annotation
before adding it to the map
view inside of the loop.
If we run this code, this is
what we'll see, but you can
see that something's missing.
We added three annotation to the
map view, but we're only
seeing two of them in the
visible map region.
What we need to do is figure out
a way to reset our region
to a region that contains
all three of those map
points all at once.
To do this, we'll need some
more information.
If we imagine that there's an
invisible box that contains
each one of those three
annotations, if we find the
center point of that box and
the width and height of the
box, we'll be able to create a
new MK coordinate region and
then use the SetRegion method
to make that the new region.
So how do we figure out the
center point and the width and
height points, which are
also called the span?
Well, here's the three points
that we have on our
map view right now.
We've got annotation one,
annotation two, and annotation
three, and they each have
their own latitude and
longitude coordinates.
In order to be able to find the
boundaries of the box that
contains them, we'll need to
find the biggest latitude and
biggest longitude of the bunch,
and we'll also need to
find the smallest latitude
and smallest
longitude of the bunch.
Here's the values that we're
looking for, but we need to
figure out a way to do this
programmatically.
So first, I'll create two new
NSMutable arrays, one to store
all the latitude values, and one
to store all the longitude
values for each one of those
three points that I'm trying
to center the map on.
Then we'll loop through each one
of the locations again in
the for loop and build up the
data inside of our lats and
longs NSMutable arrays.
Here's the contents of the lats
and longs array after
running this code.
You can see that we've sized
the value so you can easily
see which one is the biggest
value and which one is the
smallest value in each array.
Then we can use an NSMutable
array method called
sortUsingSelector and pass in
this pre-defined selector
called Compare.
But the Compare selector does
is it sorts the array from
ascending to descending order
and changes the index of each
item in the array so that
they're sorted.
After we sort the array, here's
what it looks like.
"Index 0" in each one of the
arrays is going to be the
lowest value in the list, and
lastObject is going to give us
the highest value in the list.
So let's store the biggest
and smallest latitude and
longitude in four separate
variables
that are a type double.
smallestLat and smallestLng,
we can get by accessing
the first object in the array,
and biggest lat and biggest
long we can get by accessing the
last object in the array.
You were probably hoping that
there was a first object
message that you could past to
your array to access the first
object, but unfortunately, no
first object message exists.
Remember that the whole reason
we wanted to find these points
was to find the center of the
rectangle and the width and
height span that determine
how wide and how
tall rectangle was.
So first let's find the center
coordinate of that box.
We can do a little bit of
simple math and add the
biggestLat and smallestLat
together and divide them by
two, and that's going
to give us the
midpoint for the latitude.
We can do the same thing with
the longitude values and get
the midpoint for
the longitude.
The latitude and longitude
midpoints will be the center
of the box.
To get the width of the region,
we can take the
biggest latitude and subtract
the smallest latitude from it,
and then the same for
the longitude.
We'll then take that value and
create an MKCoordinate span,
which is just a struct that
contains the width and height
together, like a coordinate.
Now that we have the center and
span, we can create a new
MKCoordinate region with those
values and then call the
setRegion method.
Running this code shows us
that the map is indeed
centered on those three
annotations.
So where are these annotations
going to come from?
You're probably not going to
have 100, 1,000 annotations
sitting inside of your app.
You're probably going to get
them from something like an
API that's going to return a set
of annotations from a JSON
file, so let's look at
how to set that up.
We've got an API endpoint that's
going to return name,
lat, and long for
a set of places.
The structure of this is
an NSArray containing
NSDictionary objects, similar to
the ones we've been working
with locally, and each
NSDictionary, again, contains
one string representing the
name of the place and two
NSNumbers representing the
latitude and the longitude.
So first, in
MapViewController.h, we're
going to add a property that's
an NSArray called
mapLocations, and this is going
to make it so we can
access these map locations from
different parts of our
application.
Then in MapViewController.m,
in our viewDidLoad method,
we'll create our boilerplate AF
networking request, and the
URL we'll pass in is the URL
of our API endpoint.
This should look familiar, as
we've learned how to do this
in previous iOS courses
at Code School.
Then in the success block of the
AF networking request, we
can set self.mapLocations
equal to the JSON object
that's been returned
from the server.
Remember that the JSON object
contained an array of
dictionaries, and our
self.mapLocations variable is
also an NSArray.
So self.mapLocations now
contains an array of
NSDictionaries.
Finally, we can take the same
for loop that we just used to
create annotation from local
data, and we can put them
inside of the AF networking
success block.
This time, all of the
NSDictionaries that we're
looping through are coming from
our JSON object from the
server, and the end result is
that we're going to have all
the annotations returned
by the API loaded
onto the map view.
Now, this piece of code is
something that we probably
want to put inside of a separate
method because we
might be calling it at
different places.
So if we declare a method in
MapViewController called
addAndCenterOnLocations, we
could take all of the code
from our for loop that creates
annotations and put it inside
this method.
In addition, we can put all the
code that centers the map
around those annotations inside
the method as well.
Now, our AF networking request
looks a lot cleaner.
We get the JSON object
in from the response.
We assign it to our NSArray
self.mapLocations, and then we
just call the
addAndCenterOnLocations method.
And here, you can see a lot of
different annotations are
being loaded into our map
view from the server.
So now, it's your turn to
practice connecting to an API
that returns multiple
map locations.