[SINGING]
He's got money in a suitcase
and a map on his phone.
He's got the secret location
of the deadliest drone.
He'll use pins and annotations
to find his destination.
The MapKit framework will help
his world domination.
He'll land at the coordinates
and load up his pack, the only
secret agent who can blow
it off the map.
He's Mr. Higgie.
Typically, when you're building
an iPhone app, you
don't want to just take
all map annotations
in at the same time.
You want to give the user a way
to search for annotations
in a certain area or maybe even
bring in annotations from
the area around the device
that they're holding.
In this level, we'll look
at how to do that.
Our Current Place Info API
returns all places at once,
but we want to give the user the
ability to return just a
smaller subset of places
from our main database.
It turns out that our API has
support for passing in a zip
code and getting back a smaller
subset of locations
that are only found
in that zip code.
The way we'll set this up
is to add a UI text
field to our map view.
And when the user types a zip
code into that UI text field
and hits return, we'll query the
API for new locations that
are just found inside
that zip code.
So first, in
MapViewController.h, we'll add
a UI text field property
named Zip Field.
And we'll also adopt the UI
text field delegate, as we
usually need to do when we
work with text fields.
You can see that we can adopt
multiple delegate protocols in
the same class by putting
commas in between
the protocol names.
So here, I'm adopting
MKMapViewDelegate and
UITextFieldDelegate.
Then in viewDidLoad, I'll create
a new instance of our
text field, set some display
properties, and then add it as
a sub4view to our main view.
Since we want to submit an API
request whenever the Return
key is tapped, we'll implement
the textfieldShouldReturn
delegate method.
You might recall from a previous
course that this code
is going to make the keyboard
go away when the
Return key is tapped.
In addition to making the
keyboard disappear, we'll want
to make an AFNetworking request,
passing in the zip
code that the user entered
into the text field.
We can do that by first creating
an NSString and using
the value of the textfield.text
property, which
should contain the zip code
numbers that the user typed
in, to create a URL to
our API end point.
Then we can take that URL and
make an AFNetworking request
using our standard AFNetworking
boilerplate code.
Since the response we're getting
from our API endpoint
is still going to be an NSArray
of NSDictionary
objects, we can use the same
code that we used before.
We can pull the map locations
from our JSON file, and we can
add all those locations as
annotations and center the map
on them using our Add and Center
on Locations method
that we created in the
previous level.
So now you see that when the
user types in a zip code into
the text field and hits Return,
the map region is
going to update to a region
that contains all the
annotations that are valid
for that zip code.
But you know how some apps allow
you to get locations
around you without having
to type in any zip code?
We can add that same
functionality to our app by
using the User Location property
that we've talked
about before.
But there's one catch.
The User Location property
doesn't contain a zip code.
It contains a latitude
and a longitude.
So we need to figure out a way
to take our latitude and
longitude value and turn them
into a zip code, because the
API we're using is expecting
us to send it a zip code.
We can do that with something
called a Geocoder.
The Geocoder in iOS
has two modes.
The first mode, called Forward
Geocoding, allows you to pass
in an address and get
a latitude and
longitude as a response.
A Reverse Geocode allows you
to pass in a latitude and
longitude value and get
an address back.
And part of the address that
comes back is likely to
contain a zip code.
So Reverse Geocoding is what
we want to do in our app.
So in MapViewController, I've
declared a method called
getDeviceZip in the Header
file, and I've added a UI
button that calls
the getDeviceZip
method when its tapped.
In this method, first I'll
create a Geocoder object using
the CLGeocoder class, and then
I'll pass the message
reverseGeocodeLocation
completionHandler to that
Geocoder object.
The location value that I'll
send in as an argument will
come from self.mapView.use
rLocation.location.
Remember that MKUserLocation is
that User Location object,
and that has a CL location
inside of it that the Geocoder
is expecting.
Now, this Completion Handler
method returns an NSArray
called "placemarks".
And that's actually at an array
of objects called "CL
placemarks."
Sometimes that placemarks
array will have
more than one value.
But the first object in the
array will always be the one
that's most accurate for
the location that
you're trying to geocode.
If we look at the properties
that are available inside of
the CLPlacemark class, you can
see that we get quite a bit of
place information.
We get things like country,
zip code, state,
county, city, and more.
But since we're trying to work
with our zip code API, the
postal code property
is going to be the
one we want to access.
So back in our Reverse Geocode
method, we're pulling out the
placemark.postalCode value which
contains our zip code,
and restoring it in an NSString
named "Zip Code."
All that's left is to make an
AFNetworking request like
we've done before, this time
passing in this NSString zip
code into the API.
You can see now that when
we tap this new button,
annotations appear around
the blue dot.
That means that we geocoded the
location of the blue dot
to get a zip code, and we pass
that zip code into our API to
return a list of locations
around it.
It's important to note here that
self.mapView.userLocation
is only going to exist if
showsUserLocation is set to yes.
So if you've turned
showsUserLocation off, then
this approach will not work.
So now it's time for you to
try some geocoding in the
challenges.