[SINGING]
He's got money in a suitcase
and a map on his phone.
He's got the secret location
of the deadliest drone.
He'll use pins and annotations
to find his destination.
The mapkit framework will help
his world domination.
He'll land at the coordinates
and load up his pack.
The only secret agent who
can blow it off the map.
He's Mr. Higgie.
In this level, we're going to
look at different ways to
organize lots of
map locations.
We're going to also learn how
to enhance some of that map
data with core location
methods.
So we've added a lot of
locations to our MapView, but
at some point, we're going to
have so many locations on the
screen that we're going to want
a better way to visualize
all of them.
One way that iPhone apps do this
is to provide a TableView
in addition to the map view to
display a simple list of all
the locations that
are visible.
So we'll add that
now to our app.
Since the structure of our views
and view controllers is
getting a little bigger, let's
take a moment to remind
ourselves where we're at.
We've got a MapView controller
that's got three subviews, an
MKMapView, a UIButton for
finding the current user
location and adding annotations,
and a UITextField
for typing in a zip code and
getting annotations around
that zip code.
Inside of that MKMapView, we're
adding MKAnnotationViews
for each one of the points that
are visible on our map.
We can add a UITableView
controller called
ListTableViewController.
And inside of that
TableViewController, we'll
have a TableView with different
cells showing
information.
We'll also want a UIButton
so we can get back to the
MapViewController when we're
done looking at the TableView.
We'll present the
ListTableViewController
modally so we don't need to
create a navigation controller
to have an interaction
between the two.
We'll start with
ListTableViewController which
needs to declare an NSArray
property - I'm calling this one
map locations - that's going to
store all the locations that
are passed over from
MapViewController.
In addition, I'll go ahead and
define my go back method that
will be called whatever the back
button is tapped inside
of the TableView.
Then in the implementation file,
I'll want to return the
count of self.map locations so
that I get the correct number
of rows in the TableView.
Then in the TableView cell for
row at index path method, I'll
want to set the textLabel.text
property of the
cell equal to the name that's
inside of the map locations NS
dictionary.
In viewDidLoad, I'll create
and add the back button, and
then in the go back method that
gets called when the back
button is tapped, I'll just
dismiss this view controller
since we're going to be
presenting it modally.
In MapViewController, I've added
some code that I'm not
showing here.
First, I've added a UIButton
that's going to call this
method called ShowTableView.
I've declared the ShowTableView
method in the
MapViewController header.
And then I've imported
ListTableViewController.h into
MapViewController.m so that I
can create a link between the
two classes.
In the ShowTableView method, I'm
first creating an instance
of ListTableViewController.
And then I'm setting the map
locations property of the
ListTableViewController equal
to the current state of
self.map locations.
This is going to take whatever
data is inside of our map
locations NSArray inside
MapViewController and make
sure that it gets put into
ListTableViewController as well.
Then I'm setting a modal
transition style of Flip
Horizontal just to add
a different style
to the modal flip.
And then finally,
I'll present the
ListTableViewController animated.
So now when we run our app,
generate some locations, and
tap on the button that links
to ListTableViewController,
you can see that we have a nice
TableView of all of the
locations that are
added to our map.
Why don't you try a similar
approach in the challenges?