[SINGING]
He's got money in a suitcase
and a map on his phone.
He's got the secret location
of the deadliest drone.
He'll use pins and annotations
to find his destination.
The MapKit framework will help
his world domination.
He'll land at the coordinates
and load up his pack, the only
secret agent who can blow
it off the map.
He's Mr. Higgy.
Having the ability to view our
added annotations both in a
map view and as cells in a table
view is pretty cool.
But as it stands right now,
we're not adding a whole lot
of information to
that table view.
So let's look at how we can use
the CoreLocation framework
to add the distance between each
one of those points to
the point that the user
is currently at.
You might remember that we
added the CoreLocation
framework way back
in level one.
And now we're going to make use
of some of the functions
inside of it.
Right now, we're sending an
array of map locations over to
ListTableViewController.
But if we want to be able to
calculate the distance between
each one of those map locations
and the current user
location, then we're also
going to need to send
information about the current
user location over to the
table view.
Since self.mapview.use
rlocation.location contains
information about where the user
currently is, I'll send
that over in a variable called
userLocation to the istTable
View controller.
In ListTableViewController's
header, I'm
adding a CLLocation property
called userLocation, so that
it's ready for the data that's
passed in from the map view
controller.
And I'm also going to want to
import the CoreLocation
framework to this view
controller, because we're
going to be calling some
CoreLocation specific methods.
The method we want is called
distance from location, and
the way that it works is if
you have two CLLocation
objects, you can take the first
location object, and
then pass at the message
distance from location,
passing the second location as
an argument, and it will
return to the distance
in meters
between those two locations.
So let's think about what
we have right now.
We have some dictionaries with
keys for name, lat, and lng.
And what we want are
dictionaries that have an
additional key for distance,
so we can display that
distance in the table view,
since these dictionaries make
up our data source for
our table view.
So one way to add a key to an
existing dictionary is to
create a mutable version of that
dictionary, which means
that we can change the
properties inside of it.
So I've created an NSMutableDictionary
called
mutableLocation, and I've set
the default state of that
mutableLocation using the AddEntriesFromDictionary
message, which takes everything
that's in the NS
Dictionary and puts it inside
of the mutable dictionary.
Then I'll declares a double
value for distance, which
we'll calculate in a second.
And then finally, I'll take my
mutable dictionary and I'll
pass the set object
for key message.
In the set object argument,
I'll pass in an NS number
version of that distance we just
created, and I'll set it
for the key distance.
What that's going to do now is
add a distance key with a
value into this mutable
dictionary.
The reason we had to create an
NS number version of our
distance is that NS dictionaries
and NS mutable
dictionaries can't take in
primitive data types, like
double, as an argument.
They need to have an
object version.
Next, since we've got more
than one dictionary in
self.maplocations, we'll wrap
the whole thing inside of a
for loop, so that we can make
sure to create one new
dictionary with a new distance
key for each dictionary that
was in the original
locations array.
And finally, we'll add the code
that actually calculates
and sets the distance.
So first we'll create a
CLLocation object called
location to test.
And we'll use the
initWithLatitude, Longitude
convenience initialization to
pass in the current locations
lat and long as a
double value.
This will give us a CLLocation
object of the current map
location in the loop.
We'll calculate the distance
as the location to test
distance from location
userLocation.
And that's going to return a
number, in meters, that's the
distance between the current
location we're looking at and
the user's position
on the map.
All of the work we're doing
calculating distance is going
to be lost unless we figure out
a way to get those new NS
mutable dictionaries into an
array so we can access them
outside of the loop.
So here we've added code to
create a temporary array
outside of the loop.
And then inside the loop, each
one of those mutableLocation
NS dictionaries is being added
to that mutable array.
And then finally, we'll take
self.maplocations outside of
the array and reassign the
value of it to our
tempLocations array.
So now all of the data we
created inside that loop is
available outside of the loop.
The last step of this process
is going to be to call
self.tableview reload data.
And that's going to make the
table view update with any of
the new distances that
have been calculated.
Now we need to get that newly
calculated distance key into
our table view.
We can do that inside the
cellForRowAtIndexPath
index path method by updating
the detail text label property
of the cell.
First we should check if the
distance key exists, because
the very first time the table's
loaded, we won't have
calculated our distances yet.
So if the distance key exists,
we'll pull that value out as a
double, and then we'll create an
NSString with that double
value and set that equal to the
detail text label, telling
how many meters away
each location is
from our current location.
But what if we don't want to
display this in meters?
In the United States,
we don't usually
use meters for distance.
We use miles.
It's really easy to
convert the two.
All we have to do is divide our
distance value by 1609.34,
and that will return the number
of miles as a distance.
So here we have our updated
table view that now takes an a
array of map locations, checks
the distance of each one of
those map locations to the
user's current location, and
shows it as a detailed
text label inside of
each one of the cells.
And now it's time for you to
try out some of these core
location methods yourself
in the challenges.