(SINGING) You started with
a string you need validated.
Used conditionals, and
things got complicated.
There's a better way.
We'll teach you the lessons,
and you'll be writing patterns
with regular expressions.
Operators add a zing.
Modifiers are the thing
to find yourself the matches
on your subject string.
You'll be parsing files
if you follow our advice.
Sooner than you know it, you'll
be breaking the ice, ice, ice.
Hi.
My name's Dan Bickford.
And together, we'll be
taking an adventure.
And in the process,
we'll be breaking the ice
with regular expressions.
Now regular expressions
are a clear and concise way
to search through text.
What you will learn
in this course
can be applied to many
different programming languages.
Our journey will consist
of five different levels.
First, we'll be introduced
to regular expressions
and strings.
Second, we'll be
validating emails,
and then third,
we'll be searching
through text for clues.
Fourth, we'll be working
with multi-line strings,
and then finally, we'll be
working with capture groups.
So let's begin our journey with
level one--The String Story.
Imagine we run a website that
asks people for their Orlando
area phone number so they
can receive local restaurant
offers to their cell phone.
Well, if we think about what
makes this number valid,
we start seeing a few rules.
For example, the first
three digits of our number
must begin with 407 or 321.
Next, the character
should be a dash.
However, this dash is optional,
and it doesn't necessarily
have to be there.
This is then followed by three
more single digit numbers.
We then have one more of
those optional dashes,
and finally, we end with four
more single digit numbers.
So what would some
code look like
to help validate these rules?
It might look a little
bit something like this.
We would have a variable holding
the characters of our subject
string, named chars.
And we would check if
the first character is 4,
the second character is 0,
and the third character is 7.
Or the first character is 3,
the second character is 2,
and the third character is 1.
We would surround
that in parentheses,
and then we'd put an "&&."
And then we'd check, does the
fourth character equal a dash,
or does the fourth character
equal an empty string?
And that's just for
the first few numbers.
By writing a regular
expression, though,
we can accomplish
the same validation
using much more concise code.
So what exactly are
regular expressions?
There are two main parts
to a regular expression.
First, we have the
subject string--
which we're going to refer to
as a subject in this course--
and it's the text
we're searching through
to find a match.
Next, we'll have our
regular expression, or regex,
and this is a
group of characters
that represents rules for
searching and matching
against text.
So how does a regular
expression engine work?
The regex engine
walks each character
in the pattern and the subject,
trying to find matches.
Here, we're going to
get a match on the 4
in the regular expression
pattern and the subject.
And then next, we're going
to get a match on the 0
in the pattern and
the 0 in the subject.
And then finally, we're
going to get a match on the 7
in the pattern and
the 7 in the subject.
And the regular
expression engine
returns that we've found
a match-- or in this case,
we get a true.
Well, how about a pattern that
does not match our subject?
Here, we're trying to match
a 4 against our subject,
which does not contain a 4.
If the regular expression
engine does not find a match,
it will backtrack, both
the regular expression
and the subject, where it can
try to find a different match.
If no matches can be found,
the regular expression
will return that there
are no available matches--
or in our case here,
we'll receive a false.
Well, how would we make a
pattern match both 407 or 321?
By adding what is known
as an OR operator right
after our 407 and then
321, we can conditionally
match 407 or 321.
So our subject beginning with
the area code 321 now matches.
So what would this
regular expression
look like outside of code?
So when we say we're writing
regex, what we're really asking
is, does this group of characters
match a specific pattern?
The pattern starts
after the first slash,
and it ends before
the final slash.
And what is in between is
known as our regular expression
pattern.
Now, the regex engine
doesn't necessarily just
match on numbers.
We can also match
on letters as well.
So here, we're using a regular
expression literal, "boat",
which literally matches every
single character in the word
"boat".
And we have our
subject "boat" as well.
And we get a positive match.
However, if we bring in
another subject, such as "ship",
we're not going to
get a match with "boat"
because "boat" and "ship"
are two different words.
How can we construct a pattern
to match on both "boat" or "ship"?
Much like our pattern with two
different numbers, 407 or 321,
we can use two different
words with an OR operator
to match either "boat" or "ship",
and we get a match on both.
Some common uses of
regular expressions
include validations of phone
numbers, emails, passwords,
and domain names,
and for searching
for words in a sentence,
unwanted characters,
extracting sections,
or replacing, cleaning,
and formatting text.
Before we let you loose
in the challenges,
I wanted to give
you a quick overview
of the regular expression
challenge interface.
Here, we have a text box
on the top where you'll
enter the regular expression.
Modifiers will be
entered on the right.
Below, you have your subject
strings and any feedback
pertaining to the challenge.
On the left are
the tasks at hand,
and new tasks will appear as
you complete your current task.
You can also hover over
the regex and subjects
to get more information on the
matches that are happening.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
How about now you go write
your first regular expression
in the challenges?
[MUSIC PLAYING]