Welcome back to section
two of The String Story.
I hope you enjoyed writing
your first regular expressions.
We're assembling a crew!
The captain of our mighty
ship has set voyage
to study the
elusive sea monster.
We need to validate that each
potential crew member has
given us the correct information
before letting them proceed.
We're going to use
regular expressions
to help us validate this data.
Our first shipmate has
signed up-- smitty.
We're going to use a regular
expression literal, like we
had before, to match every
character in the subject
"smitty", and we get
a positive match.
And our next potential
shipmate has signed up-- james.
Using the OR operator
and then "james",
we can match either
"smitty" or "james",
and we get a match on both.
Now, not all potential
shipmates are
going to give us their name.
Some are just going to say, "ar".
However, some of the
shipmates have spelled
this in several different ways.
Some have spelled it with
one "r", some with 10, and some
with more.
So we're going to
need to find a way
to account for all the different
possible combinations of "ar"
that we may encounter.
So we're going to start
with "ar" literal here, where
we'll just match the
letters "a" and "r". However,
when we start adding
more "r"s to our subject,
we're going to start
getting partial matches.
And this is undesirable.
We want to match
the entire "ar".
So what can we do?
One possible solution is to
use the OR operator like we've
been doing, and then add
every combination of "ar"
that we might encounter.
But our pattern is going to
get extremely long doing this,
and it's inefficient.
So we need a better solution.
As it turns out, we can use the
special plus character, which
is a plus operator, and it will
repeat the "r" one or more times
until it is no longer matched.
This allows us to match on a-r,
a-r-r, and every combination
that we could possibly see.
This now allows us to match
on all versions of "ar"
effectively.
Adding an OR operator and then
our different versions of "ar",
we're going to match on
"smitty", "james", or "ar",
and our expression is
looking pretty good.
Our third potential shipmate
has signed up-- jameson.
However, we're not matching
on the o-n portion of jameson.
We're only matching on "james".
Well, this is what is
known as a partial match,
and it isn't always undesirable,
but in this case, we want
to match the full name.
One possible solution would be
to add an OR operator and then
"jameson".
But the line at our
booth's getting pretty long
at this point,
and let's face it,
we're not going to be able
account for every single name
that we could see, so we
need a better solution.
Let's reanalyze our
subject strings.
What's one thing that all of
these names have in common?
They all contain letters
from the alphabet.
Using the OR operator,
we could match
every character within the
alphabet-- "a" or "b" or "c" or "d".
But this is going to
become a very long pattern,
and it's almost worse
than our previous example.
One solution would be
to use a character set.
And a character
set is represented
by these square
brackets and represents
one character in our subject.
And then within, we're
going to use a range.
And here, we're using
a range from "a" to "z"
So we will match one character
in our subject string
from "a" to "z". Now there's two
important notes about this.
A range only works
within a character set,
and a character
set only represents
one character in our subject.
Back to our original example.
We can use our character
set with the range within
to match the first character
of "smitty", and we get the "s".
So how about matching the rest
of the characters of "smitty"?
Well, one thing
we could do would
be to repeat the character
set five more times to match
all six characters of "smitty".
With our character set
repeated six times,
we do get a match on "smitty".
However, we're no longer
going to get a match on "james".
And this is because "james"
only has five characters,
and we're expecting six
with a range from "a" to "z".
So this isn't going to work.
When using the plus operator--
as we've done before-- directly
after our character
set, we can repeat
the character set one
or more times until it
is no longer matched.
This allows us to match on
"smitty", "james", and "jameson" as
well as every version of
"ar" that we could encounter.
Our next potential shipmate
has signed up-- Blackbeard.
However, we're getting
a partial match here.
We haven't matched on the
capital "B" of "Blackbeard",
and this is because
our range only
has a lowercase "a" through "z".
Well, one possible
solution would
be to add another range
to our character set.
With a capital "A" through "Z" range
added to our character set,
we're going to match
on "Blackbeard" fully.
However, there's
actually another way
that we can write this.
By adding an "i" to the right,
outside of our final slash,
we'll add what is
known as a modifier.
Now the "i" modifier
means "case insensitive"
and will match the
entire pattern--
both uppercase and lowercase.
Now one thing to keep a
note is that modifiers
are language
specific, so you want
to check your docs before
jumping into modifiers.
Our next potential shipmate
has signed up-- Captain hook.
However, it looks like we're
getting a partial match here
as well.
We're leaving off the "hook"
portion of "Captain hook".
It looks like we're not
matching on the whitespace.
So let's go ahead and
take care of this next.
We can match on white space
by using a whitespace
literal, which is just a
space within our pattern.
However, we're going
to go ahead and use
the backslash "s" metacharacter--
which will equal a space, tab,
new line, and more.
Now, it's typically best
to be more explicit,
so we're going to
go ahead and use
the backslash "s" to represent
whitespace in our pattern.
Back to our example.
We can use the backslash
"s" within our character set
to match on whitespace, and
we now match on "Captain hook".
Now one thing to note--
the order of the characters
within the character set
are irrelevant.
You can do backslash
"s" range "a" through "Z",
or range "a" through
"z" backslash "s".
They're exactly the same thing.
Our final potential
shipmate has signed up--
Long John the 3rd.
However, it looks like we're
getting a partial match here
as well.
We're not matching on the
number portion of his name.
Well, we're not
accounting for numbers
right now because we have a
lowercase "a" through "z" range
and our backslash "s".
So let's go ahead and
add another range.
By adding a 0 through 9
range to our character set,
we're going to match on numbers.
And we now match on
Long John the 3rd.
However, there's another
way we can write this.
We can refactor
our character set
to use the word
metacharacter, which
is written as backslash "w".
This literally
equals a character
set with a lowercase
range "a" through "z",
an uppercase range "A" through
"Z", and a range 0 through 9.
By adding in our backslash
"s" to the character set
with our backslash
"w", we're going
to get our desired pattern.
Now, using our new pattern,
we can drop the "i" modifier
because capital letters
are taken care of for us.
And we're now
matching on all names.
Great job.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Now let's go ahead and try
some more regular expressions
in the challenges.
[MUSIC PLAYING]