[SINGING] You started with
a string you need validated.
Used conditionals, and
things got complicated.
There's a better way.
We'll teach you the lessons,
and you'll be writing patterns
with regular expressions.
Operators add a zing.
Modifiers are the thing
to find yourself the matches
on your subject string.
You'll be parsing files
if you follow our advice.
Sooner than you know it, you'll
be breaking the ice, ice, ice.
Welcome back to Breaking the
Ice With Regular Expressions.
I hope you enjoyed
The String Story
and getting your first
taste of writing patterns.
Let's now continue our voyage
with validating crew emails.
Now, up to this
point we've verified
that each potential shipmate
has entered a correct name.
Let's now verify that each
potential shipmate has
entered a valid email address.
To begin, let's analyze our
subject that is correctly
formatted, and formulate the
requirements for our pattern.
Our subject starts with a word,
is followed by an @ symbol,
and then is followed
by another word.
Now, for the remainder
of this course
we're going to see a
pattern goals box down
to the bottom left-hand
corner of the screen.
This is to help us keep track
of the different patterns
and different matches that
we're trying to accomplish.
We will use the backslash
"w", the @ symbol, and then
another backslash "w"
to begin our pattern.
Now, if you remember,
the backslash "w"
equals one word-like
character, so in this example
we're going to get a match on
the "a", the @ symbol, and the "e"
from sara@example.com.
Now, for the rest of
this course you're
going to see colored bars
underneath the pattern
and the subject.
This is to help us visualize
some of the matches that
are going on.
So how would we go
about matching the rest
of the characters in our email?
We will add the plus operator
after each backslash "w"
to repeat the word character
one or more times until we no
longer find a word character.
This allows us to
match on "sara@example",
but we're not matching on
the .com portion of our email
address.
Well, this is because
the dot is not
considered part of
a word character,
so we're going to have to
handle this separately.
By adding a dot, and
then another backslash "w"
with a plus
operator, we're going
to match on "sara@example.com".
Looking good.
But hold on a second.
It still works with an
email like sara@example!com.
Well, why would an
exclamation mark
match when we specified a dot?
Much like other metacharacters we have seen,
the dot is a special
character that
will match any character
except the new line.
It is known as a wildcard.
In order to match
a literal dot, we
will escape it by placing
a backslash before the dot.
Back to our example.
By putting a backslash
in front of our dot,
we're now matching
"sara@example.com",
but we're no longer going
to match on an invalid email
address like sara@example!com.
As it turns out, characters
with special meanings
can be escaped to use their
literal meaning by placing
a backslash in front.
This includes the
dot, which matches
any character except new line.
A backslash dot will match
the literal dot character.
The plus, which will match
the proceeding pattern
one or more times, and
the backslash plus,
which will match a
literal plus character.
We then have the question mark,
which will make the proceeding
pattern optional, and
the backslash question
mark, which matches a literal
question mark character.
Our pattern's
looking pretty good.
Now we're going to need to
handle for different top-level
domains.
In our example, we're going to
do .com, .net, .org, and .edu.
We can do this by
using an OR operator,
and then adding net,
another OR operator
and adding org, and another
OR operator and adding edu.
And as well, we're
going to add the "i"
modifier, because our
top-level domains can
be lowercase or uppercase.
But this pattern won't work.
Our pattern is matching
"sara@example.com" or "net"
by itself, or "org" by
itself, or "edu" by itself.
Well, just like
math operations, we
can use parentheses
to create groups.
This will help the
regular expression
evaluator understand which
order to evaluate your pattern.
So now our expression
matches "sara@example.com"
or "sara@example.net", and so on.
Our pattern is almost complete,
but this invalid input
will succeed when it should
not by placing a bunch of text
after our top-level domain.
We need to take
into account what
is before and after our desired
pattern within our subject.
Using anchors, we can ensure
there is nothing before
or after our desired pattern.
In this example
here, we will match
"learn by doing" only
if "learn by doing"
is by itself within the subject.
We will put the caret directly
before "learn by doing",
which literally means "start at
the beginning of the string".
We will then put the dollar
sign after "learn by doing",
which literally means "stop
at the end of the string".
This now assures us that
there is no text before
or after our desired pattern.
Back to our original
example, we can
use anchors to ensure
that our email address is
by itself, with no text
before or after it,
and our invalid email
address is no longer passing.
It's now your turn to
try some more complex
regular expressions.
Off to the challenges.