[SINGING] You started with
a string you need validated.
Used conditionals, and
things got complicated.
There's a better way.
We'll teach you the lessons,
and you'll be writing patterns
with regular expressions.
Operators add a zing.
Modifiers are the thing
to find yourself the matches
on your subject string.
You'll be parsing files
if you follow our advice.
Sooner than you know it, you'll
be breaking the ice, ice ice.
Welcome back to Breaking the
Ice With Regular Expressions.
I hope you enjoyed
validating crew emails
and writing some more
complex patterns.
Let's now continue on
our Confirmative level.
We now have valid names
and email addresses
for our potential crew members.
The crew members
have also confirmed
that they're willing to
travel on our adventure.
However, each has answered
us in a different way.
And even more, each
potential crew member
has given us an answer
within a phrase.
So we're going to need to
extract each answer out
of these phrases
so we can decide
whether they're willing to go.
Our first acceptable
match is "OK".
So we can start our pattern
by using a literal OK, which
will match the characters "OK".
Now this gets us
on our first match.
However, it also appears we've
matched the "OK" within "okie
dokie".
Now if you remember, one of our
pattern goals is that we cannot
have a word that is
part of a larger word.
So we're going to need
to take care of this.
The word boundary
metacharacter, or backslash
"b", is an anchor like the
caret and the dollar sign,
except it allows
you to perform
matches on whole words only.
So if you look at
our example, we
put a backslash "b" before
and after our backslash "w"
with the plus.
This results in boundaries
around each word
in our subject, around "learn",
around "by", and around "doing".
Using backslash "b", we can match
based upon the surrounding
words or characters,
and now we match
the letters "OK" in our subject,
but no longer match "okie dokie".
So we're looking pretty good.
Next we need to match in
a different version of "OK",
spelled "O-k-a-y" with
a capital "O". Well,
how can we match different
versions of this word?
One thing we could do
would be to surround
our "OK" with boundary
metacharacters followed by an
or and then the other
version of "OK" that's
surrounded by boundary
metacharacters,
but this isn't very efficient.
If we had a way to
make the "a-y" optional,
we could match with
a single pattern.
So let's find a way
that we can do this.
We know that we can use
a literal to match "ship",
but if we try to match it
against something like "shirt",
we're not going to get a match.
The question mark operator
matches the proceeding pattern
zero to one time.
If we add one after
the "p" in "ship",
we're going to make
the "p" optional.
So we'll match on
"ship", but we'll also
get a partial match on "shirt".
We can also use the question
mark operator with a group.
So in this example,
we have "pirate ship".
By putting "ship" in a group
and putting a question mark
after it, we will make
the "ship" optional.
This allows us to match on both
"pirate ship" and "pirate boat".
So if we have a group
with "a-y", after the "OK",
with a question mark,
we'll make the "a-y" portion
of the pattern optional.
This will allow us to
match on "OK" or "O-k-a-y".
Just like we've
done before, we're
going to add the "i"
modifier to handle
for uppercase and lowercase
characters within our pattern.
Now both variations
of "OK" are accepted.
Another potential key word a
shipmate may enter is "sure".
However, we're not checking
for this right now.
Using the OR
operator, we can match
either version of "OK" or "sure".
And because we're
using the backslash "b",
we're automatically just
going to be matching on words.
However, we're also getting
a partial match here.
This is because
the first boundary
is right before the "OK"
portion in our pattern,
and the second boundary
is right after the "sure".
How can we make
the boundary anchor
to both the beginning and the
end of "OK" and the beginning
and the end of "sure"?
Using a group, we
can encapsulate
the "OK" and "sure"
portion of our pattern,
giving us our
intended result. This
means that our desired matches
only appear as single words
and our subject "ensure"
no longer matches.
Much like matching "sure", we
can use another OR operator
and add "yes" to match on
our next acceptable answer.
However, this won't match on
the single character "y", which
is also an acceptable answer.
So let's go ahead
and handle for this.
Well, much like our
two versions of "OK",
we can construct two versions
of "yes"-- the "y" and the "y-e-s".
By surrounding the "e-s"
in a group and adding
another one of those
question mark operators,
we'll make the "e-s" optional.
And this allows us to
match on "y" and "y-e-s".
Our pattern is now
matching all answers
from potential shipmates.
It's now your turn to
try writing some patterns
with boundaries and optionals.