Welcome back.
I hope you enjoyed
working with boundaries.
Let's now continue
on with section two.
Each potential shipmate has
entered their own custom
tagline.
Now, taglines have a few rules.
Taglines cannot contain
any numbers, and they must
have a minimum length of 20
and a maximum length of 40.
So let's continue.
As we've seen before, we
can use the plus operator
behind our character set
containing a range from "a" to "z".
This matches "work" within
our subject string,
but we're not matching
on whitespace.
So let's continue
forming our pattern.
We will add to our
character set a backslash
"s", which takes us
right up to the comma.
So let's continue forming our
pattern to match that comma.
We will add to our
character set a comma.
Now this gets us a
little bit further,
but wouldn't it be
great if there was
another way we
could represent this
based upon our pattern goals?
We're currently trying to
match against a specific set
of characters, instead
let's try to match
any character that is not a
number with this pattern here.
The caret means "not" when
placed within a character set,
and the backslash "d" means
anything that is a number.
So this pattern means
anything that is not a number.
We will now use the character
set with our not backslash "d".
This allows us to drop
the "i" modifier, as well,
because we're matching
anything that is not a number.
Now we're also going to add
the caret and dollar sign
anchors to our
pattern, because we
want to make sure
there's nothing before
or after our desired match.
But if you notice, we're
using two different carets,
which actually represent
two different things, which
can get a little bit confusing.
So let's go ahead and
refactor our pattern.
As it turns out,
capitalized metacharacters
will match the opposite of
their lowercase counterpart.
Now this includes metacharacters
that we've already used,
much like the backslash
"d", the backslash "s",
and the backslash "w".
And there's some more too.
Using the capital
backslash "D", we'll
match the opposite as
lowercase backslash "d".
We now match all characters
on our subject string
that are not numbers.
So let's go ahead
and continue matching
on the length of our subject.
We get a positive match on
a very short or very long
subject, much like our example
concatenated or repeated
over and over.
How can we ensure
that our subject
has a minimum of 20 characters?
Using an interval expression,
or these curly braces,
we can match a specific
number of times
with fine-grain control.
So this example,
with our character
set with a range
from "a" to "z", we will
match exactly two characters.
Now interval expressions can
also match across a range.
So in our example
to the right, we
have a character set
with a range from "a" to "z",
and we're going to match a
minimum number of times of 1
the maximum number
of times of 3.
So "t", "te", and "tes"
will all match.
By adding a value to
the first position
of our interval
expression, we can
include a minimum
number of characters
required to get a match.
Here, we're saying the very
minimum we will match is 20,
and our short example
is no longer matching.
Now by adding to our interval
expression a value
in our upper bound, we can
limit the number of characters
that we're going to match.
Here we're using 40, which
will limit our subject
string to 40 characters.
Now our repeated subject
is no longer matched.
It's now time to start
practicing negating characters
on your own.
Let's start some challenges.