[SINGING] You started with a
string you need validated.
Used conditionals, and
things got complicated.
There's a better way.
We'll teach you the lessons,
and you'll be writing patterns
with regular expressions.
Operators add a zing.
Modifiers are the thing
to find yourself the matches
on your subject string.
You'll be parsing files
if you follow our advice.
Sooner than you know it, you'll
be breaking the ice, ice, ice.
Welcome back to Breaking the
Ice With Regular Expressions.
I hope you enjoyed the
confirmative challenges.
Let's now continue
on with working
with multi-line strings.
We've been cataloging
every animal that we've
encountered on our voyage.
We now have a very
large document
containing multiple lines
of different animals.
We need a way to
look through the data
set that's longer than just one
line to find all of the birds.
Now in case you're not
aware, our available birds
are penguins,
albatrosses, and terns.
So far, we've worked with
very small subject strings
that just contain one line.
Let's now work with
a multi-line subject.
But what exactly is
a multi-line string?
The list you see here is
actually a multi-line subject.
Hidden at the end of each
line is a newline character.
As you can see here,
the newline character
is usually written
with a backslash "n".
Let's start by
analyzing our subject.
We have multiple lines separated
by newline characters.
Each animal is approximately
one to two words in length,
and we have a mix of uppercase
and lowercase characters.
So we can start there.
First, we're going to use
a literal to match "penguin".
We will also add the "i"
modifier, but we only
match on the first
occurrence of "penguin",
and then we ignore the rest.
So how can we solve this?
By adding a "g" to the
modifier section,
we'll add what is known
as a global modifier.
A global modifier will match
every instance of "penguin",
instead of just the first one.
So let's continue on by
matching the entire name.
If we add a word and a space,
before our penguin literal,
we'll match on our full name.
And we're looking
really, really good.
We now match on all
instances of "penguin".
As we've done
previously, we can use
anchors to ensure
there's nothing before
or after our desired pattern.
However, when we do this
here, we don't get a match.
It looks like we've
broken our pattern.
Well, this is because
anchors, typically,
will check to
the very beginning
to the very end of the subject.
We need it to check
from the very beginning
to the very end of
each individual line.
Now, typically, an anchor
in this example will
start at "king" and
will end at "seal".
By placing an "m" in
our modifier section,
we'll add what is known
as a multi-line modifier.
So instead of the
caret anchor anchoring
to the beginning of
our subject, it's
going to anchor to the
beginning of every single line.
And instead of the
dollar sign anchoring
to the very end
of our subject, it
is going to anchor to the
very end of every single line.
Now we can be sure
there's nothing
before or after our bird names.
We can now continue matching
on additional birds.
We're going to add a group
around our penguin literal
add an OR operator, and
then "albatross" within.
And we're now matching
on "wandering albatross".
Using one final OR operator, we
can add "tern" to our pattern.
And we're now matching
on all available birds,
and we're not matching on
anything that is not a bird.
Let's now try using
some of the modifiers
we've learned in this
section on the challenges.