[SINGING] You started with
a string you need validated.
Used conditionals, and
things got complicated.
There's a better way.
We'll teach you the lessons,
and you'll be writing patterns
with regular expressions.
Operators add a zing.
Modifiers are the thing
to find yourself the matches
on your subject string.
You'll be parsing files
if you follow our advice.
Sooner than you know it, you'll
be breaking the ice, ice, ice.
Welcome back to Breaking the
Ice With Regular Expressions.
I hope you enjoyed working
with our new modifiers.
Let's now wrap up our final
level-- Capture Groups.
Each shipmate has
entered their address.
Wouldn't it be great
if we could break apart
each section of the address
to store separately?
Here, that includes the
street, city, state, and zip.
Because this pattern
is getting pretty long,
we're going to need to
break it apart and look
at each individual section.
So the first part,
the street name, we
match any amount of numbers.
This is followed by a space,
and then a word of any length.
This is then followed
by another space
and a word of exactly four
to six characters in length.
Finally, we end with a
comma and a white space
to finish off the first
section of our pattern.
Continuing with the city, we're
going to match on one to two
words, followed by a comma, and
then followed by another space.
Moving to our two-letter
state abbreviation,
we will match using
a two-letter word.
This is then
followed by a space.
Wrapping up our
pattern, we're going
to match on the zip, which
is a number of exactly five
characters in length.
We can also add our
anchor characters
to ensure there's nothing
before or after our address,
and we're looking pretty good.
However, wouldn't
it be great if we
could extract different
sections of the pattern
to be used later?
We've used parentheses
up to this point
to create groups for
evaluation purposes,
but did you know that
groups can actually be
used to return values to you?
So let's start with
a simple example.
Here, we have a
regular expression--
literal learn by doing.
And let's say we get the
subject-- "learn by doing".
We're going to get
a direct match.
Now what if we put parentheses
around our pattern,
"learn by doing"?
Well, this still matches
our subject, "learn by doing",
but it also returns
us an extra thing,
that we capture everything
within our parentheses
and we get returned to us
a match group containing
"learn by doing".
Now we can actually
nest parentheses too
to return even more groups.
By wrapping the "by doing"
within "learn by doing",
we'll not only extract our first
match group of "learn by doing",
but we'll also extract "by doing".
And finally, surrounding
the "by" with parentheses,
we will extract our third
and final group, the "by",
which will give us three
match groups-- "learn by doing",
"by doing", and "by".
And keep in mind, we still
match our original subject--
"learn by doing".
Now we can easily return
the house number and street
by surrounding them
in parentheses, which
will create a
capturing group for us,
and will get returned
to us "1 Reindeer Lane".
Continuing on, we'll surround the
second section of our pattern
to return the city.
And in this case, we're
going to get North Pole.
We're looking pretty good.
Now notice that we did not
extract the comma or the space
in our capture group.
Well, this is
because we only will
capture anything that's
inside of our parentheses,
and those existed outside.
Adding parentheses
around the third section
will give us our third
returned match, or in this case
"AK" or "Alaska".
We're almost there.
Wrapping the final digit
metacharacter in parentheses
will return us our
five-digit zip.
We've now got all four
groups returned to us,
exactly what we needed.
Lastly, we need to restrict
any potential street
names to only "street" or "lane".
We can add another group
to our street name section
to make sure that we only
match on "street" or "lane",
and this works.
We're getting a match
on our subjects.
But, wait, we just added
parentheses around our street
or lane, however, this
just returned "lane" to us
as one of our match groups.
Well, we can't have this.
We can only have four matches
consisting of a street, city,
state, and zip.
So how can we still
use this group,
but make sure that it does not
return the street name back
to us?
We can use the
question mark colon
at the beginning of our group
to create a non-capturing group.
This way we can do
evaluations within our group
without returning a value.
And now we only have
four match groups
consisting of 1 Reindeer Lane,
North Pole, AK, and 99705.
Looking really good.
It's time to
practice some capture
groups in the challenges.
I'll see you again
at the wrap-up video.
The next want to.
Dang.
Base.
Empty string.
G in moder-- moderfiers.
Modifiers.
There's your
blooper.