Welcome back.
In this section we're going to
be learning about controllers.
Controllers help us get
data on to the page.
Here you can see we have
a JavaScript object.
It's a gem and we need to
sell this in our store.
So how do we get it out of this
variable and onto our page?
To do this, we need
to use a controller.
Controllers are where we define
our applications behavior
by defining
functions and values.
Here we are back in our app.js.
We're going to wrap our entire
application here in a closure,
it's just a good
habit to get into.
Then we'll specify the
name of our controller.
In this case, StoreController.
It's important that
this is in capital case
and we always use
the word controller.
The second parameter
that we pass in
is an anonymous function.
The code in here is
what will be executed
when our StoreController
is called.
Now let's move our gem
variable into our app.js.
Now from inside
of our controller,
we need to set this gem equal to
a property of this controller.
So we'll call
this dot product, product
is a property of our controller,
and set that equal to gem.
Now need to figure out how
to get access to this data
from inside of our HTML.
Back inside of our
HTML, you can see
I've written out a
template for where
I want to display
the gem information.
That's where we want to
load it onto the page.
Let's bring back up our
controller, just for reference.
The first thing we
want to do is to use
the ng-controller directive.
This allows us to
attach our controller
to this element
inside of our HTML.
As the value of this attribute
will write the controller name,
in this case StoreController,
we'll use the keyword "as"
and then specify an alias for
this StoreController, which
will use inside of
our expressions.
Then inside of our
expressions we'll
write store dot product dot name -
to access
the value we want to
print out to the page.
And then store.product.price
and store.product.description.
If we called up our browser,
we would see that it properly
prints out the values from
this JavaScript object.
So we attached to the store
controller to that div.
What would happen if
we tried to access
a property from
that StoreController
outside of the div?
Well, it wouldn't work.
That's because we
all only have access
to the StoreController
inside the div.
The scope of the controller is
only inside that DOM element.
Why don't you try
writing a controller
and playing around with the
ng-controller directive?