Welcome back.
Let's learn about a
couple new directives.
There's a bunch of them
and they're really useful.
Here you can see we're
inside of our index.html
and we have our gem data.
Let's add a new key in value
to our gem called canPurchase.
We'll set it to false because
we can't purchase this gem.
Then inside of our
index.html there's
a button there
called "Add to Cart."
And we only want that to show
up when canPurchase is true.
How might we use a directive
to create this behavior?
So here we'll use
the ng-show directive
and specify an expression.
That expression is going to
be store.product.canPurchase.
This directive is
telling our button
to only show if the value
of its expression is true.
In our case, it's false.
So that button element
won't show up on the page.
So here we are in our webpage
and as you can see,
there's no "Add to Cart" button.
However, if we go
back into our code,
change canPurchase to
true, and refresh the page,
you'll see now it's there.
What would happen,
though, if we didn't
have a canPurchase property
on our current gem?
Well, Angular is nice
enough to interpret
that as a false-y value.
So even without that property it's
not going to show the
"Add to Cart" button.
Let's add another
property to our gem.
We'll call it "soldOut."
And if  soldOut is
true, we don't want
to show the product
on the page at all.
So we're going to use the
directive ng-show again.
We can say ng-show equals
not store.product.soldOut.
Now there's another
way we can do
this, which is a little
bit more readable by using
the ng-hide directive.
So we can use ng-hide
store.product.soldOut.
So it's saying hide this
product when we're sold out.
And the HTML is a
little more readable.
What good is a store
without multiple products?
We only got one.
So let's jump back
into our app.js
and change gem into gems.
And you'll notice
here, now we have array
with a little bracket.
And now our products
are equal to gems.
Cool.
But how are we going to display
all these products inside
of our index.html?
Maybe a directive?
If you think so,
maybe you're right.
Let's check it out.
So back in our index.html
we can print out
each of these
products to the screen
by accessing their array
index, as you see here.
But this is not very
dynamic, just listing out
each of the products using
their arrays indexes.
So, let's use a
directive to iterate
through each of the
items in the array.
To do this we'll use
the ng-repeat directive.
The ng-repeat directive takes
a special angular expression.
In this case, we're saying
product in store.products.
store.products is the array
we want to iterate through.
Inside of this element product
refers to the current product,
and we can print out
all of its properties.
And this will get repeated for
as many products as we have.
So now if we jump
into our browser,
we can see that it shows
us all of the products.
In this level we learned about
four core angular concepts.
We learned about
directives, which
are HTML annotations that
trigger JavaScript behaviors.
We learned about
modules, which is
where our application
components live.
We learned about
controllers, which
is where we add
application behavior.
And lastly, we learned
about expressions,
which is how we get values
displayed onto our page.
With this understanding I turn
you over to the challenges
and I'll see you
in the next level.
You try your hands at writing
a control, like this.
Angular rocks my socks.
Yes, ship it, done!