[SINGING] The Flatlanders
need a store
to sell their gems and more.
They need it really quick,
Angular will do the trick.
Directives set the
stage in your HTML page,
controllers give your wrap
the behavior that it lacks.
Write expressions so that
you can add your data
to the view and modules
make connections
with dependency injections.
You're a scripting
connoisseur when
shaping up with Angular.JS.
You're watching Shaping
Up With Angular.JS. This
is Level Two where we're going
to be talking about filters,
more directives, and how to
keep your code clean.
To review some of the
directives we've gone over,
we've got ng-app - that's how
we attach the application
module to the page.
We have ng-controller - that's
how we attach a controller
function to the page.
We have ng-show and
ng-hide to display or hide
a section based
on an expression.
And we have ng-repeat
to repeat a section
for each item in an array.
Now jumping back into
our current example,
we've prettied up
some of our code
to use some Twitter
Bootstrap elements.
But we're still
doing the same thing,
iterating through
each of our products
and printing it
out to the screen.
If we were to call
us up in a browser
it might look
something like this.
Now you'll notice here that
something doesn't quite
look right with
our dollar values.
We're simply putting a
dollar sign before the price
and one of our prices
is 2, so it's not
showing the right number
of decimal points.
Luckily, Angular has a better
way to deal with currency.
We can use the currency filter
in our price expression.
Notice here, between these
two calls we have a pipe.
The pipe says take the result
of the first expression
and send the output into
the second expression, which
in this case is a filter.
Currency will print out the
proper dollar sign localized,
it will also give us the
correct number of decimals.
So now when we call this
page in our browser,
we can see their currency
is properly formatted.
Angular has a bunch of filters
and they follow this format
where you take some data and
you pipe that into a filter,
sometimes even
specifying options.
For example, if we
had a timestamp,
we could pipe that into
the date filter specifying
the format of the
date we wanted.
We can also specify a filter
of uppercase or lowercase
on a string.
Next, we have the
limitTo filter which
will allow us to limit
the number of characters
in a string, if we want.
It's also really
useful if we want
to limit the number
of items in an array.
Like if we only want to display
the first three products.
The orderBy by filter will allow us to sort our products.
In this case, if we wanted to sort our products
from most expensive to least expensive,
we would write pipe orderBy minus price.
Without the minus, products would
list in ascending order from cheapest to most expensive.
Each of our products
has a bunch of pictures
that are associated with it.
So we need add that
to our data set.
So here you can see we now
have an images property which
contains a new array.
Inside of that array
there are a series
of image objects,
each of which contains
a full image and
a thumbnail image.
So, to display the first
image of your product,
we might write product dot images,
specify the index, dot full.
If we took that and put it as
an expression inside the source
attribute of an image tag,
well, it wouldn't work.
The browser tries
to load the image
before the expression evaluates.
So to print out
this image, we need
to use the ng-source
directive like you see here.
Then if we jump back into our browser,
we can see that all the images are showing properly.
Why don't you try using
some filters and ng-source?
And I'll see you in
the next section.