Welcome back.
Now, let's add some
more interactivity
to our application
by adding some tabs.
As you can see,
each of our products
has a description,
specification, and reviews tab.
Twitter Bootstrap
comes with some classes,
which make it pretty
easy to construct
some tabs, like you see here.
But how do we add
behavior to these tabs
so that when we select
one, it becomes active
and the content gets
displayed in the page?
One way to do this in Angular is
by using the ng-click directive
which takes an
expression to evaluate.
So here we're
saying tab equals 1
- when we click on
the first one, tab
equals 2 when we
click on the second,
and tab equals 3 when
we click on the third.
If we want to print out
this value to the page,
we can simply write
tab as an expression.
Let's see what this
is going to do.
So if we jump into
the browser, we
can see that if we click
on the different tabs,
the tab value gets
printed out to the screen.
Pretty neat, huh?
We never defined tab.
But just by clicking on
those different tabs,
it changes the value.
We're starting to get
into the magic of Angular.
When we click on one
of those tab items,
the tab expression
automatically gets updated.
See, expressions like this
define a 2-way Data Binding.
A 2-way way Data Binding.
This means that expressions
are re-evaluated when
the property changes.
So that expression
is keeping an eye
out for when that
value of tab changes
and if it does get changed, it
gets updated in the web page.
Now that we have the tab
navigation figured out,
we need to create
the tab panels.
You know, where the
content for the tab goes.
So let's flesh that out
as you can see here.
Content in each of them.
But how do we get the proper panel
to show up when we click on that corresponding tab navigation?
Well, we need to
use ng-show again.
We can say ng-show and this
time pass in an expression.
When tab is equal to
1, display this one.
When tabs equal to 2, show this
one, and when tab's equal to 3,
show that one.
Now when a tab is selected it's
going to show the proper panel.
Here we are back in our browser.
And you'll see when
we click on a tab it
shows the proper panel.
But when we refresh the
page none of the panels
are showing up.
It would be good to set
an initial value for tab.
How do we do that?
The ng-init directive
allows us to evaluate
an expression in
the current scope.
So here we're going to write
ng-init equals tab equals
1, which is going to initialize
the value of tab to 1.
So if we jump back
into the browser,
we can see that tab
is initialized to 1
and the description
panel is shown.
But wouldn't it be nice to
show which tab is active?
And in fact,
bootstrap has classes
so that the right
tab gets highlighted.
How might we detect
which tab is active
and then add a class
to the appropriate tab?
To do this, big surprise, we
need to use a new directive.
The ng-class directive, which
takes a bunch of arguments,
but we're going to
send in an object.
In this object we're
going to specify,
as a key, the name of
the class we want to set.
And then as a value, an
expression to evaluate.
If this expression
is true, we'll
append this class
to the element.
And if it's not, we're not.
In our case, we're
going to check
to see if the tab is equal to 1.
And if it is we'll set
the class to active.
And then, of course, 2
and 3 for the other tabs.
Then back in our browser you
can see that our tabs are now
using the active class properly.
Much nicer.
If it's starting to
feel a little bit
dirty, a little bit of
a wrong, that you're
putting all this logic
inside your HTML page,
well, you're kind of right.
We need to figure out how to
pull that logic into something
to organize it.
The best place here
might be a controller.
Not our store controller,
we need a new controller
for this logic.
Maybe we'll call it
our panel controller.
First we'll use the
ng-controller directive,
specifying our PanelController as panel.
Panel is our alias that we'll
be using inside of this element
to refer to our
PanelController.
Then our app.js will define
our PanelController.
Our next step is to move
the tab initialization
inside of our PanelController.
ng-init is great
for prototyping,
but really initialization and configuration
should go inside of a controller.
In this case, we'll make tab a property of our controller.
So we'll be able to refer to it as panel dot tab.
Next, let's take the assignment
logic out of our HTML
and create a function expression.
This is going to take a parameter - setTab -
and inside this function we'll set
the tab property equal to that variable.
And then inside of our ng-click expression,
we'll simply call panel.selectTab(1),
panel.selectTab(2), and panel.selectTab(3).
Lastly, let's create a function for our comparison.
We'll call it "isSelected."
Now we'll check to see if the current tab is
equal to this tab to check and return the value.
This will be either true or false.
And notice here that we're calling
isSelected both inside the ng-class directive
and in the panels to detect which one is selected.
Now if we jump back over into the browser
and select the different tabs, we
can see that the behavior hasn't changed.
Everything still works, but
our code is a little cleaner.
It's challenge time.
So why don't you shape up
with some Angular and I'll
see you in Level Three?
Welcome back.
[MUMBLING]
Prettied out.
Prettied out?