[SINGING] The Flatlanders need a store
to sell their gems and more.
They need it really quick -
Angular will do the trick.
Directives set the stage
and your HTML page.
Controllers give your wrap
the behavior that it lacks.
Write expressions so that you
can add your data to the view.
And modules make connections
with dependency injections.
You're a scripting connoisseur
when Shaping Up with Angular.JS
You're watching
Shaping Up with Angular
and this is Level
Three, where we're
going to be talking about
creating your own form to add
new reviews, in our case.
So here we are
back in our store.
And you'll notice when
I click on it Reviews,
it lists out all the
different reviews for product.
And I can rate the product.
As I start typing
out the review,
it gives me a nice
live preview so I
can see what my review
is going to look like.
When I submit it, the
review get solidified
on to the page and
my form gets reset.
Let's figure out how to do this.
We haven't dealt
with reviews before.
Here you can see we just added
it to our products array.
So you can see
each product has at
an array of reviews, which
each have properties.
Next, inside of
our reviews panel
we'll simply do another
ng-repeat for review
in product.reviews.
So this is another loop inside
of our original product loop.
And inside there we'll
print out the review stars,
review body, and review author.
If we call this
up in our browser,
here's what our reviews
would look like.
Nothing new here that
you haven't seen before.
But how do we start to implement
a form to post a new review?
Without any new Angular elements,
here's the HTML for our form.
We simply have a select
field, a text area,
and if you input elements
so that our form on our page
is going to look
something like this.
Next, let's add our
live preview code.
So here, just like when we
printed out each review,
we're going to block
quote, print out
the stars, the body,
and the author.
Now, we haven't defined
this review variable yet.
Just like in the previous
level, we didn't really
define the tab variable, we
could just start using it.
But now we need a way
to bind each of these
to the proper form element. Hm ...
We do this using the
ng-model directive.
So we can see
ng-model review.stars,
which will bind to
this form element
to the review.stars
stars value in our page.
Here we're going to see more
of that Angular magic is
that 2-way Binding.
So if we jump back
into the page,
we're going to see that
as we update the form,
the live preview
automatically gets
updated for each
of these fields.
Obviously, our form
isn't going to work yet,
we haven't told it what to
do when it gets submitted.
But before we do
that, I want to let
you know about two
more binding examples.
First, if you have
a checkbox, we
could use ng-model to bind
to the checkbox, which
we'll set it to true or false.
Also with radio buttons
we could set ng-model.
In this case, of
course, the value
would be red, blue, or green
- based on which is selected.
Before we move any
further, I want
to make sure you're
comfortable with using ng-model
to create forms.
Give it a try and then
we'll take the next step.