So we're back
working on our form.
And before we get
any further we need
to organize our
code a little bit.
See that review variable?
We didn't define it anywhere.
And it's good
practice to define it.
We can use ng-init, but
like we mentioned before,
it's better to do initialization
inside a controller.
So let's create a controller
for our review form.
We'll call it ReviewController.
and the only thing we
need to do inside of it
so far is to initialize
a property called review
and set it equal
to an empty object.
Then on our form we're going to
use the ng-controller directive
and attach the review
controller as reviewCtrl.
Why are we using Ctrl?
Because if you read other
people's Angular code
they'll often use that as
an alias, just adding Ctrl.
Now we need to update
all the expressions
to use this controller alias.
So let's do that.
Perfect.
Now let's make our form actually
submit and do something.
We need a new
directive for that.
In this case, ng-submit.
ng-submit allows us
to call a function
when the form is submitted.
So we'll simply specify
ng-submit reviwCtrl.addReview
and we're going to send
in the current product
that we're iterating
through, you
know, from our StoreController.
Next step, we need to
define this function
inside of our ReviewController.
So here's the add
review function.
It takes in product
as a single argument,
then we'll get the
product's current reviews
by calling product.reviews.
And we'll push the controller's
review, this.review,
on to the reviews array.
Now if we jump
back into the form,
we can go ahead and
submit our review.
You can see it gets added, but
now the form wasn't cleared out
and our live preview
wasn't either.
So it looks like we have
two different reviews.
That's not good.
So how might we
reset the form, which
will clear up the live
preview as well?
So now jumping
back into our code,
inside the addReview
function, we simply
need to set this.review equal to
a brand new JavaScript object.
This should properly
clear out the form
and hide that live preview.
Now let's jump into the
form and see what happens.
So now, if we type in
a review, hit Submit,
you can see that the
form gets cleared out,
and we no longer see
duplicate reviews.
Before getting to
the challenges,
you might have noticed
if you're playing along
at home, that we're not
persisting this data.
If you were to refresh the
page after adding a review,
it would get blown away.
We're not saving this to a
server anywhere and that's OK.
We'll get so that
eventually in this course.
But in the meantime,
go practice this stuff.