Welcome back.
In this section, we're going
to be going over validations
because every form
needs good validations,
and Angular comes with some
great built-in ones that you're
going to want to use.
To add validations
to our view form,
the first thing we need
to do is to turn off
default HTML validations.
Browsers sometimes
have this built-in,
and we don't want to do it.
We want to be more consistent.
So let's run novalidate in
our form tag as an attribute.
Next, let's mark the fields
that are required for our form
by simply adding the required
attribute, like you see here.
Lastly, to see if our form
is validating properly,
let's simply add some
debugging code here.
We'll say reviewForm
is reviewForm.$valid,
which will be true or false.
There's some Angular
magic going on here.
First, notice that our form
has a name -- attribute --
and the name is reviewForm.
That's where we get that
first part of that expression.
And then when .$valid, $ means
we're referencing a property
on the form, and that's a
built-in property from Angular.
We're not having to
define valid anywhere.
It comes with Angular.
Now if we jump
back into our form,
and we fill out all
the fields, you'll
see that valid turns
from false to true,
as you might expect it to.
There's another cool
thing here going on
where, if we play around
with the email address,
you'll notice that it's
validating that it's
a proper email address.
Kind of neat.
Now, if we have this
invalid email address,
and the form is invalid,
can we submit the form?
Yeah.
We can still submit the form.
We don't want that.
We'll need to prevent that
from getting submitted.
Really, we only
one that addReview
function to be called
if the form is valid.
So using our knowledge of the
reviewForm valid property,
we can put that
inside ng-submit.
So when this form is
submitted, if valid is false,
then addReview will
never get called.
Only if valid is true will the
second part of the expression
be evaluated and
addReview get called.
Now, if we have an invalid form,
and we attempt to submit it,
nothing happens.
Well, that's good,
but we still need
to give the user
some sort of hint
of why their form is invalid.
Well, if we looked
at the HTML that
gets rendered on our
page -- in particular,
the form elements -- we would see
that the input value before we
started typing email has a
class of ng-pristine -- which
means it hasn't been
touched -- and ng-invalid,
which means the
email is not valid.
As we start typing inside
that field, the class changes.
The class gets
updated to ng-dirty,
but it's still invalid.
So it still has ng-invalid.
Then, after we
have a valid email,
that ng-invalid
turns into ng-valid.
All this is default magic
that Angular adds for you.
So with this in mind, let's
highlight these form fields
using classes after
we start typing to see
if a field is valid or invalid.
So let's jump in
and write some CSS.
We can check to see if
it's invalid and dirty,
then we'll use one border
color:  this is red.
And if it's valid and dirty,
we'll change it to green.
You might be wondering why
we use ng-dirty at all.
That's because we don't want
these borders to show up
until they've started typing.
Now if we jump
back into our form,
you can see as we start
typing an email address,
it turns red until it's valid,
and then it turns green.
You might also notice the
live preview doesn't render
this value until it's valid.
It's kind of neat.
As you see, Angular has
built-in email validation, a lot
like HTML5 form validation.
It also can validate
URLs or even numbers.
And when you have a
number, you can even
specify a minimum and maximum.
Time for you to
try out validation.
And I'll see you in level four.
You're watching Warming
Up with Angular.
Welcome to Warming
Up With Angular.
[LAUGHTER]