[SINGING] The
Flatlanders need to store
to sell their gems and more -
and they need it really quick.
Angular will do the trick.
Directives set the
stage in your HTML page.
Controllers give your wrap
the behavior that it lacks.
Write expressions so that
you can add your data
to the view. And modules
make connections
with dependency injections.
You're a scripting
connoisseur when
shaping up with Angular JS.
You're watching
Shaping Up With Angular
and this is level
four where we're
going to be talking about
using ng-include and creating
our own custom directives.
Jumping back into
our existing code,
we have this snippet of
HTML where we print out
the product name and
the product price.
If there were multiple
places in our application--
and let's assume
there are-- where
we reuse this identical
piece of code,
we may want to eliminate that
duplication by pulling it out
into an HTML snippet.
To do this first we'll pull out
that duplicate code into a new
file that we'll name
product-title.html.
Then inside of our
index.html we'll
use the ng-include
directive, specifying
the name of the file
we want to include.
You'll notice here
that we're using
double quotes and single quotes.
That's because ng-include
is expecting a variable
with the name of the file.
If we want to pass a name
directly as a string,
we've got to use
the single quotes
inside of the double quotes.
Once this file's included, you'll
see the generated HTML look
something like this.
So if we jump into our
browser, we can see here
that nothing's changed, but the
way that our page is loading
is slightly different.
When our browser does a web
request it can only pull down
one HTML file, that's
going to be the index.
It's going to pull
that down and it's
going to load everything up.
And then when it gets
to that ng-include
it gives it the name of
a file or even a URL.
And it's actually going to
be doing an AJAX request back
to the server to pull down
the contents of that file
and load it into the page.
Using ng-include
works but there's
a preferable way when we
want to include a template.
And that's by using
a custom directive.
It might look
something like this.
There's a little more code we
have to write behind the scenes
to make it work,
but this is what
it would look like
inside your index.html.
Why should you write
a directive instead?
Well, directives are part of
the secret sauce of Angular
because they allow
you to write HTML
that expresses behavior
of your application.
Typically, HTML only tells
you about the structure.
It doesn't tell you what
your application does.
But if you look at a
typical Angular application,
like this one, even
though you've never
seen this application
before or even played
with it on your browser,
I bet you can still
understand what it does.
So expressiveness
is the real power
of writing custom directives.
And there are several
different types
of directives you can use.
First, there's template-expanding directives.
Those are the simplest ones.
We define a custom
tag or attribute
which expands and
shows a template,
like an ng-include would.
These can also include
controller logic.
Directives can also be used
for expressing complex UIs,
calling events,
registering event handlers,
and reusing common components.
But for this course,
we're going to stick
to the first most basic way
to use a custom directive.
To make this product title
custom directive work,
we need to define this directive
from inside our app.js.
We'll write app.directive
specify "productTitle"
and the second argument is going
to be an anonymous function, which
returns a directive
definition object.
This is basically
a configuration
defining how your
directive is going to work.
You might also have noticed
here that the dash in the HTML
of the directive will translate
to camelCase in JavaScript when
we define the directive.
We'll want to declare
two configuration
options for this directive.
The first is
restrict 'E'.  This is
where we specify the
type of directive.
In this case E
stands for element,
since we're declaring
a new HTML element.
Then we'll specify
the URL of a template
we want this directive
to load into the page.
In this case, just
"product-title.html" Then,
when we use this directive,
it'll simply render out
the template into
our index.html.
Now if we jump into the web
page, it should look the same.
Which it does, but this time
it's using the directive
and our HTML is more expressive.
Directives in Angular can either
be elements like you see here.
And notice, we're not
using a self-closing tag.
You might be
wondering about that.
We don't want to use
a self-closing tag
because some browsers don't
like self-closing tags when
using custom elements.
So that's why we're
not using one.
If we wanted to write this
directive as an attribute
directive, it might
look like this.
Where we specify
product-title as an attribute
inside an h3 element.
It's best practice to use an
element directive when you're
doing things like UI widgets and
attribute style directives when
you have things like mixins,
which add behaviors to HTML,
like maybe a tool tip.
If we wanted to use a
directive attribute instead,
our definition would
look slightly different.
We'd specify
restrict 'A' because
in this case, A
stands for attribute.
And then we could properly
use an attribute directive.
When you pick up the source
for somebody's web application,
do you think you
could understand
the behavior of the application
just by reading the HTML?
Typically not.
This is why Angular
is so awesome.
It allows you to
write expressive HTML
through custom directives.
So that people
can read your HTML
and understand the behavior
and intent of your application.
Time for you to write your
first custom directives.
I hope you're excited.
And I'll see you in
the next section.