In this section we're going
to add another directive,
and this time, attach
a controller to it.
So in our previous
section, we had
this HTML we encapsulated
into an attribute directive,
and an element directive.
Here's some additional code
that we can encapsulate
into a directive,
but you'll notice
it also has a controller.
So let's change this
into a directive
and then figure out how
to add the controller.
First step, as
you might imagine,
is we're going to take this code
and we're going to pull it out
into the product-panels.html.
Inside our index.html
we'll create
the product-panels
custom directive.
Then our app.js will start
defining the custom directive.
We'll call it productPanels,
notice the camel case,
it's an element directive.
So we write restrict 'E'.
And the template here is going
to be product-panels.html.
Now how do we move the
controller into the directive?
Well first things
first, we're going
to move the functionality
of the controller
into the directive using
the controller keyword.
So we have our
product-panels directive
with our panel controller
and it works fine.
We would just have to
remember every time
we add this
product-panels directive
to also include this controller.
So how might we
move this controller
inside the directive?
The first thing
we need to do, we
need to specify that alias
we'll want to use inside
of this directive to
refer to the controller.
In this case, panels.
And that's all there is to it.
And we can see that
everything works as it should,
nothing much has changed,
except our HTML has
become more organized
and expressive.
Time for you to jump
into the challenges.
Try this out and I'll see
you in the next level.
Director [MUMBLING]
Tells web page [NONSENSE SPEAK]
Or attribute or att-- [LAUGHS]