[SINGING] The
Flatlanders need to store
to sell their gems and more -
and they need it really quick.
Angular will do the trick.
Directives set the
stage in your HTML page.
Controllers give your wrap
the behavior that it lacks.
Write expressions so that
you can add your data
to the view. And modules
make connections
with dependency injections.
You're a scripting
connoisseur when
shaping up with Angular JS.
You're watching Shaping up with
Angular and this is level five.
where we're going to be talking about
dependencies and services.
Back in our app.js,
our application
is starting to get pretty long.
And well, we've got a lot of
different things happening.
Directives that are
concerned with one thing
are mingling with
other directives
and you need a way to
organize this code.
To do that, we're going to
start isolating some of our code
in their own modules.
The first step here
is to pull out,
let's say, all of our
product related directives
into the products.js file.
Here we're going to wrap
it in its own closure
and then define app
equals angular.module,
declaring a new module
just for product things,
and then specify the module
name of store-products.
There's nothing magical
about the module name here,
we just decided to
call it store-products,
because it's the products
which belong to the store.
You'll notice we're using that
app variable in both our app.js
and products.js, which is
fine because they're both
wrapped in a closure.
Now we need to tell
our store module
and it depends on this
store-products module.
To do that, we simply add
it to that blank array
when we initialize
our store module.
The other thing we need
to do to make this work
is to include this products.js
file inside our index.html.
Now, if we go back to our
web page-- hey big surprise--
it still works, but
this time our code
is a little more maintainable.
It's best to split up modules
based on their functionality.
So in our case, we'll take all
the functionality for products,
and only products, and
put it inside products.js.
Directives like product
title and product panels.
If we had a shopping cart or
a contact page on our store,
it might be good to create
module files for those as well.
Why don't you try creating a
module and I'll see you back
in the last section.