Welcome back.
In this last section we're going
to be talking about services.
One of which will
allow us to get rid
of this array of data we're
storing right here in our page
and instead pull it from an API.
So here you might
see a sample URL
that we might call out
to products.json which
will return us a JSON array
of all of our products,
which we want to load
in our store controller.
Hm.
So what does that
code look like?
As I mentioned,
we need a service.
Angular comes with
a bunch of services
built in which you
can use to give
your controller
additional functionality.
You could do things
like fetching JSON
from a web service
using the HTTP service.
You can also log out messages
to the JavaScript console
with a log service.
Or you could filter out an
array with the filter service.
As you might have noticed,
all these services
begin with a dollar sign.
That's because they're built-in
services with Angular.
The HTTP service
is the one we need
to use to get that JSON
data from our server.
We can do this by
using the HTTP method
as a function with an options
object, like you see here,
sending in the
method and the url.
Or we can use one of
the shortcut methods,
using the get method,
sending in a URL,
and any additional
query parameters
by sending in a
JavaScript object.
Both of these methods
return a promise.
And if you're not
familiar with promises,
check out our JQuery
courses on Code School.
A promise object allows
you to call backs on it,
like success or error, which
you'll see in a minute.
One nice feature of
the service is it
if we tell HTTP to
fetch JSON, the result
will automatically be decoded
into JavaScript objects
in arrays.
Pretty nice.
We need our controllers
to tell Angular
which services they need.
To do this, we use a
funky array syntax.
First in this array
syntax we specify
the names of the services
that our controller needs.
These services become arguments
in our controller function.
Here we can then use $http
inside the controller.
This way of specifying
the different services
our controller needs is
called dependency injection.
And if you needed more
than one service here's
what that might look like.
I know this looks
a little funky,
this dependency injection
thing's a little weird.
So let me see if I can try to
explain what's going on here.
When Angular loads it creates
something called an injector.
When these built-in
services load,
they register with the injector
as being available libraries.
Then when our application loads,
it registers our controller
with the injector, telling
it that when it gets
executed it's going to need
the HTTP and log services.
Injector says, cool.
Then when our page loads,
and our controller gets used,
the injector grabs the
services that our controller
needs and passes
them in as arguments.
That's called
dependency injection
because it's injecting the
dependencies-- in this case,
the services-- into the
controller as arguments.
So here we are back in
our store controller.
And we need that HTTP service.
So, we use that weird
array syntax and we specify
'$http' there as a
service it needs,
and then we specify
$http has an argument.
Now we can use it
inside our controller.
So we'll write $http.get
specify the URL to call.
Now we need to tell it what to
do when it gets the data back.
So we'll write .success,
sending a call back to success,
because it's going
to return some data.
And now we need to do
something with that data.
Really, we need to set it
equal to this.products,
but can we write this.products
inside that callback?
No.
Because this inside of that
callback is the service, $http.
So here we need to do
something a little funky.
We're going to create a
variable called store.
Set it equal to this, and
now inside of our callback
we can write
store.products = data.
This request might
take a second,
but our page isn't
going to wait for it.
It's going to go ahead and load.
So it might be a good idea
to initialize products
to an empty array.
That way when the page
loads there's no errors.
Then later on, after
we fetch the JSON,
we can load that data
into the products,
and the page will
automatically get updated.
Here you can see
our page loading
and our products getting loaded
dynamically from a remote API.
In addition to get requests,
HTTP can do things like post,
put, and delete.
And here's the syntax for that.
It can also go load
any other HTTP method
by using a config object,
like you see here.
You'll need some
of these commands
in the challenges which I'm
going to set you loose on.
Complete those
challenges and I will
see you in the outro video
at the end of the course.
Thanks for watching.
In the HTTP [NONSENSICAL SOUNDS]
It's over here
[NONSENSICAL SOUNDS]
Cool, I got it!