Hello.
I'm Gregg Pollack, and you're
watching Level 1 of Try iOS.
You're going to need to know a
little bit of Objective C to
get through this tutorial.
If you haven't seen Objective C
before, see the Objective C
Primer, which you should find
the link below this video.
Once you've done that, come
back, and we'll get going.
In this level, we're going to
be going over starting your
first iPhone project, the
Application Delegate.
We'll be building our
first iPhone app.
Finally, how to draw on our
screen, and then we're going
to be refactoring some code to
make it a little bit cleaner.
Along the way, we're going to
have Mr. Higgie to keep us
company, as you see here.
And as he says, you don't need
any Xcode to run this.
You don't need a Mac.
You don't need to install Xcode
to do this tutorial.
However, if you do have
Xcode installed--
Xcode, by the way, is how you
develop iOS applications--
you can follow along.
So we'll show you how
to build what we're
building inside Xcode.
But like I said, you
don't have to.
You can code right along
in the browser.
Our first iPhone application
is going to do two things.
It's going to have a background
color, and we're
going to be able to click to
change the transparency.
So let's go ahead and
show you what that's
going to look like.
So as you can see here, as I
click the screen, it's going
to change its transparency
levels so it'll get brighter
and darker.
I compare learning how to build
iOS applications to
maybe learning how to
drive a submarine.
If I were to sit you down at
the navigator's seat and I
were to teach you all the
different knobs and levers and
instrumentation, well, we
wouldn't be diving for a long
time, because there's
a lot to learn.
There's also a lot to learn
in iOS development.
So as we go through this
tutorial, we're going to be
ignoring certain knobs
and levers.
Some of the code's going
to look intimidating,
but don't freak out.
We're going to simply go through
it so we can get you
building iOS apps in no time.
And those little details, well,
you'll come back to
later and learn as you become
a better iOS developer.
As I mentioned, you don't need
Xcode to do this tutorial.
But if you already have it
installed, here is how you
would create a new project for
what we're about to build.
After creating a new project,
you would select a Single View
Application.
You can give it any name
that you want.
Here we're calling
it AlphaTouch.
And here are the files that
it would create for you.
Notice we have some dot h files,
which are header files
in C; and some dot m files,
where we put our
implementation.
The first file we're going
to jump into is our
AppDelegate.m.
Inside this file we have a bunch
of methods which are
called at different points in
our application lifecycle.
There's only one that we're
going to look into for now
called application:
didFinishLaunchingWithOptions,
which gets called when our
application is launched.
Here's what the method
definition looks like.
It's large and intimidating, as
are many Objective C method
definitions.
Sometimes we're going to list
this on two different lines.
So here you can see the
same method but
listed on two lines.
Here's the different
parts of it.
We have the method name, which
is
application:didFinishLaunchingWithOptions.
We have the parameter types, and
then finally we have the
two different parameter names
which get sent in when we call
this method.
In our new application, well,
there's not much inside of
that method except for a return
YES, which basically
means we want to continue
launching the application.
Now, remember, back in that
primer, you should have seen
an NSLog function.
That's how we log out
to the console.
In this next challenge, you're
simply going to take that
NSLog function, and you're going
to put it inside the
application:
didFinishLaunchingWithOptions
and see if you can get something
printing out when you launch
your iPhone app.