Good job.
You just built your
first iPhone app.
Before we go on though, we need
to think a little bit
about what does an artist
need to paint?
No really, what does an
artist need to paint?
Well there's three different
things--
you've got your canvas, you have
your paintbrush, and then
you have your paint.
Now we're going to ask the
question, what does an iOS app
need to draw something?
Well it's pretty similar.
You need the window, we
need a viewController,
and we need the view.
And their functions
kind of resemble
what the artist needs.
Now let's jump into the code
and see how to create our
window, viewController,
and view.
So here we are back in
our AppDelegate file.
Here's our first method call.
If you're coming from a
different language, we're used
to calling methods on objects.
We don't use that terminology in
Objective C. We simply say
that we're sending a message.
So sending a message
is equivalent
to calling a method.
So here, we're sending the
message, main screen, into the
UIScreen class.
We're going to store
that inside a
variable called screen.
Then we're going to send the
bounds message into that
screen object, which is going to
return for us the bounds of
the screen.
The bounds of the screen is
simply an object that contains
the screen's width and the
height of our iOS application.
We're going to store the
bounds inside a CGRect.
And then using a log message,
we can log out how high and
how wide our screen is
using this command.
In this case, it's telling us
that our screen is 480 tall
and 320 wide.
In case you want to learn more
about the methods that we're
using in this class, underneath
the video there
should be buttons that you
should be able to press to
look at the documentation behind
each of these classes,
and learn more about the
properties and its methods.
Do we really need the
screen variable?
Actually, Mr. Higgie, we don't
need that screen variable.
That's a good observation.
We can write those two lines
in one, so let's
combine them together.
So here we're sending the main
screen message into UIScreen
and what gets returned, we send
in the bound message too.
It's a little simpler.
Next, we need to create our
UIWindow, or our canvas.
Here we're going to allocate
memory for it, and initialize
it with the frame size set to
the bounds of the screen,
which we just retrieved.
We'll then store that inside
of our window variable.
And we'll use this little canvas
icon here on the left
to remind us that that's where
we built our window.
This is already a property!
You're right, Mr. Higgie.
This is already a property.
You're probably wondering
what he means by that.
Well if we look inside the
AppDelegate.h file, we would
see that there's a property in
here called window, which is
an instance variable.
Meaning every time we create an
object from this class, we
get this variable to use.
So back down in our
AppDelegate.m we can just use
self.window, because we have
that instance variable.
The next thing we need to build
our iPhone app is to
call makeKeyAndVisible
on our window.
This means it's going to receive
all keyboard events
and all non-touch events.
And if we built this
application, we get an error
message that says we need
a root view controller.
So our next step, we need to
create that ViewController
object, which is represented
here by our paint brush.
Our UIViewController is going
to be called colorTouchVC.
That's our variable name, and
we're simply going to allocate
some memory for it,
and initialize it.
Then we'll set this
ViewController equal to our
rootViewController
on the window.
This is basically telling the
window to use this paint
brush, or view controller,
to draw the view.
Now it needs some paint
to put on our canvas.
So let's create the view here.
We're going to allocate memory
for it and initialize it with
our viewRect, which is basically
the entire bounds of
the screen.
Then we simply set the .view
property on our view
controller equal to that view.
Now we can start coloring
on the screen.
We're going to do that by simply
setting the background
color of our view.
We do that by sending
in a UIColor.
And there's a bunch of different
colors you can use
here, and methods that you can
use to create a UIColor and
set the background color.
Now it's time for you to jump
into the challenges, and start
building iPhone apps with pretty
background colors.