Welcome back.
Now before we move on, let's
review the code that we've
written in our app delegate.
So here, up at the top, we have
our bounds, we have our
window, we have our
UIViewController.
Then we have our view.
And then finally we set the
rootViewController.
And send the message,
makeKeyAndVisible, and log out
the size of the screen.
This code needs to
be refactored!
Oh you're right, Mr. Higgie.
There's a bunch of stuff that we
can do to factor this code.
And if we look back at our
file system, we'll notice
there's a file there called
ViewController.
If we look inside the
ViewController.h we'll see
that it declares a class called
ViewController, which
has a parent class of
UIViewController.
This is a pretty common pattern
in iOS applications.
When we need a class to have a
custom behavior, we'll often
subclass it and then
add that behavior.
Often we say superclass instead
of parent class.
Oh, you're right, Mr. Higgie.
Often we say superclass instead
of parent class.
You'll see them both used.
Let's move that file over.
And now, if we look inside our
AppDelegate.h, we'll see that
it already included this
ViewController class, and it
has an @property.
So every time we declare an
AppDelegate, well, it's going
to have a ViewController.
And also insider our
AppDelegate.m, it's already
imported the ViewController
for us so that we
can use this class.
Now let's jump back to our
old code and refactor it.
So rather than creating our own
UIViewController, we're
simply going to use the
ViewController property with
self.viewController.
Then we simply call self.
when we're setting the view
for this ViewController.
And again self.
when we're setting the
routeViewController on our window.
Our paintbrush is in charge of
taking the paint and putting
it on to the canvas.
In the same way, our
ViewController is in charge of
taking the views and painting
the views onto our window.
So our view here in the
AppDelegate really needs to be
inside of the ViewController.
So let's do that now.
Woah, woah, woah.
A bunch of code moved around
there, don't freak out.
Here we are inside of our
ViewController.m.
We just moved some code over.
Inside of there we have
a loadView method.
And this is called the
first time the
view property is accessed.
Inside there the only
thing we need to
change is call self.view.
Then, inside of viewDidLoad
method, which is
called after loadView--
typically this is where you
would put all of your buttons
and labels, which we'll
get to later--
you'll also notice in here
that we're sending the
viewDidLoad message into super,
meaning our superclass,
or the parent class.
It's important to do this in
case there's set up that it
needs to do too.
And if we take a look back at
out AppDelegate.m now that
we've refactored, we'll notice
that there's no mention of the
view inside of it.
Much better.
It's not good to have views
in your AppDelegate.
Right, it's usually not good to
have views inside of your
AppDelegate.
We want to encapsulate those
inside of our ViewControllers.
So our application so
far-- we've got the
window up at the top.
Windows can have multiple
ViewControllers, which we'll
see in the next level.
Usually each ViewController
encapsulates a piece of behavior.
Then each of those
ViewControllers has a single
view, which we use to
draw things on.
One of those ViewControllers
is the rootViewController,
which is the one that gets
displayed onto the screen.
So we're building iPhone
applications, but what good is
an app, if we can't
interact with it.
So in our next task let's figure
out how to make it do
something when we touch
the screen.
As you remember from earlier,
ViewController, inherits from
UIViewController.
Well UIViewController inherits
from UIResponder, which is an
interface for responding
to events.
Our view also inherits
from UIResponder.
UIResponder gives us
a bunch of methods.
If we implement these methods
inside of our ViewController
or View, those will
get called when we
interact with the screen.
Now back in our ViewController,
we're going to
implement the touchesBegan
withEvent method.
And now this is going to get
called whenever we begin to
touch our iPhone screen.
And that's all there is to it.
Now it's time for you to try
this in the challenges.
And I'll see you on level two.