All right, so let's take
another look at this
code we have here.
In the viewDidLoad we declare
two buttons, then we have the
buttonPressed method.
There's a couple things that
kind of suck about this code.
I'm going to let Mr. Higgie
point them out.
We're doing a comparison
on the button title.
Right.
We're doing a comparison on a
title, which may not be the
safest thing to do.
There's going to be a better
way to do that comparison.
The variable names are awful.
Right, and the variable names
don't really say what they
do-- we've got first button
and second button.
So let's fix that right now.
The first thing that we're
going to do to clean this
stuff up is inside of our
ViewController.h, our header file.
We're going to declare
two properties,
for each of our UIButtons.
This is a pretty common pattern
you'll see in iOS
applications, where all the
different subviews we declare
as properties on the
ViewController they're going
to be displayed in.
So we have our 50button, our
100button, then inside of
our ViewController.m,
here's the old code.
Let's go ahead and revise it
to use these @properties.
All we have to do is use
self.fiftyPercentButton in
many different places, as
well as doing that with
self.hundredPercentButton
for the other button.
But I'm not going to
show you that.
Now how do we improve
the conditional?
Here's our conditional, where
we're comparing two strings.
Well now that our entire class
has access to these UIButton
properties, we can use those to
check to see if the sender
is equal to the 50button.
In case you're wondering, that
isEqual method comes from NS
object, which all objects
in iOS inherit from.
It's the most root object.
Much cleaner.
Now it's time for you to clean
up some of your code.
And I'll see you
in level three.