Hello.
I'm Gregg Pollack, and you're
watching Try iOS Level Two,
where we're going to be talking
about subviews.
In this level, we'll be creating
some buttons, some
labels, making the buttons work,
making multiple buttons
on the screen, and then finally,
cleaning up our code.
So let's jump into it.
So back in level one, we had
a window or a canvas.
We also had a ViewController
represented here by the
paintbrush.
And then finally, we had a
View, which is the paint,
which gets painted
onto our window.
If we had a screen that looked
something like this, the view
in our case is that beautiful
yellow background.
But how do we add buttons
like the Click Me
button you see here?
Well, we do this by adding
subviews onto our views.
So this button here
is a subview.
And we're going to figure
out how to create one
of those right now.
So here we are back in our
ViewController. m in our
viewDidLoad method.
We set the background color.
And now we're going to create
a UI button, just like so.
When we a create UI button, we
tell it what type of button.
In this case, the
UIButtonTypeRoundedRect, which
is the most standard iPhone
button that you've definitely
seen before.
You might notice that when we
declare this UI button, we
don't have to allocate memory
for it or instantiate.
But some classes we
have to do this.
The best way to figure out
whether you do or you don't is
to simply look at the
documentation.
Under the video, you should see
a link which will bring
you to more documentation
about a UI button.
And really what this means is
that it's still getting
allocated and initialized.
But, well, the iOS is
doing it for you.
Next, we need to send them
the button frame.
We do this by creating another
one of those CGRects.
And we send in four
parameters.
The first is the x parameter,
then the y, then the width,
and the height.
And we'll explain this in
more detail in a minute.
Then, we can set the
button title.
And we also need to send
in the parameter
forState:UIControlStateNormal.
So what we're saying
here is, what does
the button say normally?
And then lastly, we add the UI
button as a subview onto our
ViewController's
existing view.
So, sweet.
Here's our iPhone.
There's our button.
We can click it.
It doesn't do anything
yet, but well,
that's our first subview.
Cool.
Now let's go into this code in
a little more depth, starting
with when we declare
our button.
In case you're wondering, if we
look in the documentation,
we would see that UIButton
inherits from UIView.
It's a type of view.
And UIView, as we saw in the
previous level, inherits from
UIResponder.
Now there's a couple
different types of
buttons that we can create.
Here is the RoundedRect.
Here's the detailed
disclosure.
TypeInfoLight, TypeInfoDark,
and TypeContactAdd.
So we can create all these
different types of buttons
pretty easily.
The next line of code we're
going to look at
is setting the frame.
And as we mentioned, it sets the
x, y, width, and height.
But when we're talking about x,
y, how do we plot that onto
our iOS device frame?
Well, basically 0,0 is in the
top left-hand corner.
So if we're plotting this button
at 100, 100, well, it's
going to use those points to
figure out where it goes.
And then, it is 100 points wide
and 44 points in height.
So there's our button.
And--
You must be wondering
what points are.
Yeah.
You're probably wondering
what points are.
why I'm not
talking in terms of pixels.
Well, allow me to explain.
With a Non Retina iPhone, one
1 point is equal to 1 pixel,
so you can kind of use
them interchangeably.
So the size here for a
Non Retina iPhone in
points is 320 by 480.
And that same size in pixels
is 320 by 480.
It's the same, because it's
a one to one relationship.
However, when we have an iPhone
4 with a Retina screen,
1 point is equal to 4 pixels.
So the points remain the same,
which allow us to plot things
using the same coordinate system
no matter what device
we're using.
However, when it comes
to pixels--
well, it's going to be
double the number of
pixels in each direction.
Now, you might be wondering
where the iPhone 5 fits in.
Well, the iPhone 5 has the
same pixel density
as the iPhone 4.
So in this case, it actually has
more points because it's
taller, and the pixels are
the same sort of multiple
as the iPhone 4.
Next up, we set this
button title.
As we mentioned, it sets the
title that gets displayed
normally on the button.
Well, if we wanted to change the
title when the button gets
pressed, we could send this
message in again with the
parameter
UIControlStateHighlighted,
which we'll be doing in
the challenges later.
And lastly, we're going to add
our button as a subview onto
our view controller's view.
And as you can imagine, you
might want to have multiple
subviews on top of your view if
you want multiple buttons
or say, a label.
Let's add a label.
Just like we have a UI button
class, we also have a helper
class called UILabel.
And we can initialize it by
sending in the x, y, width,
and the height.
Then we can set the
text on the label.
And finally, add it
as a subview.
And this is what we would get.
What's with the white background
on UILable?
Good point, Mr. Higgie.
I was wondering this myself when
I first put this label on
the screen.
Why is there a white
background there?
We can get rid of the white
background pretty easily,
simply by specifying the
background color equal to
UIColor clearColor.
And it does what you
expect it to.
Much better.