So we've got buttons.
But how do we make
them do stuff?
How do we make them work?
Well if we look into the
UIButton hierarchy, we would
see that UIButton inherits
from UIControl, and then
UIView, and then UIResponder.
And it's that UIControl
class which allows us
to convey user intent.
If we looked inside of
that documentation--
which you can, of course, by
pressing the button below--
we would find a method called
addTarget:action
:forControlEvents:.
And we use this on the UIButton
object to listen for
particular events and call
methods, when events happen.
We don't have to define
the method.
But the declaration of the
method itself looks
something like this.
We can tell because it has that
minus symbol, that it's
an instance method.
So we can call that
on our UIButton.
The controlEvents, that last
parameter, is the event we
want to be listening
for on our button.
Then the target parameter is a
target object that we want to
send a message into, when it
gets pressed or whatnot.
And the action is the message we
want to send on the target,
when the event gets triggered.
So let's go ahead and implement
this method.
Back in our ViewController,
we're going to declare a new
method called buttonPressed,
which we want to get called
when the button is pressed.
And we're simply going to log
out when it gets pressed.
And then randomize the alpha
transparency on the view, kind
of like we did in level one.
If we wanted to call our newly
created method from inside of
our ViewController, we would
call self, and send in the
message
buttonPressed:firstButton.
This is the call we want
to happen when
the event gets triggered.
So now let's hook this
all together.
Back in our viewDidLoad, on our
firstButton, we're going
to call that method you saw
on the previous slide.
The event we want to listen
for is TouchUpInside.
So whenever we get done touching
the button, and our
finger goes up, we want
to trigger an event.
When it gets triggered, we want
to send a message to the
ViewController.
So here we're sending in self,
and the method we want to call
is buttonPressed.
You might be wondering
what that selector,
that @selector is.
That's simply how, in Objective
C, we send in method names as
parameters.
We wrap them in a selector.
One last thing before we see
our button in action.
Since we are writing C, we need
to jump back into the
ViewController.h,
the header file.
And since we declared a method,
we need to declare it
as part of the interface,
here.
And now if we run our app, we
can see right here that every
time we click the button, it
changes our transparency.
And it outputs this log.
There are a bunch of different
UIControl events that
we can listen to.
And here's a list of
a bunch of them.
So a lot of these have to do
with touching, or editing, or
if you want to listen to all
these events you can do that
with some of these
at the bottom.
Just like you can add a subview
to a view, you can
also remove one.
And I want to show you how to do
that before we get into the
challenges.
So if we want to remove the
button right after it got
pressed, the buttonPressed
method gets called.
We can simply call
sender, sender in
this case is the UIButton.
As you can see, it gets
passed in when
this method gets called.
And we can send the
removeFromSuperview message on
it, so it removes itself.