Welcome back.
Now let's jump back into our
iPhone app, and this time
we're going to have two
different buttons.
You'll notice here, our first
button we're now setting a
title called Make 50
And we're going to have a second
button that has the
title Make 100
The thing to notice here is that
they're both calling the
same method when they're
pressed--
the buttonPressed method.
So here we are.
But they both do
the same thing.
Yeah, you're right,
Mr. Higgie.
They both do the same thing.
We need to fix that.
So how might we fix that?
Well, inside of our
buttonPressed method, we might
have a conditional.
We need to figure out what
that conditional is.
Obviously this isn't it.
We need to figure out how to
make it to check if it is the
50button that got sent
in, or the 100
So if it's the 50button, we're
going to set the alpha
to 0.5, and then otherwise it's
going to be just one.
So how do we build
that conditional?
Well, you might want to jump
into the documentation and see
what we can find.
So if we look in the UIButton
documentation, we might find
that it has a titleLabel
property that
we have access to.
So that's the beginning of our
conditional down here at the
bottom, sender.titleLabel.
And if you look in the
documentation for UILabel, we
can see that UILabel has
a text property.
So that's the next part.
And that returns an NSString.
So if we look in the NSString
documentation, we might see
that it has a method called
isEqualToString, which takes
two strings to see
if they're equal.
So we can write the rest of
our conditional like so.
Then bring that back in to our
buttonPressed method, and
hopefully it'll work.
So now if we build and compile
this application, and we run
it, we can see that when we
click make 50, it makes it 50
transparent.
And when we click 100 120720t makes
it completely opaque.
Groovy buttons.
And even Mr. Higgie likes it.
Now let's use this information
in the challenges to make two
different buttons work as
they're supposed to.