Hello.
I'm Gregg Pollack, and you're
watching Try iOS, and this is
level three, where we're going
to be going over tabs, images,
and scrolling.
But before we get into it, we
need to talk about the demo
app that we're going to be
building together over the
remainder of the course.
It's called InstaPhoto.
It has three main pieces
of functionality.
The first, it has
a photo feed.
So we can view the latest photos
off of the internet.
It then has a favorites
tab where we can
save photos for later.
And then finally, it has a
profiles tab, which we can see
information about ourselves
and edit that information.
How very original.
Yeah.
It's not totally original, but
it's a good demonstration of
what you can do with iOS.
Our topic list for level three
looks something like this.
First, we're going to introduce
the UITabBarController,
then we're going
to add images to the tabs.
Then we're going to refactor
our view controllers.
We're going to add images to
our view controllers, and
finally, we'll learn about
UI scroll view.
The applications we've built
thus far only have one view
controller, right?
There's a window, it points to
a view controller, which
points to a view.
A view controller should only
have one primary job.
Right.
It should only have one primary
job, which means as
our application gets more
complex and has different
behaviors, we're probably going
to want to separate
those behaviors out into
different view controllers.
Let's take a look inside a
common iOS application, and
see if we can figure out how
it might separate its
different view controllers.
So inside the Clock app, we have
the World Clock, we have
the Alarm Settings, we
have the Stopwatch,
and we have the Timer.
These are each separate
functionalities.
So if we were to get access to
the code, odds are we would
find that it has a World Clock
view controller, it has an
Alarm view controller, it has
a Stopwatch view controller,
and it has a Timer
view controller.
And that is controlled by the
UI tab bar controller, which
is a type of container
view controller.
Meaning that it contains
other view controllers.
So we have our window
here at the top.
Then our Window is going to
point to our UI tab bar
controller.
In this case, our window's view
controller is set to
UITabBarController, which
contains the rest of our view
controllers.
As you might have already
imagined, when you tap on the
different tabs, the UITabBarController
will display the
corresponding view controller.
Let's jump back into our
application.m and
implement a  UITabBarController.
So first step here is we
allocate the memory for and
initialize it.
We don't need to create
it as a subclass.
We can just instantiate
it here.
And we'll set our window root
view controller equal to the
tab bar controller.
Now, we can't run this
code as it is yet.
We need to add some view
controllers inside of it.
We're building InstaPhoto,
and InstaPhoto
has a feed of photos.
So let's create  feedViewController, just like so.
Give it a title, which will
be the title of the tab.
And then we'll create
favoritesViewController, and
also set the title as well.
Then let's at these each to a
different background color, so
we can tell we're switching
back and
forth between the two.
And then finally, we send the
setViewControllers message
into the tab bar controller, and
send it the view controllers
that it should contain.
By default, the first view
controller in this list will
be shown when we start
up our application.
So here we are inside of our UI
tab bar controller, and we
can switch back and forth
between two to switch between
blue and red.
Just add a police siren, and
you could pull someone oer
with this app.
Very funny, Mr. Higgie.
And now it's time for you to
jump into the code and start
creating some tabs of your own.