One more section before we get
done with level three.
What we want to do here is
build out our profile.
So we might want to display not
only the profile image,
but the name, city, biography,
and member since.
So here we are back in our
ProfileViewController.
There's the image
we just created.
That's our old code.
Let's first make this a smaller
profile image to make
some room for the text that
we're going to be
putting on the page.
One way we can do that is by
setting the frame equal to a
CG rectangle, where we specify
the x-y width and height.
Cool.
So now this is what our screen
currently looks like with our
picture up there.
Now we need to add some more
views, maybe a UILabel,
another UILabel for city, a
UITextView for biography
because, well, it's going to be
a paragraph of information,
and then another UILabel
for member since.
So jumping back into our
ProfileViewController, here's
our UILabel.
This code should
look familiar.
Then a city label, and then our
UITextView, which is new.
And we're going to initialize
it by sending
in rectangle again.
Then we can set the
font because we
want a smaller font.
By default, a UITextView is
editable, so we want to set it
to not be editable.
So we'll send in no.
And then we add the text and
add it as a subview.
Lastly, we're going to add
the memberSince UILabel.
And that's about it.
So now if we go back into
our view, it looks
something like this.
And if we--
Where did member since go?
Yeah, Mr. Higgie, where did
our member since go?
It's sort of getting hidden
behind there, and for some
reason, we can't scroll
down to see it.
Well, that's because we need to
learn about UIScrollView.
It's pretty common in lots of
iOS applications to have a big
screen worth of data, and you
can scroll down to see the
rest of it.
Sometimes you can scroll
vertically, sometimes even
horizontally.
So we need to implement
a scroll view to
be able to do that.
So the first step is to declare
a property in our
header file called
UIScrollView.
And inside of our
ProfileViewController, we're
going to initialize that
scrollView, set it to the
bounds of the view that we're
putting it inside.
Now we need to set
the content size.
And this is probably
going to be bigger
than the frame, right?
Because we want to be able to
scroll down to other items.
So we need to specify in here
the content size for the total
amount of space we want
to be able to
scroll within the frame.
How do we figure that out?
Well, one way to figure
that out is to
look at the last UILabel.
We can see here that the
y-coordinate is 440, and its
total height is 40.
So if we add these together,
we're going to get the total
content size that we want to
be able to scroll down to.
In this case, it's 480.
The next thing we have to
change inside of our
ProfileViewController is
whenever we go to add
subviews, instead of adding them
to the view controller's
main view, we're going
to add these sub views
into our scroll view.
Here we add biography as a
subview to scroll view.
Then lastly, we're going to want
to add the scroll view
itself as a subview on to our
main ViewController view.
So here we are back
in our app.
Now we can scroll.
Hey, wait a second.
Where did we go wrong?
The scroll doesn't stick!
You see that?
We're scrolling up, but
it's not sticking.
For some reason, we can't
scroll down to
that and let go.
I wonder what went wrong.
Well, in order to figure that
out, we need to understand a
little bit about how things
get resized inside iOS.
So inside of our
ProfileViewController, it's
320 by 460.
You might be wondering why
it's 460 and not 480.
Well, that's because the time
and your cell carrier little
line at the top, that
takes up 20 points.
So that's why this
is 320 by 460.
Then we're setting the
scrollView's frame to the same
as the profileViewController's
frame.
This needs to go inside the
tabBarController, which has a
320 by 460 frame.
When the profileViewController
gets displayed inside the tab
bar, the profileViewController
by default gets resized to 320
by 411, as you would hope.
However, the scrollView
does not get resized.
We need some way of telling
the scrollView to resize
itself when the view that
it's in gets resized.
We can do this by specifying
the autoresizingMask on the
scrollView, which we're
setting here to
be a flexible height.
Here are a bunch of other resize
settings that you might
want to use.
Sometimes you might even want
to use two at the same time,
in the case where you have a
view that you want to be
flexible both for height
and width.
This is useful if you're
switching an app into
landscape view, for example.
So here we are again.
And now we can scroll,
and it sticks.
Scrolly goodness!
Awesome.
Now it's time for you to add
another UILabel to the profile
and adjust the scrollView
accordingly.