You probably noticed that the
tabs you're creating don't
have any icons.
Well, let's add some icons.
Icons are typically
30 by 30 points.
They're usually PNG with just
the Alpha channel, and they're
usually just imported into
your XCode project.
And you can just drag and
drop them inside.
Then inside of your AppDelegate,
we can specify on
that feedViewController the
tabBar image, and we can send
in a UIImage.
So here we actually just specify
the name of the file,
which in this case
is tab_icon_feed.
And by default it's going
to look in the cache.
If it doesn't find it
there, it's going to
look in the file system.
And it will look for a
.PNG file by default.
Go ahead and add the other
icons to the tabs.
I'll wait here.