Welcome back.
Here's our AppDelegate again.
And the code in here, well, it's
starting to feel a little
bit cluttered.
You need to create
FeedViewController to
encapsulate the behavior.
Right, Mr. Higgie.
We need to encapsulate all of
the behavior inside of a
ViewController.
Remember back in level one we
had a ViewController class?
Just like that, we need to
create some classes here,
maybe one called
FeedViewController.
To do that, if you're in Xcode,
you're going to go up,
and you're going to
select New File.
Then you're going to select
Objective C Class.
Then you'll specify the name of
this class-- in this case,
FeedViewController.
And it's important that you
specify the subclass of this
class, because it's going to
create some boilerplate code
for you inside of that subclass
that we're creating.
These are the files that will be
created, FeedViewController
dot m and dot h.
And it'll also add this file to
be compiled when you build
the application.
So now let's go back into the
old code, and let's refactor
it to use this
FeedViewController that we
just created.
We need to do two things here.
First, we need to import the new
class, and then we need to
use the new class.
So let's do that.
So here's our import line
at the top, import
FeedViewController.h.
And then we just simply use
FeedViewController,
FeedViewController.
And that's all there
really is to it.
However, now we need to move
the ViewController behavior
into this FeedViewController.
So those are those two lines
right there at the bottom.
So here's the FeedViewController
that was
created for us, and it gives us
this initialization method
that is really quite ugly.
This is one of those submarine
knobs and instrumentation.
You can just ignore it.
Don't try to understand it.
Just understand that inside of
this if conditional is where
you put your custom
implementation.
Namely, here we're going
to put the title
and the tabBar image.
Then inside of our viewDidLoad
at the bottom, that's where we
can put our background color and
create additional subviews
if we'd like.
Now it's time for you to finish
up our refactoring, and
I'll see you in a minute.