Next up, let's try to figure
out how to add
pictures onto our views.
So here inside viewDidLoad--
that's where we add subviews--
we're going to create
a UIImage view.
It's going to be called
greggView.
We're going to allocate the
memory for it and initialize
it by sending in a UIImage.
Notice here that I'm
specifying the file
name with a dot jpg.
Because it's not a png, we need
to specify the extension.
We want this view to take
up the entire screen.
So instead of sending in the x,
y width and height, we're
going to set the ContentMode
to ScaleAspectFit.
We're then going to set the
frame of this image equal to
the frame of the view that
it's in so it'll
be the whole frame.
And then, of course, we just
need to add it as a subview.
Let's go through this
one more time.
So we're creating a view for
displaying the image.
It's not a png, so we need
to specify the extension.
We have the ContentMode, which
determines how a view lays out
the content.
We set the frame, which
describes the view's
location and size.
And then lastly, we add
it as a subview.
Now it's time for you to add
some of your own images, and
I'll catch you on
the flip side.