Hello.
I'm Gregg Pollack.
And you're watching Try iOS.
This is level four, where we're
going to be going over
UINavigationController
and custom buttons.
Our topics look something
like this.
We're going to start out with
UINavigationController, then
figure out how to do custom
buttons, how to create custom
View Controllers on the fly.
And then finally, we'll figure
out how to use both navigation
and TabBar Controllers
together.
How else can we navigate
ViewControllers?
Well, let's pop open another app
and see if we can figure
out how they do it.
Here inside of our settings
iPhone app, you can see we
maybe have the
SettingsViewController.
Then, maybe also when we
click on something, the
GeneralViewController for
the general settings.
And then you have the
AboutViewController.
You can probably see where
this is going.
Here's a quick video, where
you can see where in the
SettingsController, we'll
click on General.
That pushes control to the
GeneralViewController.
And that pushes control to
the AboutViewControl.
It's almost like we're pushing
and popping from a stack of
ViewControllers.
Look up at the top there.
Settings.
Now we're in General.
Now we're in About.
And it remembers where
we came from.
So it remembers that the
settings is where we started,
so we can pop those other
ViewControllers off of our
virtual stack.
Let's jump back into our code
from the previous level, where
we were using the
tabBarController.
And let's revise it to use
the NavigationController.
So let's take away the tabBar.
And now what we're going
to do is create a
UINavigationController.
And you'll notice here we
initialize it by sending in
our FeedViewController.
Then, when we go to set our
window.rootViewController, we
just set it equal to our new
NavigationController.
Now if we go to our application,
we would see
something that looks
like this.
You can see that title
bar across the top.
And it actually defaulted to
Feed, which is just the name
of the ViewController.
FeedViewController, so it took
Feed and assumed that was the
name, and put it
up at the top.
Pretty cool.
Now if we wanted to push to
another ViewController, we
would use this piece of code
you see here, where we push
onto our stack another
ViewController.
So now that we're in our
FeedViewController, how might
we create a button that
then pushes to our
FavoritesViewController?
To do this, we're going
to jump into our
FeedViewController.
And inside viewDidLoad under our
background color, we're going
to create a UI button.
This should all look
very familiar.
Then we're going to add a
target to the Favorites
button, so that when somebody
presses this button, it calls
the new showFavorites
method, which we are
now about to define.
Inside showFavorites, we're
going to instantiate a new
FavoritesViewController.
Then, since our
FeedViewController is wrapped
in a NavigationController,
we can call
self.navigationController, get
a hold of it, and then send a
message, pushViewController,
and then push our
FavoritesViewController
onto our stack.
If we built and ran the
application, here's what it
would look like.
So we start out in the
FeedViewController.
And when we press the button,
we're pushed to the
FavoritesViewController.
But it remembers that our first
ViewController was the
FeedViewController, so we can
navigate easily back and forth
between the two.
Now it's time for you to
play around with the
NavigationController.