Now, let's jump back into our
Favorites View Controller.
Wouldn't it be nice if clicking
that button linked to
a bigger image?
It would be nice, Mr. Higgie.
How might we do that so when
we click on that button it
brings us to a full
view image?
And is that image in another
view controller?
And how do we push
that onto the
Navigation Controller stack?
So if we jump back into the
Favorites View Controller, as
we did before, we can see here
we are creating a UIImageView.
Instead of that, we're going
to create a UIButton.
This button is of type custom.
We're then going to set the
image for this button for
State Normal.
But we also have to set the
image for State Highlighted.
We have to do this because
it's a custom button.
You might be able to derive from
these two lines of code
how you might have a custom
press state for a button.
So you might have one image--
what it looks like when it's
not pressed, another
image when it's
highlighted or pressed.
We then have to set the
frame of the button.
And then finally, we're going to
add an action so that when
somebody touches this button, it
calls a method called show
zoomed picture, which we're
going to define in a moment.
So now, we have a button
that looks like this.
And we need to figure out how
to send control to another
view controller.
So we need to create another
view controller which displays
the image in a full size.
Do we need to create
another subclass?
But hold your horses, you don't
need another subclass!
Oh.
Mr. Higgie says we don't
need another subclass.
And we don't.
We can create a UI View
Controller on the fly.
Let me show you what I mean.
So inside our Favorites View
Controller, here's our show
zoomed picture method.
Inside there, we're simply going
to create a new view
controller which is
not subclassed.
We're going to set the frame to
the entire view frame, set
the title, which will show
at the top of our view
controller.
Then we need the image.
So we create an image, just like
we did before, and add
that as a subview into our new
Image View Controller.
Finally, we grab our Navigation
Controller and push
onto our stack the new
Image View Controller
that we just created.
If we build and run our
application, here's what it
looks like.
So we start in the
FeedViewController, push to
the Favorites, and
then push to our
tryiosImageViewController,
just like that.
And it remembers which one is
previous in the stack so that
we can navigate back and
forth pretty easily.
So we know about the Tab Bar
Controller and about the
Navigation Controller, but
how might we use the
two at the same time?
Well, here we have our
basic profile view.
What we do is we wrap that
inside the Profile Navigation
Controller, which gives us
that bar at the top.
And then we're going to wrap
that inside the Tab Bar
Controller like you see here.
In our code, what is that
going to look like?
Well, first we have our Profile
View Controller.
We wrap that inside of our
Navigation Controller just
like we did a moment ago.
Then we'll create our window,
then instantiate our Tab Bar
Controller and set the View
Controllers for that to Tab
Bar Controller and set that Tab
Bar Controller as the root
view so it gets displayed.
So here's what it ends up
looking like with both the Tab
Bar and the Navigation
View Controllers.
Where did your other tabs go?
Oh, Mr. Higgie's right.
We lost our other tabs.
Well, maybe we'll leave that
you do in the challenges.