You're watching Try iOS, and
this is level five, where
we're going to be going over
table view controllers.
In this level, we're going to
introduce you to UITableView,
figure out how to get data
inside of the cells inside
your TableViews, figure out
how to push to another
controller by tapping on a cell,
and then finally, how to
change the TableView style.
UITableViews are really
common in iPhone apps.
You can see them just
about everywhere.
Here's a couple examples
of UITableViews.
It's hard to find a non-game
app that doesn't contain at
least one UITableView.
Yeah.
They're all over the place.
If we wanted an app which just
has a UITableViewController,
we would have the window review
controller just have
the TableView just
like so, and that
UITableViewController, as you
might imagine, inherits from
the superclass UIViewController.
Then, inside of that
TableViewController, we have
to use a UITableView.
And then, for the different
cells in the table, we use
UITableViewCells.
So on this window, each one of
the cities you see here,
they're each UITableViewCells.
So let's create our first
UITableViewController class by
creating a new file, and a
new Objective C class.
We're going to call it
FeedTableViewController, and
it's a subclass of
UITableViewController.
That's going to create two files
for us, which are going
to have some boilerplate
code, which we need
to display our table.
Let's take a look back
at our AppDelegate.m.
Here's where we have
FeedViewController that we
wrap in a
UINavigationController.
So let's get rid of that.
Let's replace that with the
feedTableViewController.
First, we need to import
the proper file.
Then, we're going to instantiate
it, and we're
going to initialize it with
a TableViewStyle.
In this case, we're going
to call it Plain.
There's also a group style
option, which you're going to
play around with in
the challenges.
Then we're going to send in this
feedTableViewController
into our NavigationController.
As I mentioned before, these two
files that it creates for
us have a lot of boilerplate
code.
However, there are three methods
that we want to pay
attention to.
The first is the number of
sections in TableView, which
returns the number
of sections.
If we don't have any sections,
then we just put one.
We're going to have
one section.
Then we have tableView:number
OfRowsInSection, and this
method returns the number of
rows or cells for our table.
And then lastly, there's
tableView: cellForRowAtIndexPath.
This is going to get called
every time your application
needs to draw the cell.
So it's going to be called for
each cell in your table.
Let's go ahead and implement
these methods inside our
FeedTableViewController.
So here, we're only going
to have one section.
So we just return one.
Then we're going to
have five rows.
So we just say return five.
And before we jump into this
last one, we need to
understand a little bit more
about how cells work in our
tableViews.
Here's a very basic TableView,
which has a bunch of cells,
each which tells us which
row number it's in.
Now, so it rendered out row
zero through row 10.
And for each of those,
it created a cell.
It allocated the memory and
created a cell for us.
Now, if we scroll down, let's
say three rows, we need to
obviously render out
11, 12, and 13.
Is it going to allocate the
memory for more cells?
No.
What it's going to do is it's
going to grab cells that fell
off the screen--
in this case, zero,
one, and two--
and it's going to reuse them to
create row 11, 12, and 13,
which is going to save us some
memory and make it faster.
With this information, let's
jump back into the
tableView:cellForRowAtIndexPath
method, which, as I mentioned,
is going to get called
every time we draw a
cell into our table.
So here it is.
First, we're going to check to
see if there's any cells that
we can reuse.
So as you can see from this
message,
dequeueReusableCellWithIdentifier.
So it's going to see if we have
a reusable cell that has
an identifier of Title
that we can reuse.
If it does not, if it returns
nil, then we're going to
allocate the memory for a
new one and use that.
And finally, we're going to
return that cell so that it
can be rendered into
our table.
Here's a quick demonstration
where we
can see this in action.
So when we first load up this
page, it allocates the memory
for each of these cells.
But as soon as we start
scrolling, we can see that
each of these cells is getting
creative with that reuse
identifier.
It's reusing the
existing cells.
And as we scroll up a little
bit, we can see that it's
reusing them.
If we scroll down, as the ones
at the top of the page scroll
off, they get reused at the
bottom as we scroll down.
How do we set the
text for a cell?
Well, if we look at the
documentation for UITableView,
we can see that it has a
textLabel, which, of course,
big surprise, is a UILabel.
UILabel, like we saw earlier,
has a text property.
And so we can simply set that
text label by just doing this,
as you see here.
Now it's time for you to get
into the challenges and make
some tables and some cells.