So we have a table.
And we need to load some
data into the table.
And well, we have
a list of items.
So obviously we might want to
load that data from an array.
Let's review NSArray.
So to create an NSArray of
strings, we would do
something like that.
Then to reference values from
that array we simply just
specify the index.
In this case we're reading out
the second object, which is
going to print out Eric.
We can also send in a
variable to get the
index for that array.
In this case, the fourth object
in the array, or John.
To determine how many elements
are in an array, we simply use
the count property.
This is going to be really
useful when we need to tell
our table how many
cells are in it.
If we're dealing with an array,
we can simply return
the count of items
in that array.
One more method that's really
useful that we can declare
inside our
FeedTableViewController is
tableview  didSelectRowAtIndexPath.
So didSelect- this gets called
whenever you tap
on one of the cells.
And the index path parameter
tells you which
cell has been tapped.
If we call .row it's going
to give you back an integer,
which represents the index
of that tapped cell.
We can also call
indexPath.section if you want
to figure out which section
that cell is in.
So in the challenges coming
up, we're going
to give you an array.
You're going to use that
array, to populate the
different cells of table.
And then to figure out which
cell has been tapped.
Good luck.