So now you know how
to determine which
cell has been tapped.
But how do we use that
information to then push to
another ViewController which
will then display that image?
To do this it's going to
take a couple steps.
First we're going to create a
PhotoViewController class.
Inside of that it's going to
have an @property which stores
the imageFileName which is--
we're going to figure out by
looking at the table which
cell was pressed.
Then we're going to create a
UIImageView to show the image
in that ViewController.
And finally we'll modify
our TableView's
didSelectRowAtIndexPath method
so that it creates this
ViewController, sets the file
name that we want to show, and
then uses the navigation
controller to display that new
ViewController.
All right.
So let's create a
PhotoViewController.
We've done this before.
We go and create a new file.
It's an Objective C Class.
And it's a UIViewController,
creates two files for us.
Pretty simple.
Now we need to define
that property.
So inside the
PhotoViewController.h, we
define a string, which
is the imageFileName
that we want to display.
Then inside of the
PhotoViewController, inside
the viewDidLoad, we're going to
create a UIImageView, which
will display in the middle
of the screen, and
add that as a subview.
Our last step is to jump back
into our TableViewController
in the didSelectRowAtIndexPath
method.
Inside there, we're going
to instantiate a
PhotoViewController.
Then we're going to set the
imageFileName based on the
index path that was sent in, and
then finally we're going
to push control to that
ViewController using our
navigationController.
That's all there is to it, and
I know you must be eager to
play around with it.
But before we go there, let's
take a moment to talk about
different cell styles.
So here we're using the
CellStyleDefault, but there's
a couple other ones that
you should know about.
So here we have
CellStyleValue1, Value2, and Subtitle.
And on the left side, you can
see how these are displayed.
You already know how to
set the textLabel.
To set the detailTextLabel,
you would do
something like this.
And then finally, if you
wanted to set a image
thumbnail on the left side, you
would use the syntax I'm
showing here.
Now it's time for you to build
out the rest of our
FeedTableViewController.