I'm Gregg Pollack, and you're
watching Level Six of Try iOS,
where we're going to be talking
about AFNetworking.
In this level, we're going
to be learning about the
AFNetworking library.
It'll show us how to load
images from the
internet into our app.
We'll then figure out how to
take JSON from the internet
and parse it into
our application.
Then we'll learn about the
NSDictionary data structure.
And finally, we'll use all of
these techniques to complete
our FeedTableViewController.
So remember our
ProfileViewController?
Remember the one that
we made scroll?
Well, what if that image that
you saw in there we wanted to
load from a URL from
the internet?
One way we could do that
is by using this
AFNetworking library.
It was created by Matt Thompson
and Scott Raymond
when they worked over
at Gowalla.
It is a open source library
they created.
There's lots of ways in iOS to
do networking requests, and
this is just one popular
way to do them.
This isn't the only way to do
network requests in iOS.
One way to download the
AFNetworking files to get them
into your application
is to head over to
their GitHub page.
There, you can download the
zip, unzip them, in your X
code, click Add files
to your project.
Then you're going to navigate
to that directory.
And inside of that unzipped
directory, there's a
AFNetworking directory, and it's
that that you want to add
to your app.
There's other things inside, as
you can see there, inside
of that unzipped directory,
one of which is an example
folder, which is worth a look,
if you want other examples of
how to use this library.
Now, let's jump back into our
ProfileViewController.
Here's our old code,
where we're
creating a UI image view.
However, we want to load our
image from this URL you see
here, and we also are going to
need a placeholder image that
is going to be shown in its
place until our application is
done downloading the image
off the internet.
To use AFNetworking, we only
want to include the parts of
it that we're using
in this file.
In this case, it's a file
that looks like this.
You see how it says UIImageView
plus AFNetworking?
What that's telling us is that
this file loads additional
behavior into the UIImageView
class, which
we'll see in a minute.
We're then just going
to initialize our
ProfileImageView.
And then we're going to call
setImageWithURL on our
UIImageView.
That's that new method
that it added.
Then we need to send in those
parameters, the URL and the
placeholder image
as a UI image.
Using a placeholder image isn't
required, but it's a
good practice.
Right.
This code would work if we
didn't have a placeholder
image, but it's a real good
practice to always have one in
case the image you're trying
to fetch off the internet
takes a while to download,
or it's not there.
That way, your user experience
doesn't suffer.
All right, now we're pulling
that image from the internet,
but what if we wanted to pull
all the profile data off the
internet from a URL that
looked like this?
And here's the JSON that
it might return.
That's what we want to use
to render out the page.
Before we get into that, we need
to make sure everybody
understands the difference
between synchronous and
asynchronous code.
So if we were to write this out
using synchronous code,
we'd want to go and fetch the
JSON content from the
internet, then, once that's
returned, load as a Subview.
And then lastly, we could
add other subviews.
So basically, it's going to
fetch the JSON code, and it's
going to stop.
It's going to stop until
the request gets back.
Then once it gets back, it's
going to load it as a Subview,
and then do whatever else
comes next on the page.
That's synchronous.
If we wanted to do this
asynchronously, it would go
fetch the JSON code, once that's
returned, load it as a
Subview, and then add
other subviews.
So here's how execution
works here.
It's going to go
fetch the JSON.
While it's waiting to return,
it's going to
continue down the page.
And only once it gets returned,
then it goes back
and it calls back to load
that data as a Subview.
So that's sort of a non-blocking
way of doing it.
It doesn't stop the world.
Code continues, and then once
that request returns, it then
loads the Subview.
We call that a callback because
it's calling back and
running the code once the
networking code gets back from
the internet.
Now, let's jump back into our
ProfileViewControllers
viewDidLoad method, and let's
call out to the internet.
We need to import the
AFJSONRequestOperation, which
is what we're about to use.
And now I'm going to show you
some pseudo code so that when
I show you the real code you
understand what's going on.
First we need to create an NSURL
and set our endpoint.
Then we're going to wrap that
URL inside of a NSURLRequest.
Then we're going to create an
AFJSONRequestOperation.
That's the operation that's
going to do the call to the
internet when we tell it to.
Then we specify our callbacks.
So if it's successful, then we
can do something with the data
that gets returned.
And if the request fails, well,
we can just log out the
error message.
And then finally, we tell
it when we want
to start this operation.
All right, so let's take a look
at the actual code now.
So here's where we
create the URL,
initialize it with a string.
We're going to wrap that URL
inside a NSURLRequest.
Then we're going to create our
AFJSONRequestOperation and
send in the request
as a parameter.
To do asynchronous operations in
Objective C, we're going to
use a block.
So we're basically sending
in a bunch of
code as a block parameter.
So here you can see that
little caret there.
That signifies this parameter
is a block.
Then, as you can see down here,
we have another block,
which specifies what to do
if the request fails.
Then at the bottom, we just send
the start message into
the operation.
Now it's time for you to jump
into the challenges and start
playing with AFNetworking.