As you saw with the previous
challenge, you logged out the
JSON object that was coming back
from the internet, and it
probably looked something
like this.
Kind of looks a lot like the
JSON, except in this case
we've got equal signs
and semicolons.
Wonder what sort of
object that is?
Well, if we call class on that
object, we simply get back
that it's an NSDictionary.
NSDictionary is a key
value store, kind
of like a Ruby Hash.
You're right, Mr. Higgie.
It's a key value store, kind
of like a Ruby Hash.
Or if you're familiar with
JavaScript, it's like a
JavaScript object.
If you want to look at all of
the helper methods that come
along with that NSDictionary
class, you can sort of click
the button below.
There's a bunch of utility
methods, including the allKeys
message, which is going to
return you all of the keys for
this NSDictionary.
We could also call allValues,
which is going to return to
you all the values.
And of course if we want to
reference a particular value
by using its key, we can do
something like this, and
specify the key that
corresponds to the
value that we want.
In this case it would print out
first name is Gregg, and
if we wanted to get memberSince,
we could simply
get the value this way.
To complete our networking
code and keep things
organized, we're going to add a
property to the profile view
controller, which is
a NSDictionary.
This is where we're going to
store the NSDictionary object
we get back from our request,
so that we can use it
elsewhere inside of our class.
Then inside of our
ProfileViewController we're
going to store our NSDictionary
inside of this property.
Then we're going to call a new
method we're about to create,
called requestSuccessful,
that'll use this NSDictionary
to print out the right
values to the screen.
Let's jump into that
method and see
what we need to implement.
So if we just pull over our
code from previous levels
where we define the
ProfileViewController, we
would have the image.
And we'd have the UILabel.
This is our old code but we need
to change it to load in
the code that we just got
from the internet.
To do this it's pretty simple.
We simply need to reference
self.userprofile and send in
the proper key to get back
the proper value.
Then down in our name label,
we need to combine two
different values--
the first name and last name.
We can do that by using the
stringwithformat from NSString.
So here you can see that we're
sending in a string as well as
the data from our user
profile dictionary.
Now it's time for you
to finish the
RequestSuccessfulMethod by
referencing the proper values
from the user profile.
Good luck.