Here's the feed view table
view controller, which you
helped us build.
How might we load data from the
internet to populate the
latest photos?
Well here's the URL that we
might use, and here's the data
that might get returned.
That's an NSArray of
NSDictionaries.
You're right, Mr. Higgie.
We can see the brackets here,
which tell us it's probably
going to be an NSArray
of NSDictonaries.
So to get the data that we want
out of this NSArray, we
first need to give it the index
of the array that we
want, and then the key for the
value that we want from the
NSDictionary.
So in this case we would
get back image one.
If we sent this in, we
would get image two.
And if we sent this in, with the
detail key, we would get
back, some bright stars here.
Just like we did before with
the ProfileViewController,
we're going to specify a
property to store what comes
back from our AF networking
library.
In this case it's going to
be an NSArray of photos.
So we're going to
specify that.
Then inside the
FeedViewController we have our
AF JSON Request Operation.
Inside there we're simply going
to set this property.
Then unlike our previous
example, we need
to redraw the table.
This basically goes through and
redraws each table cell.
Because we've loaded this data
from the internet, we need to
go back and redraw each cell
with this new data.
Then we specify what to
do on failure, and
finally start the operation.
In order for your table view to
use this data that we just
fetched using AF networking,
there's a couple things we
need to do.
And we're going to leave them
to you in the challenges.
Here are the steps.
First, we're going to have to
revise the number of rows in
section to return the number
of photos from the array.
Then, we have to revise the
cellForRowIndexPath so that it
accesses the particular
NSDictionary, from what we got
returned from the internet.
And then lastly, we have to
revise didSelectRowIndexPath
so it'll pass the proper
values to our
PhotoViewController,
and display it
big, full on the screen.
Good luck.
Once you complete all of these,
you'll see the app in
action, you lucky duck.