Welcome back to Level 3,
Section 2, where we'll
be introducing the Django Admin.
One of the most
powerful parts of Django
is the automatic
admin interface,
located at localhost/admin.
It reads metadata
from your models
to provide a quick interface
for viewing and editing them.
This is where trusted users,
that are marked as staff,
can log in and manage
content on your site.
For instance, you can view
the objects in your model,
edit them, and create new ones.
To use the admin site, we
need to create a super user.
To do that we run the
command, python manage.py
createsuperuser.
Then enter your user
name, email, and password.
Now in our browser, we can go
to localhost/admin and login.
When we login, we can see
our automatically generated
groups and users, but
not our treasure model.
We actually have to register our
models with the admin for them
to show up.
In order to see our
models in the admin,
will need to register
them in admin.py.
We do this by importing
our treasure model
and then registering
Treasure with the command,
admin.site.register.
Now when we login,
we can see our treasure model.
We can see all of the
objects inside of our model
and we can add more
treasures, using the form,
like an arrowhead,
and a horseshoe.
If we demo our
app again, we have
the new items we just added,
the arrowhead and horseshoe.
Congratulations on
finishing Try Django.
First, you have a few challenges
to complete on using the admin,
and then I'll see you
in the outro video.
For fool's gold.
I'm sorry.
We need to--