Welcome back to
Level 2, Section 2,
where we'll be covering
more on templates.
We previously used
a context dictionary
to send two values
to the template.
And this worked fine for that.
But what if we have more
complex data, like name, value,
material, and
location associated
with a treasure or a
bunch of treasures?
How would we send that to
the template in a context?
We can use a class to store
information about a treasure
object and then
use a list to store
all of the treasure objects.
And we can name that Treasures.
Then we have just
one variable to put
in our context, treasures.
When we create our
Treasure class,
we'll write class and then
the name of the class,
here it's Treasure.
Then we'll define
a method called
init, which sets all of the
attributes that we pass in.
Then we can create
a treasure object
and set its attributes
with just one line of code.
t1 here is a Gold
Nugget Treasure.
And t2 is a Fool's
Gold Treasure.
And they each are
separate instances
of the Treasure class.
We'll then move
our Treasure class
to the bottom of the views.py.
And then instead of creating
individual treasure objects,
we'll create a list
called Treasures
to hold a few treasure objects.
Then we can pass this
treasures list in our context.
Also notice we put
the context directly
in line instead of
creating a separate context
variable first.
How do we then display HTML for
each object in the treasurer's
list?
If this was a regular
Python script,
we could write a ForLoop.
But we're inside a template,
so we use the Django template
language and its
corresponding tags that
start with a curly
bracket percent
and then we write
our ForLoop and end
with percent curly bracket.
We can then close the for
block with an endfor tag, which
tells Django where
the for block ends
since we don't have
indentation like we would
in a regular Python script.
You can see here we've
added this ForLoop inside
of our index.html template.
Now when we view our page, we
can see each treasure object's
name and value displayed.
Let's make another change.
You can see we have
a 0 for Fool's Gold.
And we want to
replace 0 with unknown
since that means we
really don't know what
the value of that thing is.
To do this, we'll
add a conditional,
which looks similar
to Python except we
have the curly bracket
percent symbol wrapped
around the conditional.
And we also add the endif
tag to end the conditional.
Inside the first
if statement, we'll
check if the value's
greater than 0.
If so, we'll display the value.
Otherwise, we'll display
the text unknown.
If we look at our page again, we
can see Fool's Gold is unknown.
That's because its value
was not greater than 0.
That's it for Level 2 Section 2.
Now it's time for you
to use Django template
tags in the challenges.
Good luck.