[SINGING] Hitch up your
wagon and mosey out west.
There's gold to find
and knowledge to test.
We'll build an app for
the treasure we seek.
Django's got the tools
for our trek to the creek.
Prospect for riches with
the model, template, view.
Route to your data,
and render HTML too.
Now pack up your gear,
it's time to make some dough.
You're fixin' to strike
gold as you try Django.
Hi, I'm Sara Holderness.
And welcome to Try
Django where we'll
be learning about the
Django web framework
and building an app along the way.
In level 1, section
1, we'll be going
over getting
started with Django.
Coming into this
course, we're expecting
you to have some experience
with Python, HTML, and database
concepts.
If you need a refresher
on any of those things,
you can check out our
prerequisite courses.
Django is an open source MVC
framework written in Python
for building web application.
Django's website says
it makes it easier
to build better web apps more
quickly and with less code.
And it does this by handling
common web development
tasks right out of the box.
We'll explain these
points in a second,
but first let's
see who's using it.
One company that uses Django
is Disqus, a discussion service
that can be added
to your website.
Another one you
might have heard of
is Instagram, a photo
sharing website,
and Pinterest, a visual
link sharing social network.
Let's look at how Django
works from a high level.
Today, most web applications
send a web request
to the server for validation,
processing, and rendering,
and then send HTML and
assets back to the browser.
Django is what's being
run on the server
and handles the validation,
processing, and rendering.
If we look at this in a little
more detail, we see that first,
the user requests a URL, like
instagram.com/codeschool.
Then the request is sent to
the Django app for processing.
All of the user info is
looked up and validated,
and then data is passed
off for rendering,
and HTML is sent
back to the user.
Django separates these duties
into separate components
to make projects easier to
maintain and collaborate on.
Django has specific names for
each one of these components.
The part which processes
data is called the view.
The part which stores
and validates data
is called the model.
And the part that renders
HTML is called the template.
The model, template, and
view make up the Django app.
If you are familiar with MVC
or model, view, controller
frameworks, then you
can think of the view
as the controller and
the template as the view,
and MVC becomes MTV in Django.
This might be a little
confusing if you're
used to MVC frameworks,
but you'll get used to it.
In this course we'll
be creating a site
to keep track of our treasures
found along our journey west.
It'll have an image,
the name, the material,
and the location found.
If you're going to follow
along with the challenges
in this course, then you
don't need to install Django.
But if you'd like to play with
Django on your own computer,
you should install it first.
If you have Python
installed, it's
as easy as typing pip install
django in your terminal.
You'll see some information
about the progress
of downloading and
installing Django.
To learn more about setting
up your Django environment,
you can check out
our install video.
Here's all of the
different places
we'll be writing code in this
course-- in the console, which
uses a single carat in
the Django shell, which
uses the three carat symbol, and
in scripts inside your Django
project.
Before we create
our Django project,
it's important to know the
difference between projects
and apps in Django.
For example, if we're going
to create a project called
Pinterest, inside we'd
could have separate apps
for the main dotcom, the
blog, and the jobs posting.
In Django, each
of the apps would
live inside the outer
Pinterest project,
but would have separate
directories for each app.
So before we start
writing the actual code,
we'll need to create
a project and an app.
We create our Django project
with the command django-admin
startproject and the name of
our project, Treasuregram.
This will create a
directory structure
for our Django project.
Under the folder
Treasuregram, there
will be several
files created for us.
settings.py will hold
our project settings.
urls.py will hold
our project's URLs.
And manage.py is a utility
for administrative tasks.
Now we'll run our Django server
to see our project running.
To serve our site locally,
we can type Python manage.py
runserver.
Manage.py is in the top
level Treasuregram directory,
so you should navigate
there to run this command.
That output tells us our site
is running at local host port
8000.
If we go there in
our browser, we
can see a
congratulations message.
It also tells us to start
our first app by running
python manage.py startapp.
Now we'll create our first app
by running Python manage.py
startapp and the name
of our app, main_app.
This will create a directory for
main_app plus a bunch of files
inside.
We won't go into what each
of these files does yet,
but we'll focus on creating
our first view in views.py.
A view is simply
a Python function
that takes in a web request
and returns a web response.
For our first view, we want to
keep it simple and just return
a text response that
says, "Hello explorers!".
If we open up
views.py, we can see
there's a single import
statement that imports
render from django.shortcuts.
Render is used to
render templates,
which we'll do later.
But for now we're just going to
return a simple HTTP response.
To do this, we'll need to import
HttpResponse from django.http.
This imports that specific
class from a specific module.
Now we can define our
view function called
index that takes in a request.
This function will return an
HTTP response with an HTML
string as the parameter.
You might think you
could go to your browser
and load this view now,
but there's actually
one more step we need to do.
We need to map
this view to a URL.
So let's say we want the URL
/index to go to the index view
we just wrote.
Django has a URL
dispatcher whose job
is to map a URL to its
corresponding view.
So what this will look like
is you will type the URL
localhost:8000/index/.
The URL dispatcher will map the
URL to the corresponding view.
And then the view will
return that HTTP response,
"Hello Explorers!"
The URL dispatcher lives inside
the project's url.py file.
If we open that up, we see
there's a URL patterns list.
And there's one URL in that
list that goes to the admin.
We won't need to
touch that right now,
but we'll need to add a
new URL for the index path.
To do this, we'll create a URL
object with two parameters.
The first one is the path
that we want to match.
And the second one
is the view function.
This path might look
kind of strange.
It actually holds a
regular expression
that starts with r to
mean the string is raw
and won't be escaped.
And the carat means the
start of the string.
The second parameter just
accesses the index function
in the views file.
And to access that view,
we'll also need to import
main_app.views.
If you want to learn more
about regular expressions,
check out our Breaking the
Ice With Regular Expressions
course.
If this pattern is
matched, then the request
will be sent to the view.
This second parameter means
go inside the main_app,
look inside the views.py
file, then call the index view
function, which will send us
to the index view function
we wrote previously.
Now if the user visits
localhost/index,
they'll be sent to
main_app's index view, which
will return the HTTP response.
So if we preview
that in the browser,
we'll see the heading
text, "Hello Explorers!"
That's it for
level 1, section 1.
Now it's time for
you to practice
getting a simple Django app up
and running in the challenges.
Good luck.