Welcome back to
Level 1 Section 2
where we'll be covering URL
dispatcher best practices.
Right now, localhost/index
goes to our homepage,
but this is kind of an ugly URL.
If you were going
to go to google.com,
you wouldn't type
google.com/index,
so we'd like to get
rid of that /index.
First, we'll remove index/ from
our regular expression and then
send an empty path
to load our view.
Our pattern is now an empty
string with just a carat.
And if we load local host, we
see that our view loads without
typing /index.
In Django, it's a best
practice to have a project URL
dispatcher and an
app URL dispatcher.
Right now, our
project's URL dispatcher
is handling all of
the requests, but we'd
like to funnel requests
for our main app
to our main app's
URL dispatcher.
So the first thing we'll do is
create that new urls.py file
in the main app folder.
So now in the
projects urls.py file,
instead of mapping to
main apps view.index
we'll instead include
all of main apps URLs.
Notice to use that include
function, we need to import
include from django.conf.urls.
So now we'll create our
urls.py file in our main app.
We'll still need to
import URL, and we'll also
want to import our views.
If you want to import a specific
module from your current app,
you can leave off the
package and just type dot.
So now we want to create our
app specific URL patterns.
We'll start with
an empty string,
but we'll also terminate
it with a dollar sign
so that this doesn't
match all strings.
And then the second parameter
will be our views.index.
Now if we load local host with
no path, we see our homepage.
So things are working the
same as they did before,
even though we've refactored
things behind the scenes.
And this will allow us
to stay more organized
as our app grows.
That's it for Level 1.
Now it's time for you to
refactor your URL dispatcher
in the challenges.
Have fun.
Let's get--
[BEEP]
Django from a-- OK.
Creating in this course--
[BEEP]
That would have sceptre--