If we look at where
we left off, we
have the basic building
blocks for our final page,
but we'll need to add some
style to get to our end goal.
We'll start by
adding a CSS file.
Like with templates,
Django automatically
looks for static
files and directories
named static in your app.
So we'll create a
directory called static,
and then create our
style.css file in there.
For now, it will just
turn the heading green.
Then in our template, we'll
need to use the tag load
staticfiles to make
our static files
available to the template.
We'll also need to link
to our style sheet.
So inside the link
tags href attribute,
we'll add the static tag
that tells Django where
our style.css file is located.
If we look at our
rendered template,
we can see our H1 is now green,
so our style.css is working.
We can also add a CSS
framework like Bootstrap
to do some style work for us.
We'll make sure the
minified Bootstrap
file is in our Static
folder, and then we'll
link to it just like
we did with style.css.
We won't cover
this in the slides,
but we added a few
Bootstrap customizations
to our style.css file.
We'll also add a
static images directory
to hold some static images to
style our site, like our logo.
Now we'll start adding Bootstrap
elements to our template,
like a nav bar that
displays our static logo
image and a container
and some panels
to organize the page better.
If you're curious about what
all of these Bootstrap classes
are doing, you can find
out more in our Blasting
Off with Bootstrap course.
If we look at our page,
it's looking way better,
but we want to add a table
to organize these attributes
a little better.
We'll add a table with some
icons for the material location
and value.
You can see this page is
getting a little complex,
but at its core, it's just HTML
tags and our Django template
tags loading dynamic data.
Now our site is starting
to look really nice,
but it would look even
better if we could add images
for each treasure object.
Since this is a
new piece of data,
we'll update our treasure class
to add the img_url attribute.
Then when we create
our treasures,
we'll also add the img_url's.
Notice that these images
aren't in our static folder.
This is because these
images aren't static
and are hosted elsewhere.
Now we'll just reference
the treasure's img_url
inside an image tag.
It's been a long journey,
but we finally made it.
We have a styled site
with dynamic data,
and our objects' images that
matches our designer's mockup.
Now it's time for you to add
some styles to your Django
app in the challenges.
Have fun.
[BEEP]
HTTP res-- I hate saying that.
Can--
the- view-- do?
We'll re-- sorry.
We get our home page.
[BEEP]