[SINGING] Hitch your web
again and mosey out west.
There's gold to find
and knowledge to test.
We'll build an app for
the treasure we seek.
Django's got the tools
for our trek to the creek.
Prospect for riches with
the model, template, view.
Route to your data,
and render HTML too.
Now pack up your gear;
it's time to make some dough.
You're fixin' to strike
gold as you Try Django.
Hi, I'm Sarah Holderness,
and welcome back
to Try Django level 3,
section 1, covering models.
We've seen the URL to view
to template process before.
But now we want to add in our
model to organize and provide
our view with data.
Right now we're
storing our treasures
in a list in views.py.
But there's not a good interface
for adding new ones directly
from the website.
And we want something that's
easy to maintain over time.
A model is how you
would do this in Django.
So we'll replace our Treasure
class with a Treasure model.
We'll create the Treasure model
in models.py following
these three steps.
First we'll import
models from django.db.
Then we'll create a
class called Treasure
that inherits from
models.Model so that Django
knows we're creating a model.
Then we'll create our same
attributes we had before,
but using special
model types that
correspond to database types.
If we compare our old Treasure
class to our new Treasure
model, you can see
a few differences.
But overall the
structure's the same.
Notice we didn't need to create
a constructor in our Treasure
model, because the
model has one built
in where you use the attribute
names to set each one like so.
We also use special
Django field types
that correspond to Python
types and SQL types.
For instance, models.CharField
corresponds to a Python string
and an SQL VARCHAR.
A models.IntegerField
corresponds
to a Python int or an
SQL INTEGER, and so on.
There are many more
Django model field types
that you can find
in the docs here.
In our model, we'll also
need to define some rules
for our attributes.
Otherwise we would
get errors like these.
We'll set the max
length of our CharFields
and the max digits and decimal
places for our DecimalField.
Our model now
describes how we want
to store data in the database.
But do we actually
have to write any SQL?
No, actually we don't.
That's covered by
the Django ORM.
The ORM will usually
work automatically
behind the scenes
translating Python commands
to SQL commands, unless you edit
the structure of your model.
Then you'll need to do an
extra step called a migration.
And we'll need to do
that now since we just
created our model.
How do we then
perform a migration?
We actually have to run two
commands in the console.
The first one is python
manage.py makemigrations,
which makes a migration file.
Then to apply the
migration to the database,
we run python manage.py migrate.
These separate steps let you
review the migration before you
actually run migrate.
And since migrations are kind
of like a version control
system for your database,
that can come in handy.
Let's actually run those
commands on our project.
We'll run python
manage.py makemigrations.
And we can see this
generates 001_initial.py,
which is our migration file.
And then we can see
a list of the things
that that migration file does.
And ours just creates
the model Treasure.
Before running migrate,
we can actually
preview the SQL commands
that will be run
by doing an intermediate step.
We can type this command
and then see all the SQL
that will get run as a preview.
You don't need to do this,
but it can come in handy
if you want to see if
your Python code is
doing what you expect.
Now let's run migrate
for real on our project.
The output shows us all the
migrations that are run.
And you can see
there are a few we
didn't create that are
related to some other Django
components.
The last one,
main_app, is the one
we just created, and
is getting run now.
Now if you're wondering if
your project is up to date
with all of its migrations, you
can try running makemigrations,
and it'll say no changes
detected if you're up to date.
And then if you run
migrate, it will
say no migrations to apply.
Now that we've
done our migration,
we can actually use
our Treasure model
and create Treasure objects.
And we'll do this in the
Django interactive shell.
We'll run python manage.py
shell to open the Django shell.
The Django shell is a
great way to play around
with creating models and
writing queries before you
write actual Python code.
To start, we'll need to
import our Treasure model from
main_app.models.
Then we'll type our first
query, Treasure.objects.all.
And we can see we get an empty
list since we haven't created
any Treasure objects yet.
We did that
Treasure.objects.all,
which is a Django QuerySet.
A QuerySet is like a
SELECT statement in SQL.
All QuerySets start with
the model name dot objects.
So here it would be
Treasure.objects.
And that's like a
SELECT statement in SQL.
To retrieve all
objects in SQL, we
would write SELECT
* FROM Treasure.
As a QuerySet, we would
write Treasure.objects.all.
We can also use filters
like SQL WHERE or LIMIT
by doing
Treasure.objects.filter.
And in the filter, we want
to create in parentheses like
location = 'Orlando, Florida.'
If you know there's only one
element matched in your query,
you can use get.
Treasure.objects.get(pk
= 1) is an example.
pk is the primary key and
we know will be unique.
So this will return
only the Treasure object
with the matching primary key.
Back in our shell we'll create
our first Treasure object
with our model.
Then if we use the query
Treasure.objects.all,
we see an empty list.
That's because we forgot to
save our Treasure object.
We can do that with t.save.
Now if we repeat the query
Treasure.objects.all,
we'll see we have one
Treasure object in our list.
But this description, Treasure
object, isn't very specific.
We can make this more specific
in our Treasure model.
In our Treasure model, we'll
add a method called __str__,
which will define a description
for a Treasure model.
And we'll just have it return
the name of the Treasure.
Now the Treasure's
name will be shown
whenever we output that object
in the interactive shell.
Let's create a couple more
Treasure objects, Gold Nugget
and Fool's Gold.
And remember after each
one we have to save.
Then if we query
Treasure.objects.all again,
we see all the names of the
objects we just created.
Great, now these objects
are in our database.
So we'll need to
update our view to pull
this data from our
database and then pass it
to the template for rendering.
Since the way we interact
with database objects
is through our model, we'll
need to import our Treasure
model into our view.
Then inside of the
index function,
we can call Treasure.objects.all
and store it
in a variable called treasures.
Since our template
was already set up
to handle a list of
Treasure objects,
we actually don't have
to edit our template.
We can see our rendered
page, and it already
loads all of our Treasure
objects from our model.
That's it for
level 3, section 1.
Now it's time for you to
create models and migrations
in the challenges.
Good luck.