[SINGING] Hitch up your
wagon and mosey out west.
There's gold to find
and knowledge to test.
We'll build an app for
the treasure we seek.
Django's got the tools
for our trek to the creek.
Prospect for riches with
the model, template, view.
Route to your data
and render HTML too.
Now pack up your gear, it's
time to make some dough.
You're fixin' to strike
gold as you Try Django.
Hi, I'm Sara Holderness.
And welcome back to Try
Django, level 2, section 1,
covering Templates.
If you remember, this
is the app that we're
trying to build-- a
list of our treasures.
So now we're going
to start building out
the UI for this page.
And to do that, we'll
need to use a template.
Before we do that, let's look
at our app flow diagram again.
A request comes in,
the URL Dispatcher
matches the correct
view, and then
the view should
render a template.
A template is just an HTML file
that can have dynamic data.
This is the part
we'll be adding now.
We need to create an HTML
file since we already
have the URL and view set up.
To do this, we'll need
a Templates Directory
to store our templates.
See, Django automatically
looks for directories named
"templates" for template files.
But this is only if
your app is registered
with the Django project in
settings, so we'll do that now.
In this settings.py
file, you'll see
a list called INSTALLED_APPS.
We'll add our main
app to this list.
And you can see a few
of the apps that come
installed with Django already.
Now we can get to creating
our first template
in a file called index.html.
And this contains just some
basic HTML and the heading
that display TreasureGram.
So this template will
render like this.
Now we want to go
into our Index view,
and instead of
returning and http
response, like we
were doing before,
we'll render our template.
So we can actually delete
the import of http response.
And we'll return a render
object that takes in a request,
and a string that
contains the name
of our template index.html.
So if we load our page, we
can see the text TreasureGram.
And if we view the source of
the page, we can see the HTML
we just created.
So our template is working.
Now we'd like to display a list
of our treasures on our page.
But to do that, we need
dynamic data in our template.
This is a two-step process.
First, we want to send data
from our view to our template.
And second, we want to access
that data inside our template.
So inside our view,
we'll create some data--
a variable name that holds
the string "Gold Nugget,"
a variable value
equal to 1000.00,
and we'll wrap these
variables in a context,
which is a dictionary that
maps variable names to Python
objects.
Then we can pass this context
as the third parameter
of our render function.
In the template, you can access
a variable from the context
by surrounding it with
double curly brackets, which
is part of the Django
Template language.
During the rendering
of the template,
all of the variables inside
double curly brackets
are replaced with their values.
So you can see in our rendered
template that the values "Gold
Nugget" and 1000.00.
Show up.
That's it for
level 2, section 1.
Now it's time for you to create
a template in the Challenges.
Good luck.