[SINGING]
From the labyrinth of loops to
the variable valley, we'll see
the cliffs of value first.
JavaScript's
right up your alley.
Built-ins Bluff, Files Falls,
Array Archipelago.
Declarations in a desert
where you'll find out
how far you'll go.
Learn the program.
Take a ride.
Buy a ticket.
Step inside.
All aboard -
you're at the station to
increase your education.
Bon voyage and skinny dip -
as long as functions you
don't skimp on this - The
JavaScript Road Trip.
So, variables are pretty
cool, right?
I hope you enjoyed Level Two.
But who wants to code in the
console all day long?
Not me.
Not you.
We need a way to build some
JavaScript source files and
run them inside our HTML code.
So, here comes level three:
Files Falls.
Don't jump.
At the end of the last level,
we started talking about a
system of trains, in which some
were running and some
were not running.
Our goal for this level is to
print out a list of trains
that are running.
So, let's say for the sake of
consistency that our trains
are numbered according to
who's running first.
And then thereafter, the trains
that are not running
are numbered later.
So here in our images, we see
that we have trains 1
through 8 that are running
and trains 9 through 12,
which are not running today.
We have a relatively easy way to
print these messages out on
our console.
We can just concatenate
a few strings
together with some values.
And we can get statements like
"Train #1 is running,"
"Train #2 is running,"
"Train #3 is running."
And then we would do a whole
bunch of that and realize that
none of it gets printed out
in our user's browser.
We need a way to be able to
convey the messages that we
want to display to our customers
in their browser.
And that's why we need
a JavaScript file.
A JavaScript file is for running
our written JavaScript
code in somebody
else's browser.
Here we have an index.html
file.
Inside, you'll see some common
HTML code with some common
HTML elements.
Once the user's browser loads
this HTML code, we want it to
execute some JavaScript code.
To do this, we'll use a script
tag inside the HTML code.
And that script tag will tell
the HTML file which JavaScript
file contains the code
that we want to run.
You'll notice inside the script
tag that we have an SRC
keyword that's being assigned
to the file trains.js.
That is our JavaScript file for
this particular system.
Notice also that you need to
turn off the script tag inside
your HTML so that the
HTML file knows when
your script tag ends.
So now what is inside
that trains.js file?
Well, it's our JavaScript
code, of course.
We want to build a file of
JavaScript code that can be
used every time a user
opens our website.
To create this file, you can
use any text-based editor,
like TextEdit or Notepad.
Inside that file, we're going to
produce all the JavaScript
code that we want our user's
browser to execute when it
reaches the script tag
inside the HTML code.
So now, we have an index.html
file, and we
have a trains.js file.
And we want to give you a little
bit of file structure
here, so that you can keep
your website organized.
Let's see where we can
add our files in
an appropriate location.
So here we have a root folder
for our entire website.
Everything about our website
is contained
within our root folder.
And inside that root folder,
meaning in the same directory,
we have an index.html file
and our trains.js file.
Since our script tag has a
source that reads trains.js,
our trains.js file needs to be
in the exact same directory as
our index.html file.
Many websites, however will keep
all of their JavaScript
files in one convenient
location.
We want to be able to stay
organized as you code.
So here you can see a root
folder that contains the
index.html file, but also
scripts folder.
And inside the scripts folder
is our trains.js.
Now, how would we show that in
our source link inside the
index.html file?
You can see here that we have
the scripts file listed first,
followed by a forward slash
and then trains.js.
What does that say to
the index.html file?
It says first go down to the
scripts folder, and there you
will find trains.js.
What happens if the files are
really far apart, like nowhere
near each other?
Well, we can still find a way to
stay organized as we code,
but we have to be a little bit
more detailed inside of our
source links and incorporate a
little bit different syntax.
So here we've got
a root folder.
But now, our index.html file
is in its own folder called
pages, because it's one of
the pages of our website.
And our scripts contains
trains.js.
So how do we show this
in our source link?
Well, we need what's called
a double dot notation.
That signals to the browser to
go up a folder first and then
go down to the scripts file and
then find the trains.js
file there.