Cool, now we know where
our files are.
And we know how to make them.
So let's see if we can put some
JavaScript code in our
trains.js file and get
something to execute.
Let's put a few console-style
expressions inside our
trains.js file just to see if
we get a good response from
our compiler.
Uh oh, error -
what's up?
Well, compiler does not like
how we have entered our
statements into the file.
We need something a little
different so it can understand
our file representation.
We have to have a way to
differentiate between the
statements themselves.
So here's our console
entry, right?
If we were declaring a variable
for trainsOperational
we would just declare it and
say that it equals 8.
And it would be ready to go and
everything would be great.
But if we put multiple console
statements to execute inside
one file, the compiler looks
at it like this--
which is just back to back
garbage nonsense.
And it has no idea where your
statement begins, where it
ends, or what to do.
So, we need a way to tell the
compiler, we're done making
this particular statement.
Enter the semicolon.
Semicolon is very cool.
We like it.
So here we have what a normal
console entry would be for our
trainsOperational variable.
And the only thing we would
need to do to tell the
compiler in a file that we are
done making that statement is
to throw a semicolon right on
the end of that statement.
It says, "Hey, we're done with
this particular expression.
Go ahead and do that before even
looking at the next one."
So now if we had a wootForSemicolons
file and put all of
our statements in there, each
of them separated by a
semicolon, we would get
a fantastic blank.
What?!
What's going on?
Why didn't we get anything?
We just put all that stuff in
there with our semicolons.
It executed the statements
just fine.
But we got nothing.
And that's because everything
that happened with those
statements happened inside the
compiler and the compiler
never printed anything
out for the user.
We need a way to get the results
of our computations in
the compiler out to the user.
So, in order to print from a file
to the console, we'll use
this cool method called the
console.log method.
It's going to output the result
of your code operations
from your file to the console.
So, let's say in our train system
we had 12 total trains,
as we know, but we also have
today 8 operational trains.
If we wanted to build a message
for the user on the
console that told them how many
running trains we have
today, we could use the
console.log method and place
an expression that builds a
string inside its parameters.
This would log out, or print,
the contents of the string it
to the browser's console.
And notice that there are no
more quotation marks around
that string.
Now we can place any expression
that we want inside
of a console.log method.
We can even ask if the
trainsOperational is equal to
the totalTrains.
And since it's not, console.log
will say, false.
So, now we kind of have a way to
get our messages printed to
the screen so that the user can
see them, and they won't
stay just inside the
compiler itself.
We can use console.log inside of
our trains.js file to print
out every running train.
So, let's do that.
Here's every last one of
the running trains.
Wow, and let's see
what we get.
Every single one prints
in order.
And we see exactly how many
trains are running and which
ones are running.
So here we have our
index.html file.
And we know that references
our trains.js - JavaScript
source file.
And if we open our index.html
file we can see the generic
JavaScript express header
that we stuck into
our HTML file before.
But we don't see any of our
running train printouts.
Why is that?
We put our semicolons
in, right?
Well, remember that our
console.log method prints its
messages only to the console.
So, all would we do here to see
our results is go up to the
menu and open our JavaScript
console, which we
already know how to do.
And there on the left you can
see our running train
printouts exactly as we
wanted them to be.
You might ask what these
notations are over here on the
right hand side of our log.
And that would be an
excellent question.
These are indicators that show
which files caused the current
line of output on the left
along with the exact line
within the file that
caused the output.
This is very useful when you
have a lot of code in a source
file, or even multiple source
files, and you need to
pinpoint how or why certain
printouts appeared.
Now we have combined semicolons
and the console.log
method to produce each message
for each train.
And you can see that the console
obeys conveniently and
produces every single message
that we wanted.
So, let's look at our current
train status system.
We have an index.html
file that will load
all of the HTML code.
And once it's loaded it
will go and fetch
the trains.js file.
And inside that trains.js file
it will execute a whole bunch
of our JavaScript code to
get our trains messages
printed to the user.
Guess what?
This code kind of sucks, too.
Whomp, whomp.
Why?
Because what if there
were 124 trains?
Would you want to type every
single one of those
console.log log messages into
your trains.js file?
I think not.
And we need a way to solve this
repetitive code issue.
And that will be in
the next section.
See you soon.
[BEEP BEEP]
TM of pbbt -
That can be used multiple
times, every time.
Multiple times?
[BEEP BEEP]
So how do we show, show, show--