Next we have strings.
Strings are JavaScript's way
of handling and storing and
processing flat text.
In order to signal to JavaScript
that we want to
process some flat text, we
need to use a pair of
quotation marks surroundings
some text as we enter the
string into the console.
Here you can see two different
strings, "Raindrops On Roses"
and "Whiskers On Kittens".
When we surround the text with
quotation marks, JavaScript
recognizes it as a string and
then returns the string right
back to us.
We can also use the plus
operator uniquely with strings
in a process called
concatenation.
Concatenation places strings
together inside of one string
and returns one master
string at the end.
Here you can see "Raindrops On
Roses" concatenated with
another string that says space
and space, concatenated with
another string that says
"Whiskers On Kittens".
As a result, we get
"Raindrops On Roses
And Whiskers On Kittens".
Now, it's time for a few
of my favorite … strings.
Concatenation will also work
with numbers and their
expressions, too.
In this first example, we can
see that when we try to
concatenate "The meaning of life
is" with the value "42", we
get a perfectly valid string
at the end, but it's not
formatted exactly like
we would want.
It seems to be that we're
missing a space.
Since concatenation does not
provide a space for you, all
we need to do to fix this is
place a space inside the very
first string.
We can also concatenate
expressions into strings.
However, expressions will get
evaluated by the console.
As you see here with 0.75,
3/4 got evaluated.
In order to fix that, we
actually need to place the
expression inside of the string
so we get the flat text
of "3/4" instead of 0.75.
When working with strings,
you'll need some special
characters to achieve some
specific formatting.
Here in this example, you can
see a  \t, which
represents an advancement
to the next tab stop.
Here, in the output, you can
see that the \t's
have disappeared, and in their
place is an advancement to the
next tab stop inside
the string?
What if we needed double
quotation marks
inside of our string.
Well, the console looks at
double quotation marks as
beginning or ending a string.
So we need a special way of
escaping that double quotation
mark, and so we use a backslash
before quotation
mark in that case as well.
In our output result, we can
see that we have a set of
double quotation marks
inside the string.
What if we want a backslash
inside of a string?
Well, since it's a special
character, we need to use a
double backslash to produce just
one backslash inside of
the string.
Following that, we have
a \ n that
represents a new line.
You can see in the output here,
that the string is split
up across multiple lines because
of the
.
This is by no means an
exhaustive compilation of
special characters for use in
string formatting, and you can
research the rest
on the internet.
Sometimes we'd like to compare
strings for alphabetical
ordering or for matching
strings.
JavaScript allows us to compare
strings with specific
comparators.
We can use the double equal
sign to compare "The Wright
Brothers" with "The Wright
Brothers", which returns a
truth value because those
strings are exactly the same.
We can see that if we use double
equal on "The Wright
Brothers" and "Super Mario
Brothers", that we would get a
false value, because
those strings are
not at all the same.
Now, here's a tricky one.
If we see "The Wright Brothers"
compared with "the wright
brothers" in a not equal
situation, this will return a
truth value.
The reason that is is because
those strings are not exactly
the same because JavaScript
is case sensitive
with regard to strings.
So, they are not equal.
We can also access the length
of strings using the .
length property.
You can see here that if we
have a super long English
word,
"antidisestablishmentarianism",
and we use the  .length
property, that the JavaScript
console would return a very
nice value to us of 28.
And again, when we used "One
Fish, Two Fish, Red Fish, Blue
Fish", if we used the .length
property on that,
JavaScript will return a 39.
Now, what's really important
here is that the .length
property will calculate all of
the spaces and all of the
punctuation in determining
your length.
Now, it's time for you to use
your brand new JavaScript
skills in the challenges
section.
We'll see you in the next one.
Backslash.
Multiple, multiple special
characters for use for string
formatting.
I don't know why you're saying that word twice
[Laughing in background]