[SINGING]
From the labyrinth of the loops
to the variable valley,
we'll see the cliffs
of value first.
JavaScript's right
up your alley.
Built-in bluffs, files falls,
array archipelago,
declarations in a desert
where you'll find out
how far you'll go.
Learn the program.
Take a ride.
Buy a ticket, step inside.
All aboard, you're
at the station to
increase your education.
Bon voyage and skinny dip!
As long as functions
you don't skimp on
this, the JavaScript ... Road Trip.
Howdy, road trippers.
Hope you enjoyed level one.
And now you know how to make
some data, but we need to know
where to store it.
So, that's what we're going
to do in the next level.
Here comes level two,
Variable Calley.
JavaScript uses variables to
store and manage data.
You can see here a basic
assignment syntax for a
variable called trainWhistles.
That var is the variable
keyword.
It's what tells the browser to
set some space aside for the
variable itself.
The next thing you see is
the trainWhistles' name.
That's the name of
the variable.
The equal sign is the
assignment operator.
Notice that it's a single
equal sign.
And lastly, the value 3.
That's the value that's going
to be stored inside our
variable trainWhistles.
Now when we call the variable
trainWhistles, we
automatically get a value
of three returned to us.
Now there are some rules and
regulations that we follow in
JavaScript for naming
variables.
The first is that we can't
have any spaces in the
variable name.
The compiler will return an
error to you if you try to put
spaces inside a variable name.
The next thing is that we can't
have any digits at the
front of our variable names.
We don't like that.
The compiler doesn't
like that.
We can use underscores,
although they're often
irritating.
We can use dollar signs,
but don't be that guy.
We can even use dollar signs
and underscores together.
So, this is slightly stupid, but
it's technically legal.
Now here's a great
variable name.
Notice at the beginning is a
lower case letter and every
subsequent word is
capitalized.
You may have heard this referred
to as camel case.
And then this final variable
name uses a
digit at the very end.
Fatality.
What if we wanted to change
a variable's contents?
Guess what?
It is your lucky day.
Currently our trainWhistles
variable is set to 3.
But if we wanted to change our
trainWhistles amount, we just
reuse the assignment
operator and set it
equal to a new value.
Notice that we don't use the
var key word because the
console already knows that the
variable trainWhistles is
inside memory.
Now our trainWhistles
value is 9.
We can also use the
trainWhistles value itself to
modify the contents of the
trainWhistles variable.
Here you can see that we're
saying, take the trainWhistles
value, add 3 to it, and store
it back inside the
trainWhistles variable.
Now because the earlier value of
trainWhistles was 9, we get
9 plus 3 stored in trainWhistles,
which
results in a 12.
Another way to say that exact
same expression is with the
plus equals operator.
That signals to the console
to take the trainWhistles
variable, and add 3 to it, and
store it back inside the
trainWhistles variable.
Now we have 15 total
train whistles.
All of the operations can
be used with variable
assignments.
Here we can see that the
trainWhistles variable is
being multiplied by 2 before
being stored back inside the
trainWhistles variable.
Now we have 30 train whistles.
And again, the times equals
operator is the exact same as
the previous expression.
And we get 60 train whistles.
Whoa, 60 whistles -
that's a lot.
Variable names can also act as
substitutes for the data that
they point to.
That means that I can use
variables inside of
concatenations with strings to
refer to the data that's
actually inside the variable.
Here you can see a concatenation
of "All of our
trains have" with the variable
trainWhistles, and then the
string whistles.
What happens in the output?
"All of our trains
have 3 whistles!"
The variable name disappears and
instead the data that the
variable contains is placed
inside the string.
Additionally, we can place
variables inside of
expressions that are
concatenated with strings.
In this string, when
trainWhistles is multiplied by
3, we get 9.
And in the final string
we see, "But the
Pollock 9000 has 9!"
But wait, this code kind
of sucks a little bit.
Because the Pollock 9000 needs
its own whistles variable.
Let's do that.
All we have to do is declare
a new variable -
we'll call it the pollock9000 -
and then assign that
expression that we were using
in the string to this
new variable.
And now we can see that
the pollock9000
has 9 train whistles.
Now that the pollock9000 has
its own variable, we can use
that inside the string.
There's a simple way to
increase or decrease a
variable's value by 1
in either direction.
This is called incrementing
and decrementing.
Here on the left side, you can
see that we have trainWhistles
plus plus, which is a simple
syntax for increasing a
variable's value by 1.
Now you can see the
trainWhistles value is 4.
If we wanted to decrease the
variable by 1, we would have
used a minus minus syntax, which
would have produced a
value of 2 inside the
trainWhistles variable.