Hi everyone, and welcome to
the JavaScript Road Trip.
If you've ever surfed the
internet before -
and who hasn't -
chances are you've run
thousands, if not millions, of
lines of JavaScript code.
Now although JavaScript is
primarily designed for
interactive web pages, in this
tutorial, we'll be focused
primarily on the fundamental
building blocks of the
JavaScript language itself, so
that later, you'll be able to
engage with more advanced
frameworks like jQuery.
Now in this first course on
the Road Trip, we'll be
looking at the fundamental
building blocks of the
JavaScript language, including
how to manipulate values with
operators, as well as how to
create and store those values
inside variables, and then how
to find, and create, and run
JavaScript source files
within HTML code.
And with that, all aboard!
It's time to start your
journey on the
JavaScript road trip.
[SINGING]
From the labyrinth of loops to
the variable valley, we'll see
the cliffs of value first.
JavaScript's right
up your alley.
Built-in bluffs, files falls,
array, archipelago.
Declarations in a desert,
where you'll find out
how far you'll go.
Learn the program.
Take a ride.
Buy a ticket.
Step inside.
All aboard, you're
at the station to
increase your education.
Bon voyage and skinny dip! As
long as functions you don't
skimp on this, the JavaScript ...
Road Trip.
Hey, road trippers.
Welcome to Level 1 -
The Cliffs of Value.
Get ready to learn
about numbers,
operators, and strings.
There are two symbols that we'd
like to be familiar with
as we move through
this course.
The first is the greater than
symbol, which represents the
JavaScript prompt.
Here, we will place the code
that will actually be entered
into the console.
The arrow that follows
that is what gets
returned from the code.
The JavaScript language
automatically recognizes numbers.
So you can see that if we
entered a 24 into the console,
the console will return
24 right back to us.
The same goes for
decimal values.
If we entered 3.14, we'd also
see a 3.14 come right back.
Let's try to do some
math in JavaScript.
There are common operations that
the console will accept.
The first one is addition.
The second one is subtraction
The third is multiplication.
Next, we have division.
And then, we have a special
operator that you see a lot in
computer programming
called the modulus.
Modulus will return the
remainder after division.
You can see there that if we
divide 43 by 10, even though
it goes in four times, the
remainder from that
operation is 3.
Along with the basic operations,
JavaScript
recognizes the standard order of
operations in mathematics.
You may remember this by
the familiar acronym -
Parentheses, Exponents,
Multiplication, Division,
Addition, and Subtraction,
or PEMDAS.
We can see here that if we enter
an expression into the
JavaScript console, the first
thing that would be evaluated
is the parentheses that
contains 5 plus 7.
That would become a 12.
And then that 12 would be
multiplied by 3 to get 36.
Here's another longer
expression.
We can see that we'd hit
the parentheses first.
The 3 times 4 becoming a 12, and
the rest of the expression
coming down.
Followed by that, we would
tackle the 12 divided by 2,
which becomes a 6.
And, then we would do straight
addition and subtraction, left
to right, to produce a 9.
In this third expression, we
see some negative numbers.
JavaScript recognizes
those too.
And the first thing we would
tackle here is the negative 5
times 6 inside the
parentheses.
That would give us a negative
30, and the rest of the
expression would come down.
And then we would evaluate the
7 times the negative 2 to
arrive at negative 14, and
then negative 30 minus
negative 14 produces
a negative 16.
In this last expression, we can
see a modulus operation.
You can think of modulus as
being contained within the M
of PEMDAS, along with
multiplication, because it
exists in the same hierarchical
level.
Here in this operation, what
we would do first is the
innermost parentheses:
that 3 plus 1.
That would become a 4.
And then, we'd be left with an
8 modulus 4 inside that last
parenthesis.
The remainder after 8 is
divided by 4 is 0.
And then we would add 4 and
0 together, and get 4.
There are some unique
comparators in the JavaScript
language that allow us
to compare values.
When you use a comparator, it
will return something called a
Boolean value, which is
either true or false.
Here, you can see the comparator
greater than, which
you're probably familiar with.
The question asks, is
6 greater than 4?
And JavaScript returns true.
Along with greater than,
we have the less than.
And here, the question asks,
is 9 less than 5?
And that is false.
To compare equality of numbers
in JavaScript, we have to use
a special syntax.
We don't use a single
equal sign.
Instead here, we use a
double equal sign to
return a Boolean value.
This question asks, is
3 equal to 4, which
of course, is false.
JavaScript has a special syntax
to ask whether two
values are not equal.
We use an exclamation point in
front of an equal sign to ask
the not equal question.
And this particular question
says, is 12 not equal to 4?
Which gives us a value of
true, because those two
numbers are not equal.
We also, of course,
have a greater
than or equal to syntax.
This question asks whether 8
is greater than or equal to
negative 2.
Notice that the greater
than comes in front
of the equal sign.
This question returns a value of
true, because 8 is greater
than or equal to negative 2.
Along with greater or equal,
we have less than or equal.
This question asks, is 10 the
less than or equal to 10?
And since it is equal,
we get a truth value.