We can store anything inside
of JavaScript variables.
Up until now we've been using
numbers, but we can also store
strings inside of variables.
Here we have a welcome variable
as well as a safety
tip variable.
We can use both of those
variables that contain strings
in concatenation with a new line
character to produce a
specifically formatted string in
the output on the console.
If our variable contains a
string, we can use the
.length property to access the
length of that string instead
of typing the entire
string out.
Here you can see our variable
longString, with a string that
I wouldn't want to retype
every time.
And if we use the .length
property on longString, we can
see it returns the value
49 as the length.
We can also compare string
lengths using the length
property and a comparator.
So if we made two variables
here, longWordoOne and
longWordTwo, and they're both
huge and we don't want to
count each one or compare which
one is longer, we can
use the greater than operator
to ask whether the length of
the first string is greater
than the length
of the second string.
When we use the .length
property on two variables,
we're comparing two numbers.
And here we get a result of
false, because longWordOne is
not longer than longWordTwo.
Now, JavaScript strings have
a way of finding specific
characters within that string.
Each position inside a string
has a numbered index that
begins from zero.
Here we have a variable
called sentence.
And inside is a sentence,
a very long string.
You can see that the index
zero, we have the capital
letter A. You want to think of
index numbers as being a
certain distance away from
the starting character.
And thus, the first character in
a string is
zero away from itself.
Then you can see at index
eight that we
have a lowercase 's'.
At index 28, we have
a space character.
That's right, spaces
are characters, too.
And then in the very last index,
index 42, we have an
exclamation point.
Now, if we took the length of
the sentence variable using
the .length property,
JavaScript will return a 43.
What?
Why?
We just said that the last
character was index 42.
That's because string positions
are zero-based.
And so there will always be one
less index then the total
length of the string.
Another cool helper method for
strings is the charAt method.
If you place in index inside the
parentheses of the charAt
method, JavaScript will return
the character that's exactly
at that index for you.
So you can see that the
11th index would
contain the letter b.
The 31st index would contain
a space character.
And JavaScript will return a
space to you, surrounded by
two quotation marks.
And at the 42nd index, we
can see that we get the
exclamation point.
Variables are essentially the
foundation of programming.
They help us organize
our data.
And we're able to create very
powerful and complex and
flexible messages
using variables,
which can be modified.
Let's say that we were designing
a train system, and
we have a certain amount of
operational trains out of a
certain amount of
total trains.
Let's see how we can make a
message to print to the user
at the console about
how many running
trains there are today.
If we wanted to make our message
using these particular
variables, we could do
trainsOperational concatenated
with out of, then the variable
total trains, and then the
operating status message.
Together, those would produce
8 out of 12 trains are
operational today.
Now, say we had to run the train
system message again the
next day, but there was a
different amount of trains
that were operational.
Too easy -
we can change the
trainsOperational variable to
a value of 10.
And now, when the message gets
printed out to the user, we
get 10 out of 12 trains
are operational today.
That's it for the variables
section.
We're going to release
you to the hounds in
the challenge section.
Good luck, and we'll see you
in the next section.
We can even use dollar scores -
dollar scores.
That's a lot of whistles ... [pfft!]
... if you know what I mean.
Long wood two -
long wood.
I might have had three beers.
It is a Road Trip after all. [laughing]