Welcome back to Level Two.
We just have a few more HTML5
elements to look at.
So now let's take a look at the
article element in HTML5.
Now, by definition, the article
element represents a
complete or self-contained part
of a document that is
technically just independently
reusable or distributable.
It's just something that we
could use in syndication.
Now, an article element is
essentially just another type
of section.
It's used for self-contained
related content.
Now, you might ask, how do we
determine if a particular
piece of content is
self-contained?
That's a great question.
You need to ask yourself if
you would syndicate that
particular piece of content
in an RSS or Atom feed.
So let's look at some example
uses for the article tag.
We have things like a blog post,
a news story, a comment
on a post, or even a review.
Looking at our sample art
gallery site, we can see that
we have syndicated content for
each new gallery item.
This is a great example of using
the article element.
So let's go ahead and look at
how we would mark this up.
Prior to HTML5, we would have
marked this up with a div,
with a class or ID of article,
and then all of the markup
contained within.
In HTML5, though, we can
instead use the article
element, which is going to make
our document and this
particular piece of syndicated
content more semantic.
And again, that will make our
markup have more meaning.
So now let's move on
to talk about the
main element in HTML5.
The main element, as you might
expect, represents the main
content of the body of a
document or application.
The main content area consists
of content that either
directly relates to or expands
upon the central
topic of the document.
Let's look at a couple of don'ts
with the main element.
We don't want to include more
than one main element in our
document, and we also don't
want to include the main
element inside of other HTML5
elements like the article,
aside, footer, the header,
and the nav element.
Jumping back to our art gallery,
we can see we have a
main content section that
directly relates to the
central topic of this document,
which is a gallery.
Let's see how we can mark up
this particular section.
Prior to HTML5, we would have
marked this up using a div
with a class or ID of main, and
then our markup contained
within that.
In HTML5, though, we can instead
use the main element
to wrap this markup, which
gives our document more
semantic meaning.
Once again, we've
achieved further
clarity in our HTML document.
So that's it for the
main element.
Let's now look at
the figure and
figcaption elements in HTML5.
First, let's look at the
figure element.
The figure element, by
definition, represents a unit
of content that may or may
not have a caption that's
self-contained that, if removed
from the flow of the
document, will not affect
the document's meaning.
A common use case for the figure
element is for an image
within an article.
Here we have a figure element,
and then an image nested
inside of that.
Now let's quickly look at the
figcaption element to see how
it works with the
figure element.
By definition, the figcaption
element represents a caption
or a legend for its parent
figure, the element
we just looked at.
So for our existing figure
element, we add a figcaption
element that contains a caption
for the picture.
The output of these elements
looks something like this.
We have our image and the
caption for that image within
the figure element.
So now let's wrap up the HTML5
elements by talking about the
time element.
The time element, by definition,
represents either
a time on a 24 hour clock or a
precise date in the proleptic
Gregorian calendar, optionally
with a time
and a time zone offset.
Looking at our art gallery site,
you can see that we have
these published on dates for
each of our new gallery items.
This is a perfect use for
the time element.
So here we're using the time
element with our date in
between that.
But we actually want to use
a different format for our
date - the one we just showed -
so we're going to put that date
format here within the
content for our time tag.
We need to make an important
change in order to use that
date format.
We have to add the datetime
attribute to our time element
with that particular date
format, and this allows us to
use any relevant content to the
date or time within the
time element.
If we didn't use that datetime
attribute on the time element,
the content must either
be a valid date, time,
or a precise datetime.
There they are -
all of the HTML5 elements.
We're going to give you a few
challenges, and we'll see you
back in level three.
FOO-TA. The FOO-TA!
Hey, Footer, we're going
down to Jim's Crocodile Bar.
So the footer - so the
footer is a footer?
Is that what you're telling me?
All right.