I'm Drew Barontini.
This is Front-End Formations,
Level One:
Overview and Updates.
In this level, we're going to
give a brief overview of
HTML5, we're going to give an
overview CSS3, talk about some
of the updated HTML elements in
HTML5, and then talk about
the updates to some existing
HTML tags in HTML5.
Now we're going to start by
giving an overview of HTML5.
HTML5 is really only a
definition used to refer to
the latest version of HTML -
the latest standard.
And it includes several new
features, such as new HTML
elements and attributes, full
CSS3 support, video and audio
elements, 2D and 3D graphics,
local storage,
and a local SQL database.
Now in this course, we're just
going to focus on the new HTML
elements and attributes, and
also the full CSS3 support.
So now that we've given an
overview of HTML5, let's give
a brief overview of CSS3.
Like HTML5, CSS3 is really only
used as a definition for
the latest standard of CSS.
And there are several new
features in CSS3, and we'll
cover several of those here,
such as border radius, box
shadow and text shadow,
transitions and transforms,
gradients, multiple backgrounds,
and font face.
Now text shadow and font face
will actually predate CSS3,
but they're still important
components to modern CSS.
So we're going to cover
them in this course.
So now that we've given a brief
overview CSS3, let's
move on to talk about
some of the updated
HTML elements in HTML5.
And those elements include,
the doctype, the meta
declaration, the script
tag, and the link tag.
So let's start by talking
about the doctype.
Now in HTML 4.01, there
were a few doctypes.
We had the strict doctype, the
transitional doctype, and
frameset doctype.
Now these are really difficult
to remember, and you were used
to just copying and pasting them
from project to project.
In HTML5, though, we have
one simple doctype and
it looks like this.
Now a quick convention note
here, when you see this HTML5
logo on top of a code block,
it signifies that the code
being shown is the
updated HTML5
version, like it is here.
The next HTML5 element that's
been updated is the meta
declaration.
Now in HTML4, it looked
something like this.
You recognize this because it's
the tag you put inside
the head of your document to
specify the character encoding
for your HTML document.
Now this is, again, long, like
those doctypes in HTML4, so
it's something that we were
copying and pasting from
project to project.
But in HTML5 it's
really simple.
You just need to specify the
charset attribute, and in this
case, our character
encoding is UTF-8.
The next HTML tag that receives
an update in HTML5 is
the script tag,
and this is what you use to
reference external JavaScript
files, or write inline
JavaScript.
Now in HTML4, you need to
specify the type attribute to
be text/JavaScript.
And in HTML5, we don't need this
type attribute, because
the browser will infer that
JavaScript is the type.
In HTML 4.01, the link tag
required the type attribute to
be text/CSS.
In HTML5, though, we don't
need this type
attribute at all.
The browser will infer
that CSS is the type
for the link tag.
So now that we've talked about
some of the updated HTML
elements in HTML5, let's wrap up
this level by talking about
the updates to the existing
HTML elements in HTML5.
The i, and b, and em, and strong
tags were traditionally
considered presentational
tags.
But in HTML5, they've been given
new semantic meanings.
The i and b tags were considered
font style
decorations in HTML4.
The i tag rendered text in a
italic font style, while the b
tag rendered text in
a bold font style.
In HTML5, though, these tags
have new meanings.
The i tag now represents text
that is in an alternate voice
or mood, and the b tag
represents text that is
stylistically offset.
So now let's look at some
example uses for the i tag.
We have things like a taxonomic
designation, a
technical term, an idiomatic
phrase from another language,
a transliteration, a thought, a
ship name in Western texts.
Now these are real technical
terms that the spec gives us,
so let's look at a more
practical example
of using the i tag.
So here we have this paragraph
text, "I hope
this works," he thought.
We're wrapping "I hope this
works" in an i tag to
designate this text as being in
an alternate voice or mood.
It's considered a thought.
So now let's look at some
example uses for the b tag.
We have things like keywords in
a document, product names
in a review, actionable words
in interactive software, or
something like an
article lead.
Now these examples are a little
bit better than the
ones we were given for the i tag.
But again, let's look at a
more practical example of
using the b tag.
Here we have a paragraph, and
we're wrapping the text in a b
tag with a class of lead.
Now we're doing this, because
we want this text to be
stylistically offset from the
paragraphs that follow it,
because it's going to
be an article lead.
And in addition, we add a class
of lead to the b tag to
give it further semantic
meaning.
Next up, we have the
em and strong tags.
And in HTML4, the em tag meant
emphasis, while the strong tag
meant strong emphasis.
But in HTML5, they have
new meanings.
The em tag now mean stress
emphasis, while the strong tag
now means strong importance.
So let's look at some
examples of these.
So here we have a paragraph with
the text, "Make sure to
sign up before the day of the
event, September 16, 2013."
We're wrapping the word "before"
in an em tag in
order to give stress emphasis
to the word "before." it's a
linguistic change.
For the strong tag, in that same
sentence, we're wrapping
the date, September 16, 2013,
in a strong tag, in order to
give strong importance to
the date of the event.
With that, you now have a basic
introduction to the
changes in HTML5.
Let's see what you can do
with some challenges.
Let's look at some
"exsample" uses -
example.
Look at some "exsample" uses -
good lord!
Ex samples, they're
no longer samples.