Welcome back.
Hope you had some success with
those Level Two challenges.
This is Level Three: HTML5 Forms.
In this level, we're going to
talk about the new HTML5 input
types, the new form elements,
and then we're going to wrap
things up with the new
form attributes.
So let's start off by talking
about the new
input types in HTML5.
HTML5 provides several
new input types.
And we're going to look at
each of these in turn.
Now something that we just need
to be aware of is that if
a browser doesn't support a
particular input type, it
defaults to text.
First off, we're going to look
at the search input type,
which is just a control
for entering one
or more search terms.
We can see that we have
a search input
here at the top right.
Let's see how we can convert
this input from a text input
to a search input.
To use a search input type,
we simply change the type
attribute from text to search.
And you can see here that we're
not specifying a value,
so it's going to be an
empty search input.
Now when that's rendered, we see
that we get a search input
with rounded corners that we can
enter our search term into
and then clear it out with the
conveniently located x icon
off to the right.
Additionally, in mobile browsers
like here in mobile
Safari, we get some added
usability benefits.
The primary action button
changes to search, which
reinforces what the user
is currently doing.
Now let's look at
the email input.
The email input looks just like
a regular text input, but
it also gives us added usability
on mobile devices.
Looking at our art gallery, we
can see that we have an email
input down here at
the bottom right.
Now don't worry about that
enter your email
text inside the input.
We'll look at that later and see
how we can spruce it up.
To use the email input type,
all we have to do is change
the type attribute from text
to email just like we did
before with search.
And again, on the mobile safari
keyboard we can see
that we now get useful email
related keys like the at
symbol and the period.
Next up, we have the URL input,
which again, looks just
like a regular text input, but
gives us some nice usability
on mobile devices.
Again, on the mobile Safari
keyboard, we can see that we
get useful URL related keys such
as the slash and .com.
Next up, we have the date
input type which is
essentially just a control that
lets you set a string
that represents a date.
To use the date input type, all
we have to do is change
the type attribute from text to
date, just as we did with
the other
HTML5 input types.
Now, here we can see in the
browser that we get a date
picker when we click on the
arrow to the right side of the
input allowing us to
conveniently select a date.
And in mobile Safari, we get
the native iOS date picker.
Next up, we have
the tel input.
Now the tel input, again, like
some of the other input types
just looks like a regular text
input, but we do get some
added usability on
mobile devices.
To use the tel input type,
again, you just need to change
the type attribute
from text to tel.
Real simple.
And, again, here in mobile
Safari, the keyboard now
changes to be the telephone
keyboard on iOS.
Another input type
is the number.
Which essentially just let's
us set a string value that
represents a number.
To use the number input type,
we just change the type
attribute from text to number.
And then we can see here that we
get a convenient control to
the right side of the input that
allows us to increase or
decrease the value
in the input.
And in mobile Safari the
keyboard now changes so that
we have a row of number keys at
the top when we're focused
on a number input.
The range input type is
an imprecise control
for setting a number.
To use the range input type, we
change the type attribute
from text to range.
And then we can see that we get
a control that allows us
to drag a slider to change
the number value.
Taking a look at two similar
input types, the month and the
week, we specify them by
changing the type attribute
from text to month and
week, respectively.
We can see here on the left side
that we have the month
input type that allows us to
select a month at a time.
And then on the right, we have
the week input type to select
a given week.
Two more similar input types,
the time and date time local
are specified by changing the
type attribute to time and
datetime-local.
We can see here that on the left
we have a time input type
that allows you to select
a given time.
And then on the right, we have
a datetime-local input type
that not only allows you
to select the date,
but the time as well.
There's a clear distinction
between the datetime-local and
datetime input types.
Now the datetime-local input
type has no time zone
information associated
with it.
The final HTML5 input type we're
going to take a look at
is the color.
Now a color input type simply
lets us set a string that
represents a color.
To use the input type of color,
we simply change the
type attribute to be color.
And then we can see here that we
get a toggle that allows us
to bring up the color picker
to select a color.
Wow.
That's a lot of input types.
So now let's take a look
at some of the new
form elements in HTML5.
In HTML5, we get a few different
form elements
provided to us.
Those are the datalist element,
the keygen element,
and the output element.
Now we're just going to focus
on the datalist form element
because it's the most
commonly used one.
The datalist form element allows
you to set predefined
options that you can use
for other controls.
Let's take a look at
how we do this.
The first thing we need to do
is specify an input and here
we're just using a regular
text input.
But we're also adding a list
attribute of browsers.
Now, I'll get to how this
works in a second.
Let's look at how we specify
the datalist element.
So here we simply use the
datalist tag and then we're
specifying an ID of browsers.
The list and ID attributes need
to sync up so that the
input knows about the
datalist options.
The next thing we need to do is
specify each of our options
with values.
Now you'll recognize this
because these are the same
ones that we use within
a select tag.
And these are the option
values that will now be
available to our input.
Our input looks just like a
regular text input, but when
we start typing, we can see
that we get auto-complete
suggestions based on the
option values that we
specified within the
datalist element.
How cool is that?
And we'll wrap this level up by
talking about the new HTML5
form attributes.
HTML5 provides several
new form attributes.
Things like placeholder,
autofocus, autocomplete,
required, pattern, and several
others that are
available to us.
Now we're going to focus
primarily on the placeholder,
autofocus, required, and
pattern attributes.
The placeholder attribute
allows you to specify a
message that's shown
inside the input.
That message is hidden when
the user starts typing and
then it returns when focus
is lost on that input.
Looking at our art gallery site,
we can see that we have
this enter your email
placeholder text.
Now I referenced this earlier.
So I'm going to show you how
we can use the placeholder
attribute to spruce this up.
In order to do so, we need to
change the value attribute as
it's currently set to
be placeholder.
The advantage here is with the
value attribute there, the
user has to select that text and
clear it out before they
can start typing.
The placeholder attribute
actually makes it much nicer.
We can see on the rendered input
that we get slightly
grayed out text that's removed
when the user starts typing
and then returns again
when they remove the
text from the input.
Next up, we have the autofocus
attribute, which as the name
implies, automatically
focuses an input
when the page is rendered.
To use the autofocus attribute,
you just need to
add autofocus to the input
that you want to
automatically focus on.
When the page is rendered,
that input is now
automatically focused.
And this is something that we
had to previously do in
JavaScript.
Now in HTML5 we just need
to add one simple word.
A third attribute is the
required attribute.
When a form is submitted, the
user will be notified of an
error if the field
is left blank.
Let's see how we can use this.
Like the autofocus attribute,
all we have to do to use the
required attribute is add
that text to an input.
When the user submits the form,
if they leave that field
blank, they're given an error
message telling them that they
need to fill in that
required field.
Lastly, we have the pattern
attribute which accepts a
JavaScript regular expression
that will be matched against
the user's entry to ensure they
have the correct pattern.
Now let's look at an example
of how we'll
use the pattern attribute.
You might not be familiar
with JavaScript regular
expressions, but don't
worry about that.
We'll provide resources at
the end of the course.
For now, just know that we're
matching three digits.
When the form is submitted, if
the user's entry doesn't
exactly match the pattern,
they're notified of an error
until the pattern is matched.
That concludes level 3.
So now that you're a little more
comfortable with HTML5
forms, let's give you
some challenges.
And we'll see you
back in level 4.
[BEEPING]
You like the dancing?
I did and I didn't
say this before.
[LAUGHTER]
Wrong emphasis on the
wrong syllable.
[LAUGHTER]
Not even close.