Welcome back.
We finally made it to Level
Five: Fonts and Interactions.
In this level, we're going to
cover font face, transforms,
transitions, and finally, we'll
wrap things up with
progressive enhancement.
Now let's start by talking
about font face.
Using font face, we actually
have the ability to provide
online fonts for use
on our websites.
Now, let's jump right into
an example of font face.
First, we specify the font
family property to be the name
that we want to call this
font, and in our case,
OpenSansRegular.
Next, we specify the source
attribute to be the URLs to
the local versions
of those fonts.
It's important to note that
we'll have to specify multiple
font types here which can be
added as additional URLs to
the source attribute.
Next, we specify the font style
to be normal, and then
we specify the font weight
property to be normal as well.
To use our new font in our style
sheet, we set the font
family attribute to be the
same name as the one
that we just set.
Now with font face fonts,
just like any other font
declaration that we use in our
styles, we should specify
fallback fonts in case that
font isn't supported.
So here, in addition to the
OpenSansRegular font
family, we're also specifying
three different fonts that can
be used as fallbacks if that
one is not available.
We can also use varying weights
of font face fonts.
Like here in this example,
we're using OpenSansBold,
which is a bold version
of the previous font.
Now in our style sheet, in
order to use this bold
version, all we have to do is
change the font family, which
was previously OpenSansRegular,
to OpenSansBold.
And now we're using
the bold version.
We can alter our font face
call In order to use the
font-style and font-weight
properties as we normally do
when we're using varying weights
of a specific font.
Now to do this, we need to make
some changes to the bold
version that we were referencing
earlier.
We start by changing the font
family property to be the same
name as the regular weight
version that
we referenced earlier.
We keep the source attribute the
same, referencing the bold
version of the font because
that's the one we want here.
We change the font-weight
from normal to bold.
And then in our style sheet, we
can use this bold version
by now changing the font-weight
to bold rather
than changing the font family.
Next up, we're going to talk
about CSS transforms.
Now using the transform property
in CSS3, we can
translate, rotate, scale, and
skew various elements in CSS.
First up, we have translate,
which allows you to create a
2D translation using the
transform property.
You can see here that we're
setting a 20-pixel x-axis
value and a 30-pixel y-axis
value, which moves our element
20 pixels to the right
and 30 pixels down.
Let's see what that
looks like.
So here, we can see our element
move 20 pixels to the
right and 30 pixels down
as we specified.
The translate function, as we
just saw, takes two arguments,
the translation value for the
x-axis, which can either be a
length or a percentage, and the
translation value for the
y-axis, which can either be
a length or a percentage.
If we don't specify
this value, the
value is set to zero.
You can use the translateX and
translateY functions to
translate the x and y values
individually as seen here.
Our first element is using the
translateX function to move
the element 20 pixels to the
right along the x-axis.
Our second element is using
the translateY function to
move the element down 30 pixels
along the y-axis.
The translateX function takes
a translation value for the
x-axis, and the translateY
function takes a transition
value for the y-axis.
Next up, we have the rotate
transform, which allows you to
rotate an element clockwise
around its origin by a
specified angle.
Let's look at an example here.
We're using the transform
property and the rotate
function to rotate an
element 45 degrees.
We can see the output here, and
as you might expect, our
element is rotated 45 degrees.
With the scale transform, you
can do a 2D scale by a
specified, unitless number.
So here, we're performing
a scale transform to
the value of 1.2.
And we can see our output
looks like this.
Our element scales up by a
unitless number of 1.2.
Our scale transform takes two
arguments, the value for the
x-axis, which again is a
unitless number, and the value
for the y-axis, which is a
unitless number as well.
If you don't specify the y-axis
value, it'll default to
what you specified in
the first argument.
Here, we can see we're using
both the scaleX and scaleY
like we did with translate to
scale the x and y values
individually.
In our first example, we're
scaling our element along the
x-axis to a unitless
number of 1.2.
In our second example we're
scaling our element to the
value of 0.3 along the y-axis.
Just like translate, you can
use the scaleX and scaleY
functions to scale the x and
y values individually.
Lastly, we have the skew
transform, which allows you to
skew an element around
the x or y-axis
by a specified angle.
Unlike translate and scale, the
skew transform only allows
you to skew the x and y
values individually
using skewX and skewY.
Here, we're using skewX to skew
an element negative 25
degrees along the x-axis.
Here's what that looks like.
We can see our element
skewed negative 25
degrees along the x-axis.
SkewX takes in an angle for
the x-axis, and the skewY
function takes in an angle
for the y-axis.
We can see here that we're
using the skewX and skewY
transforms on each
of our elements.
In the first example, we're
skewing x 25 degrees, and in
the second example, we're
skewing y negative 85 degrees.
And here's what those
skews look like.
The first one is using the skewX
function, and the second
one is using the
skewY function.
Next, let's talk about
CSS transitions.
CSS3 provides transitions, which
allow you to transition
between two states of
a given element.
Let's look at an example
of a transition.
Let's say we have this
element that has a
background color of black.
When we hover over that
element, we want it
to change to blue.
But we don't want this to be a
jarring, immediate change.
We want to do it over
a slow duration.
We do this by using the
transition property.
In here, we're transitioning
the background color from
black to blue over the period
of 0.2 seconds.
And here, we can see how that
change takes effect.
The background color transitions
from black to blue
over the course of
0.2 seconds.
The transition property takes
a few different values.
Let's go through each
of these in turn.
The first of which is the CSS
property that you actually
want to transition
like we just did
with background color.
The next is the duration value,
which is the amount of
time that you want the
transition to take place.
Next, we specify the timing
function value, which is the
timing of the transition itself,
and this takes a few
different key words.
We have ease, ease-in,
ease-in-out, linear,
cubic-bezier, step-start and
step-end, and then steps().
We'll give you some resources
for learning more about these
transitions after the course.
Finally, we specify the delay
value, which is the amount of
time you want to wait, if at
all, until the transition
should take place.
Instead of setting those
transition values all on one
line like we just did, we can
do that individually.
We first set the transition
property using the
transition-property to
background color.
Next, we set the transition
duration to 0.2 seconds.
Then, we set the transition
timing function to be
ease-in-out.
And finally, we set
the transition
delay to be 0.1 seconds.
We can transition multiple
properties at once using the
all keyword for the transition
property.
Let's look at an example.
So on our element, we now not
only have a background color
of black, but we have
a color of white.
When you hover over that
element, we change the
background color to gray,
and the color to black.
We then set a transition to
transition both of those
properties, the background color
and the color, over the
period of 0.2 seconds.
And now we can see when we hover
over our element, both the
background color and the color
properties are transitioned
because we used the
all keyword.
That's it for transitions.
Let's wrap things up by talking
about progressive
enhancement.
The term progressive enhancement
refers to the use
of newer features that add to
the experience in modern
browsers that support those
features, but doesn't detract
from the experience in older
browsers that don't support
those features.
Let's look at an example here.
Let's say we had an element
with a gray background, a
border radius of 10 pixels,
and a box shadow.
That element, in browsers that
support the border radius and
box shadow properties,
would look like this.
Now if a browser did not support
those border radius
and box shadow properties, we
would get this gray box that
contains no border radius or
box shadow, but it's still
usable, which is what
progressive
enhancement is all about.
Progressive enhancement is
important to keep in mind
because we want to make sure
that we're creating
experiences that degrade
gracefully for browsers that
don't support a lot of the
features we've covered.
And that's it for Front-end
Formations.
I hope you enjoyed
this course.
Now head over to the challenges
because they're the
last ones you're going to get.
See you soon.
I'm in their failure,
because I finally made them fail.
[IN BACKGROUND] Yeah, you caused
their failure.
We can alter our font face -
font face.
We can alter our font f -
Get out of here, font face.
Head over to the challenges,
because they're the last ones
you'll get. [LAUGHING]