Welcome back.
Hope you enjoyed those
challenges.
This is Level Two:
HTML5 Elements.
So in this level, we're covering
the new HTML5 section
elements, such as the section,
the header, the footer, the
aside, the nav, the article,
the main, the figure and
figcaption elements.
And then finally, we'll
wrap up by talking
about the time element.
In this level, we'll be using
this example art gallery site,
that you'll see repeatedly when
we talk about these new
HTML5 elements.
So let's start by talking about
the section element.
Now by definition, the section
element represents a generic
document or application
section.
Now I know what you're
thinking.
The definition for that sounds
a lot like the definition for
a div, which is just a generic
container that conveys no
particular meaning.
Now there's a very important
distinction between a
section and a div.
While a div has no semantic
meaning, a
section element does,
and it's used for grouping
together
thematically related content.
In the book, HTML5 For Web
Designers, Jeremy Keith tells
us, when we're trying to
determine between using divs
or section elements to ask
ourselves, "Is all of the
content related?"
If you answered yes to that
question, then a section
element might be appropriate.
Looking at our art gallery site,
we can see that we have
a grouping of thematically
related content that contains
a natural heading.
While all section elements
don't have to necessarily
contain a heading, they
generally do.
And in this instance,
ours does.
And it has the heading,
"The Gallery."
Now let's look at how
we'd mark this up.
Prior to HTML5, we would have
marked this up with a div,
with a class or ID of section,
and then the
markup contained within.
In HTML5, though, we can
instead use the section
element to wrap our markup,
which makes our document much
more semantic.
Now I briefly want to mention
the document outline, which is
what's used to produce an
outline summary of an HTML
document, based on the markup
that's used in that document.
A few of the HTML5 elements
have their own
self-contained outline.
And those elements are the
article element, the aside
element, the nav element,
and the section element.
Now let's look at an example of
this to see how it works.
In this example, we have an h1
here, that says, "This is the
title of the page." We have
a section element,
and inside that section element,
we have an h2 that
says, "This is the title
of a subsection."
The document outline for this
particular piece of markup
would look something
like this.
We have a first, main heading
for "This is the title of the
page," our h1.
And then we have the first main
subheading, which is,
"This is the title of a
subsection." Because the
document outline is actually
self-contained within this
section element, we can
instead replace the h2 in
this section with an h1,
and our document
outline remains the same.
Now that we talked about the
section element, let's move on
to talk about the
header element.
Now the header element is
defined as a group of
introductory or navigation
aids.
It's important to note that you
can include more than one
header on your page.
It's not just limited to the
top portion of your site.
While the header generally
appears at the top of a
document or section, it's
defined more by its content
rather than its position.
Looking at our sample art
gallery site, we can see at
the top that we have a section
that contains introductory
content, as well as
navigational aids.
This is a good use of
the header element.
Let's see how we'd
mark that up.
Prior to HTML5, we would have
marked this up with a div,
with a class or ID of
header, and then our
markup contained within.
In HTML5, though, we can
instead use the header
element, and then all of our
markup contained within that.
This makes our document
more semantic.
In other words, the meaning
of our HTML
document is more clear.
Now like I said before, you can
have header elements in
different parts of your page.
So here we're showing that we
have a header element inside
of a section element.
So this is the header for
this particular section.
So now that we talked about the
header element in HTML5,
let's move on to talk about the
footer element in HTML5.
By definition, the footer
element represents a footer
for its nearest ancestor
sectioning content, or
sectioning root element.
Now similar to the header,
the footer element is not
dependent on its position.
It needs to be describing
the content that
it's contained within.
Looking at our sample art
gallery site, we can see that
we have a footer for
entire site.
So now let's see how this
element is marked up.
Prior to HTML5, we'd mark this
up with a div, with a class or
ID of footer, and then
all of the markup
contained within that.
In HTML5, though, we can
instead use the footer
element to wrap all of our
markup, which again makes our
document more semantic.
Like the header, we can also
put the footer within other
HTML5 elements.
So notice how this is a footer
for this particular section.
Now let's talk about the
aside element in HTML5.
The aside element was initially
defined by the HTML5
spec, as being tangentially
related to the content
surrounding it.
Now what in the world
does that mean?
Tangentially related to the
content surrounding it just
means that it's not directly
related to, but it expands
upon the content
surrounding it.
However, in HTML5, the
aside element now
covers various contexts.
When used within an article
element, the aside content
should be related to that
particular article that it's
contained within.
However, when it's used outside
an article element,
the aside content should be
specifically related to the
site as a whole.
The second definition closely
resembles the definition for a
sidebar of a site.
Now it's important to note that
an aside element is most
appropriate when it's used to
represent content that's not
the primary focus of an article
or page, but it's
still related to that
article or page.
Over here, we can see that we
have secondary content related
to the site as a whole.
So let's look at how we
could mark this up.
Now prior to HTML5, we would
have marked this up with a
div, with a class or ID of
sidebar, and then the markup
contained within.
In HTML5, though, we can
instead use the aside
element, and then all of our
markup contained within that,
which, again, makes our document
more semantic.
Like the header and footer
elements, we can also nest the
aside within HTML elements,
such as the
section, like here.
Now this is an aside for this
particular section element.
So now that we've covered the
aside element, let's move on
to talk about the nav element.
Now by definition, the nav
element represents a section
of a page that links to
other pages, or to
parts within that page.
It's essentially just a
section with navigation links.
Now it's important to note
that the nav element is
intended for major navigation.
We can see that we have major
navigation for the site, which
is a good use of the
nav element.
Prior to HTML5, we would have
marked this up with, probably,
an unordered list, with a class
or ID of nav, and then
our list items and anchor links
contained within that.
In HTML5, though, we can
instead use the nav element
and nest our unordered list with
the list items and anchor
links inside of that
nav element.
Again this is making our
document more semantic.
It's more clear, and it
has more meaning.
So that's it for the first
group of HTML5 elements.
Now let's give you some
challenges so you can test out
your skills.