Welcome back to Level Four.
We're done talking about HTML5,
so now we're going to
move on and talk about CSS3.
Particularly, we're going to
cover the CSS3 styles.
In this level, we'll be covering
several styles
including border radius, box
shadow, text shadow, box
sizing, multiple backgrounds,
color, opacity, and then we're
going to wrap things up by
talking about gradients.
Now let's first start by talking
about the border
radius property in CSS3.
The border radius property
allows us to apply rounded
corners to borders.
Let's look at an example here.
So we're going to be working
with this box element that has
a grey background, and it's 50
pixels tall and 200 pixels
wide, and it looks
just like this.
It's a simple box.
If we wanted to apply rounded
corners to our box, we could
do it by specifying four
different properties, and
therefore each of the four
sides of the box.
We have the top left, top
right, bottom right, and
bottom left.
And in this case, we're
specifying a 15-pixel border
radius for each of those
four corners.
Now this is what our box now
looks like with that 15-pixel
border radius on each
of the corners.
We can also use the shorthand
border-radius property to
specify all sides at once.
So here we're specifying
15-pixel border radius that'll
get applied to each of those
four corners You can also
specify the border radius
values for each corner
individually like we're
doing here.
We're specifying four pixels, 15
pixels, 12, and 10 for each
of the four sides, and it gives
our box an irregular
regular shape.
Now let's see how you set
the order of those
border radius values.
First, we're going to set
the top left value.
Next, the top right, then the
bottom right, and finally, the
bottom left.
Now in addition to specifying
those pixel values that we
were just using, you can also
use percentages with the
border radius property.
So here, we're specifying a 50%
border radius which, when
applied to our box, gives
it an oval shape.
Now if we had the same
dimensions, so the same width
and same height on our box, if
we applied a border radius of
50%, we'd get a perfect
circle.
The next CSS3 property
we're going to talk
about is box shadow.
Box shadow, as the name implies,
allows us to specify
a shadow on a given element.
So here's a quick example of
what a box shadow looks like,
and you can see on our box that
we now have a shadow on
that element.
Now let's look at each of the
values specified on the box
shadow property.
The first value is
the inset value.
If you don't specify this, which
is the default, a drop
shadow is created.
If you do use the keyword
"inset," then a box shadow has
an insect shadow.
A quick convention note here.
If you see this question mark
icon on top of a particular
argument, it means that that
argument is optional, just
like it is here with
the inset value.
The next value is the offset x
value, which is going to move
the shadow along the x-axis,
so left and right.
Then you specify the offset y
value, which is how you want
the shadow to move
up and down.
Next, you specify the blur
radius, which is going to
change the blur amount of the
shadow, which will cause it to
become bigger and lighter
with a larger value.
Next, we specify the spread
radius, which will cause the
shadow to grow or shrink, so it
essentially just adjusting
the size of our shadow.
The final thing that
we specify is the
color of the shadow.
What color you want your
box shadow to be.
Coming back to our example, we
can see that we're specifying
a box shadow that has no inset
value, so it's going to be a
drop shadow.
Then, we're specifying a
one-pixel offset x value, so
we're moving our shadow one
pixel to the right.
Then we specify the offset y
value, which will move our
shadow two pixels down.
Then we specify a two-pixel
blur radius.
We're not specifying a spread
radius here, so the size of
the shadow is just going to
default to being the size of
the element.
The last value we specify is the
color of the drop shadow,
and in this case, black.
And here's what our drop shadow
looks like, like you
saw earlier.
You might ask, what if you
wanted to set the spread
radius instead of
the blur radius?
In order to do this, we need to
specify zero as the value
for the blur radius, which
comes before the
spread radius value.
So here, you can see we're
specifying zero as the blur
radius value, which allows us
to specify two pixels as the
spread radius.
Just to point out the difference
between the blur
radius and spread radius
properties, let's look at the
example here.
So we can see that the blur
radius, as the value gets
larger, is expanding and
becoming lighter.
Now the spread radius, the
actual size of the drop
shadow, is increasing as
the value gets higher.
You can also specify multiple
box shadows through a
comma-separated list.
Here, we're specifying our first
box shadow with a comma,
and then we specify our
second box shadow.
You can see then on our box
that we now have two box
shadows, one that's inset, and
one that's a drop shadow.
In addition, you can
specify negative
values on your box shadow.
So here, we're specifying a
negative 1 pixel x offset, so
we're moving the shadow one
pixel to the left, and we're
specifying a negative 2 pixel
offset for the y, which moves
the shadow two pixels up, which
is the reverse of what
we were doing previously.
So you can see here now how our
drop shadow is affected.
Next up, we have the text
shadow property, which
although it's not a CSS3
property, it's still important
to teach here.
The tech shadow property is very
similar to box shadow,
but it applies the shadow to the
text, as the name implies.
So let's look at an
example of using
the text shadow property.
So let's assume that we
have this h1 here that
says, "I have a shadow."
So then, we apply this text
shadow to the h1, and you can
see here that the order of
values is very similar to the
one specified on the box
shadow property.
The output of this
looks like this.
We have a shadow on our text,
and we're actually changing
the color of this h1 to be white
rather than the default
black, but we're just doing that
so you can see the shadow
more clearly.
Now let's look at the order of
values that we specify on the
text shadow property.
We start by specifying the
offset x value, just like we
did with box shadow.
Then, we specify the
offset y value.
Then, we specify the blur
radius, which functions the
same way it does
on box shadow.
And finally we specify the
color of the shadow.
So again, looking at our text
shadow example, we can see
that we're specifying a
one-pixel offset x value,
moving our shadow one pixel to
the right, a two-pixel offset
y value, moving our shadow two
pixels down, a two-pixel blur
radius, and then finally a color
of black for the shadow.
And again, you can see
what that looks like.
So now the last one we'll
look at in this
section is box sizing.
Now the box sizing property is
what's used to change the
default CSS box model, which
is what we use to calculate
the dimensions of elements
in HTML, so the
width and the height.
First, let's have a quick
refresher on the box model.
The CSS box model references
the design and layout of
certain HTML elements.
Each HTML element is considered
a box, and it
contains margins, borders,
padding, and the content of
the element.
The box model refers to how
those properties are
calculated in conjunction with
one another, in order to set an
element's dimensions.
Let's take a look at each of
these properties in turn.
First, we have the content of
the box, which is where the
text and images are located,
and it looks
something like this.
Next, we have the padding, which
clears the area around
the content.
We have the border, which goes
around both the padding and
the content.
And then finally, we have the
margin, which clears the area
around the border.
Using what we just learned about
the CSS box model, let's
calculate the width
of this box.
Now you'll recognize the border
margin and padding
properties , but that width
property is there, and it's
specifying a 300-pixel width.
Now you might ask, why are we
going to try and determine the
width of this box if the
width is already there?
Well, the width is affected
by those three previous
properties.
Let's take a look at how.
First up, we can see that this
300-pixel width actually
represents the content
of the box.
Then, we have a 10-pixel
padding, which is 10 pixels of
padding on all sides.
And since we're trying to
calculate the width here, we
need to add up the left and
right values to get 20 pixels.
Next, we have the border,
which is two
pixels on all sides.
And again, we're trying to
calculate the left and right
value to get the width,
so we add those
up to get four pixels.
And then finally, we have the
margin of 20 pixels on all
sides that we add up on the left
and right to get a value
of 40 pixels.
Now, the total width is actually
only determined by
the content, the padding,
and the border.
The margin only affects
the elements that are
outside of the box.
So it's not taken into
account in the width.
When we add up each of those
values, the 300-pixel content,
the 20-pixel padding, and the
four-pixel border, we get a
total of 324 pixels.
Now again, the box sizing
property is used to change the
way that that default
CSS box model works.
So let's look at each of
the different values.
For the box sizing property,
we can specify content-box,
padding-box, or border-box.
First up, we have content-box,
which is the default value,
and that's exactly what
we just looked at.
The width and the height are
only measured by including the
content, but it does not
include the border, the
margin, or the padding.
Padding-box is a little bit
different, and the width and
height include the padding
as the name implies.
But it does not include the
border or the margin.
Let's see how that property
affects our box that we looked
at earlier.
When we add the padding-box
value to the box-sizing
property, the padding is now
taken into account within the
width property.
Now what does that do to
the content width?
Well, it's actually
280 pixels.
We're deducting the size
of the padding.
However, the border and the
margin exist outside of that
total width.
So the calculated width of our
box is 304 pixels, down from
324 pixels.
The final value that we can
specify for the box sizing
property is border-box.
The width and the height will
now include both the padding
and the border, but still
not the margin.
Let's see how this
affects our box.
If we add the border box value,
to our box sizing
property, the padding and the
border are now taken into
account within the
width property.
So the content area is
actually 276 pixels.
We're deducting both the
20-pixel padding and the four
pixels of border.
And now, since the margin is
still never included in that
total width, the calculated
width is 300 pixels.
[SIGH] Man.
Addition, subtraction,
that stuff is hard.
But hopefully, the challenges
aren't nearly as bad.
We'll see you in the
next section.