We're back with the second
CSS style section.
Let's move on to talk about
multiple backgrounds.
CSS3 gives us the ability to
specify multiple backgrounds
on a particular element.
Those background images are
stacked in the order in which
you specify them.
Let's look at an example here.
So I'm specifying my background
image and I'm
specifying two separate
background images.
So here we have the
first URL -
bg1.png -
and the second URL -
bg2.png.
We separate these two
with a comma.
Next, we specify the background
position for each
of those two images.
The first one is top left, then
we set a comma, and the
second one is center right.
Finally, we specify the
background repeat for each of
those two images.
Each of them are no repeat.
This is what our two background
images look like.
We have the first one on the
left, which again, is stacked
above the second one, because
it was specified first.
And then we have our second
background image on the right
at center bottom.
You can also specify multiple
backgrounds using the
shorthand background property
doing this all on one line.
So here we're specifying the
URL, the background position,
and the background repeat for
the first image with a comma.
Then we specify our second
background image with a
background position and the
background repeat, and we get
the same output.
Moving right along, we have
the color property.
Now, CSS3 gives us
a few different
ways to specify colors.
We can use the RGBa function
or the HSLa function.
Let's look at each
of these in turn.
Now, RGB represents the three
additive primary colors red,
green, and blue.
But in CSS3, we additionally
get the "a" value, or alpha
value, which allows
us to specify the
opacity of a color.
Let's look at a quick
example here.
We're specifying the color
property to have a 75% opaque
black color value.
We do this by specifying 0, 0, 0
as the RG&B values, and that
represents the color of black.
Then we specify the a value, or
alpha, to be 0.75, and that
is 75% opaque black.
Now, HSLa is different
than RGB.
HSL stands for hue, saturation,
and lightness.
And in addition to those three
values, we can also specify
the a value, which is the alpha
value to represent the
opacity of a color.
Let's look at an example
of the HSLa function.
So here we're specifying a 240
hue value, 100% saturation
value, a 50% lightness value,
and then, finally, that 0.75
alpha value -
so 75% of the color.
When choosing between HSLa and
RGBa, it's important to point
out that HSLa is generally
more intuitive than RGBa,
because it's easier to make
color adjustments on the fly.
However, use whichever color
utility you're most
comfortable with.
And if you want to learn more
about HSL and RGB, take our
Fundamentals of Design course.
Next up, we're going to talk
about the opacity property
specifically.
CSS3 allows you to specify the
opacity, or transparency, of
an element using the
opacity property.
So let's look at an example.
Here, we're specifying the
opacity property to be 0.45.
The 0.45 value here represents
a 45% opaque color value,
which is essentially just
affecting the transparency of
the element.
If we apply that 0.45 opacity
value to our image here, we
can see it gets an opacity
value of 45%.
Now, it's also important to
note that the opacity on a
given element affects the
elements nested inside of it.
Let's look at an example.
So let's say that I had this div
with a class of element on
it, and then an h2
inside of that.
If I was to specify a background
on that element and
then adjust the opacity value
setting at 0.45 value, like we
just did, it would affect both
the text and the image.
If I was to apply a background
and an opacity value of 0.45
on that element, it would affect
both the image and the
text, as seen here.
We'll wrap up this level
on CSS3 styles by
talking about gradients.
CSS3 gives us the ability to
create gradients, which are
smooth transitions between
two or more colors.
There are two main types
of gradients
that browsers support -
linear gradients and
radial radians.
We'll start by covering
linear gradients.
In order to create a linear
gradient, we specify the
starting point, the ending
point, and then
optional color stops.
Let's look at an example.
So here I'm specifying a
linear gradient on the
background property by using the
linear gradient function.
In that function, I'm passing
different values.
And the output of that
looks like this.
Let's examine how each
of these values work.
First, we're going to specify
the direction of the gradient
through either an angle
or a keyword.
Now, the angle is generally
going to be a degree, so
something like 45 degrees.
The key word is going to consist
of the word "to"
followed by a side-or-corner,
which also consists of two key
words: horizontal values of left
or right, and vertical
values of top or bottom.
Now, the last thing that we need
to specify for our linear
gradient are color stops.
We'll specify one or more color
stops that consist of a
color and an optional
stop-position, that can either
be a link or a percentage.
Going back to our initial linear
gradient example, you
can see that we're not setting
an angle value, but we are
specifying the side-or-corner
to be "to bottom", which is
going to make the gradient go
from the top to the bottom.
Now, how's it doing that?
Well, it's important to note
that the keywords "to top," "to
bottom", "to right", and "to
left" correspond to specific
degree values.
Those are 0 degrees,
180 degrees, 270
degrees, and 90 degrees.
So our keyword "to bottom" is
actually translated into 180
degrees, as seen here.
The first color stop we specify
is red, which is where
the top of the gradient
starts.
And then the second and last
color stop we specify is
yellow, and that's where
the gradient
will end at the bottom.
Now, a radial gradient is
different than a linear
gradient, because it extends
from an origin, the center of
the element, and it extends
outward in either a circular
or elliptical shape.
A radial grading consists of
three different parts--
the center, the ending shape
contour and position, and,
finally, color stops - just
like we specified for the
linear gradient.
So now, let's look
at a real simple
example of a radial gradient.
So here, we're specifying two
color stops - aqua and blue -
and we can see what the
output looks like.
This creates a two-color
elliptical gradient that
extends outward from the
center of the element.
Now, let's look more in depth at
each of the values that we
can pass in to the radial
gradient function.
First, you specify the shape
or size of the gradient.
The shape of the gradient can
either be a circle or an
ellipsis. The default of
which is an ellipsis.
The size of the gradient
consists of keywords, and
those keywords are
"closest-side,"
"closest-corner,"
"farthest-side," and
"farthest-corner."
Now, "farthest-corner" here is
the default value, if we don't
pass one in.
Additionally, you can actually
change the size to be of
length or a percentage.
Next, we specify the position of
the radial gradient, using
the "at" keyword, followed
by the position.
The default for this is center,
but you can specify
any value you can use for the
background position property.
Finally, we specify one or
more color stops, which
again, consist of a color and
an optional stop-position,
which can either be a length
or a percentage.
So now, let's look at an example
of a radial gradient.
So here we're specifying a
radial gradient function on
the background property.
We first set the shape of the
gradient to be circle, rather
than ellipsis.
Next, we set the position of the
gradient to be top left,
so it's going to start
up at the top left.
Next, we specify the first color
stop, which is aqua, and
then we specify the last color
stop, which is blue.
Here, we can see the output
of that radial gradient.
We have a two-color circular
radial gradient that extends
outward from the top left.
That's it for Level Four.
You now know all the
new CSS3 styles.
Have fun using them
in the challenges.
[In the back] One pixels.
Move it one pixels.
[INAUDIBLE] the limiges -
The limiges?
The limiges are located.
The color of the drop shadow,
in this case - zero.
The color zero.
Color zero.