Now that we've got
a handle on how
to start working
with storyboards,
let's build the first
screen in our application--
the product screen.
This screen is going to
display an image that's
going to have a label with
the name of the phone on top
of that, and there's going
to be an add to cart button.
Let's jump back into
Xcode to set this up.
Before we try to connect up a
Swift file to the storyboard,
let's delete this default
scene that the project gave us
when we selected single
view application template.
We can delete this
view in the storyboard
by clicking the View Controller
Scene and then hitting Delete.
And we can also delete the
autogenerated ViewController
dot Swift file by right clicking
on it and choosing Delete
and then selecting
move to trash.
We can add a new view
controller to our storyboard
by dragging from the object
panel to the storyboard editor.
The object panel is
at the bottom right
corner of the
screen and contains
a list of all of the
objects and views
that you can place
in a storyboard.
View Controller is the
very first one in the list,
so we'll click and drag
that view controller object
onto the storyboard
editor, and we
can see that it creates
a new scene for us,
complete with a view.
There's another
option that we have
to check because we
created this from scratch,
and that's Is Initial
View Controller, which
you can find in the Attributes
panel of the Inspector.
Checking this makes
this view the one
that opens up whenever
this app runs.
We'll also want to go into the
first page of the Inspector
panel, which opens up
the file inspector.
And in here we'll want
to disable Size Classes.
We get a Warning that we have
to confirm before disabling.
This is because a
fully completed app
that runs on both
iPhone and iPad
would be using Size Classes.
But right now, it will be a lot
easier for us to learn together
without Size Classes
turned on because they
add a lot of complexity
to layout in an app.
We recommend
ignoring Size Classes
when you're first
learning iOS development
and picking them up later.
If we disable Size Classes,
now the storyboard scene
looks a lot more like the
dimensions of a normal iPhone.
We'll make one more
change here by going back
into the Inspector
panel, and we'll
set the simulated metric
size of this view controller
to 4.7 inches.
The default setting of
inferred was actually
displaying a view size
for the four inch iPhones,
not the 4.7 inch screen
that the iPhone 6S has.
Now let's jump back
into some slides
to see what we need to do next.
Now that our product
ViewController is set up,
we need to add a label, image,
and button to the main view.
Whenever we put views
inside of the main view,
we refer to them as subviews.
So let's jump back
into Xcode now
and add some of those subviews.
Let's start building
out this main view
by dragging a label
from the object panel.
We can either
search by scrolling
or just type in the
search bar at the bottom,
and it will update the list
to show us only the views that
match our search term.
As we click and drag the
label onto the main view,
you'll notice some
dotted blue lines appear.
They appear on the very left and
very right edges of the view,
and they also
appear in the center
to help you try
to center objects.
We'll drop this label right
in the middle of the screen.
We can set the text for
this label in the Attributes
Inspector, and here we'll type
1937 Desk Phone and hit Return.
When we do that, you can
see that our label text got
truncated down with three dots.
The reason this is
happening is that the width
of the label in the
storyboard is not big enough
to hold all of the text.
So since we know we want
this button to be centered,
we can just grab these anchors
on the sides of the label
and drag them all the way out
to the left and right edges.
Then, back in the
attributes inspector,
we can center the label text.
That font doesn't look
too exciting, either,
so we can change the font
properties by clicking
on the small T icon
next to the font name,
and instead of
using a system font
we can choose a custom font.
Here we'll use Damascus.
Set the style to bold and
up the size to 24 points,
and then hit done.
As you can see, the very top
line of the text looks cut off.
So we can drag the
labels height to make
it a little bigger so everything
is able to be displayed.
Now let's add an image
to our main view.
The object that displays an
image is called an Image View.
We can search for Image
View in the object panel,
then we'll click and drag
it onto our main view.
Notice that I'm not specifically
placing it anywhere yet.
The reason for that is
we need to actually add
the image file to
our Xcode project
before we can put it
inside of an Image View.
Images in Xcode
projects are stored
in something called
an asset catalog,
and every project
by default gets
an Assets dot XCassets file.
If we click on that asset
catalog in the project
navigator, you can see there's
not much in here right now.
You can add assets
to the catalog
by clicking the Plus button that
appears in the second column
and choosing import from
the menu that pops up.
We've created a folder called
Image Files on our desktop
that will contain
some of the images
we'll be using in this course.
You can see there's two
images currently in here,
so you can drag and
select both to import them
both at the same time.
Then hit Open and they'll
be added to the project.
The first is called
button dash add to cart,
and the second is called
phone dash full screen 3,
and that's the image
we'll use right now.
Now back in main dot
storyboard file, make sure
we've selected the Image View
from the storyboard scene
navigator, and then in
the Attributes panel
we can see the first
option for the image
view is a field called Image.
If we click on the
drop down, we'll
get a list of any images that
are in our asset catalog.
So we'll pick the phone
full screen 3.
When we do that, it
doesn't quite look right.
The reason for this is that
the image view container
is one size, but the image we're
trying to display is another.
We can fix this by clicking
on the image in the Image
View-- you'll know that it's
selected because everything
around it gets grayed out-- and
then going to the editor menu
and choosing Size
to Fit Content.
This updates the
image view to be
the exact size of the image
displayed inside of it.
We can click on the Image View
object again so it's selected,
and then we can click
and drag the Image View
so that it fits perfectly
inside of our main view.
There's one other
little problem,
though-- our label
just disappeared.
This is because we put the
image view on top of the label
so it's completely obscuring it.
To fix this, just
rearrange the position
of the label and Image View in
the storyboard scene navigator.
Click and hold the Image
View and move it up
one spot so that the label
object is below the Image View
object.
And now the label
appears on top.
Finally, let's add a
button to this interface.
Since we already have
the storyboard open,
we can just search for
button in the object panel.
We want the first button
that comes up in the list,
and we'll click and drag it to
the center of the main view.
We could just put some
text for this button,
but our designers have created
a custom button image that
fits the theme really well.
Over in the
Attributes Inspector,
we can choose the default
image for the button
and pick button add
to cart from the list.
When we do this, you can see
that the original default
text for the button is
sitting on the right.
So again, in the
attribute panel,
we can highlight
that default text,
hit delete, and hit Enter.
Now we've got a
sharp looking button.
Let's build and run our app
to see what this looks like.
And there you have it.
Our very first product
screen laid out
in a storyboard
that's displaying
great in the simulator.
Now it's your turn to
create some subviews
and take some challenges.
Remember, if you're
following along
in your own copy
of Xcode, you can
download all of the image
assets that we showed you
in this level.
Have fun.