[SINGING] Starting back
in the machine age,
the telephone had
just taken the stage.
No one predicted
it's acceleration,
evolving all of
our communication.
Today we build with
storyboard, use Xcode projects
where they're stored.
Controllers with scroll
navigating, tables, outlets,
actions, buttons, and labels.
To code a phone is a learned
gift with the App Evolution
with Swift.
Welcome back to App
Evolution with Swift.
Our product view controller
is in a really good place,
so we're going to switch gears
and work on a different screen
for our contact view.
Now, that contact view is
going to contain more content
than can fit on the device.
So we're going to add
a scroll view that
allows for stretching beyond
the bottom of the device screen,
and scrolling up and down.
Scroll views look a
lot like a normal view
except for one thing.
If you have subviews
that are outside
of the visible
screen on the device,
you can scroll up and
down, left and right,
or both to see all
of the content.
Now, the scroll view is still
a subview of the main view,
but all of the rest of
the subviews on the screen
go inside of the scroll view.
So let's jump into Xcode,
and create our contact screen
in a scroll view.
To get started creating
our scroll view,
we're going to create a brand
new view controller scene
called contact view controller.
We'll search for a view
controller in the object panel.
And slide our storyboard
to the right a little bit,
so we've got some
more empty room.
Then we'll click and drag on
the view controller object,
and place it on the
storyboard editor.
We've also got the
assistant editor still open,
so let's turn that off by
clicking on the first icon
to turn the standard
editor back on.
Now we've got a full
view of the storyboard.
We'll go back into
the attributes panel,
and set the size to
4.7, so that it matches
the product view controller.
Let's also go ahead and
create the Swift file
for this view controller too.
We'll click on the
project folder,
then right click
and choose New File.
Then Cocoa Touch Class from
the iOS Source section,
and click Next.
For the name of this
view controller,
we'll call it the
Contact View Controller.
Make sure it's a
UI View Controller,
and that the language is Swift.
And we'll save it in our
project folder like before.
And also like before, we'll
delete all that boilerplate
code, except for the
view Did Load function.
Back in the storyboard, we'll
click on the view controller.
Open up the class page
of the inspector panel,
and set the name to
Contact View Controller.
Now let's go back
into the object panel
and search for scroll
view, and drag it
into the view controller.
We'll make this view full
screen by grabbing the anchors
and adjusting the
width and height,
so that it takes
up the entire width
and height of the main view.
Now we're ready to start loading
content into the scroll view.
First, let's head over
to the asset catalog,
and add some new images that
we'll use on this screen.
In the asset catalog,
we click the + button
at the bottom of the
panel, choose Import.
And on our desktop, in
our image files folder,
we've added a few more images.
One for the header,
and three icons
we can use in the
context section.
Back in our storyboard
let's look for an image view
in the object panel.
And we'll drag that to
inside of the scroll view.
Set the image for that image
view in the Attributes panel,
choosing the image
header contact.
Then we'll click inside
of the image view,
so the image is selected.
And choose Editor,
Size to Fit Content.
Click out of the image,
and click and drag
the image view into place
at the top of the screen.
Now let's grab a label and
drag it onto the scroll view,
and expand the
width to both edges.
We'll center the text, change
the font from System to Custom.
And use Damascus again,
setting the style to bold,
and the size to 24.
We'll also set the text to ABOUT
US, in all capital letters.
And then we'll adjust
the height of the label,
so we can see all of the text.
Now let's drag in another label.
But this label we're not
going to make full width,
we're going to leave
some space on both sides.
And we'll set the alignment
to Justify instead of Center.
Our copywriter has
given us some text
that we can input into our
app for the About Us page.
So let's grab the
first line and copy it
with Command-C,
and back in Xcode,
paste it with Command-V into
the label's text attribute.
You can see that
the storyboard is
trying to fit all of
that text onto one line.
Even if we increase the
height of that label box,
it's still going to
fit all on one line.
Strangely enough, the way
you support multiple lines
on a label is to set the
number of lines to zero.
If we flip the number of
lines from one to zero,
now all of the text fits
across multiple lines.
We can tighten up the
label's width and height,
so it's not using any
more space than is needed.
For this font, instead
of using the system font,
we'll change it to Custom.
Use Iowan Old Style, with the
Roman style for the family.
And we'll drop it
down to 16 points,
and readjust the anchor
so the text fits nicely.
Rather than create
a brand new label
for the next block
of text, let's
just duplicate the one we have
since all of the attributes
will be the same.
We can click on the
label, and hit Command-D,
and that will create a
duplicate that we can just
move below the first label.
You can see that the
storyboard is even
drawing some of those blue
anchor lines on the screen
to show how
everything is aligned.
We'll go back over to
our copywriter text,
copy the second line with
Command-C. Go back into Xcode,
select the text in
the attributes panel.
Hit Command-V to paste it
in, and then hit Return.
For the last label
we'll do the same thing.
Click on the label,
hit Command-D,
line it up into place.
Go back into the About
Us Copy, select the text,
hit Command-C to copy.
Back in Xcode highlight
the label text,
hit Command-V to
paste, and hit Return.
Since this text is only one line
we can bump the number of lines
back up to one.
We'll also change the font
properties from Roman style
to Italic, and drop
the size down to 14.
Then we'll scroll the
storyboard down a bit,
and drag the bottom
label anchor up,
so it's not taking
up too much space.
Let's even make the bottom
label a little bit closer
to the middle label.
Now let's duplicate the About Us
header, and drag it down here.
And change the text to
say CONTACT, in full caps.
If we want to add some icons
to this contact section,
we can start by searching
for an image view object,
and drag it onto
the scroll view.
We'll set the image for that
image view to icon-about-email.
We'll select the image,
like we've done before,
and choose Editor,
Size to Fit Content.
Then we'll click
out of the image,
so we can pick it up
and drag it into place.
We can drag another
label in, setting it
to a custom font using
Iowan Old Style text.
Drop the text size down to 13,
and for the text we'll write
good-as-old@example.com .
We can stretch out the email
address label so it all fits.
And now we have a
little bit of a problem.
We want to be able to add
two more images, and two more
labels for the phone number
and website for our store,
but we don't have any more
room in our scroll view.
We've reached the
very bottom of it.
We could try to make
the scroll view taller,
but the main view isn't
going to get taller.
So we still wouldn't be
able to drag and drop
more stuff in the storyboard.
One way to fix this
is a little weird.
We can take the scroll view
object, which is currently
a subview of the main view, and
we can click and drag it out
of the view
controller hierarchy,
and down below, so that it's
still part of the contact view
controller scene, but it's
not part of the contact view
controller main view.
As you can see, the
contact view controller
is still in the
storyboard editor,
but up above there's a new
associated view that looks just
like our scroll view.
We can't even pick this
up and move it around,
it's, sort of, locked into
place above the contact view
controller.
What that enables us to do
is click on the scroll view,
and go into the Inspector
panel's fifth page, which
is the size inspector.
Let's scroll down to the bottom
so we can see this changing.
As we click on
the Height button,
we can see the height
getting bigger and bigger.
If we hold the
button down we keep
increasing the height
of the scroll view,
or we can just key in
the value that we want.
It seems like 800 is going
to give us enough space
to put all of our content.
Now we'll go duplicate the icon
in the contact section three
times, and duplicate
the label three times.
And then change the images
for the two new icons
back in the Attributes
panel to icon-about-phone,
and icon-about-website.
We'll also change our label
text for both the phone
number, and website.
And we can even select and move
all of those labels and images,
so that it looks a little
more centered than before.
Now what we need to do is, still
with our scroll view selected,
go back into the size
inspector, and change it
to what it was before.
The main view height for
an iPhone 6s is 667 points,
so we can enter that.
And now it looks like our
content is gone, but it's not,
it's just, sort of,
hiding below the scroll.
Next, we can create
a scroll view outlet
to the contact view controller.
So we'll select our contact
view controller object,
turn the assistant
editor back on.
And then Control-Click and
drag from the scroll view
down to the
ContactViewController code,
and let go.
We'll call this
outlet scroll View,
and we'll actually change the
storage from Strong to Weak.
Every time we have
a subview that's
going to be attached to
a controller's main view,
we can mark that
subview as a Weak.
Then we hit Connect,
and now we have
an outlet to our scroll view
that's in our contact view
controller scene.
One last step.
We'll click on the contact view
controller in the storyboard,
and click Is Initial
View Controller,
so that this view is
the one that displays
when we build and run the app.
Now let's see how we can connect
the scroll view to the contact
view controller with
code, back in the slides.
Our scroll view and subviews
are all set up properly,
but we've got another problem.
Our scroll view
isn't showing up when
we build and run our app
because the scroll view is not
a subview of the main view.
Since we have an outlet to the
scroll view in the storyboard,
we can fix that pretty easily
by typing view.addSubview,
and passing it that
scrollView variable
between the parentheses.
This attaches the scroll view
to the main view hierarchy,
and thus the scroll
view and everything else
that's in it can now be seen.
And there it is, but wait,
we're still not scrolling.
Well, that's because we've
set the scroll view's frame,
but not the content size.
So the scroll view doesn't
know how much content
it should try to display.
We need to explicitly tell
the scroll view how wide,
and how high the content
is that's inside of it.
The place to do this is another
view controller function
that runs after viewDidLoad,
called viewWillLayoutSubviews.
Anytime you're changing the
size of a subview with code,
you should do it
in this function.
Inside of that function, we'll
set the scroll view's content
size equal to the output of
a function called CGSizeMake.
CGSizeMake creates
a CGsize struct,
and that's what the
content size property
is expecting to receive.
So it all works out.
The content size needs to be
bigger than the frame, which
was 667 for the iPhone 6s.
We used 800 before when
we were laying things out
on the storyboard, so
we'll use that again here.
And now you can see we've got
a working scroll view that
displays all of our
content, and allows
us to scroll up and
down to see things that
don't fit on the device screen.
Now it's time for you to create
a scroll view in your project,
and take some challenges.
And I'll see you
in the next level.