[MUSIC PLAYING]
Starting back in
the machine age,
the telephone had
just taken the stage.
No one predicted
its acceleration,
evolving all of
our communication.
Today we build with storyboards,
use Xcode projects where
they're stored, controllers
with scroll, navigating tables,
outlets, actions,
buttons, and labels.
To code a phone is a learned
gift with the App Evolution
with Swift.
Welcome back to App
Evolution with Swift.
In this level, we'll
look at how to display
lists of data in tables.
Dropping labels and image views
directly onto the main view
makes sense to
display our content
until we have something that
would naturally appear better
in a list, like
this list of phones.
In this case, it
makes more sense
to use a table view
instead of a normal view,
and we'll hook that up to a
table view controller instead
of a normal view controller.
A table view controller is
just a special view controller
object that has
support for working
with table views built in.
The main view of a
table view controller
is a special object
called table view,
and table views have subviews
just like view controllers do,
but those subviews are
called table cells.
Any normal subviews
like labels and image
views then go inside
of those table cells.
So let's jump back into Xcode
to create our first table view
controller.
To start, we'll turn
off the assistant editor
and go back into
standard editor mode,
and we'll scroll over so we
have some more room to work.
Then we'll create
a brand new scene
using a table view controller
instead of a regular view
controller.
Set the size from
inferred to 4.7 inches,
and line it up a bit next to
the first view controller.
We'll also make sure it's
the initial view controller
so that we'll see it when
we build and run the app.
Now let's click on the good
as old phones folder, right
click and choose New
File, and, again,
we'll use the Cocoa Touch Class
in the iOS source section.
Hit next, but this time,
instead of subclassing
UI View Controller, we'll
subclass UI Table View Controller,
and we'll name this class
Products Table View Controller.
We don't need to create a XIB
file because we've already
got that in our
storyboard, and we'll
keep the language as Swift.
Then we'll hit Next, save
it in our project folder,
and you'll notice there's a ton
of boilerplate code in table
view controllers.
We're not going to need most
of this for this course,
so let's just delete all of
it so we can start fresh.
Don't forget to leave that
last curly brace because it
closes out the class.
Back in the main
storyboard, we'll
click on the table
view controller scene
and go into the class
inspector, and set our class
to products table view
controller and hit return.
And now the storyboard
table view controller
is associated with our
products table view
controller Swift file.
We need to do one more
thing now, though.
You can see that there's already
a prototype cell in this table
view.
If we click it to select it and
look at the attributes panel,
you'll see there's a
field labeled identifier.
We want to set that
identifier to product cell,
and that's going to let
us access this prototype
cell in our Swift file.
Let's jump back in the slides
to talk about reuse identifiers
and how dynamic cells work.
Table cells are recycled
as they scroll off screen,
and the only new cells
that ever get created
are the very first ones as
the table view first loads.
Every other cell that's
created after that
is just pulled out of
that recycling queue.
Let's take a look
at how this works.
On load, three new
cells are created.
We've labeled them A, B, and C.
As the tableview scrolls a
bit, now four unique cells
are visible.
The original A,B, and
C, but also cell D.
So in our application's memory,
there's four cells loaded.
Then, after some more scrolling,
cell A is no longer visible.
But rather than completely
removing it from memory,
it gets placed in
this recycling queue.
On screen, only cells
B, C, and D are visible.
After even more scrolling, a new
cell is ready to be displayed,
but there's no need to create
a brand new cell object
because the recycled cell
A can just be reused.
At the end here, there's still
only four cells in memory,
even though our table view has
displayed a total of five cells
with different content.
This is a simple
example, but think
of a table view in
something like the music
app, where you might have
300 or 400 rows of albums.
It wouldn't be memory efficient
to load all 300 of those cells
into memory, so this
recycling approach
makes sure that there's only
a few cells that are ever
created and just recycled
with new content and new data
as the table scrolls.
It's really memory efficient.
Because these
cells get recycled,
unlike normal view controllers
the content for a table cell
needs to be set in code.
UI table view controller is like
a view controller with table
specific functions,
and two of those
that we'll use and
are automatically
run for us are the
functions table view
number of rows in
section and table view
cell for row at index path.
The first sets the number
of rows in the table view,
and the second is
responsible for creating
one cell for each row.
This function looks really
long, so let's break apart
what it means.
First is the name of the
function-- table view,
and there's
parentheses after it.
Inside of those parentheses
are two parameters
as variables, which are then
available inside of the body
of the function so we can
use them if we need them.
The variables
tableview and section.
The arrow Int at the end
means that the function
should return a number.
Now, you might have
noticed something strange
about these two functions--
they both have the same name,
table view.
But they're actually
different functions
because they have different
parameter names inside
of the function declaration.
The first one has the parameter
names table view and number
of rows in section,
and the second
has the parameters table view
and cell for row at index path.
Because of that, they're
different functions
and they perform
different operations.
Back in the table
view number of rows
in section version
of the function,
we need to return an Int.
So if we start simple
and do just that we
can write return 5 in
the body of this function,
and that means this table
view will have five rows.
Now on to our second
table view function.
The cell for row
at index path one.
This function runs one time
for each number of rows
that we set in the function
above, which was five.
Based on the arrow at
the end of the function,
we can see this one should
return a UI table view cell
object.
We can create the cell by
writing this line of code,
which looks at the storyboard
for any prototype cells
with the reuse identifier
of product cell,
and then creates a cell
object when it finds one.
Remember that we set that
reuse identifier back in Xcode.
Then we can just return our
new cell from the function.
Now we've got our code in
the table view controller
to create five rows and five
cells to go in those rows.
But if we build
and run right now,
our table view is
a bit confusing.
It looks like it's showing
way more than five rows,
but that's not accurate.
It's a little bit
easier to see what's
going on by stopping the app,
clicking on the table view,
and in the attribute
inspector changing the style
from plain to grouped.
When we do that, we can
even see that the prototype
cell looks a bit different.
It looks like the row is
isolated with grey above
and below it.
Now when we build and
run the app again,
we can clearly see that the
table view has five cells.
They don't look like
much yet, but before we
go any further, why don't you
practice creating some cells
and take some
challenges, and I'll
see you in the next section.