Welcome back.
Now that we've got
some cells, we're
going to put some
content inside of them.
UI table view cells actually come
preloaded with a few subviews
that we don't even have to
wire up in the storyboard.
They're already wired up for us.
One is called image
view, and it can
be used to display a small image
in the left side of the cell.
Another is called
text label, and it's
a UI label that
stretches across the rest
of the length of the cell.
We can create the
cell by writing
this line of code
here, which looks
at the storyboard
for any prototype
cells with a reuse
identifier of products cell
and then creates a cell
object when it finds one.
Now you might have
noticed that we're
creating this variable
with let instead of var.
If you have a
variable where you're
going to change it
after it's been created,
you want to use var.
But if not, you want
to use let, because it
makes the variable immutable.
So let's try setting
the cell's textLabel
dot text property
to Hello friend.
If we try that though, we get
an error that looks like this.
What's going on here?
Let's take a look at the docs
for the UI table view cell
to find out.
When we do that, we'll
see something interesting.
The text label property in the
cell isn't just a UI label.
It's a UI label with a
question mark after it.
That question mark means
that this label is optional.
It may or may not exist.
So what would that
mean if the text label
property didn't exist?
That would mean you'd
still have a cell object.
The text label property
wouldn't exist,
which means the text property
of it wouldn't exist.
So trying to set it
would crash the app.
This could actually
happen, because it's
possible to create a custom cell
that doesn't have a text label
property.
That's why Swift has a way
to mark types as optional.
It's a way to say the data
could or could not exist.
Because the text
labels optional,
we first have to check if
it exists before we try
to set the text property on it.
The one way we can do that
is with a conditional.
We can just check if
cell dot textLabel is not nil,
then set the text.
There's an even better
way to write this
without using a conditional
using something called
optional chaining.
And that looks like this.
We just write cell dot textLabel
with a question mark after it dot text equals
a string.
Adding that question mark
after an optional property
means first check
if this exists.
If it does exist, we'll continue
running this line of code
in setting the text.
And if it doesn't exist, we'll
stop running the line of code
right there thus
avoiding a crash.
If we put that updated code back
in our cell creation function,
we can see that we've now
got five cells that all
have the text Hello friend.
The cells image view
property is also optional.
So we can set it the same
way by adding a question
mark after the
image view property,
then we just set that image
property to a UI image
named something that matches
an image in our asset catalog.
Here we're setting
it to image-cell1,
because that's something we
just added to our asset catalog.
And you can see the result here.
Now let's jump back
into Xcode really quick
to see how we can customize
cells in the storyboard.
We can actually adjust some
properties of the prototype
cell from the storyboard.
For example, if we
click on the cell,
we can click and drag
the anchor at the bottom
to make the height
of the cell bigger.
We'll set it to 100
points high and that
should let the
cell image display
in it's full resolution.
If we build and
run again, now you
can see that the cell
height is changed
and the image fits nicely
in there without resizing.
So why don't you try displaying
some dynamic data in your cells
and take some challenges, and
I'll see you in the next level.