Welcome back to App
Evolution with Swift.
In this level,
we're going to look
at how we can link views
and buttons up to code.
We've already got a
label displaying text,
and an image view displaying
an image in our storyboard.
But we want to be able to
set those values in code.
We also want to make the
button respond to being tapped.
The place we're going
to write that code
is in a view controller.
You might have noticed
in the storyboard
that the main view is embedded
inside of a view controller.
The reason for having
a controller object
separate from a view object is
that you can separate program
logic from the display of data.
This is commonly referred to
as MVC, model view controller.
Separating these two
out makes code easier
to understand than just having
all of it in one big file.
View controllers can tell
a view what to display,
and then views can
tell controllers
when the user is
interacting with them.
We've got to do a
little bit of setup
in the storyboard to connect the
view controller to Swift code,
so let's jump back into
Xcode and get that set up.
Let's create our
first Swift file
so we can write code
to change the label
text, the image
displayed, and that we
can use to respond to
taps on the button.
To start, click on the folder
name in the project navigator.
Right click on it,
and choose New File.
In this list of file
templates that come up,
we'll want to make sure we're
looking at the iOS source
section.
And you might think we want
the Swift file template,
but we actually want
Cocoa Touch Class.
Then we hit Next and
we're asked what name
we want for this class.
We'll delete what's there and
type ProductViewController,
and for the subclass we'll
type UIViewController.
We don't need to
create a XIB file,
but we do want to make sure
the language for the project
is set to Swift.
Then when we hit Next,
we're asked where
we want to save this file.
In our default save location
is the project folder,
which is a good
place to save it.
When we hit Create, we'll get
our ProductViewController dot
Swift file.
You'll notice there's
some starter code.
We won't need all of that.
We don't need the
didReceiveMemoryWarning
function or the whole navigation
section at the bottom.
Notice that we are leaving one
curly bracket after the stuff
we're deleting.
This is the closing curly
bracket for that class
that's opened on line 11,
so that one needs to stay.
So we'll highlight both
of those and hit Delete.
When we delete that code,
we've got a really nice start
to the Swift file.
There's one more
step, though-- we
need to associate this
ViewController Swift
file with the view
controller object that's
in the storyboard.
So we'll go back into
the storyboard file,
click on the View Controller
in the scene navigator,
and click on the third page
of the Inspector panel.
In that panel, we'll click
into the class setting
at the top for the custom
class section and type
ProductViewController
and hit Enter.
We can check that it worked
because the scene navigator now
updates to show that the name
changed from ViewController
to ProductViewController.
Now our storyboard
ProductViewController
is linked up with our
ProductViewController dot Swift
file.
To be able to change a subview
in a storyboard with code,
we need to create an outlet.
Outlets are a way
to make a connection
between a storyboard object
and a variable in a Swift file.
Although the main
view was automatically
connected when we
linked our Swift
file to the ViewController
in the storyboard,
all the subviews still need
to be manually connected.
These connections
are called outlets,
and we need to create one
between our ViewController
and label subview so that
the controller can tell
the label what text to show.
Then in the Swift file,
you can create a variable
and mark it as an
outlet there, too.
Remember the controller Swift
file and the storyboard view
controller are
already connected,
but that outlet makes a
connection with the subviews,
as well.
Let's jump back into Xcode to
see how to create an outlet.
To create an outlet
between the Swift file
and storyboard, the
easiest thing to do
is open up the assistant editor.
The icon looks like two
interlocking circles up
in the toolbar.
When we click that
icon, it's kind of
hard to read what's
on the screen.
The default layout is
to have the storyboard
on the left and the associated
Swift file on the right.
We're going to
change that, though,
by clicking on the
tiny drop down arrow
and setting the assistant
editor to appear on the bottom.
Now it's easier to see
the storyboard scene
navigator and editor, and
the Swift file down below.
Next we'll click on the label in
the scene navigator and control
click from that label
down to the Swift file,
right in between the class line
and the viewDidLoad function.
When we let go of
the mouse button,
another little helper pops up.
We want to create an outlet, so
the first default is correct.
It's happening on the Product
View Controller object,
and we need a name that will
become a variable in the Swift
file that we can use to access
the label in the storyboard.
This name could be anything,
but it's a good idea
to name it something obvious.
So here we'll use the
name productNameLabel.
The type is a
UILabel-- that just
has to match the type of the
object in the storyboard--
and the storage should
be left as Weak.
Then when you hit
Connect the outlet code
gets automatically
generated for you,
and you see a darkened in
circle to the left of the line
numbers.
That means the
outlet is connected.
We're going to make one
more change here, though.
Instead of putting
the name of this phone
inside of the label
in the storyboard,
we're going to go back
into the Attributes panel
and we're going to change
the text to Phone Name.
That way, we'll know for sure
if setting the name of the phone
and code works because if
the text when we're done
is different from
phone and name,
we know we successfully
changed the text from code.
Here's what
ProductViewController
dot Swift looks like after
we create that outlet.
Now we can access
our storyboard label
in the controller with
the name productNameLabel.
But where do we write code that
will change the label's text?
To answer that, let's look at
what happens when an app runs.
You might have noticed
a file in your project
that was automatically created
called AppDelegate dot swift.
That runs a function
called UIApplicationMain
that actually starts your app.
Once the app starts, it
looks for a file called
Info dot plist, which is also
automatically created for you,
and that Info dot
plist file is where
the name of the
storyboard file is set.
Next, the storyboard loads
the view controller that's
set as the initial
ViewController,
then that View Controller
loads its view,
and loading that
view automatically
runs the viewDidLoad function.
And we'll set the text
for the label inside
of that viewDidLoad function.
We can do it like this-- by
writing productNameLabel dot
text and setting it
equal to a string, which
is just some characters
or numbers in quotes.
We can do this because the
type of the label variable
is UI label, and UI labels
have a property called text
that we can set to change
the text of the label.
But how did we know that UI
labels have this property?
If you want to check
out what properties you
can set for each
type of object, you
can check out Apple's
official documentation.
Here's one item from the Swift
documentation for UI label.
Docs show properties and
functions for each class.
The colon string here means that
the text property is expecting
us to assign a string to it.
It's impossible to remember
every property of every class
in UI Kit, so you
end up referencing
the documentation a lot
when you're building an app.
When we build and
run our app, we
see that our text
did, in fact, change.
Remember in our storyboard, we
just set some placeholder text,
but our Swift file
code overwrote that.
Now let's jump back into
Xcode and do the same thing
with an image.
Still in our
assistant editor view
where the storyboard
is at the top
and the code is at the
bottom, let's click
on the Image View in
the scene navigator,
and control click and
drag from the image view
object down to the Swift file
in between the first outlet
and the viewDidLoad function.
We get a little helper
like we did before.
This is, again, an outlet on
the Product View Controller.
For the name this time,
we'll use productImageView,
the type is a UIImageView, and
the storage will be Weak again.
Now we've got another outlet,
this time connecting the Image
View to a variable in code.
Like before, when we wanted
to test if this was working,
we deleted the label text.
So we'll go into the Inspector
panel for the image view,
highlight the image name,
delete it, and hit Return.
Now there's no image
set in this view
controller in the storyboard.
So we're going to have to
be able to set it in code.
Let's jump back into slides
to see how to do that.
Just like before, our
controller Swift file now
has a property for
accessing the Image View,
and we can set the image
property of that Image View
to a new UIImage
object, and we'll
pass in the string phone
dash full screen 3
for the name of that image.
Let's look at how the
UIImage class works.
Writing the name of a
class with parentheses
after it, like we did here,
runs an initializer function,
and that initializer function
returns a UIImage object.
Here in the documentation
for UIImage,
you can see there's
an init function.
That init function
is expecting you
to put a string with
the named parameter
inside the parentheses.
This initializer might
look a little confusing
because it looks like it has
two parameters-- named and name.
But you don't actually
have to worry about that.
You just have to know that the
first word, named, is the one
that you'll use when
you're passing a parameter
into the initializer.
When we were sending a label,
we set the text property
equal to a string.
But here we're setting an
Image View's image property
equal to a UIImage object,
and this initializer
returns a UIImage object
that the Image View wants.
And now you can see
that the image is still
appearing even though we turned
it off in the storyboard.
That's because it's
set by our code.
Now you try setting some
text and images in code,
and take some
challenges, and I'll
see you in the next section.