[SINGING] Starting back
in the machine age,
the telephone had
just taken the stage,
no one predicted
its acceleration,
evolving all of our communication.
Today we build with
storyboards, use Xcode
projects where they're stored.
Controllers with scroll,
navigate, and tables.
Outlets, actions,
buttons, and labels.
To code a phone
is a learned gift,
with the App
Evolution with Swift.
Welcome back to App
evolution with Swift.
In this level, we'll
be looking at how
to connect to view
controllers together, and then
transition between them.
We've got a great start
on our table view.
But now it's time
to connect that up
to our product view controller,
so that when we tap on a cell,
we can show some detailed
information about each product.
On the surface, doing
this is pretty simple
and involves something called
a navigation controller.
A navigation controller
manages moving
between any view controllers.
And the way you set it
up is to set one view
controller as the root view
controller for the navigation
stack, and then transition
to any other view controller
with something called a segue.
Yes, that's how that
word pronounced, segue.
And it literally
means to transition
from one thing to another.
So let's jump into Xcode,
add a navigation controller,
and create a segue.
Before we add a
navigation controller,
let's organize our
storyboard a bit.
If we double click
on the background
of the storyboard
editor, it zooms out
so we can see all of our
view controllers at once.
We want to organize
these a bit differently.
We'll take the contact view
controller and move it up.
We'll take the products table
view controller, and move it
all the way to the left.
And take the
product view controller,
and move it to the right of
the table view controller.
Now we'll click on the
products table view controller
again and choose editor, embed
in, navigation controller.
Because our table
view controller
is now in this
navigation controller,
if we connect up segues
between other view controllers,
we'll be able to
transition between them.
We'll scroll a bit so we
can see both controllers.
And we'll right click and
drag from the prototype cell
to the product view controller.
In the segue helper
that comes up,
we'll choose push
segue, which means
we're going to do a push
transition from one view
controller to another.
If we click on that segue,
we can give it a name.
In the attributes inspector,
we'll type Show Product
and hit Enter.
Since that's what the
segue is responsible for,
showing a product.
Now if we build and
run our app, and we
tap on one of those cells,
we see that it pushes over
to the product view controller.
Our segue's working great, so
now let's make a plan of attack
for passing data from the first
view controller to the second.
Every view controller, even
table view controllers,
has a function called
prepare For Segue
that gets called
whenever a segue happens.
We need to override
that function
and pass the product name to
the product view controller
during the segue.
We'll also need to add
a product Name property
to the product view controller
that will store the value when
it gets passed over.
Adding that product Name
property in the product view
controller's Swift
file looks like this.
Note that we made this
variable an optional string,
because any data that we
don't know until the app runs
has to be marked as optional.
Then we'll update the
product Name Label's text
to come from the
product Name variable
instead of just hard
coding a string.
Over in products
table view controller,
we'll add the
prepare For Segue function.
Remember, this function runs
every time a segue happens,
so whenever we tap a cell in
our app, this function will run.
Since there can be multiple
segues in one controller,
we should first check if
the segue's identifier
is Show Product.
Remember when we set the segue
name in the storyboard, here's
where that's paying off.
So inside of this
conditional, we
need a way to capture
the view controller
that we're transitioning
to, so that we can
set the product Name property.
Looking at the documentation
UI Storyboard Segue,
we can see that it
has a property called
destination View Controller.
If we access that
property, we get a copy
of the view controller
we're transitioning to,
which in this case is our
product view controller.
So we can grab a copy of
that product view controller
like this, and assign it to
a variable named product VC.
But that alone is not enough.
destination View Controller
returns a UI View Controller,
but we want Swift to know
that this is specifically
a product View Controller.
We can do that by adding
as Product View Controller
to the end of this statement.
As is a way to convert from
one data type to another.
So here we're trying to
let the compiler know
that our
destination View Controller is
in fact a Product View Controller.
When we do that though, we run
into another little problem,
an error message that says
UI View Controller is not
convertible to
Product View Controller,
did you mean to use
as to force downcast?
That's a crazy error
message, right?
So what's happening
is the compiler
can't just take our
word for it, and be sure
that the
destination View Controller
is a
Product View Controller.
And if it's not sure, it won't
compile your code and run.
That's because if
it guesses wrong,
the app's going to crash.
We can fix this by
again using optionals.
Remember, if we can't be
sure that a value will exist,
it should probably be
marked as optional.
Adding the question mark
to the end of the as word
here returns an optional
Product View Controller,
and stores it in the
product VC variable.
We can use that same question
mark trick from before
by writing product VC
question mark dot product Name
and setting that
equal to a string.
Remember, this means
only set the product Name
if the product VC exists.
If it doesn't exist,
the code won't run
and therefore won't crash.
It's also important to note
that in this scenario,
the segue would still transition
between the view controllers.
We just wouldn't be sending
any extra data along
with the segue.
Now whenever we tap
on a cell, we're
directed to the
product view controller,
and we're shown the
text that we set
in the prepare For Segue method.
This is pretty powerful stuff.
We were able to get one view
controller to tell another view
controller what data to display.
So now it's your turn to
try passing some data along
with a segue in your app,
and take some challenges.
And I'll see you in
the next section.