Welcome back to App
Evolution with Swift.
Our table view has dynamic
data, but when we tap on a cell,
our product view
controller is always
showing the same string still.
That's because we've
got to update our segue
to use data from the array
instead of a fixed value.
So here's the plan.
Instead of setting the product
name to a hard-coded string,
we can first get the
cell that was tapped,
then get the index
path for that cell,
then use the index
path to get the product
name from the array.
And finally, we can
send the product name
to the product view controller.
So getting a copy of
the cell that was tapped
is a little trickier
than it was before.
Because this prepare for
segue function doesn't just
have an index path lying
around like the cell for row
at index path function did.
What we do have though is
this unassuming property
called sender.
Sender is the cell
that caused the segue
to happen, in other
words the tapped cell.
Let's grab that cell in
a variable like this.
Notice we've got to write
as question mark again,
because the compiler
can't be sure
that the sender was definitely
a UI table view cell,
so our cell variable
has to be optional.
Since it is optional, we
first have to unwrap up
the cell with optional binding.
And if it exists, we
can grab the index path
for that cell as
another variable
by calling the table view dot
index path for cell function,
and passing our
unwrapped cell into it.
That index path we get
back is also an optional,
so we'll unwrap that with
optional binding as well.
And if it exists, we
can get the product name
from the product names
array at the position index
path or IP dot row.
Then we can set the product
view controller's product name
property to the product
name from the array
that we just got.
And we can see that, now
when we tap on a cell,
the corresponding text is set
in the product view controller.
Things are working
great, but this code
is pretty messy
and hard to read.
So there's a few
things that we can
do to make it a little bit
easier to read and maintain.
For example, we're using
really ambiguous variable names
like c and IP.
There's also a lot of code block
nesting that we can get rid of.
First, we can use the
same variable name
for both the object we're
checking with if let,
and the variable we
assign to it if it exists.
Here you can see we've
reused the cell and index
path names instead of
just the letter c and IP.
Next, we can combine
getting a copy
of the cell from
the sender object
and unwrapping it
on the same line.
We get an optional index path
back from the table view index
path for cell function,
and assign and unwrap it
with if let all on one line.
Then, we can do the same thing
with the product name value
from our array.
We can read it and set
it on the same line.
Looking better, right,
a lot easier to read.
Well there's, even
one more step we
can take that's even smarter.
Instead of if let, we
can use a statement
called guard, along
with both our let cell
equal and let index path equal
lines separated by commas.
Guard first checks of both
the cell and the index path
values that you're
trying to set exist.
And if they do exist,
it assigns those values
to the cell and
index path variables.
After those, you can
write else return,
which means that if those
variables don't have values
the function will just
stop running right there
and early exit.
That means that you can safely
use the cell and index path
variables anywhere
later in the function,
because you know the
rest of the function
wouldn't have kept running
unless cell and index
path exist.
So here you can see that
our table view works exactly
like it did before, and
the code's easier to read
and easier to maintain.
So why don't you try
passing some dynamic data
through a segue in
your project and take
some challenges, and I'll
see you in the next level.