[SINGING] Starting back
in the machine age,
the telephone had
just taken the stage.
No one predicted
its acceleration
evolving all of
our communication.
Today we build with
storyboards, use Xcode
projects where they're stored.
Controllers with scroll,
navigate and tables, outlets,
actions, buttons and labels.
To code a phone is a learned
gift with the App Evolution
with Swift.
Welcome back to App
Evolution with Swift.
Right now, we're passing
just product Name
into the
Product View Controller, but that
means we can only pass
one piece of data.
What if we wanted to also pass
stuff like the product image
name, or even the cell
image for that cell?
One thing we could do is create
multiple variables inside
of Product View Controller
and pass values into them,
but that would quickly
get really messy,
especially as we
had more and more
values that we wanted to pass.
So instead, we can
create a new class
to hold all of those
variables as properties
and then just pass one
object over instead of three.
So let's jump into Xcode
to see how we can do that.
The first thing we'll do is
create a brand new Swift file,
and instead of choosing
a Cocoa Touch class,
we'll just choose
an empty Swift file.
This is because we're not
going to need to subclass
any of the UI kit's classes.
So instead, we'll
just start fresh.
We'll name this file Product
with a capital P dot swift
and hit Create.
Since we do want this
to be a class file,
we'll type class,
Product with a capital P,
and the opening and
closing curly brackets.
And we'll create three
variables in this class.
The first one will
be called name,
and it will be an
optional string.
The next one will be
called product image,
and it will also be
an optional string,
and the third will
be cell image,
and again, it will be
an optional string.
Now we'll be able to create
objects of type Product,
and then we'll be able to
set each one of those three
variables for those
objects with dot notation
to the info for each
individual product.
We'll do that inside of our
Products Table View Controller,
and we can create those product
objects inside of view Did Load,
like this.
Then for each one of
these product objects,
we need to set their name,
product image, and cell image.
We should also note that we've
added all of the remaining
necessary images to
our asset catalog,
so we've got all four full
screen images loaded in.
Now we need to fill in the
rest of the data for each
of these products,
and we'll skip
ahead here so you don't have to
watch us type all of this in.
The place we need to put all
this data is in an array,
and we don't even need our
product Names array anymore,
so we'll rename it from
product Names to products.
And instead of holding
a group of strings,
it will hold a group
of product objects.
We'll adjust the
name of the array
in view Did Load to
products and instead
of using these
hard coded strings,
we can use the product 1,
2, 3, and 4 objects.
Down in the table View
number Of Rows In Section function,
we can update this code to
unwrap the optional products
array instead of product
names, and we'll also
make these unwrapped variable
names a little shorter.
Down in the table View
cell For Row At Index Path function,
we'll do something similar.
We'll grab just one
product object and grab it
from the products array and
let p equal that product,
unwrapping the optional.
Then we can adjust
the text Label dot text
to come from p dot name,
which is the string
inside of the product object.
We can move the image
setting code up as well.
But if we try to replace
the hard coded image
with p dot cell Image,
we'll get an error,
and that's because cell
image isn't optional,
and this UI image
initializer has
to be absolutely sure that the
image we're using to create it
exists.
So we can unwrap
that too by typing
if let i equals p dot cell Image
and move the cell image
creation code inside
of that if let block,
then we can use the unwrapped
image name from the variable i,
and that will show the right
image view in the cell.
Next, down in the
prepare For Segue function,
we can just pass a product
object over instead
of a product name string
and pull the product
from the product's array,
but we still get an error
because the
Product View Controller still
doesn't have the
right variable set.
So, if we go into the
Product View Controller,
we can change our product
name variable to just product.
And instead of having
a string as the type,
we'll use that product class.
Just like in the cell, we can
unwrap that product object,
pull our label code inside
of that unwrapped block,
and then grab p dot name as
the text for the label.
Then we can unwrap the image
and copy the image view
inside of that block.
And instead of the
hard coded image name,
we can just pass i,
which is going to be
the unwrapped product Image.
Now, if we build
and run the app,
you can see we've got dynamic
cell images for each cell,
dynamic cell text,
and when we tap on
each one of the cells,
the correct text and
correct product image
is shown in the
Product View Controller.
And there you have it.
Now we're passing
only one object
from our
Products Table View Controller
over to the
Product View Controller,
and we're able to read from
that object any place that we
need to display data.
So now it's your turn to
go try adding a custom
class to hold your
data in your project
and take some
challenges, and I'll
see you in the wrap up video.
Screencasts.
More for screencast.
Oh, screencast.
I didn't see you there.
Have you been here all along?
Screencasts.
I can't even do fake angry.
This is what I talk
like when I'm angry.
Screencasts.
If I ever talk to
you like this, it
means I'm really angry with you.
Screencasts.
Ooh, screencasts.
What are you holding?
Just holding screencasts.
UI label.
Just in case you need
that for an outtake.