Welcome back.
In this section, we'll
looking at how we can display
dynamic table cell data.
So our table view is
working really well,
but it's always showing the
same label for each line
because we're hard-coding
the label's text.
Let's update our
tableview to show
different data in each cell.
There's a few steps to
setting up dynamic data.
First, we need to
create a variable that
will store multiple
product names,
and we'll use an array for this.
Next, we need to update all
of our table view controller
functions to use the
data from that array,
instead of the hard-coded data
that's in there right now.
Let's start by
creating an array.
Arrays can store multiple
values of a single type of data.
In this case we'll
store strings.
We'll also need to make
this array optional.
We can set the product
names in view Did Load,
and we'll just make four
values for each one of our four
phones.
Now that we've got
some data, we need
to update the table view number
of rows in section function
to return the number of
items in the array instead
of a hard-coded number.
Then we'll need to update
the table view cell for row
at index path version
of the function
to display one of the names
in the array for each cell,
instead of the hard-coded
text that's in there now.
First, in the table view number
of rows in section function,
instead of just returning
a hard-coded number five,
we can instead return the count
property of the product names
array.
Remember that product
names is an optional,
so we've got to put the
question mark after it when
we're writing it.
The count property returns the
number of items in the array.
So since we've got four array
items, we'll get four rows.
If we try to write it
just like this though,
we're going to
run into an error.
The problem is, is that if
product names doesn't exist,
then the count property
won't exist either.
And therefore, this function
is returning an optional Int
instead of a regular Int.
To fix this we can write
if let p Names equals
product names, and inside
of that conditional, return
p Names dot count.
If let is a special way of
working with optionals called
optional binding,
and it combines
checking if the value
exists, and assigning it
to a new variable
all in one line.
Here, the if part is checking
if product names exists.
And if it does, it
copies everything
that's in product names
into a new variable called
p Names that's only accessible
inside of the if statement.
Since we know anything inside
of the if statement exists,
we can just return
p Names dot count and we
can be sure that we're
returning a real Int.
After this optional binding,
we also need to return zero.
That's because if the product
names array doesn't exist,
we still need to return an Int.
Next, we need to map
each item in the array
to a corresponding
cell in the table.
We've got an array
with four strings,
and we've got four cells.
So if each cell were
displaying the text of one
of those product names,
that would work out great.
So in the table view cell for
row at index path function,
we first need to get a copy
of the name from the array
and store it in a variable
called product Name.
Just pretend for a minute
that we've got that already.
Then, since that product name
variable will be optional,
we can unwrap it with if left.
And if it does exist,
we set the cells text
label dot text property to
the product name variable.
So as you may know,
each value in an array
can be accessed by
putting a number
inside of square brackets
after the array variable name.
So here, the first value could
be accessed with the number
zero, like this.
And the last value can be
accessed with a number three,
like this.
Here we've set the product name
equal to the product name's
arrays at position zero.
Remember that this function runs
once for each row in the table,
so doing this will
actually set the name to be
the same for all four rows.
We need that number
to be dynamic
based on the current cell,
and not just always zero.
The answer lies in index paths.
Every cell in the table view
has an index path property,
and every index path
property has a row property.
And that row property is just
a number, starting at zero
for the first cell, ending
at three for the last cell.
This is really convenient
because our array also starts
at zero and ends in three.
So instead of
hard-coding a number,
we can use Index Path dot row
for the index of the array,
and then we should
be good to go.
As you can see, each cell
now displays the name
from one item in the array.
So now it's time for you
to add some dynamic data
to your cells, and
take some challenges.
And I'll see you in
the next section.