[SINGING]
From the Labyrinth of Loops to
the Variable Valley, we'll see
the Cliffs of Value first.
JavaScript'ss right
up your alley.
Built-ins Bluff, Files Falls,
Array Archipelago.
Declarations in a desert,
where you'll find out
how far you'll go.
Learn to program.
Take a ride.
Buy a ticket. Step inside.
All aboard,
you're at the station to
increase your education.
Bon voyage
and skinny dip! As long as
functions you don't skip, on
this the JavaScript ...
... Road Trip
All right, Road Trippers,
we are coming
down the home stretch.
And now, you are masters of
the declared function
and you can build your own
basic functionality.
Pretty cool, huh?
And now we're going to move to
exploring how we can put a
list of data inside of one
convenient variable.
Welcome to Level 5: The
Array Archipelago.
So we're back on our train,
and what if we wanted a
passenger list for
our train car?
How would we structure a list
of passengers inside our new
train system?
Well, taking a look inside of
our trains.js file, we could
make a function.
And we could call it "makeList".
And you can see that has an
empty set of parameters.
And inside the function,
we could make a
whole bunch of variables.
One for passenger one, one for
passenger two, one for
passenger three, and
so on and so on.
But what if we have
60 passengers?
And then what if they changed?
This would kind of suck just
a little bit, right?
So we need to find a way,
through one variable, to
access an entire list
of people that are
passengers on our train.
For that we have a
very special data
structure called an array.
An array is a data structure
that we can reference with a
variable name, and it has
automatically indexed positions.
Let's take a look at a six
cell array of passengers.
Here you can see a bunch of
people that are passengers on
our new six cell train.
Just like strings, arrays have
indices that are zero-based.
So, if we referenced cell 0
here, we would get Gregg
Pollack, who is in the very
first cell of the array.
And in cell four, despite his
excellent mustachioed figure,
we have Jon Friskics.
Even though we currently have
a picture array that has all
these guys in it, we could also
have an array of strings
that has their names.
We can build a string array very
easily, and we can have
easy access to its contents
using indices.
So, if we wanted to build this
six cell string array, we
could make a variable called
passengers, and then using a
set of square brackets, build an
entire list of the strings
that we would like inside
of our array.
When the array is built
internally, it will
automatically place each of the
strings in order into each
of the array's indices
in order.
If we wanted to access any
particular indexes value, we
would use the notation, for
example here, passengers five,
and that says to return
the value at index five.
If we did that here, we would
get Ashley Smith, which is
obviously in the very last
cell of our array.
Another cool thing about
arrays is that we can
reference and change the
contents of specific cells
using the same indices that
we used to just get
the contents out.
If we wanted to change the
value contained at any
particular index, we would use
the same style of notation to
reference which cell we
want to deal with.
Here, if we wanted to place
Eric Allam's name into the
second cell, we would say
passengers, 2, and set that
equal to Eric Allom
as a string.
Again, this particular syntax
says, go over to the index 2
and change the value that's
there to whatever comes after
the equals assignment sign.
Just like strings, we could
access the length of arrays if
we type the variable's name
and the .length property.
Having done that, we see that
this returns a value of six,
because there are six cells.
Arrays come with a whole bunch
of methods that you can use to
manipulate the contents of the
array, as well as manipulate
the length of the array.
Here we'll look at
the pop method.
Not only does pop delete the
last position in the array -
in this case, it would
be Ashley Smith
in the fifth cell -
but it will return the
string as a value.
After we call the pop method, we
can see here that our array
now has one less cell.
Well, if we've taken a piece off
the back of an array, we
should also be able to
put a piece back on.
We can do that with
the push method.
So, if we start here with our
previously shortened array,
and we call the push method on
our array passengers using the
string Adam Rensel, we see that
Adam gets added to the
very last cell in the array,
and the length is
automatically increased.
An interesting thing about
arrays is that
they can hold anything--
strings, values, variables,
even other arrays, or
combinations of them all.
So, here in our first array,
combo1, we've got "One",
"fish", 2, "fish".
And that is a string, another
string, then a number, and
then a final string.
Arrays can also accept
variables when
they're being built.
If we established a variable
called poisson, and set it
equal to the string "fish", we
could then use poisson inside
of this second combo array,
where we use "Red", poisson,
"Blue", and another poisson.
And then when the array actually
gets built, poisson
gets replaced with its
evaluation, which is fish.
So, are you ready for
a mind meld?
Well, arrays can hold other
arrays as well.
Check out this arrayOfArrays.
This arrayOfArrays includes
both combo1 and combo2.
When the array actually is
built the contents of combo1
and combo2 get placed inside
arrayOfArrays.
The entire contents of combo1
go in the first cell of
arrayOfArrays, and the entire
contents of combo2 go in the
second cell.
You can see that when we use
console.log to print out the
arrayOfArrays to the console, we
can see that it returns an
array that contains
two arrays, each
of different length.
Notice also that the names
of combo1 and combo2 have
disappeared inside
arrayOfArrays.
So now we can use the variable
arrayOfArrays to access an
entire array that it holds.
You can see that if we use
the console.log method on
arrayOfArrays 1, it will move
over to the second cell of the
array and retrieve the entire
array present there.
Then we get "Red", "fish",
"Blue", "fish" as a result.
Sometimes this type of
array is called a
two dimensional array.
That's because we have the cell
of the largest array,
arrayOfArrays, and then we have
the cells of the internal
arrays as well.
We can select individual
components of the internal
arrays here.
You can see that if we use two
brackets, and we tried to
console.log out, arrayOfArrays
1 and then 2 in the second
bracket, what happens is we
look in the second cell of
arrayOfArrays, and then in the
third cell of that array we
find there, which
gives us Blue.
Similarly, if we used the log
method on arrayOfArrays
0, 1, we'd go to the first cell
of arrayOfArrays, and
then the second cell of
the internal array.
And we get fish.