So now, let's see if we can
add to our complex
list of special trains.
We want to make train number 12
become a special train just
like number 10.
They both begin running
at noon.
But, how can we do that?
We want to make sure that we
only handle that particular
special case with
one conditional.
Let's look at how
we can do that.
So, in our original loop, where
we checked each train number
to see what we should print for
that train number, we're
going to need something a little
extra in the Else-If
condition to see whether we've
got train 10 or train 12.
Also, we need to change the
console.log statement, because
we don't want to print that
train number 10 is running
when it's actually
train number 12.
So, we'll concatenate a
trainNumber variable inside
there to handle that.
The special syntax that we
have to evaluate two
conditions at once is called
a complex conditional.
And we have the binary "And",
which is two ampersand
symbols in a row.
And that's going to return true
if both the values on the
left-hand and right-hand side
of the ampersands are true.
And we also have the binary
"Or", which returns true if
either value on the left-hand
or right-hand side is true.
If we have a situation true
and false, that's going to
evaluate to false, because not
both of the values are true.
If we had a situation where both
values were true, then
that's going to turn
out to be true.
If we also had a situation where
both the values were
false, well, we don't have any
truth value there, so that's
going to be false, too.
Moving on to Or, if we saw a
situation where the left-hand
side was false and the
right-hand side was true,
well, all we need is one
truth value to make
that Or return a true.
And so this will return true.
Next we have a false or false.
If you see that situation, well,
we don't have any truth
value, so that will give
us a false back.
Similarly, if we had a true Or
a true, we've got more than
enough truth value to make
that Or work out.
And so we have a true.
Let's take a look at how these
might be evaluated with
expressions.
Here you can see that 11 is
greater than or equal to 11.
That's true.
And negative 7 is less than 6.
That's also true.
Since we have two expressions
that evaluate to true, that
entire truth value expression
returns a true.
Over here, if we have 2 greater
than or equal to 0,
that is true.
But then 9 is not less than 4.
And so that returns false.
And this entire complex
conditional will return false.
Next, we have is 5 less than 7?
Yes, it is.
Is 8 greater than 10?
No it is not.
And so we have a true
Or false situation.
But that's OK, because Or only
needs one truth value to
return a true.
And then lastly, we can see
is 3 greater than 8?
No, it is not.
So, it is a false situation.
And is 7 less than 3?
No, it's not.
It's false.
And so a false Or a false will
return a false, because we
need at least one truth value
to return a true.
Now let's see how we
can use that inside
our trains.js system.
Let's think about how we can add
a complex conditional to
our Else-If statement to make
sure that both train 10 and
train 12 get printed correctly
as express
trains starting at noon.
So, what we would want there is
to check whether the train
number is 10 or whether the
train number is 12.
If it is either, train number 10
or train number 12, then we
will print out that that
particular train number will
begin running at noon.
Let's take a look at our
new status loop.
We can see that as normal, all
of the operational trains will
run, 1 through 8.
And then we hit train 9 and
we see that that's not
operational.
And then at train 10, we trigger
the Else-If to show
that train number 10 begins
running at noon.
At train 11, we say that
that's just a regular
not-operational train.
And train number 12 will now
trigger our Else-If block with
our complex conditional.
And we see that it begins
running at noon.
Guess what.
We're going to continue
now adding to our
list of special trains.
Oh no.
But it's going to
be a different
special train this time.
It's going to be
train number 3.
And we're going to say
that train number 3
only runs on Sunday.
So, it is not a regular train.
It is not an express train.
It is not a non-operational
train.
It is only a Sunday
running train.
We're going to use our binary
And complex conditional syntax
to manage this situation.
We want to make sure
that train number 3
runs only on Sunday.
So, we will need a day of
the week variable.
And we're going to initialize
today to be Friday.
We know that if today is Friday,
then train number 3
should not be running.
So, let's see about making some
code that makes that happen.
So, here's our regular status for
loop that checks the train
number to see what should
happen in the printout.
What we need to do here is add
an extra Else-If condition
that checks two things, whether
the train number is 3
and if the day is Sunday.
If that's the case, then we can
print that train number 3
is running.
How can we show that with our
complex conditional syntax?
We can ask whether the train
number is equal to 3 and the
day of the week is Sunday.
If the left-hand side of that
And and the right-hand side of
that And both evaluate to
true, then we will get a
printout that says train
number 3 is running.
We can go ahead and hard-code
that 3 in the string, because
we know that train number 3 is
the only Sunday-running train.
So, let's run this code
and see what happens.
We should get that the train
number 3 is not -
oh no.
The train number 3 running.
What happened?
Something's wrong
with our code.
Why didn't we get the
right status?
Let's trace our loop logic
and see exactly
what the problem is.
So far, day of the
week is Friday,
and we know that we have
12 total trains and
8 operational trans.
We know that at some point in
our status loop, the train
number will become 3.
If that's the case, then when we
go to check that the train
number is less than or equal
to the operation trains, we
will get a true, which means
that we will go ahead and
print that train number 3 is
running without ever having
checked whether it's Sunday.
But we know that it shouldn't
be running,
because it's Friday.
So, we have to make a shift
in some part of our code.
How can we do that?
Well, we found our logic bug
and it's in that check of
train number less than or equal
to operational trains.
That's because for train numbers
1 through 8, they will
always trigger that very first
If block and we will never
reach the Else-If block
that checks if today
happens to be Sunday.
How can we fix that?
We can put an extra condition
inside the very first If
statement that says if the train
number is less than or
equal to the operational
trains and the train
number is not 3.
Now, how can we get some syntax
that says the train
number is not 3?
Well, that's very simple.
You've seen that before.
We would just have double And
train number not equals 3.
And that will also ensure that
when we get to the train
number 3, we will fall all the
way down to the second Else-
If, check both that the train
number is equal to 3 and that
the day of the week is Sunday,
and then print that the train
number 3 is running.
Now we'll get correct
printouts with
this particular syntax.
We can see that when the day of
the week is Friday, we now
get the correct printout that
train number 3 is not
operational.
And, when we set the day of the
week finally to that glorious
day of Sunday, we get that
the train number 3 is
running after all.
So, let's look at how this
complex conditional arrives at
the different unique printouts
for train number 3.
Well, let's say our day
of the week's Friday.
We'll look at the Friday
condition.
We know that at some point our
status loop will arrive at
train number 3.
And when that happens, it's
going to then check to see if
the train number is less than
or equal to the operational
trains, which it is.
And, then it will also check to
see that train number is not
equal to 3.
That will be false.
And it will make sure that we
do not enter that if clause.
And then we will check to see
whether the train number is 10
or whether it's 12.
And since it is neither,
that entire
condition will be false.
And then we will check to see
if the train number is equal
to 3, which it is.
And then we will check to see
the day of the week is Sunday.
In this case, it is not.
And so we will get that train
number 3 is not operational.
Now what happens when the day
of the week is Sunday?
We get nearly the same situation
all the way through,
except when we check whether
the train number is 3 and
whether the day of the
week is Sunday.
And since both of those
situations are true, we
finally get that train
number 3 is running.
Congratulations.
You've completed the
Conditionals level of
JavaScript Road Trip.
Enjoy the challenges -
they're a doozy.
We'll see you in the
next section.
[TRUMPETING]
Rolling, rolling, rolling.
Then, here's what
would happen -
[LAUGHTER]
Here's what's gonna happen.
God, that's stupid.
[RASPBERRY]