[SINGING]
From the Labyrinth of Loops
to the Variable Valley.
We'll see the Cliffs of Value
first, JavaScript's right up
your alley.
Built-in Bluffs, Files,
Falls, Array Archipelago.
Declarations in a desert,
where you'll find out
how far you'll go.
Learn to program.
Take a ride.
Buy a ticket step inside!
All aboard, you're
at the station to
increase your education.
Bon voyage and skinny dip.
As long as functions you don't
skimp on, on this the
JavaScript.
Road Trip.
So, those are some of the
functions that JavaScript has
built in directly for you.
But what happens when you
want to build your own
functionality.
That's the glory of computer
programming, right?
We want to build what we want.
So, in this level, we're going to
teach you how to build your
own function declarations.
In this, Level 4: The Desert
Of Declarations.
First of all, what's
a function for?
Well, if we give a function
some input, it will do some
work on that input -
some stuff to it -
and then it will output
something on the back end of
the function as a result.
A function will solve problems
for developers.
It will do something step by
step that we need to do
repeatedly.
Here let's take a look at a
basic function that's going to
sum together two cubes.
We'll call it the sum
of two cubes.
The first step would be
to get two numbers.
So, let's say we had
four and we had nine.
Then we would cube each number
as the next step.
So, four cubed would be 64 and
9 cubed would be 729.
The third step in our function
would actually be to sum the
cubes together.
So, we'd get 64 plus 729 and
that will give us 793.
The last step, which is of
course important is to return
the answer from the function.
So, we get 793 as the output
of our function.
So, what are these steps if we
were to write code for them?
Let's see some syntax for
finding the sum of our cubes.
Well, the first step
of getting four, we
would establish a variable.
Let's call it "a"
and set it equal to four.
Then, we would do the same thing
for nine, but we would
establish the variable as "b".
Then we want to start cubing the
values, we'll start with four
cubed equals 64.
We'll establish a variable
called a cubed and set that
equal to a times a times a.
Then we'll do the same
thing for b cubed.
Ultimately, we'll make a
variable called sum.
And add a cubed and
b cubed together.
So ultimately at the end of our
coded function, we would
have 793 as the output.
Now, the cool thing about
functions is that they are
very reusable and that makes
them very useful.
We can wrap our code in a
function that will allow us to
reuse it frequently.
Here you can see when we put four
and nine into the function, we'll
get 793 as the output.
But when we put five and six into the
same function, we get 341.
Now, let's look carefully at how
to build a function with
syntax in JavaScript code.
We'll start our function with
the actual keyword function.
We'll also need two braces
that enclose the entire
function into a code block.
Next, we need to title
the function.
We'll call ours sum of cubes.
And then we need a set of
parameters that are enclosed
in parentheses.
Here, because we have two inputs
to our function, we
have two parameters, a and b.
But you can have just as many
parameters as you want in any
declared function.
You can think of these
parameters, you know which are just
basically our inputs to the
function, as the materials
that the function either uses or
does work on to produce the
output you're looking for.
Inside the braces, of course, the
function will actually do
some stuff.
That's what we want the
function to do.
And then at the end of the
function, we'll return
something or even a nothing
from the process.
That return keyword tells the
function OK you're done, go
ahead and exit, and
give us whatever
follows the return keyword.
An important thing to note about
the return key word, is
that you'll often see it
anywhere inside the function
because it can be used to
instantly exit at any time.
Here however, we want
it at the end of our
sum of cubes function.
So, now let's actually build out
our sum of cubes function.
Remember our four steps
that we made?
Let's see where they
fall inside the
syntax of our function.
If we were to get two numbers
as our first step, those are
the parameters, which get passed
into the function when
it is called.
The second step would be
to cube each number.
So, that's going to be a process
we do inside the
function body.
Then we will sum the cubes -
that's another step we'll do
in the function body -
and at the end, we'll
return that sum.
And that's our final step
of returning the answer.
So, now let's transfer
in the actual
syntax into those steps.
Well our parameters don't
change, they'll
still be a and b.
Once the parameters are actually
passed into the
function, they can be
used at any point in
the functions process.
And of course, our next step will
be cubing a, which you
can see a cubed equals
a times a times a.
Followed by cubing b with
the same procedure.
And then a sum, where we add a
cubed and b cubed together.
And then we will return that sum
value from the function.
Now that we have built our
super cool sum of cubes
function, we can call it by
using the function's name
followed by a set of parentheses
within which we
place the parameters
for our function.
Here, when we place our four and
our nine into the sum of cubes
function, we get a 793
instantly returned.
Now, we can do a lot
of things with our
sum of cubes function.
We could use it in an assignment
expression.
So, if we wanted to
make a variable,
let's call it my sum.
And then we call sum of cubes,
let's say on five and six.
And then tried to alert our my
sum variable, after that
calculation, to the screen.
We would get 341 alerted
to our user.
Now that we know how to build
a function, let's see if we
can also put in a little bit of
efficiency into our functions.
Because being concise helps
us with memory and storage
operations.
Our function works great, but
we've made three unnecessary
variables that all have to
be allocated in memory.
Let's see if there's a way
to get rid of those.
Well first of all, we've made a
sum variable that's a cubed
plus b cubed.
Why don't we just return
a cubed plus b cubed?
The return keyword will
evaluate that
expression and return it.
Now we don't need a sum
variable anymore.
Well if that's true, we don't
need a b cubed variable.
We can just put b times b times
b in place of b cubed.
And you can probably see
where that's going.
Because if we don't need a b
cubed variable, then we don't
need an a cubed variable
either.
And we can just write
a times a times a.
So now we've got one statement
that says, return a times a
times a plus b times
b times b,
which is what we wanted to
do in the first place.
Now, we've eliminated three
different variables and
simplified our function.
Now, as you saw before we can
call our sum of cubes function
with two numbers passed
in as parameters.
But we can also pass in
expressions as parameters.
JavaScript will go ahead and
evaluate and simplify those
expressions before calling
the actual function.
So you can see here that if we
called the sum of cubes with
two expressions as parameters,
1 plus 2 and three plus five, that
would be the exact same thing
as calling sum of
cubes on three and eight.
And of course, we would get
a 539 as the output.
We can also use variables
as parameters.
Here you can see, we've
established a variable called
x that we've set to three.
And then we used x inside
the parameters in a
sum of cubes call.
So this particular call of sum
of cubes would be the same as
sum of cubes six and 12
because x is three.
And so we would get an
output of 1,494.