[SINGING]
From the Labyrinth of Loops to
the Variable Valley, we'll see
the Cliffs of Value first.
JavaScript's right
up your alley.
Built-ins Bluff, Files Falls,
Array Archipelago.
Declarations in a desert,
where you'll find out
how far you'll go.
Learn to program.
Take a ride.
Buy a ticket. Step inside.
All aboard,
you're at the station to
increase your education.
Bon voyage
and skinny dip! As long as
functions you don't skip, on
this the JavaScript Road Trip.
So that was Level 2.
Conditionals are pretty
cool, huh?
And another cool thing about
the JavaScript language is
that it has tons of built-in
functions that you
can use at any time.
You can call them whenever
you want.
And we're going to look at a few
of those in this Level 3:
Built-ins Bluff.
Let's take a look at some
existing JavaScript functions
that you can use to get and send
information from the user
of your website.
The first on we'll take
a look at is alert.
This will send a message to the
user of your website in a
small pop-up window.
You can see here that when we
call the alert function, we've
placed a string inside of a set
of parentheses that will
get alerted to the user.
But you can put any expression
inside these parentheses that
will be evaluated and then
presented to the user.
Once the alert function is
evaluated, a small pop-up
window is present in the browser
that the user can
click OK on, acknowledging that
they have seen the alert.
Another built-in in function
is the confirm function.
It asks users for a consent
to move forward
with a specific action.
Here we're using the confirm
function to make sure that a
passenger wants to
ride Train 8.
A small window appears when
the confirmed function is
evaluated, presenting the user
with the opportunity
to say "OK" or "Cancel."
If the user actually hits OK,
the confirm function is going
to return a true
Boolean value.
If they hit Cancel, we'll get
a false Boolean value.
Yet another built-in function is
called the prompt function.
This will send a message
to the user and
also retrieve an entry.
So, here we've got a prompt
function that says, "What soul
hath allowed the canines
to exit?"
And the user appropriately
responds, "Woof, woof, woof,
woof," and then hits "OK" to say,
yes, that is acceptable.
Prompt is a cool function,
because you can request
information from the user and
then store it in a variable.
Here you can see a prompt
function that requests the
user's name,
and that name gets stored inside
the variable userName.
When we run this code, a small
window will pop up in the
internet browser.
And the user can enter their
name in the field that's
inside the window.
So, if code school professor Gregg
Pollack was sitting at
our website and entered his name
into our prompt window,
his name would get stored in
the userName variable.
We could then call
that variable,
and his name would
be returned.
Now, let's see how the confirm
and the prompt methods can
work together to ensure
we have correct
information from the user.
If we're prompted,
"Yo, passenger!
What's your name?"
And Gregg enters his name
and selects "OK."
His name will be stored in
the userName variable.
And then we can use the userName
variable inside of a
confirm function to
ensure that he has
entered his name correctly.
A small window will pop up in
the internet browser and ask
Gregg if he's sure that
that's his name.
And he can say "OK" for yes
or "Cancel" for no.
But wait a minute.
What happens if Gregg presses
"Cancel" on either the prompt or
the confirm?
We need a way of verifying
whether he has actually
inputted something for his name
and then whether his name
is correct, or not, in
the confirm box.
To do that, we'll need
the type of operator.
The type of operator allows us
identify the kind, or type, of
course, of value inside a
variable or an expression.
Here you can see that if we
take the typeof true as an
entry, we get Boolean as a
response, because true is a
Boolean value.
If we do typeof that's not a
valid entry, we get a string,
because the expression that
follows typeof is a string.
typeof 42 will return number.
And typeof undefined will return
the type undefined,
which is its own type.
And typeof null, which is
special, and we'll need it
soon, returns an object
as a type.
The typeof operator is useful
in checking a variable's
contents, very useful here.
You can see that if we prompted,
"Yo, passenger!
What's your name?"
And we stored that in the
variable userName, now, if the
user ever selects cancel,
regardless of whether they've
input anything into the field,
prompt will return a special
value called null.
And null is not a string.
So now, if we were to take the
typeof of userName, which had
a value of null, we would
get a return from
the typeof of object.
That's because null is a generic
JavaScript object.
This is really cool and useful,
because then we can
alert the user that they have
not entered a valid entry.
We can do that by saying, if
the typeof the userName
variable is not a string, uh-oh,
whoops, you didn't
enter your name.
And then we can start that cycle
over to make sure that
they have entered something
acceptable.
Now that we know how to handle
a cancel from a prompt
function, let's look at
how to handle a cancel
from a confirm function.
It's pretty easy, because the
confirm function returns a
false value if we get a cancel
from the user at any time.
Then we can just use a simple if
statement, a Boolean check,
to make sure that the user has
confirmed their entry.
If, in fact, we get a truth
value from confirm, then we
can do some code.
All right.
So now that we're masters of
confirm, prompt, and alert and
know how to move between the
three, let's see if we can
make a simple name entry system
for our train service.
We're going to write a
confirmation loop.
And let's prepare some pseudo
code first that plans our
solution using these
functions.
So in our trains.js file, you
see these three dots here?
That just means we've got a
whole bunch of extra code
handling our trains.
And here we will start our
confirmation loop.
We know that we want the loop to
continue until the user has
confirmed a name.
And inside the loop, the first
thing that we'll do is we'll
request the name using our
prompt function that we know.
Following that, if the user says
OK at a confirm function,
we will acknowledge their
accepted entry and then exit
the loop, because we're done.
We don't need to check
it anymore.
Otherwise, we'll cycle back to
the top of the loop and start
the service over.
OK.
Now, let's fill this in
with some real code.
The first thing we'll
need is a variable -
we'll call it gotName - that
will tell us whether we
actually have the user's
name correct or not.
And we will use that
in our loop.
You can see here that we have a
while loop this says, while
our gotName is false, that means
we don't have the name
yet, we'll do the following
things.
The first thing is that we'll
establish a userName variable,
just like we did before, and
then prompt to the passenger.
"Yo, passenger!
What's your name?"
And here's our cool if statement
that says, if we get
a confirmation with the
statement, "Are you
sure your name is?"
And then the userName
variable.
If that returns a truth value,
then we'll alert to the user,
"Sup, username?"
And then here's the money.
We have to set the gotName
variable, which
is a flag, to true.
So now, the loop knows that
we have the user's name.
Once that's true,
what happens?
We go back to the top
of the while loop.
And we see now that gotName
is no longer false,
and we would exit the
loop, because we
have the user's name.
But what would happen if the
If statement didn't trigger
because we did not get
a confirmation?
Well, we would cycle back to
the top of the loop and
continue the process again.
So now, let's see this
loop in action.
Up here we have our index.html
file, as well as our trains.js
source file, within which is
this code down here, our very
basic confirmation loop
that we just built.
When we load our index.html
file, our loop in trains.js
starts to load.
And we get our very
first prompt.
And it says, "Yo, passenger!
What's your name?"
That's this part right
here inside our loop.
And we're going to go ahead
and type in a wrong name -
Johnny Appleseed -
and select OK.
Our loop says, "Are you sure your
name is Johnny Appleseed?"
That's this part right here -
the confirm box -
and since that's not
me, I'm going to go
ahead and say Cancel.
No, that's not me.
And then it cycles back to the
top of the loop and re-prompts
us for my correct name.
So I'm going to go ahead and
type in my right name -
Jason Millhouse -
and hit OK.
Now, it says, "Are you sure your
name is Jason Millhouse?"
Which it is.
So, I'm going to go ahead
and hit the OK.
And it says, "Sup,
Jason Millhouse?"
And I can close that box out.
And notice no more pop-up
boxes appear.
That's because internally the
gotName variable is now true,
and so the loop will exit.
And the pop-up boxes will
cease appearing.
This is a very common way to use
built-in pop-up windows to
retrieve and ensure correct
information.
I hope you've had a great time
with built-in functions,
and now, we will release
you to the challenges.
The-- the-- adayeedem.
For the bloopers.
To the user, sup?
And then - [LAUGHTER]
I can't get through it.
Something valid -
Jason Millhouse.
Enter.