Now, we'll throw a special
case into the scenario.
What if we had a train - a
special train, an express
train - that starts later?
Let's add a train that isn't
one of the regular running
trains, but it also is not a
non-operational train, because
it will start at noon.
It's a special train.
To do this in our code, we will
need the Else-If syntax.
That's for when two conditions
just is not enough.
So, let's take a look at that.
We already know our If block,
where if some condition is
true we're going to
do some code.
The Else-If comes in when we
need an extra condition to
check before we fall to
the final else block.
You can see that in the Else-
If block, if some other
condition is true we will
do the code inside that
particular block before we will
allow the code to proceed
down to the else block.
Something to remember is that
if any condition is ever met
inside the if block or in the
Else-If block, the else will
never get evaluated.
Else-If allows us to check
multiple conditions.
It can be used when
many specific
scenarios need attention.
So, let's take a look at how we
might apply the Else-If block
to our special train
situation.
Here we have our normal if the
train number is less than or
equal to the operational trains,
let's just go ahead
and print that that
train is running.
But now we need to check
something specific.
Otherwise, first check if the
train is the express train.
Then we want to print that train
number 10 begins running
at noon, because it has its
own special message.
Otherwise, we know it is neither
a running train nor an
express train,
and so it is a not-operational
train.
How can we implement that
particular part
of the Else-If statement?
Well, all we have to do is ask
whether the train number is
exactly equal to 10.
If it is, we know it's train 10
and we can print out that
that particular train
is running at noon.
Something to note is that the
Else-If condition is never
evaluated at all if the very
first condition in the If
block is checked and
is satisfied.
Similarly, the else block will
only trigger when the above
two blocks have failed.
So now,let's update our system
status loop with our cool new
Else-If statement.
We can print based on multiple
conditions now.
So you can see that in our for-
loop, most of which you've
seen before, we've added in the
Else-If statement to check
to see whether we have train
number 10 and then print out
that it runs at noon.
So let's go through the
execution board again and see
exactly when that Else-If
block is triggered.
You can see that for the first
8 trains, that Else-If is
completely ignored, because
the if block is triggered.
And then on train number 9,
since 9 is not equal to train
number 10, we go straight to the
else block and print the
9th train is not operational.
On the 10th train,
finally we have
triggered our Else-If block.
And we see the print out
that train number 10
begins running at noon.
And then the rest of the trains
proceed as normal.
And the loop stops
at train 13.
Sometimes when we check a
condition, we need to check
another condition inside
that block before we
continue with the code.
A nested conditional will
help us do that.
Let's say we had some shapes.
We've got two sizes
for squares.
And we've got one size
for circles.
We want to color big squares
red and small squares blue.
And since there's only
one size circle,
we'll color that purple.
How can we do that
in pseudo code?
How can we make the decision as
to whether a shape should
be colored red, blue,
or purple?
Well, we know that if it's
a square, we should check
whether it is big.
If it is big, we want to
make that square red.
Now, if it is not big, we will
move straight into the Else
block, which means it must
be a small square.
And so we should make it blue.
Now, this extra else down here
on the bottom is going to take
care of our circle.
Why?
Because we know that if our
shape is not a square, it must
be a circle.
And so therefore, we're going
to make that purple.
This is an example of
nested conditionals.
Something to note here is that
the innermost Else block only
responds to the innermost
If block.
Additionally, the very last else
block only responds to
that first if conditional
that checks whether
the shape is a square.
Say that in our train system
we wanted to print out a
special message to our users
that said whether all trains
were running or none
of them are.
We can use nested conditionals
to check whether we have all
trains running or none.
How can we demonstrate
that kind of
situation in pseudo code?
Let's take a look.
So, if there are any running
trains, meaning any running
trains at all, the first thing
we want to do is check to see
if the amount of running
trains is the
amount of total trains.
And then we want to print out
to the passengers that all
trains are running
if that is true.
Otherwise, we'll just execute
our normal loop code to decide
whether we have a running train
or a not-running train
or a special train.
And then outside all of that
nested conditional, we'll have
that final else block
that says there must
be no running trains.
And so we will print that out.
How do we know that?
Well, if the very first if
statement fails, that means
there's no running trains.
And so we can go straight to the
Else block and print out
that there are no
running trains.
So, let's check out how we would
make some code out of
that situation.
Well, in our first if
conditional, we would say if
the trainsOperational is greater
than 0 that means we
have some running
trains today.
If that's true, then the first
thing we need to check is
whether the trainsOperational,
meaning the amount of running
trains, is equal to
the total trains.
If that's true, then of course
we know that all of the trains
are running.
And so, we can print that
out to the user.
Otherwise, then we run our basic
for-loop that we have
already designed to
differentiate between the
running trains, the not-running
trains, and our
special train.
And then on the very last else
block, we will know that there
are no operational trains.
And so, we can print to the
user that no trains are
operational today.
Bummer.
So now if we update our
trains.js file with our
special new nested conditionals,
our passengers
will know whether all of the
trains are running today, or
whether none are, or whether
it's a mix of the two.
Something to note here is that
all of our code is very
efficient because it's
controlled by just two variables.
Let's see what would happen as
we trace through our crazy
nested conditional code.
Let's see how we'd get these
particular situations where
we'd have all trains
running or none.
Well, first we know that we have
12 total trains, right?
And we also have in this
particular case
12 operational trains.
Hmm.
They equal each other.
Well, we know that the
trainsOperational variable is
greater than 0, so we
will move into the
very first if block.
And then we will check to see
if the trainsOperational
variable is the exact same as
the totalTrains variable.
In this case, it is.
And so we will instantly print
out that all trains are
running at the JavaScript
Express.
Woo-hoo!
Now what would happen if we
set our trainsOperational
variable to zero?
That means we have no running
trains today.
It must be holiday.
So now, we'll come down and we'll
say is trainsOperational
greater than zero?
It is not.
And so we will move straight
to printing "No trains are
operational today.
Bummer!" in the final
Else block.