[SINGING]
From the Labyrinth of Loops to
the Variable Valley, we'll see
the Cliffs of Value first.
JavaScript's right
up your alley.
Built-ins Bluff, Files Falls,
Array Archipelago.
Declarations in a desert,
where you'll find out
how far you'll go.
Learn to program.
Take a ride.
Buy a ticket. Step
in inside.
All aboard.
You're at the station to
increase your education.
Bon voyage
and skinny dip! As long as
functions you don't skip, on this
the JavaScript Road Trip.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
So now, you're a master
of the loop, right?
Hope you enjoyed Level 1,
and now on to Level 2.
Sometimes when we're developing,
our code needs to
decide whether to take one
track or the other.
And, so we have arrived at Level
2: Conditional Canyon.
You'll remember in the previous
level that we printed
out all operational trains, as
well as all non-operational
trains in our new
train system.
We used two loops to do that,
and here is our previous code.
You can see that we used both a
While loop and a for-loop to
get through all of the trains.
Our goal here is now to
get all of that code
inside one for-loop.
How would we design that?
Well, here we have a for-loop
that loops through not just
the operational trains, but
through all of the trains.
We have it checking to see
whether the train number is
less than or equal to the
total amount of trains.
That means that this for-loop
will move over every single
possible train number.
But now we need to know how to
differentiate between whether
the train is running or whether
it's not running.
So if the train is currently
running, we want to print this
particular statement, and if
it's not, we want to print
this other statement that
shows that it's not
operational.
How can we do that?
Again, the goal here is to
figure out how we can run
different lines of code based
on different conditions.
Guess what?
We have a JavaScript trick for
that, and it's called If, and
her buddy, Else.
The If and Else statements allow
us to execute certain
code, but based on specific
conditions.
Here is the basic shell of an
If and an Else statement.
If some condition is
true, then we're
going to do this code.
This code is the code
inside the If block.
Else says otherwise do
this code instead.
Notice that if the condition in
the If block is true, only
the If code gets executed.
And the Else code only gets
executed if the If
condition is false.
Here's a basic example of
conditional execution.
Say we had two values, value 1
and value 2, and we've set
them to 4 and 9.
Let's use some conditional
statements to compare and
print out whether one is
greater than the other.
Here, we can see that if we do a
comparison of if the value 1
is less than the value 2, we
print out that that is true.
Value 1 is less than value 2.
Else, or otherwise, meaning if
value 1 is not less than value
2, we would print out that value
1 must be greater than
or equal to value 2.
That's because we don't strictly
know whether value 1
is greater than because
it might be equal to.
So in this case, because value
1 is 4 and value 2 is 9, the
If block would trigger
because it's
conditional would be true.
Value 1 is less than value 9,
and so we would get the
printout that 4 is
less than 9.
What happens if we change
value 1 to 12?
Obviously, we have a different
relationship now.
So now the If block
will not trigger.
Why?
Because 12 is not less than 9.
And so we will move into the
Else block, and we will get a
printout that says 12 is greater
than or equal to 9.
Just trust us.
Now that we've got some
experience with an If and an
Else block, let's go see
if we can make a
difference in our problem.
Our original problem was that
we needed to figure out
whether a train was running
or whether it
wasn't inside one loop.
And now you can probably see how
we would use and If and an
Else to make that situation
work out.
So, we know that if the train
number is less than or equal
to the operational trains, that
means that it's a running
train because we know that all
operational trains are
numbered from one moving
forward.
Therefore, we can print out
that that particular train
number is operating.
Next, we know that if train
number was not less than or
equal to the operational trains,
it must be greater
than the operational trains
and, therefore,
a non-running train.
So we would print out that
it was not operational.
So now, let's run our new single
loop with our special
conditionals.
We can see that when train
number is 1, the first thing
that happens inside
the loop is it
checks the loop condition.
Is 1 less than or equal to 12?
Yes, it is.
That's true.
So we will move forward
with the loop.
The loop will actually
continue.
And then it will check the
condition, is the train number
1 less than or equal to 8?
Yes, it is.
And so we will move into the
If block and print out that
train number 1 is running.
That same procedure will happen
all the way through
train number 8, where we'll get
printouts that each one of
those trains is running.
When we finally get the train
number 9, what will happen is
the loop condition
will check out.
It will be cool, and we
will continue to loop.
But our train number 9 is not
less than or equal to 8, and
so we will move to the Else
block instead of the If block.
And now we will see that train
number 9 is not operational.
That same procedure will occur
through the remaining trains
all the way to train
number 12.
That will be our last
non-operational train.
But when the train number becomes 13, finally the loop
condition itself will be false, and the
entire loop will stop.
So now, we have printed out every
last train and whether
it is running or whether
it is not.
And we have done it all in
one magical loop using
conditionals.