So, we've done the simple
function, now let's try a more
complex function.
Let's make a function that
counts the E's in a
user-entered phrase.
We will combine the built-in
functions of Level 5 with our
declared function of Level 6.
Let's call our function
countE.
And in this particular function,
we'll have no
parameters.
That often happens in
JavaScript code.
The first thing we'll do in our
function is we'll ask the
user for a phrase to check.
And then if that particular
entry is invalid, the first
thing we'll do is alert the
user, and then we would exit
the function with a
failure report.
As you know, we'll exit
the function by
using the return keyword.
Otherwise, if the entry is
valid, we'll go ahead and
start counting the E's inside
the user's phrase.
The first thing we'll do is
we'll make a counter variable
for the E's.
Then we'll have a for-loop that
goes over each character
in the user's entry.
If that particular character
is a capital E or an e, we
will increment our E
counter variable.
Finally, we'll alert the amount
of E's in the phrase
and return a success
from the function.
OK.
So, let's start coding.
We'll establish a variable
called phrase, and we'll
assign to that the results of
a prompt function that asks,
which phrase would you
like to examine?
Then if that entry is valid,
we will know it because the
phrase variable is a string.
So we say, if the type of the
phrase is not a string, we
will alert to the user that
that's not a valid entry and
then return a false, which will
instantly exit the function.
Our "otherwise" becomes an Else,
which is where we will
actually count the E's.
So first of all, we'll establish
a variable called
eCount that gets set to the
value zero because we don't know
how many E's are
in our phrase.
Then we'll make a For loop,
which will start at the very
first index of the phrase,
proceed all the way through
all the characters of the
phrase, incrementing the index
through each loop.
Inside the loop, we'll have
a complex conditional -
remember those? -
where we check to see if the
character at the current index
we're looking at is either a
lowercase e or whether that
character is a capital E. And
if that is true, if we get a
truth value out of that complex
conditional, we'll go
ahead and increase the
eCount variable.
Once that loop is entirely
complete, we will have in our
hands the amount of E's in that
phrase, and we can tell
the user, with an alert method,
there are however many
E's in that phrase.
Then we can return
true, which will
instantly exit the function.
So, let's see this in action.
So now, if we were to call our
countE function, notice with
no parameters, we would get a
small pop-up window from our
website that says, "Which phrase
would you like to examine?"
So, let's do "Excellent elephants",
which has a few E's
in it as you can see.
Once we've entered that phrase,
the countE function
will proceed, and we will find
that there are five E's in
"excellent elephants".
Now let's take a little bit
closer look at how that works
internally.
So, if we want to trace our
E-counter, we know that we're
going to start at index zero.
The first thing that will
happen is that we check
whether the index is less than
the length to make sure that
we don't go over the
edge of the string.
For index zero, of course, that's
true, and the character at
that index is a capital E.
So when we ask the question, is
the character at that index
a capital E or a lowercase e, we
get a truth value from our
complex conditional, and
so our eCount is
instantly turned to one.
As the loop continues, this
procedure will occur for every
character, including spaces
and punctuation.
And when we finally get to the
index that is just past the
end of the string, we'll get
a false value from the loop
condition and stop the loop.
The function will instantly
return a eCount of 5.
So, now that we've tackled a more
complex function, we will
wrap up our function level with
an examination of local
and global scope inside
JavaScript.
Let's say we've got a program,
and the program has some
variables, and it also has
a couple functions.
You can see our variables are x
and y, and our functions are
add, and lower, subtract.
Now, here in this space, in the
main program, the scope is
called global, which means that
variables declared there
are potentially accessible from
any place, even within
the functions below.
Inside the functions, the scope
is called local, and all
of the variables that are
declared inside the functions
are only contained within
those functions.
You can think of global and
local scope as being like the
global planet Earth having many
nations, and within each
of the nation's, they have their
own government and their
own way of doing things.
An important thing to know about
functions is that they
will always create a
new local scope.
The variables that are declared
inside of a function
will stay in that function.
So, let's take a look at this
tiny snippet of code here,
where we outside the function
declare a variable and set it
equal to six.
But then, inside a new function
add, we rename a new
variable x and set it equal to
the parameters a plus b.
So, you can see that I've got a
variable keyword on that x.
When that happens in a local
scope, an entirely new
variable is created with the
name x that is only accessible
to the function block for add.
So, here you can see that if we
called the add function and
passed in the values nine and tw,
add itself would return 11.
But then if we logged out
the variable x, we
would still get six.
And that's because the internal
variable x that got
set equal to a plus b did not
modify the variable that's on
the outside of the function.
In JavaScript, however, we need
to be careful because if
we don't declare the variable x,
JavaScript thinks that you
mean the global variable on the
outside of the function.
So you can see in this second
snippet of code that we've
still got our variable x
declared outside the function.
But inside, we no longer have
declared a new variable x, and
instead, just used the name x.
So, you can see here that if
we actually called the add
function this time with nine and two,
yes, the add function would
return 11, but when we log out
the x variable, its value has
been changed to 11.
It's always important to
declare your variables
carefully and know the
relationship between the local
and global scopes
in JavaScript.
So, coming back to our earlier
program, if our program had
the variables x and y and the
functions add and subtract, we
know that the add function would
create its own local
scope with the parameters
a, which is local to the
function, and b, which is also
local to the function.
Then inside that add function,
we would have a variable
called x that would be local
as well to the function.
Now take a look at the
subtract function.
It also has local parameters a
and b, but when it uses the
variable y, it is the global
variable y that it modifies.
How can we tell that
in the code?
There is no variable
keyword next to
the y inside of subtract.
Now we release you to
the challenges.
See you back for
the last level.
JavaScript word-trippers,
you are here.
We will wrap up our
function lebel -
lebel.
Oh, o's ...
Look at that horrible [BLEEP]
on the bottom.