Now we'll move on to a different
style of loop, but
one that has similar
functionality.
It's called the for-loop.
It's a different way of
producing nearly the same the
looping behavior.
Here you can see the basic
outline of a for-loop.
It starts with the for keyword
and then has a relatively long
set of parentheses.
Inside that parentheses you can
see two semicolons that
break up three separate
statements that will go in the
for-loop's parameters.
In the first expression.
We typically initialize our
variable counter there.
The second expression is
typically the condition we
check to see if the loop
will continue.
And the final statement inside
the for-loop's parameters is
the thing that we want to do
code-wise after each loop.
Usually this is an increment
or decrement statement to
control the loop.
Of course, inside the loop is
the code that we want to be
repeated over and over.
So now if we think back to our
train while-loop, we can
demonstrate the same exact
functionality with a for-loop.
Let's see how we do that.
In our starting expression we
would have the variable
trainNumber assigned
to the value 1.
Remember that was the statement
that we executed on
the outside of our while-loop.
Again, the second statement is
just going to be that same
condition that we checked for
the while-loop to see if the
train number is actually less
than or equal to the
trainsOperational there.
And the third statement will
increment our trainNumber
every time our loop executes.
Now let's take a look at how
this for-loop actually
proceeds through the code to
sort of get a visualization
for the flow of the for-loop.
In the first statement, the
trainNumber variable will be
initialized to 1.
After that happens, that
particular code will
never be run again.
Once that first statement
is executed, it is
finished and over.
It will move on to check
the condition
in the second statement.
We will see if the trainNumber
is actually less than or equal
to trainsOperational.
If it is, we will go ahead and
execute the loop's code.
All of the code contained
within the
loop will be executed.
Once that code is finished, we
will come back to the third
statement in the parameters.
And here we would increment the
trainNumber variable so we
can move on to the next train
and also get ready to stop our
loop eventually.
From there, we go back to the
second statement and see if
the trainNumber variable is
still less than or equal to
trainsOperational.
If it is, we continue the loop
again and the cycle continues
until when?
The trainNumber variable
is greater than
trainsOperational.
We used a while-loop to print
the numbers from 1 to 5 in
ascending order.
So now we're going to use the
for-loop to print those
numbers in descending order.
Let's take a look at how
we might do that.
So the first thing we do in our
for-loop is we initialize
the number variable to 5.
That's going to be our
counter variable.
Then we only want to run the
loop as long as that number is
greater than 0.
And at the end of the loop, we
want to decrease that number's
value by 1.
Inside the loop we will log the
number out to the console.
Let's take a look at this
code's execution.
When the value of number is 5,
well, clearly 5 is greater
than 0, so that condition
would evaluate to true.
And then we would get a printout
of the number 5 for
that particular loop.
That cycle would continue
until number
reached a value of 0.
And when number was 0,
it would clearly not
be bigger than 0.
And so the condition would be
false and the loop would stop.
Great.
So we know while-loops and
we know for-loops.
So now let's see if we
can identify the
non-operational trains.
So we've already identified the
operational trains, now
we're going to identify
the ones that are not
running for the user.
And this time we're going
to use a for-loop.
So, let's see.
Which trains are not running?
We know we have 8 operational
trains today.
So probably the very
first train will be
9 that's not running.
But we have to think about how
to put that into the for-loop
a little bit creatively.
So, we know we have 8 operational
trains and 12
total trains.
So, let's start our for-loop by
creating a variable called
stoppedTrain.
And we don't want to hard-code
this value.
We want to make sure that we use
a variable to signal which
of the stopped trains
it should be.
Here we know that the very first
stopped train will be
the one immediately following
the last operational train.
So therefore, if we just added
1 to the trainsOperational
variable, we will have the train
number for the first
stopped train.
Then for our condition, we want
to make sure that our
stoppedTrains list never
goes past the
total amount of trains.
This is the first time we've
used that totalTrains
variable in a loop.
And then at the end of the
loop, we should of course
increase our stoppedTrain number
so that we can get all
of the right stoppedTrains
printed and
then stop the loop.
Inside the loop, we will of
course print out a message to
the user that this particular
train is not running.
If we were to execute that
code, we would get the
following four statements
today.
Wahoo, stopped
trains only!
OK, now we have a list of running
trains with our while-loop.
Cool.
And we also have a list of
our not running trains
with our for-loop.
We're going to add both
of those now to
our trains.js file.
If you take a look here, you can
see we've established both
the totalTrains and the
trainsOperational variables in
our trains.js file.
Then we have our while-loop
that we built before.
This will print all of
the running trains.
To that we are going to add at
the end our for-loop that then
prints the stoppedTrains.
What will this look like if we
run our current solution?
Well, the first thing that will
happen is it will execute
the while-loop.
And it will proceed in the exact
same fashion that our
previous while-loop proceeded.
It will cycle all the way
through train number 8,
printing that each one of
those trains is running.
And then when it arrives at
trainNumber equals 9, we will
get a false value in the
loops condition and
the loop will stop.
Then it will proceed
to the for-loop.
Now we can see our entire
solution running with two
loops, where we get all of the
running trains printed and
then all of the stopped
trains printed.
Wahoo!
Now you are ready to go do
your own looping in the
challenges.
Now you are ready to go do
your own looping in the
challenges.
And we will see you in
the next section.
- road trip.
And this is level -
[LAUGHTER]
- repeatedly without typing
it all in forever.
- out typing the code
in forever.
- out typing forever.
- without typing forever.
It looks like he's
having a stroke.
[LAUGHTER]
I can't wait to see
the outtakes.
Wait.