Since arrays are, in their very
nature, list-oriented,
you might expect that we could
use a loop to iterate over all
the contents inside
of an array.
And it's true.
They help us out very much.
Let's take a look at
this number list.
So, you can see here that we have
10 numbers in a new array
called numberList.
If we wanted to iterate through
every one of those
numbers in the array, we could
establish a for-loop that
starts at the very first index,
notice that that is 0,
and proceeds all the way through
the very last index.
Notice that that is nine even
though the length of
the array is 10.
Then we could use the
console.log method to produce
a string that says, the value
in cell i, notice we're
referring to the particular
index that we're at, is
numberList i.
And numberList i refers to the
actual contents of the
cell at index i.
Remember not to confuse the
index, which is the position
we're at, with its actual
contents, which is the value.
So, let's kind of take a look at
how this works in action.
So when we start at i equals zero,
our very first index, we'll
ask the question whether i is
less than the length of the
entire array.
And of course, that's true.
And then we retrieve the value
at numberList i, which is two,
and our printout becomes "The
value in cell 0 is 2."
We do the same thing when
we get to index one.
We ask the question, is i less
than numberList.length?
Yes, it is.
And the value in that cell is five,
and so we get "The value in
cell 1 is 5." That procedure
repeats throughout the entire
loop until we get to the actual
length of the array
when our question becomes false,
and we stop the loop.
So, we've looked at arrays
that have a whole lot
of contents in them.
And you might ask the question,
can you have an
array with no contents in it?
Or can you have an array with
cells that are empty?
Yes, you can.
Let's take a look at that.
We can use the undefined value
to create empty cells because
the undefined value just
means no contents.
Looking at our existing numbers
list array, if we
wanted to make cell five empty, we
could just use our regular
cell reference notation with
numbers list five and set that
equal to undefined.
That instantly makes that
cell the fifth index
in the array empty.
So, now that we know how to erase
contents from arrays,
let's see if we can write some
code that will do two things.
We want to count the even
numbers in our numberList, as
well as erase the odd numbers.
Ready?
Here we go.
So, we've got our numberList
array already.
And we know that we're going
to need to count our even
values, so we'll set up a
variable called evenCount that
will gradually count the even
numbers in our array.
Then we'll start our For loop
that progresses through the
array just as our previous
For loop did.
Inside the loop, we need
a way to check if we
have an even number.
If our reference value divided
by two has a remainder of 0, we
will increase the evenCount
variable because we have found
an even number.
But otherwise, if we
don't have an even
number, what do we have?
An odd number.
And so we should erase
that number.
How do we do that?
Well, we say that the numbersList
i, in other words, the
value at the current index,
should be undefined.
And once we have done that, that
value is no longer there.
At the end of this code, we
could also log out the current
evenCount, and that
would be five.
Let's take a look at that
code in action.
When the index is 0, we check to
see if we are still within
the array length, and we are.
So then we get the numberList
value, which is two, and then we
check to see if two is
an even number.
two, of course, is an even number,
and so our evenCount
would advance to one.
This procedure reoccurs
throughout the entire array,
erasing odd values, and counting
the even values.
When we finally get to the end
of the array, the loop stops,
and you can see that we have
an evenCount of five.
What if we were to now log out
our changed numberList?
What would that look like?
Taking a look, we see here that
our array kept all of our
even numbers and erased all of
the odds, but still left empty
cells where the odds
used to be.
Those are represented here
by the undefineds.
And to show that the size of
our array hasn't really
changed at all, we can log out
that using the .length
property to see that the array
is still of length 10.
Now that we know significantly
more about arrays, we're going
to build a function that solves
our initial problem of
building a passenger list.
So, here's our function called
addPassenger, and we know that
that function is going to
need two parameters.
The first is the passenger's
name that we're adding, as
well as the array of passengers
that we want to add
the passenger to.
Inside our function, we know
that if the list is empty, we
may as well just add the
passenger to the list.
We're OK with that.
Otherwise, we know the list is
not empty, and so we need to
find the exact right spot to
put the new passenger.
So, what we do is we iterate
over all spots in our
passenger list, and if the
current spot is empty, we want
to add our current passenger to
that spot since it's empty.
And then we want to
exit the function.
Otherwise, if we've gotten all
the way to the end of the
list, and the passenger still
has not been added, we need to
add that passenger to the
back of the array,
increasing its size.
So that's our pseudocode, let's
see if we can get some
real code in its place.
The first thing we know is
that if the list.length
property is 0, then the
list is empty, right?
So, we can just push
the name of the
passenger onto the list.
Otherwise, the list is not
empty, so we know we're going
to need a loop to check
for empty spots.
Here's our loop.
It looks just like
the other one.
We will proceed through the
entire length of the array
looking for empty spots.
Well, how do we know if
it's an empty spot?
We have to use our
undefined trick.
If the current spot we're
looking at, list i, is the
undefined value, we
know it's empty.
So therefore, we can place the
name of the current passenger
being added in that cell.
Then we can immediately exit
the function because we're
done adding that passenger.
Notice that the return keyword
here has nothing following it.
That's totally acceptable when
you just want to exit the
function with no value.
Now we also have an Else-If
statement that follows that
checks to see if we have
reached the very
last cell of the array.
If we have, what do we know?
We know that we have not reached
an empty spot yet for
this array.
So, we can go ahead and push the
current passenger onto the
back end of the array,
increasing its size.
Then, at the very bottom of the
function, we'll put one
final return list so that we can
ensure that the modified
list has been returned
to the program.
Great.
So, now we've got a
passenger-adding function.
How awesome.
Let's see if we can build a
passenger list from scratch
and start adding some
passengers to it.
Here we go.
So, we'll start a variable called
passengerList list, and
we'll set it up as
an empty list.
We can do that with
just two brackets.
Then we'll call our addPassenger
function, and
we're going to add
Gregg to it.
So you can see our very first
parameter is Gregg Pollack as
a string, followed by our newly
created, but empty,
passengerList.
What gets returned is a new
array with Gregg Pollack as
the very first and only cell.
Then, let's add Ashley
Smith using
the same exact procedure.
What gets returned is our
modified array that has Gregg
in the first spot and Ashley
in the second spot.
We could do it one more
time and put John
in the third spot.
Awesome.
We've got a full list of,
well, three, passengers.
So let's see if we can now
delete some passengers by
building a delete passenger
function.
Here we go.
So we've got our deletePassenger
function.
It's also going to take in
a name and also the list.
You can see that we'll check
if the list length is 0.
That means there's no passengers
in this list, so
how could we possibly delete
anybody from it?
And all we need to log out is
that the "List is empty,
dude!" Otherwise, we'll start
our loop that checks the
entire contents of the array.
Inside the loop, if the cell
that we're currently checking
is the name that we're looking
for, we'll go ahead and set
that cell to be empty, having
removed the passenger.
Then we can return the list
because we don't need to look
for that passenger anymore.
Otherwise, we have an Else-If
here that checks to see if we
have arrived at the
very last cell.
If we have arrived at the very
last cell, but we have deleted
no passenger, that means that
the passenger does not exist
in our current list.
And so we can report, with
a console.log, that the
"Passenger was not found!"
At the very end, we will
also return the list.
Why?
Because if we have returned the
list somewhere else in the
function, we know that our
exterior program is expecting
some kind of list
to be returned.
So, it's good practice to make
sure that we return the list,
whether it has been
modified or not.
So, now we've built both
an addPassenger and a
deletePassenger list.
We have full control of
our passenger list.
Let's go ahead and mess
around with it.
First, we'll take out Ashley
Smith from our existing list.
So our loop seeks through the
array, finds her in the second
cell, and erases her
from that cell.
Notice now that we get a return
of an array that has
the second cell empty.
Then we'll add Adam
to the list.
And notice that our addPassenger
function finds
the very first empty spot
and places Adam
inside that spot first.
Then, we'll try to delete
Ashley again.
Uh, oh.
She's not found.
That's, of course, because
we deleted her before.
Then if we try to delete Gregg,
he'll be removed from
the very first spot.
And then if we try to add
Jennifer, she'll be placed in
Gregg's old spot,
the first cell.
So, now you are an
array master.
Congratulations.
We'll release you to
the challenges.
Good luck.
In there, we could
do [GIBBERISH].
Be able to push a piece
onto the end.
Uh, what?
This is No-Laughing Friday.
No-Laughing Friday.
Oh, I busted it.
[LAUGHTER]
[MUSIC PLAYING]