Hey everyone, and welcome
back to the Road
Trip, JavaScript 2.
If you completed the first
course, you now have an
elementary education in the
basic elements of the
JavaScript language.
In this course, we will be
exploring more of those
fundamental concepts that will
build the skills you need for
your future in web
development.
So all aboard.
Come back and join us on this,
the second course of the
JavaScript Road Trip.
(SINGING) From the Labyrinth
of Loops to the Variable
Valley, we'll see the Cliffs
of Value first. JavaScript's right up
your alley.
Built-ins Bluff, Files Falls,
Array Archipelago.
Declarations in a desert
where you'll find out
how far you'll go.
Learn to program.
Take a  ride.
Buy a ticket. Step inside.
All aboard,
you're at the station to
increase your education.
Bon voyage
and skinny dip! As long as
functions you don't skip, on
this the JavaScript Road Trip.
Hey guys.
Here comes level one, the
Labyrinth of Loops.
Don't get lost.
So, in our last level, we had
some pretty repetitive code
that kind of sucked a lot,
and we want to try to
improve that situation.
A loop is going to allow
us to do that.
The first loop that we'll look
at today is a while-loop.
And the while-loop will run its
code just so long as its
Boolean condition evaluates
to true.
Here, we have a basic while-loop
setup that
includes the while-loop keyword
and then a set of
parentheses.
Inside this parentheses is going
to be an expression.
And if that expression evaluates
to true, the content
of the loop, the code inside
the loop, will execute.
Then, it will go back to the top
of the loop and check the
expression again.
If the expression is still true,
the code inside the loop
will be executed again.
And this will continue until
the condition inside the
parentheses is false.
Now what does this mean?
It means that if we had a
while-loop where we explicitly
wrote "true" as the condition,
that means that while-loop we
could go on forever and
ever, ad infinitum,
and would never stop.
It's called the infinite loop.
Additionally, if we had "false"
hard-coded into the
while-loop, that while-loop
would never run at all.
So, we're good with the true
and the false conditionals
inside a while-loop.
So, now let's make a loop that
prints the numbers one through
five in ascending order.
We need to think about this a
little bit to make sure that
we get the exact right output.
The first thing that
we'll need to do
is establish a variable.
Let's call it a number.
And we will set that number
equal to one, since that's our
starting point.
Now we'll build the
while-loop.
So, here you can see inside the
while-loop that as long as our
number is less than or equal
to five, we will print the
number with the console.log.
And then we will increase
our number's value.
It's important that we increment
the number inside
the loop because it's going to
advance our number through the
numbers that we want to print,
but it's also going to
eventually become greater
than five and
therefore stop the loop.
Now if we were to run this code,
the loop would execute five
times, and within each loop a
number would get printed and
then incremented.
So, now the important thing to
understand about loops is that
they will allow us to execute
code repeatedly without typing
forever, which is
really terrible.
So, what we want to do is try
to apply this to our trains
situation where we wanted to
print a message about which
trains were running.
Here, we want to execute the
following code for every one
of the running trains.
Now, that bracketed word
"number" is just a placeholder
for the number value of the
train that we want to print.
Now we know our variables can be
changed, so let's make one
that will count our trains in
the loop that we're going to
produce for this code.
We're going to set it to one,
because obviously the first
train that we print
will be one.
Then we need a way to make our
train counter increase on
every repetition.
Obviously that will go with our
incrementation code, train
number plus plus.
When we put those code items
together, we can see that the
following code will need to loop
back until all running
trains have been listed.
And we could also say that this
code needs to run as long
as the trainNumber is less than
or equal to eight, because
there are eight running
train today.
Let's trace through the
loop we actually need.
First, we'll initialize our
trainNumber value to one.
This will both help control
the loop and
be used in our printouts.
From there, the loop will only
continue if the trainNumber
is less than or equal to eight.
Then, our loop will actually
execute its contents.
And what are those?
Well, they're printing out our
running train message using
the trainNumber variable inside
a console.log method.
Once that code is finished,
we'll perform the very
important step of incrementing
our trainNumber, which steps
forward to the next train and
will eventually stop our loop.
After incrementing our variable
with trainNumber plus plus,
we'll cycle back up to check
the less than or equal
condition again.
This looping procedure will
continue until the train
number is greater than eight, and
the loop should stop.
Now the while-loop for
this is going to look
something like this.
In there, you can see our
initialization of the train
number one, you could see our
condition to check, which is
the trainNumber less than or
equal to eight, you could see our
printout of the train message,
you could see our
incrementation of the
trainNumber.
Let's take a closer look at the
values that happen when we
run the loop.
The very first thing the train
number gets set to
is the value one.
Is the trainNumber less
than or equal to eight?
Yes it is, so that condition
will be true, and so the loop
output will be "Train #1
is running." After that
gets printed, trainNumber
gets incremented to two.
And the same procedure occurs
all the way through the loop,
printing out new training
numbers until the
trainNumber is nine.
As soon as that happens, train
number is no longer less than
or equal to 8, and so that
condition is false, and the
loop will stop.
Let's migrate our while-loop
over to the trains.js file.
Now in our trains.js file, we
want to use variables instead
of hard coded values to control
our train loop.
Why would we want to do that?
Because not every day
will there be
eight operational trains.
Some days, we will have
operational trains of 10, so
we want to be able to make our
loop respond to the contents
of a variable and not to
a hard-coded value.
So, here we can see that we have
our trains operational
variable set to eight today, and our
trainNumber variable of
course will start at one.
Here's our while-loop.
And notice that inside our
conditional, now we check to
see if the trainNumber is
less than or equal to the
train's operational variable.
That will ensure that on any
given day, as long as the
train's operational variable is
set to the correct amount
of running trains, we will
get the exactly correct
loop of print out.