Is there anybody out there?
All the endpoints are closed.
We haven't any rest
since the zombies arose.
They're getting all
the humans, and then
putting them down,
patching all the clients,
and deleting the town.
Surviving through the night
we need authentication.
The secret to our broadcast
is content negotiation.
They're after all
our brains and we're
biting our nails,
Surviving APIs with Rails.
I'm Carlos Souza,
and you're watching
Surviving APIs with Rails.
In this level, we're going to
be going over rest, routes,
constraints, and namespaces.
But before we dive
into these concepts,
let's take a look at
a web-based service
from the perspective
of an end user.
We're going to look at how a
music streaming service works.
Let's take a look at
an example application
that uses a web API.
This is a music
streaming service,
and it can be accessed from
different applications.
You can access it through a
web browser and, for example,
create a play list--
which you can access later
from a different application,
say, a mobile phone.
The phone connects
to that same playlist
by reading the web API,
which would provide data
for all different
sorts of applications.
Let's explore a little bit how
the communication might happen
back and forth between the web
API and its different clients.
In this example,
we have a client
that first creates a playlist.
That communication
might be something
like a Create command
to a specific thing,
in this case Playlist, passing
a couple of arguments-- song
1, song 2, and song 3.
We get a response
back from the server
that says, OK, here's a
playlist that you've created.
And it's called Playlist 13.
Then later, if we want
to read a playlist,
we can issue commands
like Read /playlist 13/.
Then the server responds with,
OK, songs 1, 2, and 3
belong to that playlist.
And the same thing-- if you
want to read all the playlists
that you have, you can ask the
server to return that for you.
And a response
might be, OK, here's
all the playlists that you
have-- playlists 11, 12,
and 13.
At the same time, if you ask for
a playlist that doesn't exist,
the server might
respond with an error
message saying Invalid Playlist.
The server knows how to respond
to different kinds of requests,
including invalid requests.
Notice the pattern here.
We're talking about
a set of commands
that are performed on things,
which generates responses.
This is the foundation
of a REST API.
As you may know, REST stands
for Representational State
Transfer, which allows
building an infrastructure that
can support different
types of applications
by following a very
strict set of operations.
Throughout this
course, we're going
to be talking all about how
to build REST APIs in Rails,
and some common practices
to keep in mind.
A good starting point
for implementing our API
is a Routes file.
In this example, we have
a resources definition
for zombies.
As you may know, the
Rate Routes command
gives us a bunch of information
related to the resources
that we have available for us.
So we can see all the different
HTTP verbs-- or methods--
listed, and the URIs that
are available for us.
We may not need all
of these routes,
and the resources method
gives us some options
that we can use to restrict
the routes that we have.
This will help us
improve memory use
and can also speed up
the routing process.
Using 'except' here, we can
restrict the 'destroy' action so
when we run RATE
routes, we can see
that the 'destroy'
action is unreachable.
Using the 'only' option, we
can restrict our routes
to only allow the 'index' action.
Both 'only' and
'except' can also take
an array of actions--
in this case,
restricting the
zombies' resource
to only allow for
'index' and 'show' actions,
and the humans' resources do not
allow 'destroy', 'edit' and 'update'.
Here's what our
routes look like.
Here in this routes
file, you can
see that we're using the same
restriction over and over
again.
The 'with_options' method
is an elegant way
to remove duplication
out of a routes file.
Here you can see we're
calling 'with_option'
with 'only: :index' as an argument.
The arguments are
automatically added
to the resources
inside of that block.
You might have seen
before APIs that
reside on its own sub-domain.
And this is smart,
because it allows
us to load balance traffic
at the DNS level, which
is way faster than doing it
at the application level.
Here in our routes
file, we can see
we have the episodes
resources, which
can be accessed through
the top-level domain.
We also have the zombies
and humans resources,
which can only be accessed
through the API sub-domain.
We can do that using
the 'constraints' option,
passing in the sub-domain
that we want to use.
Another way we can write this
is using the 'constraints' method,
that takes the sub-domain as
an argument and our resources
inside of a block.
This technique is
extremely useful
if you're using
the same Rails code
base to serve both a
website and a web API.
Now, before we can run
this in development,
there's a couple
things that we have
to do to our network
configuration.
If you're using
OS X or Linux, you
want to edit your
ETC hosts file.
Inside of that
file, we're going
to map our local network
interface-- which
is 127.0.0.1-- to URLs that
we can use in development.
A pattern that I like
to use is to append
-dev to whatever
website I'm working on.
In this example,
cs-zombies.com
is the production URL.
So we're going to create
cs-zombies-dev.com
for the
top-level domain,
and API.cs-zombies-dev.com
in the API sub-domain.
The following URLs are now
available on our local machine.
Keep in mind that the port
number is still required.
Other alternatives to do
this are tools like POW,
or services like
LVH.me, which we're not
going to go over in this
course, but here's the URL
so you can check it out.
Going back to our
previous Routes file,
let's see how we can keep our
controllers a little bit more
organized.
In this example, all
of our controllers
are under the same
namespace, which
means under the same folder,
which might be a little bit
confusing once you start adding
more classes to your project.
To fix this, we can create
a separate namespace just
for API controllers.
As you can see,
our API controllers
are now under the API folder.
We now have our
zombies' resources,
which are part of
the API namespace.
This means that when we define
our zombies controller class,
it needs to go inside
of the API module.
And that file needs to go
under the API directory.
Our pages controller, which
is not part of our API,
still remains at the
top-level main space.
Enforcing both the
sub-domain constraint
and an API namespace gives
us the following URI,
which is kind of ugly.
There's unnecessary duplication.
We're repeating API
both at the sub-domain
and as part of our path.
We can fix that by passing a
Path option to our namespace,
specifying route-- just '/'
This way we strip out
the API part of our URI,
but still preserve
the namespace,
which looks much better.
We can use a shorter syntax by
passing both the constraints
and path as options to
the namespace method.
You might have noticed
that when we defined
our zombies controller class,
we wrote our API module
in CamelCase, which
is Rails' default
convention for naming classes.
But it's kind of weird,
because we typically
write acronyms all in caps.
But if we try writing API all
in caps, it wouldn't work.
To make it work, we
need to add an entry
to our inflections file for API.
Now we can write our
API module all in caps,
which makes it a little
bit easier to read.
So that's it for Level One.
Now get ready for
some challenges.