[SINGING] Is there
anybody out there?
All the endpoints are closed.
We haven't any rest
since the zombies arose.
They're getting all
the humans and then
putting them down,
hatching all the clients
and deleting the town.
Surviving through the night,
we need authentication.
The secret to our broadcast
is content negotiation.
They're after all our brains
and we're biting our nails.
Surviving APIs with Rails.
My name is Carlos
Souza and you're
watching Surviving
APIs with Rails.
In this level, we're
going to be looking
at resources and the GET method.
REST is all
about the resources.
Pretty much anything that can be
given a name can be a resource.
For example, a Music
Playlist, a Song,
The leader of the
Zombie horde, Survivors,
and Remaining Medical Kits,
are all examples of resources.
Quoting Steve Klabnik
on this, a resource
is a conceptual mapping
to a set of entities,
not the entity that
corresponds to the mapping
at any particular point in time.
If that sounds a little
confusing, don't worry.
Let's see how that
looks in practice.
First, let's understand
how the GET method works.
We use the GET method
to retrieve information
from a given URI.
For example, to read
a specific playlist,
a client issues a GET request to
/playlist/13, which is the URI.
The server then might
respond with OK.
And return all the songs
that belong to that playlist.
Two important characteristics
about the GET method
is that it's safe.
Meaning that it should
not take any action
other than retrieval.
It should not create or update
any resources on the server.
And it's also
idempotent, which means
that sequential GET
requests to the same URI
should not cause
any side effect.
The best way to understand how
the GET method works in Rails
is by writing tests.
Integration tests, also
known as black box,
simulate how API
clients are going
to interact with
our API server.
So here we have a routes
file with the API namespace
in a constraint
for the API sub-domain.
We're going to start
writing an integration
test for listing our zombies.
The first thing
that we have to do
is called the host bang method.
This is required for
testing with sub-domains.
Rails uses the
example.com domain,
whenever it runs your
application and test.
So we need to override that
with our specific sub-domain.
In this case, api.example.com.
Once we do that, we can start
writing our actual tests.
Our first test is going
to list all the zombies.
We use the GET method,
which issues a GET request
to the given URI, /zombies.
First thing we do is
create an assertion
for the status code,
which needs to be 200.
The 200 status code means that
the request has succeeded.
The 200 status
code also indicates
that the response should include
the resource in the response
body.
Another way we can write this
assertion is by using a helper
method from Rack Utils,
assert response.success?,
which is the same thing.
Whenever you see
this symbol up here,
it means that we're
learning a new status code.
This other symbol
means that we're
talking about a test file.
And because we're going
to be going back and forth
between writing
a test that fails
and writing the production
code to make that task pass,
we have this little
badge here at the top
that indicates whether the
task is passing or not.
If you haven't seen test
code like this before,
I highly recommend you check
out Rails Testing for Zombies,
a code school
course that teaches
you all the basics on test unit.
Let's implement our
resource listing.
Inside of our
zombies controller,
which is part of the API module,
we created the index action.
Inside of that, we start
by fetching all the zombies
and returning them as JSON.
Behind the scenes, Rails is
calling the to_json method,
which serializes all the
properties of all our zombies
to JSON like this.
If we call to_json on
a single zombie object,
it would serialize
just that one object.
By default, Rails returns a 200
response for calls to render.
But we can be a little
bit more explicit
and pass the status code as
the second option to render.
The to_json method
is built into Rails,
but it doesn't scale well when
your logic for serializing
objects gets too complex.
For more advanced solution for
serialized objects to JSON,
you might want to check out
ActiveModel Serializers.
For representing
resources on the URL,
Rails uses what is called
Path Segmented Expansion which
means that arguments in the URI
are separated using a slash.
For example, when you want
a fetch a specific zombie,
you add /zombie/:id to the URI.
And the same thing for
any additional arguments.
This means that if you
access /zombies?id=1,
it will not be routed
to Zombies#show
but to Zombies#index.
Most URIs will not depend
on query string parameters,
but it's OK to use
them sometimes.
One example is filters.
In this case, we're
listing all the zombies,
but filtering for only those
whose weapon is an axe.
Or searches, if
we want to search
for all the zombies
with the keyword John.
And also for
pagination, if we want
to list all the zombies in page 2
with 25 zombies per page.
So let's implement this filter
that you see here on top.
And we'll start
by writing a test.
First, in our set
up we need to tell
that our host is going to
be using the API sub-domain.
In our test block,
we want to return
zombies filtered by weapon.
First is John, whose
weapon is an axe.
Second is Joanna, whose
weapon is a shotgun.
For now, our object creation
logic is pretty simple.
But if it gets too
verbose or too complex,
it's OK to move on to using
fixtures or another solution
like FactoryGirl.
Next, we checked
for the status code.
Now, we need to parse
out the response
body that was returned.
We use JSON.parse for that,
passing a symbolize_names
option.
This option will convert the
keys of the hash from strings
to symbols, which
is how we typically
work with hashes in Ruby.
We loop over the zombie
names that are returned
and make sure that John, which
is the zombie with the weapon,
is included.
And Joanna, which is a
zombie with a shotgun,
is not included.
We haven't implemented
this feature yet,
so our tests are
currently failing.
Inside of our API,
ZombiesController,
we start by fetching
all of the zombies.
Then, we check for
a weapons parameter.
If it's present, we're going
to filter our query only
to the zombies with
that specific weapon.
If you're wondering
about Zombie.all
issuing a query to
the database, remember
that starting in
Rails 4 the all method
returns a chainable
scope, which allows
us to add filters dynamically.
Like we're doing here.
Lastly we'll return our zombies
as JSON with the status 200,
which makes our test pass.
Now let's see how we can
retrieve one specific zombie.
And we'll start by
writing the test.
So, we create a zombie
record named Joanna.
And we issue a GET
request to that zombie ID,
which gets routed
to Zombies#show.
We check for a 200
status code and again, we
parse the response body back.
Lastly, we check that
the name that we got back
in the response matches
the name of the object
that we just created.
With the test failing, we
move on to the implementation.
On our API ZombiesController,
we create the show action,
fetch the zombie by its ID, and
return it's JSON representation
with the status 200--
which makes our test pass.
Another way that we
can define this status
is instead of using
the number 200,
we can use the OK symbol,
which is the same thing.
Visit this URL for a list
of all numeric status codes
and symbols that are
supported by Rails.
Let's go back to our
test file and see
how we can clean
it up a little bit.
You may have noticed that
we're using this JSON.parse
method over and over
again, across all
our different integration tests.
So we're going to extract
that into a helper method.
It's going to look
like this, simply
JSON which takes the
(response.body) as an argument.
To implement this method, we
go back to our test helper
file and place it inside of the
active support test case class.
We can now use this method
across all our different tests.
Another helpful way that we can
test our API as we develop it,
is using the Curl command.
Curl is a command line tool that
allows this to issue real HTTP
requests over the network.
To use it, we call Curl
from the command line,
passing the URL as an argument.
And it defaults to a
GET request to that URL.
A lot of tools use Curl as part
of the installation process,
which you might
have used before.
For example, rvm.
So here's the results that we
get from running this command.
It displays the response
body on the terminal.
Curl is shipped
with OS X and Linux,
but there's also Windows
installer available.
Curl also works fine with query
strings, as you can see here.
If we want to display
the response headers,
we can use the -I option.
We've reached the
end of level two.
Time to jump into some
challenges on resources
and GET.