[SINGING] Is there
anybody out there,
all the endpoints are closed.
We haven't any rest
since the zombies arose.
They're getting all
the humans and then
putting them down,
patching all the clients
and deleting the town.
Surviving through the night
we need authentication.
The secret to our broadcast
is content negotiation.
They're after all our brains
and we're biting our nails.
Surviving APIs with Rails.
I'm Carlos Souza, and you're
watching surviving APIs
with Rails.
In this level, we're going to
be covering content negotiation.
Web APIs need to cater to
different types of applications
that understand
different formats.
For example, a
mobile application
might ask for the
response in JSON.
An enterprise application might
ask for the response in XML.
Ha ha!
Business!
A third application might
ask for a different format
HTML in a completely
different language.
So the process in which client
and server determine the best
representation for the response
is called content negotiation.
The same web API should be
able to respond properly
to all of these three different
types of applications.
Rails gives us a nice
way to play around
with the different formats by
changing the URI extension.
If we want our zombies
in JSON format,
we can simply say .json or
for XML, we can say .xml.
And that's what
the format option
means in our routes.
The ability to play around
with the extension is
a nicety from Rails
and it's not a standard.
So do not write API clients
that rely on this feature.
The proper way to
request specific formats
is by using the accept header.
Let's see what that looks
like by writing a test.
In this test, we
want to make sure
that our API is able
to return zombies
both in JSON and in XML.
We start with a GET
request for Zombies.
The second argument
to the GET method
is the parameters that we want
to send along with the request.
For now, we don't
want to send anything.
The third argument to the GET
request is the request headers.
So that's where we're going
to place our accept header
set to Mime::JSON.
Telling the server that
we want JSON format.
MIME types, which are
now called media types,
specify this scheme for the
resource representation.
Then we check for the
proper status code of 200.
And finally, we
check that the server
was able to respond
with the proper format
by looking at the
content type header.
Now we'll do the
same thing for XML,
but instead of passing Mime::JSON
on the accept header,
we use mine XML.
So now let's implement
and make the test pass.
Here we are in the
zombies controller.
And you might notice
that this class is not
under the API module anymore.
This is because from
now on our application
is strictly serving a
web API, not a website.
Well define the index action,
then fetch all the zombies.
Then, we'll use the
respond_to method
which allows us to control
the different types of formats
that our application
will respond to.
Inside of that, we'll
implement our JSON response
sending back the zombies
with a status code 200.
And this is what the response
body looks like in JSON.
If we look at the
response headers,
we'll notice that
Content-Type is
set to the proper
application/json media type.
Checking response headers is
super useful when debugging.
Next, let's make
our index action
respond to the XML format.
The code looks very similar.
And here's what the response
body looks like in XML.
Again, if we check
the response headers,
we'll see the
content type header
was set to
application/xml.
So does this mean that I can
simply do format.anything
and Rails knows what to do?
Well, not quite.
Rails ships with 21 different
media types out of the box.
If you want to list them all,
you can fire up your Rails
console and type Mime::SET which
will list all supported media
types.
Here you can see all the
different media types
in a more readable output.
So our test now passed.
We can also use
Curl to make sure
that our application responds
to the different formats.
To send custom headers, we
use the -H option followed
by the header that
we want to send.
In this case,
"Accept: application/json".
We can see that the response
is 200 OK and that the content
type in the response is
set to application/json,
the JSON format.
And the same thing for XML.
If we send the header
"Accept: application/xml",
the response we get back
sets the content type
to application/xml.
Why don't you play
around a little bit
with negotiating
media types before we
move on to the next section?