Now it's time to take a look
at how to negotiate responses
in different languages.
We'll start out with a test.
We want to return the list
of zombies in English.
For language negotiation, we
use the accept language request
header.
Inside of our
test block, our get
request is going to set the
accept language to English, 'en'.
We also want to make sure that
the response format is JSON.
So there's the accept header
that we've just seen before.
We make sure the status
code in the response is 200.
We parse back the
response body and verify
that the message is
written in English.
Watch out for Zombie name.
Let's write another
test to make sure
that our API is also able
to respond to Portuguese.
We set accept language
header to 'pt-BR'
and then make sure that the
message is in Portuguese.
Cuidado com,
The zombie name.
With the test failing, let's
move on to implement this.
To implement
internationalization,
we'll jump into our
application controller
and create a before
action called set_locale.
Inside of the set
locale method, we'll
set the language
from the value that's
passed in the accept
language header.
We can use the
request.headers method
to access request headers.
Inside of a zombie's
controller, we
need to change a couple things.
We're still calling format.json,
but instead of using a block,
we're going to use
a j builder template
to customize our response.
J builder is a
library that provides
a DSL for customizing
JSON responses.
Inside of our template, we have
access to the JSON object,
which you can use to
build up our response.
First method recall
is array, which
insures that a JSON
array is returned.
Then we pass in a
block that takes
each zombie as an argument.
For each zombie, we'll use the
properties ID, named, and age.
And we also want to add another
property called message, which
will be our internationalize
message that we sent back
to our client.
Will use the I18NT method,
which stands for translation.
Passing in a key,
which will be used
to look up the translation.
We also passing the zombie
name as a second argument.
In order to get this
to work, we need
to build our translations file.
The English translation
files provided to us by Rails
and it's under
config/locales/en.yml.
We add an entry for
a zombie message,
passing in our
message in English,
and a placeholder for the name.
This is the syntax used
for interpolation inside
of our locale templates.
That gives us the
response in English.
For the response in Portuguese,
we need to create another file
under config/locales/pt-BR.yml.
We add an entry for
our zombie message
with a message in Portuguese
in the same placeholder.
That generates the
response in Portuguese.
And now our test passed.
We've just looked at one
way that we can add support
to our API for negotiating
different languages.
Our current implementation
is very simple
and it's not fully
compliant with HTTP spec.
Which very few API are.
But if you're looking for
a more robust solution,
I suggest you check out
the HTTP_Accept_Language
gem, which comes with a
bunch of additional features.
Like for example, it sanitizes
the list of preferred languages,
its sorts the list of
preferred languages,
and it finds the best one in
case multiple languages
are supported.
Here's an example of using
the gem. To use the gem,
you simply add it to
gem file, run bundle,
and then you have access
to the HTTP accept language
object, which you
can call methods on.
For example the compatible
language from method,
which takes as an argument
the available locales,
looks into the accept
language header
and returns the first
language compatible with it.
We've reached the end
of the second part
of content negotiation.
Now you're ready to do some
challenges for negotiating
languages and I'll see
you in the next level.