[SINGING] Is there
anybody out there?
All the end points are closed.
We haven't any rest
since the zombies arose.
They're getting all the humans
and then putting them down.
Patching all their clients
and deleting the town.
Surviving through the night,
we need authentication.
The secret to our broadcast
is content negotiation.
They're after all our brains
and we're biting our nails.
Surviving APIs with Rails.
My name is Carlos Souza, and
you're watching Surviving APIs
With Rails. In this level,
we're going to look at the post
method.
The post method is used
for creating resources
on the server.
For example, if we want
to create a new playlist,
we issue a post method
on the playlist URI,
passing in the songs that we
want to add to that playlist.
We get a response back
from the server saying
whether our request
was successful or not,
along with the playlist
that was just created.
One thing to note
about the post method
is that it's neither
safe or idempotent.
You might have seen
this confirmation
before in your
browser window, which
is a way of the
browser asking, are
you really sure you
want to do this again?
Because it will
resubmit post requests
that were already submitted.
For example, it might
issue an additional payment
if you're in a payment window.
Or it might create
another record on a record
that you've just created.
According to the HTTP
spec, a couple things
are expected from a
successful post request.
First, the status
code for the response
should be 201-Created, which
means that the request has been
fulfilled and resulted in a
new resource being created.
The response body should
include a representation
of the new resource.
And finally, the
Location response header
should be set with the
location of the new resource.
Let's start by writing a test
to see what this looks like.
Our test needs to
make sure that we
are able to create new episodes.
We start by issuing
a post request
to our episode's resource.
We need to send a representation
of the new episode resource,
and we're going to
do it using JSON.
To do that, we passed in
a hash with the properties
of our new episode.
And we must call to
JSON on that hash.
We need to tell the server that
we expect a response in JSON.
And we do that by using
the Accept header.
And we also need
to tell the server
how to parse the content
of our post request.
And we do that with the
Content-Type request
header set to Mime::JSON.
Notice that we need to
call 2_s for this one.
We checked that the
response is 201, for created,
that the content type of
the response is JSON,
we parse the episode return
to the response body,
and we check the Location
response header to make sure
that it's pointing to its URL.
With the test failing, we
move on to the implementation.
Inside of our Create action
in our Episodes Controller,
we build a new Episode Object
by using the episode params
method.
Inside of this method,
we use strong parameters
to whitelist the data that
comes in from the client.
Then, we save our
episode to the database,
return its JSON representation,
set the response status code
to 201, and add a
location header,
set to the new episode's URL.
All we have to do is send
in the ActiveRecord Object
to location, and it resolves to
the full URL for the resource.
For the Status code, instead
of using the 201 number,
we could also use the
created symbol here.
Then, we run our test again.
And it passes.
Let's see how we can
use Curl to issue a post
request to our API.
In this example, we
use the -i option
which means that we want to
see the response headers along
with the response body.
Then, the -X
option, which allows
us to specify the method that
we want our request to use.
In this case, we're
going to use a post.
And -d which allows
us to send data along
with the request.
And finally the URL
for our API server.
When we run this
command, we expect
it to work because the tests
that we just wrote are passing.
But to our surprise, the
command doesn't work.
And, instead, returns a
422 unprocessable entity.
Why is that?
A 422 unprocessable entity
means that the client submitted
a request that was well-formed
but semantically invalid.
Turns out Rails checks
for an authenticity token
on methods like POST, PUT, PATCH
and DELETE, pretty much
any method that's not GET.
And this is to prevent
cross-site request forgery
attacks on web apps.
So why didn't our tests
catch that a moment ago?
Well, this feature
is disabled in Tests.
So if we look under a
config/enviroments/test.rb file,
you can see this line
here which is the reason
that we didn't catch
this error in testing.
Since our Rails application is
going to be strictly serving
an API, we can change the
protect from forgery method
from exception to null_session.
It's a common practice
for APIs to be stateless.
This means that
post requests really
shouldn't be relying
on a session at all.
So what the null
session option does
is that it allows to post
requests with an invalid
authenticity token to go through
and not use the session at all.
Now, when we repeat
our Curl command,
we're able to create
a new episode.
And we get a successful
response back.
Not all successful responses
need to send back content.
Ajax responses,
for example, can be
made a lot faster
with no response body.
Let's change our create
action to do this.
Instead of responding
with our episode in JSON,
we're going to use nothing: true,
which returns an empty response
body.
We need to set the
status code to 204.
204 No Content responses
means the server
has fulfilled the
request, but does not
need to respond
with an entity body.
Lastly, we return the
location of the episode.
Another way we can create
responses with no content,
is by using the Head method.
The Head method creates
responses consisting solely
of HTTP headers.
So instead of
Render, we call Head,
passing in the 204 status code.
The Head method can
also take arguments
which we'll use to
patch in the location.
Instead of 204, we can
also say, head :no_content.
Testing unsuccessful
requests is just
as important as testing
successful ones.
We don't want our API to
be able to create episodes
with the title set to 'nil'.
So let's create a test for that.
We start off by
calling the Post method
to the Episodes Resources.
We patch in the representation
of an episode with the title
set to 'nil'.
Everything else
you've seen before.
But now, we want to test
for a status code of 422.
So remember, 422 means
an error occurred,
and the client is to blame.
With our test failing,
we're ready to implement
this functionality.
First, in our Episode model, we
add the validation for title.
And in our EpisodesController
Create action,
we add an else block.
Which returns the
episode errors in JSON
which can help API
clients figure out
what the cause of the error was.
Finally, we set
the status to 422
which can also be written
using the unprocessable_entity
symbol.
Now, our test should pass.
What happens when you
issue a request to an API
and it happens to hit
some buggy code which
causes some weird
internal server error?
Rails automatically
handles that for you.
And it returns a 500 response.
So the difference between
internal server error
and the 422 error
that we just saw,
is that the latter is
caused by the client.
An internal server
error is caused
by some unexpected
behavior on the server.
And the best way to
prevent against that,
is by writing tests.
So when we try to issue
a request, passing
in an invalid resource, the
server responds with the 422.
But when we issue a valid
request and something goes
wrong on the server
side of things,
we get a 500
internal server error
back, which is a way
of gracefully handling
the unexpected.
So remember, the 500
internal server error
means that the
server encountered
an unexpected condition
which prevented it
from fulfilling the request.
So it's time for challenges now.
And I'll see you back in a bit.