Welcome back.
In this level, we're going to
be looking at PUT and PATCH.
PUT and PATCH are used
for updating resources.
But what's the difference
between one and the other?
According to HTTP
spec, we're supposed
to use the PUT method to
send along the resource that
will replace the current
resource under a specific URI.
The problem with that
is that in Rails, we
use the PUT method
for partial updates.
Up until version 3,
Rails didn't quite
follow along with HTTP spec and
used PUT for partial updates.
Starting in version
4, Rails added support
for the PATCH method, which
according to the HTTP spec,
is used for requests that
contain a list of differences
between the resource that's on
the server and the one that's
being sent along
with the request.
There's still support
for the old PUT method.
And both PUT and
PATCH are routed
to the update action
of a given resource.
Let's add support for updating
our episodes resource.
The first thing we're going
to do is write a test.
In our setup block, we're
going to create an episode.
We'll then use the
PATCH method and use
that episodes ID in the URI.
We'll pass along an episode
hash with the new title
as the second argument.
As a third argument,
we're going to specify
that we're expecting JSON back
and that the content that we're
sending is also JSON.
We check back
for 200 response.
Lastly, we called
the reload method
on episode, which causes it to
be reloaded from the database
and populated with
the latest data.
Now, that we have
a failing test.
Let's move on to
the implementation.
In the update action on
our episodes controller,
we first grab the record
from the database.
Then we call
the update method
with the params that were
passed in from the client.
The update method,
which is formerly
known as update
attributes, only updates
values that differed
from the existing record.
We then return the JSON
representation of the episode
along with the 200 status code,
which makes our test pass.
Now, let's write a test for
an unsuccessful PATCH request.
We want to prevent our
API from updating episodes
when the title is too short.
So similar to our
previous test, we
call the PATCH method
using that episode's ID
as part of the URI,
we pass the episode content
as the second argument,
this test block looks very
similar to the previous one,
except that now we're passing
in an invalid title, short.
We check for 422
status code back.
That test doesn't pass, we
move on to the implementation.
Next thing we do, in
our episode model,
we add a validation
for the title,
and we need to
make sure that it's
at least 10 characters long.
Now in the update action
in our episodes controller,
we return the episodes error
along with the 422 status
code, which makes our test pass.
The last method that we're
going to be looking at
is the DELETE method.
The DELETE method is used
when the client is not
Interested in the
resource anymore.
We start by writing a test.
In our setup block, we
create a new episode.
And then, we're
going to test that we
were able to delete
that existing episode.
We use the DELETE method
and that episode's ID
as part of the URI.
Then, we check for
a 204 status code,
which means that we're
expecting a successful response.
But we're not expecting
a response body back.
So our tests failed.
Now, there's a
couple different ways
that the server can
implement the DELETE method.
The first one is by destroying
the record from the database.
So we create a destroy action
in our episode's controller.
We fetch the record
from the database.
And we call the DESTROY method.
Using the HEAD method, we
return a 204 response back.
Our test passed, and this record
was removed from the database.
If you try fetching it again,
we run into an ActiveRecord,
RecordNotFound error.
Another way that we can
implement the DELETE method
is instead of destroying the
record from the database,
we'll simply flag
it as archived.
This is useful
when we don't want
to delete records
from the database.
Perhaps for auditing
purposes, we
need to go back and
look at old data.
In our episode
model we'll create
a new method called archive.
Inside of this
method, we're going
to set an attribute archived to
true and then save the record.
We'll also create a new finder
method called find_unarchived,
which takes an ID and, inside of
that, uses the find_by method.
And inside of that
method, we look
for the record with that ID
but with archived set to false.
This way, we'll return records
only if they are not archived.
Going back to our
destroy action,
we now use the new
find_unarchive method
to fetch the record
from the database
and archive it using
the new archive method.
Archive does not call
destroy, so that record still
lives in the database.
And we can have access to
it if we really need to.
And finally, we return
a headers only response
with the 204 status code,
and our test still passed.
We need to remember
to use the new finders
from other controller actions.
For example, the
show action needs
to use the new
find_unarchived method,
and index action needs to
fetch only the records that
were not archived.
You've reached the
end of this level,
so get ready for
some more challenges.