[SINGING] Is there
anybody out there?
All the endpoints are closed.
We haven't any rest
since the zombies arose.
They're getting all
the humans and then
putting them down,
patching all the clients
and deleting the town.
Surviving through the night,
we need authentication.
The secret to our broadcast
is content negotiation.
They're after all our brains
and we're biting our nails.
Surviving APIs With Rails.
I'm Carlos Souza,
and you're watching
Surviving APIs with Rails.
In this level, we're going to
be looking at API versioning.
Once your API is
deployed to production
and then you have clients
that start relying on it,
you have to be very cautious
about introducing changes.
API versioning helps prevent
major changes to your API
from breaking these
existing clients.
Let's say your API
is in production
and you start having
clients relying on it.
For example, client
A and client B.
If you need to introduce
a breaking change
to your service, you don't
want to force existing clients
to adapt to that
change right away.
If you have any
new features, you
don't want to introduce
that in version one.
Instead you want to create
another version, a newer
version, version two.
Old clients will need
to adapt to version two,
so they won't be able
to use it right away.
But they can still
rely on version one
and keep functioning it.
On the other hand, new
clients can join in
and start using
version two of your API
and use the latest features.
API versioning is a
very controversial topic
in the REST community, and there
are different ways to do it.
The takeaway is we should avoid
introducing breaking changes as
much as possible
so that versioning
doesn't become a big issue.
The first strategy
for API versioning
that we're going to be
looking at is using the URI.
Our application now needs to
support two different versions
of our zombies resources.
Using the namespace
method, we're
going to create namespace
for v1 and namespace for v2.
Namespaces can help
us isolate controllers
for the different versions.
They also affect the URL.
For version one, the URL for
our zombies resources is going
to be /v1/zombies.
For version two, /v2/zombies.
Before we go any further,
let's run a routes test.
Routes test helps
ensure that URIs
are mapped to the proper
controller actions.
Using the assert generates
method, we pass in /v1/zombies,
and we need to make sure
that it's properly routed
to the controller under
v1/zombies in the action index.
For /v2/zombies, it needs to
map to v2/ZombiesController
in the action index.
The assert_generates
method asserts
that the provided
options can be used
to generate the expected path.
You run that test and it fails.
To make our test pass, we
implement V1 ZombiesController
and V2 ZombiesController.
Each controller lives under
its own version namespace.
Test pass.
Now let's see how we can reuse
code across different versions.
In this example, we have
a V1 ZombiesController
with a before action that reads
the remote IP from the API
client, sets it to the remote
IP instance variable, and uses
that to compose the JSON
respond that it send back.
That same before
action is repeated
for V2 ZombiesController.
So how might we remove
this duplication?
Before we do anything,
let's write a test.
In our set up block, we populate
the IP instance variable
with a dummy IP value.
The first test issues a
get request to /v1/zombies,
passing the IP set to the
remote ADDR request header.
In real life this remote ADDR
is set by your web server.
We assert that the response
and get back is a 200
and that the response body
includes the value for that IP
followed by the
string version one.
In a similar way, the test
for /v2 is supposed to return
the string for version two.
So we issue a get request as
/v2/zombies passing in the same
IP value.
We check for 200 status
code back, and finally
check that the response body
includes the IP value followed
by the Version Two string.
Notice that the API
version is part of the URI.
This is important.
Now that we have a
failing test, let's
see how we can make it pass.
So we're going to extract
the common code out
of those two controllers and
into a common base API class.
And because our app
strictly serves a web API,
we can use the application
controller for that.
So the before action now in
our application controller
is going to run
before all actions
across controllers
of all versions.
This is enough to
get our test to pass.
But we go back to
our ZombiesController
on both versions and remove
the before actions from those.
The remote IP instance
variable is now
being sent from
application controller
and our tests still pass.
Let's look at another example.
But now we're using a feature
that's specific to one version.
In this example, we have
a V2 ZombiesController
with the before action
audit_logging_for_V2.
That same before
action is repeated
for V2 EpisodesController.
Unlike we did with
the previous example,
we can't simply extract
that before action
to application
controller, because we
don't want this auditing
running for all versions,
just for version two.
What we can do
instead is to create
a base class that's
specific to version two.
We're going to call it V2
VersionController, which
inherits from
application controller.
And we're going to
move our before action
inside of this class.
Because VersionController's
a base class
and it's not supposed to
expose actions of its own,
we're going to call
the abstract method.
Using abstract also makes your
code easier to understand.
Because next time a
developer looks at this class
and sees the abstract
call, they'll
know right away that this
is purely a base class.
Finally, we need to
add this new class
as a base class for our
version 2 controllers.
So V2 ZombiesController
and V2 EpisodesController
both inherit from
version controller.
We've reached the
end of the section,
so get ready for some
challenges on URI versioning.