Welcome back.
We're now going to look
at another option we
can use to version our API, this
time using the Accept header.
As we've seen before,
the Accept header
is used to request
specific media types.
So, media types
that we've worked
are application/json
for the JSON format,
and application/xml for XML.
We're now going to create
a customize MIME type where
the API version is
going to be part of it.
We're going to call our custom
media type, "apocalypse."
And here's what is
going to look like.
Let's break it down, and go
over the different parts.
The application part
means that the payload
is application-specific.
The vnd.apocalypse means
that the media type
is vendor-specific, so it's not
part of the official HTTP spec.
Then, followed by the
version that we want to use,
and finally, +json means
that the response format
for discussing media
type should be JSON.
Before we implement any of
this, let's write a test.
So we're going to reuse
the test that we just wrote
in the previous
section, but adapt it
to use a custom media type.
In our test for version one,
instead of a get request,
as /v1/zombies, we're going to
issue a get request to, simply,
/zombies.
We'll specify the API version
by populating the Accept header
with the value application,
vmdb.apocalypse.v1+json.
We check for a 200 status
back, for our string containing
the value for the IP,
followed by version one.
Finally, we check
that the response's
content type JSON instead
of our custom media type.
This makes it easier for
different API clients
to work with,
especially in regards
to parsing the response back.
Our test for version two
is pretty much the same,
except that the MIME
type now specifies v2.
With our test failing, we
move on to the implementation.
We're going to create a
route constraint class that's
going to look into
the Accept header
and determine what version
the client is specifying.
Our API version class is
going to be initialized
with the specific
version that we want,
and whether that's the
default version or not.
we'll implement the matches
question mark method,
which states a request as an
argument and returns a Boolean.
If this happens to be
the default version,
we return right away.
Otherwise, we need to
check the Request header.
So we check the
Accept header to see
that the media type
contained there
matches a specific
version number.
Let's see how we can use this
class from our routes file.
The API version class
lives under the Lib folder.
Back in our routes file, the
first thing that we have to do
is to require our
API version class.
Because we're now passing
a constraint object,
the syntax is going to look
a little bit different.
First, we call the scope
method, passing module v1
as the first argument.
Then, the constraint
for that scope
is going to be an API
version object set to v1.
For v2, we do the
same, but instead we
create an API version
object that's set to v2.
We also pass true as the
second argument, which
means that v2 will be
the default version.
Last thing, because
we're not going
to be dealing with
content negotiation,
we need to set a default
format to respond with,
which in this case
is going to be JSON.
This applies to v1
and v2, so we need
to make sure that our JSON
format wraps both of them.
With these changes, our
tests are partially passing.
We need to make one last
change to our routes test.
Because we are no longer
including the API version
as part of the URI, there is
really only one test that we
can write in our routes test,
which is to make sure that
/zombies defaults to version two.
So using assert_generates,
we make sure that /zombies is
routed to v2/zombies
controller in the index action.
Our API version class is a
very basic implementation
of checking the Accept header
for proper API version.
If you need a more robust
solution with more features,
you might want to check
out the Versionist gem.
We've reached the
end of this level,
so get ready for more
challenges on API
versioning using
the Accept header.