[SINGING] Is there anybody out there?
All the endpoints are closed.
We haven't any rest
since the zombies arose.
They're getting all the humans
and then putting them down.
Patching all the clients
and deleting the toes.
Surviving through the night,
we need authentication.
The secret to our broadcast
is content negotiation.
They raptored all our brains
and we're biting our nails.
Surviving APIs with Rails.
I'm Carlos Souza,
and you're watching
Surviving APIs With Rails.
In this level, we're going to be
looking at API authentication.
Authentication is how servers
prevent unauthorized access
to protected resources.
For example, our
server might need
to prevent public access to
a user-specific payments.
So if Client A tries to access
payments for a specific user,
but they don't send
along proper credentials,
they'll get access denied.
Client B, on the other hand,
with the correct credentials,
has access to that
same resource.
We're going to be
looking at two ways
that we can implement
authentication on our API.
The first one is basic auth.
In basic auth,
credentials must be
provided using the
Authorization header.
This is what a request
using basic auth looks like.
We can see Authorization header
with the basic word, followed
by a Base64encoding of
the user's credentials.
Basic auth is part of the
HTTP spec under the RFC2617.
Credentials for basic auth are
expected to be Base64 encoded.
Let's see what that looks like.
For example, we get the
user name - in this case,
foo - followed by colon, followed
by the password - in this case,
secret.
We Base64 encode it,
and it looks like that.
If we want to try this in a Ruby
console, all we'd have to do
is require the base 64
library, and call the encode
64 method, with the
credentials as an argument.
Before we implement basic
auth, let's write a test.
In our set up block,
we create a user,
with username, foo,
and password, secret.
Our first ask will be for a
valid username and password.
So we issue a get request
to /episodes,
passing the Base64
encoded credentials
as the value for the
Authorization header.
We check for a
200 response back.
Our next test is going to
be for missing credentials.
So issuing a get request
to /episodes
without any
credentials is supposed
to return a 401 response back.
401 stands for
unauthorized status code.
With our test failing, we
move on to the implementation.
Turns out, Rails has built
in support for basic auth.
In our EpisodesController
we are
going to create a before
action, called authenticate.
Inside of the
authenticate method,
we're going to call the
authenticate or requests
with HTTP basic method
built into Rails, which
reads and decodes username and
password from the Authorization
header.
This method takes a
block with two arguments,
that we can use to call
our custom authentication
strategy, in this case
user.authenticate.
And this is enough to
get our task to pass.
Let's go back to
our test and see
how it can remove the
hard coded credentials.
First thing we do is, we
create an encode method that
takes the username and
password as an argument.
Inside of that method, we're
going to use action controller
HTTP authentication basic
dot encode credentials,
which is a helper
method from Rails.
that takes username and
password and returns
the encoded credentials.
Our task should
still be passing.
We can take this
one step further
and move our encode method
to our test helper file,
so that it can be used
across all different tests.
And our test file,
looks a lot cleaner.
All we have to do is call our
encode credentials method,
and our task should
still be passing.
So let's take a
closer look at what
a 401 unauthorized
response looks like.
Unauthorized HTTP
responses must include
the WWW-Authenticate header,
which you can see here,
is set to basic
realm application.
Basic means that
the given resource
uses HTTP basic authentication.
And realm application
means that the resource
is part of the
application realm.
Realms allow resources
to be partitioned
into different
protection spaces.
This means that each
realm can implement
its own authentication strategy.
In this example, we have three
different realms, episodes,
forum, and admin.
Each one of those might require
a different set of credentials.
So responding to
unauthorized requests,
including the specific realm,
might help the client figure
out what set of
credentials they need
to use for that specific
protection space.
We can respond to 401
requests with a custom realm
by passing the value of
the realm as the argument
to the authenticate or request
with HTTP basic method.
As you can see,
the response header
is properly set to
basic realm episodes.
We can also use curl to make
authenticated calls to our API
server.
And curl has built in
support for basic auth.
We can send basic
auth credentials
with a  -u option.
We could also send credentials
as part of the URL,
before the host name,
separated by a colon,
and ended by a
net sign, like so.
There are some limitations with
the authenticate or request
with HTTP basic method.
As you can see here, we're
making a curl request,
asking specifically
for JSON back,
but we're passing
invalid credentials.
We get a 401 unauthorized
response back,
but the content type is
set to text/HTML, which
might break some API clients.
One way we can fix that, is
by using the authenticate
with HTTP basic
method, which gives us
more control over the response.
So back in our
EpisodesController
we created before
action authenticate.
But instead, we call
authenticate basic auth
or render unauthorized.
The authenticate
basic auth method
calls authenticate
with HTTP basic, that
just like the
previous method, takes
a block with the
authentication strategy,
but instead it
returns a Boolean.
It does not halt the request.
And in our render
unauthorized method,
we must manually set the
WWW-Authenticate header
and we respond with the
proper content type.
Now, if we make the
same curl request
as we did before, we get a
response back with the content
type set to the proper media
type, application slash JSON.
Basic auth authentication is
simple but it's not secure.
Base64 credentials
can be easily decided.
Let's take a look at an example.
In this case, we have
user and password set
to carlos and secret.
We use a Rails
helper method encode
credentials to encode those.
We can then use the
base 64 decode 64 method
to decode those credentials.
And we have access to
the original credentials.
Anyone sniffing
the network traffic
can get access to your
encoded credentials
and use base 64 decode 64
to decode them, and then
have access to your actual
username and password.
We've reached the
end of the section
so get ready for some
challenges on basic auth.