Welcome back.
We're now going to look at
a second alternative for API
authentication, called
token based authentication.
Token based authentication
is when API clients
use a token identifier for
making authenticated HTTP
requests.
It has some benefits
over basic auth,
like more convenience, as we
can easily expire or regenerate
tokens, without affecting
the user's account password.
It's more secure,
even if compromised,
since vulnerability is
limited to the API access
and not to the user's
master account.
Also, it gives us
the ability to have
multiple tokens for
each user, which
they can use to grant access
to different API clients,
and greater control for each
token, so different access
rules can be implemented.
Just like we saw
with basic auth,
token authentication uses
the authorization header.
And this is what it looks like.
Authorization followed by
token with the token value.
There's currently a draft
for specifying HTTP token
based authentication.
For more info, visit
the following URL.
Having an API
client authenticate
using a token based
auth usually starts
with visiting a specific
services website
and getting access to
that specific token.
They're usually displayed on the
user profile page or settings
page.
Here's an example of getting
the access token from Backpack,
which is a service by 37Signals.
And this is the token that
we send in the Authorization
header.
So let's jump into our tests.
In the setup block, we
create a new user record.
Then, we test for a
valid authentication,
using the user token.
We make a get request to
/episodes and include the user
unique token at as part of
the Authorization header.
Then we check for a 200
response and for the content
type set to JSON.
For invalid authentication, if
we pass an invalid token, which
we are simulating by
appending a string fake,
we need to get back
a 401 status code.
The test's currently failing.
We move on to the
implementation.
In our user model, we'll add
a before_create callback,
called set_auth_token.
First thing we do it
our callback method,
is to check if an auth
token has already been set,
and return if so.
This is called a guard clause.
If not, we call the
generate auth token method.
It is required that
this token is unique,
because we're going
to use it to fetch
the user from our database.
So we need to make
sure that no other user
records have the same token.
So we're going to keep looping
until a unique token is
generated.
Now, let's move on to
our EpisodesController
and implement our
authentication there.
This looks very
similar to basic auth.
And rails also has
built in support
for token based authentication.
So we create a before_
action, call authenticate.
And inside of that method,
we use the authenticate
or requests with
http token, which
reads the token from
the authorization header
and passes it as an
argument to the block.
Inside of that block
we can use the token
to look for the user
in our database.
This code should be enough
to get our test to pass.
Now, let's go back
to our test file
and see how we can extract the
generation of our Authorization
header to our test helper.
So instead of hard coding the
format for the authorization
header, we're going to
create a method called
token_header, which states
the token as an argument.
We'll use the action controller,\HTTP authentication token,
and code credentials
method that returns
the proper value for
the token header.
And then we'll use that
from inside of our test.
Just like basic auth,
token based access also
uses realms for different
protection spaces.
In this example, a 401
unauthorized response
is return with the realm
set to application.
If we want to use a
custom realm instead,
we can pass that as an argument
to our authenticate or request
with http token method.
And it will be added
to the response
header for unauthorized
responses, as we can see below.
Our WWW-Authenticate header is
now set to the episodes realm
We could also use curl for token
based authentication, since it
allows us to pass
custom headers.
We can do that using
the -H option,
followed by the value
for the custom header.
In this case,
authorization token,
followed by the
value of our token.
And we get back a 200 response.
Our current solution is running
into the same limitations
that we just saw.
As you can see here
we have a curl request
that's using a fake token
and asking specifically
for application/json.
However, the response we
get back from the server
sets the content
type, to text/html.
We can fix that by replacing
our previous method
with a new authenticate with
http token method, which
reads the token from
the Authorization header
and simply returns a Boolean.
It does not halt the request.
Let's see how we can fix that.
In our EpisodesController,
we need
to make some changes
to our previous code.
We have our before action,
authenticate, and inside
of that method, we call
authenticate token method,
or render unauthorized.
Inside of authenticate
token, we use
authenticate with http token,
which reads the token off
of the Authorization header
and simply returns a Boolean.
It does not halt the request.
If the authentication
fails, then we
call a render unauthorized.
Inside of render
unauthorized, we manually
set the WWW-Authenticate
header and respond
with the proper media type.
Now, if we make the same curl
request as we did before,
we get a response back
with the content type
set to the proper media
type, application/json.
We've reached the
end of this level.
Now it's time for some
challenges on token based
authentication.